<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S961 IS: Data Security Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 961</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150415">April 15, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S277">Mr. Carper</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S342">Mr. Blunt</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To protect information relating to consumers, to require notice of security breaches, and for other
			 purposes. </official-title></form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short
 title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Data Security Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </section><section id="id0dcd173f09a64b70950c09c61601b64d"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purposes of this Act are—</text> <paragraph id="id56840AF020384B6C9F2C16C4C6F28816"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to establish strong and uniform national data security and breach notification standards for electronic data; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idC7D8C395A0EF415AB83419C7F6B56554"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to expressly preempt any related State laws in order to provide the Federal Trade Commission with authority to enforce such standards for entities covered under this Act.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="IDcc736290dda54fe1baca2d4a58b799a0"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For purposes of this Act, the following definitions shall apply:</text>
 <paragraph id="ID42e8c94e13d9418ba0c23faf6e156c80"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Affiliate</header><text>The term <term>affiliate</term> means any company that controls, is controlled by, or is under common control with another company.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idBB2BF34966DF46CD881CA65DE28BFC65"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Agency</header><text>The term <quote>agency</quote> has the same meaning as in section 551(1) of title 5, United States Code.</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="ID690a3dfc9dc646dea0a5d03a413ff7c8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Breach of data
			 security</header>
				<subparagraph id="ID81f6730ce88d4403983a99fb2a351588"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>The term <term>breach of data security</term> means the unauthorized acquisition of sensitive account information or sensitive personal information.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0a8f2698a5c7480fa3fb401041b271f5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception for data that is not in usable form</header><text>The term <term>breach of data security</term> does not include the unauthorized acquisition of sensitive account information or sensitive personal information that is encrypted, redacted, or otherwise protected by another method that renders the information unreadable and unusable if the encryption, redaction, or protection process or key is not also acquired without authorization.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id59f36d75734d407e876110b3ec695f1b"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Carrier</header><text>The term <term>carrier</term> means any entity that—</text> <subparagraph id="id0026C0459CC34DD6BD60A3F718CC610F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provides electronic data transmission, routing, intermediate, and transient storage, or connections to its system or network;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idBA971D72FCC34FCB8138DBFA2F2C3E99"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not select or modify the content of the electronic data;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA9A2C56D0D8B4AF6894DC77A44980EEB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is not the sender or the intended recipient of the data; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE3F7B93DE84F458093BE66122ABF33AE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>does not differentiate sensitive account information or sensitive personal information from other information that the entity transmits, routes, stores in intermediate or transient storage, or for which such entity provides connections.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID0f229ff306a442bdb22d640f9e4c4732"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Federal Trade Commission.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="IDed12d7acc594420285e9514e57e3a83d"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Consumer</header><text>The term <term>consumer</term> means an individual.</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="idBA6B4758051E4135B04D3F0B1F0CDE0F"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Consumer
			 reporting agency that compiles and maintains files on consumers on a
			 nationwide
 basis</header><text>The term <term>consumer reporting agency that compiles and maintains files on consumers on a nationwide basis</term> has the same meaning as in section 603(p) of the Fair Credit Reporting Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1681a">15 U.S.C. 1681a(p)</external-xref>).</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="IDa7b958d81aaa4c08a7b9f06045883521"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Covered
			 entity</header>
 <subparagraph id="idaf360bcd463848959f44f615df89b344"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>covered entity</term> means any individual, partnership, corporation, trust, estate, cooperative, association or entity that accesses, maintains, communicates, or handles sensitive account information or sensitive personal information.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id492205A1A0C74F19A9D12F22665A791C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The term <term>covered entity</term> does not include any agency or any other unit of Federal, State, or local government or any subdivision of the unit.</text>
				</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idBFE074F65B694446904EAF2BFC80E7FF"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Financial
 institution</header><text>The term <term>financial institution</term> has the same meaning as in section 509(3) of the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/6809">15 U.S.C. 6809(3)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id2e27df4d4ae04e919021437e4b00129a"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Information security program</header><text>The term <term>information security program</term> means the administrative, technical, or physical safeguards that a covered entity uses to access, collect, distribute, process, protect, store, use, transmit, dispose of, or otherwise handle sensitive account information and sensitive personal information.</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="ID3e2a1292061d482d95af3a06da975510"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Sensitive
 account information</header><text>The term <term>sensitive account information</term> means a financial account number relating to a consumer, including a credit card number or debit card number, in combination with any security code, access code, password, or other personal identification information required to access the financial account.</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="id4fd70b427b2d468eaa9ec3209dc5b456"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Sensitive personal information</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="id4b448ca4795d4900af1550e2b0585ffd"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>sensitive personal information</term> means—</text> <clause commented="no" id="id373ed775141e4574a67bda473c9f54f0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a Social Security number; or</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="idf1874518f9b2450d87384e18317ec752"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the first and last name of a consumer in combination with—</text> <subclause commented="no" id="ida317207b87114abbbbb99a3119e274a6"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the consumer’s driver’s license number, passport number, military identification number, or other similar number issued on a government document used to verify identity;</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="id807543a127084268a22f31185a08b2bd"><enum>(II)</enum><text>information that could be used to access a consumer’s account, such as a user name and password or e-mail and password; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="idcaab7dc8643c43959de0f84d3173f6e1"><enum>(III)</enum><text>biometric data of the consumer used to gain access to financial accounts of the consumer.</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idab679b3177b24e89988725591c061cd1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The term <term>sensitive personal information</term> does not include publicly available information that is lawfully made available to the general public and obtained from—</text>
 <clause id="ida97e5beee75948efb5320f3359e3febc"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Federal, State, or local government records; or</text> </clause><clause id="id04a4f5e20d404f24b74999b7ec5090ee"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>widely distributed media.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id8cd853e3eda54b3d942555ff4e386c5a"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Substantial harm or inconvenience</header><text>The term <term>substantial harm or inconvenience</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="idf4a9c79fd3184601b70c9de41b5c58d4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identity theft; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idef6111fb01b04e5db3352da34bc8f783"><enum>(B)</enum><text>fraudulent transactions on financial accounts.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9833f81b6a0e4107b7a27b416c2df811"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Third-party service provider</header><text>The term <term>third-party service provider</term> means any person that maintains, processes, or otherwise is permitted access to sensitive account information or sensitive personal information in connection with providing services to a covered entity.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="idbb2ff4984b924149a35f79c0c934e6d2"><enum>4.</enum><header>Protection of information and security breach notification</header>
			<subsection id="id25be0437abc6480ca97cea176b63fcd3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Security procedures required</header>
 <paragraph id="id0ee7b5c35e2c4d27b860ef84d5fef1bc"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each covered entity shall develop, implement, and maintain a comprehensive information security program that contains administrative, technical, and physical safeguards that are reasonably designed to achieve the objectives in paragraph (2).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id12f5e898de5d4d6f8de3a201f265dfb4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Objectives</header><text>The objectives of this subsection are to—</text> <subparagraph id="iddd6be04ff9354664a13af44710ed68cb"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ensure the security and confidentiality of sensitive account information and sensitive personal information;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4efdad43da8540be8ba52ef5ebc0d590"><enum>(B)</enum><text>protect against any anticipated threats or hazards to the security or integrity of such information; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd6d9869b8f3b4bd1a8fe40df6c689ffd"><enum>(C)</enum><text>protect against unauthorized acquisition of such information that could result in substantial harm to the individuals to whom such information relates.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id07b8ab33f9cf4eaa9c1b9d9bd9b34692"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>A covered entity’s information security program under paragraph (1) shall be appropriate to—</text> <subparagraph id="id09e1c3a4e6864c1bb3d0636a547bc43a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the size and complexity of the covered entity;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7269b70543fa4b4e8b7949b07b16449a"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the nature and scope of the activities of the covered entity; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idef30b9a8277c4b338f14a1f959bee4a7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the sensitivity of the consumer information to be protected.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id19f4695f010049ab81e065d629493112"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>In order to develop, implement, and maintain its information security program, a covered entity shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id0aa9b35482a34aa59eabc16aaef1ca2b"><enum>(A)</enum><text>designate an employee or employees to coordinate the information security program;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2af3d2f5eaec47eca2bcdbd148dd42bb"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identify reasonably foreseeable internal and external risks to the security, confidentiality, and integrity of sensitive account information and sensitive personal information and assess the sufficiency of any safeguards in place to control these risks, including consideration of risks in each relevant area of the covered entity’s operations, including—</text>
 <clause id="id877ace095b38484cae174d2adaf8a11c"><enum>(i)</enum><text>employee training and management;</text> </clause><clause id="id94d63d9d9bde484e85f19f5e1c5e30dd"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>information systems, including network and software design, as well as information processing, storage, transmission, and disposal; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id350140595238485cb780b131ae6b737d"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>detecting, preventing and responding to attacks, intrusions, or other systems failures;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida1160e9e64ec44edb1e020f56c66c7ea"><enum>(C)</enum><text>design and implement information safeguards to control the risks identified in its risk assessment, and regularly assess the effectiveness of the safeguards’ key controls, systems, and procedures;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4601a1bac5834ca090ee420c4d15227e"><enum>(D)</enum><text>oversee service providers by—</text> <clause id="ide3b1588523064a9aa1d1b72747c870f4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>taking reasonable steps to select and retain service providers that are capable of maintaining appropriate safeguards for the sensitive account information or sensitive personal information at issue;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id3e4f0c2fa1204249a9c27a83f27a1a3a"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>requiring service providers by contract to implement and maintain such safeguards; and</text> </clause><clause id="idd5ef579b64ac43abbf0d3e0da6490bfd"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>reasonably oversee or obtain an assessment of the service provider’s compliance with contractual obligations, where appropriate in light of the covered entity’s risk assessment; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9dc1345b6a33417886a8d942bd53c237"><enum>(E)</enum><text>evaluate and adjust the information security program in light of the results of the risk assessments and testing and monitoring required by subparagraphs (C) and (D) and any material changes to the covered entity’s operations or business arrangements, or any other circumstances that the covered entity knows or has reason to know may have a material impact on its information security program.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ida61182086b21426d85a8e9a1a4ecc37f"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Security controls</header><text>Each covered entity shall—</text> <subparagraph id="id00dc8928c2e5456dbae0dc0c15a87c60"><enum>(A)</enum><text>consider whether the following security measures are appropriate for the covered entity and, if so, adopt those measures that the covered entity concludes are appropriate—</text>
 <clause id="ida49fde0a93b1496ba8d791fee8af9775"><enum>(i)</enum><text>access controls on information systems, including controls to authenticate and permit access only to authorized individuals and controls to prevent employees from providing sensitive account information or sensitive personal information to unauthorized individuals who may seek to obtain this information through fraudulent means;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idf47e53b866844cf194ebba868b6bc00a"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>access restrictions at physical locations containing sensitive account information or sensitive personal information, such as buildings, computer facilities, and records storage facilities, to permit access only to authorized individuals;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id3ffdace3c2134e3cb25b75bc645bed0d"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>encryption of electronic sensitive account information or sensitive personal information, including while in transit or in storage on networks or systems to which unauthorized individuals may have access;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idde21876e26864bef86a5fecf84be9046"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>procedures designed to ensure that information system modifications are consistent with the covered entity’s information security program;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idff2de52272b8407a9ba8fa415dd2be31"><enum>(v)</enum><text>dual control procedures, segregation of duties, and employee background checks for employees with responsibilities for, or access to, sensitive account information or sensitive personal information;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id19eaee2c1148467dbd03bc965856b971"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>monitoring systems and procedures to detect actual and attempted attacks on, or intrusions into, information systems;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idc7dbe1f3db4145c1ba53e33dff7d2ec3"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>response programs that specify actions to be taken when the covered entity suspects or detects that unauthorized individuals have gained access to information systems; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id54c946a5a50942b5a962e22c11e23a40"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>measures to protect against destruction, loss, or damage of sensitive account information or sensitive personal information due to potential environmental hazards, such as fire and water damage or technological failures;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide46e4b1aeb9d43b1814c642929495466"><enum>(B)</enum><text>develop, implement, and maintain appropriate measures to properly dispose of sensitive account information and sensitive personal information; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc9d17cfaad5b4f3ebc43fc4dc31c0a7c"><enum>(C)</enum><text>train staff to implement the covered entity’s information security program.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id53c2aa55cc9545739f7af027d9dc269e"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Administrative requirements</header> <subparagraph id="idc4807cc08fa54d3f8c013cf3605abcc4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Board oversight</header><text>If a covered entity has a board of directors, the covered entity’s board of directors or an appropriate committee of the board shall—</text>
 <clause id="ida3cdd8fc55964c9697d90847b1ce06e0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>approve the covered entity’s written information security program; and</text> </clause><clause id="id86790a97995a47b7a8568011012f2be1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>oversee the development, implementation, and maintenance of the covered entity’s information security program, including assigning specific responsibility for its implementation and reviewing reports from management.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida5b3a00060324723ad801770cc4a7c69"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Report to the board</header><text>If a covered entity has a board of directors, the covered entity shall report to its board or an appropriate committee of the board at least annually, including describing—</text>
 <clause id="id0f7607eed0d349f6b461e5419ff456c2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the overall status of the information security program and the covered entity’s compliance with this Act; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id6262a1d4a90646349a1477205226dbbb"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>material matters related to its program, addressing issues such as risk assessment, risk management and control decisions, service provider arrangements, results of testing, security breaches or violations and management’s responses, and recommendations for changes in the information security program.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idd91df337d16447869850f21669f4ca38"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Investigation required</header>
 <paragraph id="idf73a71a930704c28a70853c57969136e"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If a covered entity believes that a breach of data security has or may have occurred in relation to sensitive account information or sensitive personal information that is maintained, communicated, or otherwise handled by, or on behalf of, the covered entity, the covered entity shall conduct an investigation to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idd0e95d96e2a6401589270118b7150431"><enum>(A)</enum><text>assess the nature and scope of the incident;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id377ac4610b1b417d95407a3312848e55"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identify any sensitive account information or sensitive personal information that may have been involved in the incident;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ided6d8c0b7e724ec6b9d46cc41c6890ae"><enum>(C)</enum><text>determine if the sensitive account information or sensitive personal information has been acquired without authorization; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id51ef018f5c6348c9a37ff3d2667d6ffc"><enum>(D)</enum><text>take reasonable measures to restore the security and confidentiality of the systems compromised in the breach.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4f940b7b9c804a0db161bafd11788196"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Notice required</header><text>If a covered entity determines under subsection (b)(1)(C) that the unauthorized acquisition of sensitive account information or sensitive personal information involved in a breach of data security is reasonably likely to cause substantial harm to the consumers to whom the information relates, the covered entity, or a third party acting on behalf of the covered entity, shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="ide28ee2f13f2843a49ae1c2ccf5a30fe1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>notify, without unreasonable delay—</text> <subparagraph id="id5425ddf632b24ef294dc235826e13f49"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an appropriate Federal law enforcement agency;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida1d2eb4c3f544f1cb674b0e06d054af8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the appropriate agency or authority identified in section 5;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7ae36171bbad4f07927ce3bcb6e3123c"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any relevant payment card network, if the breach involves a breach of payment card numbers;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf24a6d19af394e8784c45a540a484498"><enum>(D)</enum><text>each consumer reporting agency that compiles and maintains files on consumers on a nationwide basis, if the breach involves sensitive personal information or sensitive account information relating to 5,000 or more consumers; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idffc2fd34d3af41469fe2e31cd354910a"><enum>(E)</enum><text>all consumers to whom the sensitive account information or sensitive personal information relates;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="iddaf63686410d4a8180d60157dc9b7149"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide notice to consumers by—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idb7dc1f524a064c679fd5f8ae77a062ce"><enum>(A)</enum><text>written notification sent to the postal address of the consumer in the records of the covered entity;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida7d249a8bfc64b4a86edd7f716b1a6c0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>telephonic notification to the number of the consumer in the records of the covered entity;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1378e99a184a408da9910f14827db641"><enum>(C)</enum><text>e-mail of the consumer or other electronic means in the records of the covered entity; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide2f82bd289d544759e9231c080956b4d"><enum>(D)</enum><text>substitute notification in print and to broadcast media where the individual whose personal information was acquired resides, if providing written or e-mail notification is not feasible due to—</text>
 <clause id="idf084e4ce8c424d0794da0c73bbb81df4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>lack of sufficient contact information for the consumers that must be notified;</text> </clause><clause id="idd7373ffc10304bbc8f10815630d79b48"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>excessive cost to the covered entity; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="id6c7db5d9ddd344a0965214f106a83fe2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>exigent circumstances; and</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id48f95760230d4d9cb818a52c16bd57c5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provide notice that includes—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idd170dd4133d24feea628eb331f8982fc"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of the type of sensitive account information or sensitive personal information involved in the breach of data security;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7c17d376daa643a68b2afd5010b82cfa"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a general description of the actions taken by the covered entity to restore the security and confidentiality of the sensitive account information or sensitive personal information involved in the breach of data security; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4262b69a276d414881a006ca5c9e2b54"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a summary of rights of victims of identity theft prepared by the Commission under section 609(d) of the Fair Credit Reporting Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1681g">15 U.S.C. 1681g(d)</external-xref>), if the breach of data security involves sensitive personal information.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5e24284d44c54e949beae0a168745029"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Clarification</header><text>A financial institution shall have no obligation under this Act for a breach of security at another covered entity involving sensitive account information relating to an account owned by the financial institution.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="id2bac29b59cdc4b808ff3f872850b4a9f"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Special notification requirements</header>
 <paragraph id="idcd3597e4186941e5948fc78268d63d4d"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Third-party service providers</header><text>In the event of a breach of data security of a system maintained by a third-party entity that has been contracted to maintain, store, or process data in electronic form containing sensitive account information or sensitive personal information on behalf of a covered entity who owns or possesses such data, such third-party shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id6fb1a142603d4764b2abe0df4f72a067"><enum>(A)</enum><text>notify the covered entity; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfbc6791e2eae42d6a7e3bc64901c83ed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>notify consumers if it is agreed in writing that the third-party service provider will provide such notification on behalf of the covered entity.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id168a5a22bdf14e79938c9206bd3b23fd"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Carrier obligations</header>
 <subparagraph id="idd4cd92660fe446ccbb17e83c805fc6f0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If a carrier becomes aware of a breach of data security involving data in electronic form containing sensitive account information or sensitive personal information that is owned or licensed by a covered entity that connects to or uses a system or network provided by the carrier for the purpose of transmitting, routing, or providing intermediate or transient storage of such data, such carrier shall notify the covered entity who initiated such connection, transmission, routing, or storage of the data containing sensitive account information or sensitive personal information, if such covered entity can be reasonably identified. If a service provider is acting solely as a service provider for purposes of this subsection, the service provider has no other notification obligations under this section.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6e6aa5e7ef844afca38a232679c7dddd"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Covered entities who receive notice from carriers</header><text>Upon receiving notification from a service provider under paragraph (1), a covered entity shall provide notification as required under this section.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9d6323b414234a499e09cb67d2ae14b5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Communications with account holders</header><text>If a covered entity that is not a financial institution experiences a breach of data security involving sensitive account information, a financial institution that issues an account to which the sensitive account information relates may communicate with the account holder regarding the breach, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="ida6e8a88c007f48a1b7909e6dddc14cf5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an explanation that the financial institution was not breached, and that the breach occurred at a third-party that had access to the consumer’s sensitive account information; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0977b61fac1240f98d5de33299712ca3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identify the covered entity that experienced the breach after the covered entity has provided notice consistent with this Act.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id2a6a4e6d0c7b495fb77532fb9ea33f1e"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Compliance</header>
 <paragraph id="id747afdc08bea4f82a1cc10ea457b0042"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An entity shall be deemed to be in compliance with—</text> <subparagraph id="idee26e1fe2b334920bd947c02708f4f33"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of a financial institution—</text>
 <clause id="ida29e047aa64d4a279e23c675eee4129f"><enum>(i)</enum><text>subsection (a), if the financial institution maintains policies and procedures to protect the confidentiality and security of sensitive account information and sensitive personal information that are consistent with the policies and procedures of the financial institution that are designed to comply with the requirements of section 501(b) of the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/6801">15 U.S.C. 6801(b)</external-xref>) and any regulations or guidance prescribed under that section that are applicable to the financial institution; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id58e24810be7f4d298ce87e5f4c974213"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>subsections (b) and (c), if the financial institution—</text>
 <subclause id="id4a060a2477384858863f2a3aa1a7b795"><enum>(I)</enum><item commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id155C532EF18A4EFCB1FC11872C8E443A"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>maintains policies and procedures to investigate and provide notice to consumers of breaches of data security that are consistent with the policies and procedures of the financial institution that are designed to comply with the investigation and notice requirements established by regulations or guidance under section 501(b) of the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/6801">15 U.S.C. 6801(b)</external-xref>) that are applicable to the financial institution;</text>
 </item><item id="idbd91f4b3a8994a4fafe4169f8fadb530" indent="up1"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>is an affiliate of a bank holding company that maintains policies and procedures to investigate and provide notice to consumers of breaches of data security that are consistent with the policies and procedures of a bank that is an affiliate of the financial institution, and the policies and procedures of the bank are designed to comply with the investigation and notice requirements established by any regulations or guidance under section 501(b) of the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/6801">15 U.S.C. 6801(b)</external-xref>) that are applicable to the bank; or</text>
 </item><item id="id3b0264b5000d47e8b0f6032d5525fc41" indent="up1"><enum>(cc)</enum><subitem commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idD99155EF6DF849FBB9BD4C90BA8C07B1"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>is an affiliate of a savings and loan holding company that maintains policies and procedures to investigate and provide notice to consumers of data breaches of data security that are consistent with the policies and procedures of a savings association that is an affiliate of the financial institution; and</text>
 </subitem><subitem id="id1BDB7612D1D64E0796F0AE84A9A6D558" indent="up1"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>the policies and procedures of the savings association are designed to comply with the investigation and notice requirements established by any regulations or guidelines under section 501(b) of the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act (15 U.S. 6801(b)) that are applicable to savings associations; and</text>
 </subitem></item></subclause><subclause id="id1bd797a17594401287e0b71e2504855e"><enum>(II)</enum><text>provides for notice to the entities described under subparagraphs (B), (C), and (D) of subsection (c)(1), if notice is provided to consumers pursuant to the policies and procedures of the financial institution described in subclause (I); and</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id64faf4397be04e74901945e1431cb591"><enum>(B)</enum><text>subsections (a), (b), and (c)—</text> <clause id="id16292CB38B06402DA982A4A8C7591CAC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>if the entity is a covered entity for purposes of the regulations promulgated under section 264(c) of the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1320d-2">42 U.S.C. 1320d-2</external-xref> note), to the extent that the entity is in compliance with such regulations; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="idED147EECD5BC41D9B0856806F0E6F4F8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if the entity is in compliance with sections 13402 and 13407 of the HITECH Act (42 U.S.C. 17932 and 17937).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id12d918f3bc4d44cf8f9966a4c6edca22"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection—</text> <subparagraph id="id52e52607a26548aab25a1434bf3a78a8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the terms <term>bank holding company</term> and <term>bank</term> have the meanings given the terms in section 2 of the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1841">12 U.S.C. 1841</external-xref>);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9646c38dcecf4e08a286ec7cc1d26303"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the term <term>savings and loan holding company</term> has the meaning given the term in section 10 of the Home Owners’ Loan Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1467a">12 U.S.C. 1467a</external-xref>); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id09b5a6f2e8d847e68978eef0a184acfd"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the term <term>savings association</term> has the meaning given the term in section 2 of the Home Owners’ Loan Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1462">12 U.S.C. 1462</external-xref>).</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idf268614c4a264a62ae69751f59f6f1c2"><enum>5.</enum><header>Administrative enforcement</header>
 <subsection id="idca7a7be2bc8b4fe9b79a513f61234a08"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law section 4 shall be enforced exclusively under—</text> <paragraph id="id5ca8772ea9744e5aaa63fedac0be334a"><enum>(1)</enum><text>section 8 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1818">12 U.S.C. 1818</external-xref>), in the case of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idfefa99de232a4b3098938234a367a045"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a national bank, a Federal branch or Federal agency of a foreign bank, or any subsidiary thereof (other than a broker, dealer, person providing insurance, investment company, or investment adviser), or a savings association, the deposits of which are insured by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, or any subsidiary thereof (other than a broker, dealer, person providing insurance, investment company, or investment adviser), by the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idef4538c9ffa74006891aea742ed54a22"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a member bank of the Federal Reserve System (other than a national bank), a branch or agency of a foreign bank (other than a Federal branch, Federal agency, or insured State branch of a foreign bank), a commercial lending company owned or controlled by a foreign bank, an organization operating under section 25 or 25A of the Federal Reserve Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/601">12 U.S.C. 601</external-xref>, 611), or a bank holding company and its nonbank subsidiary or affiliate (other than a broker, dealer, person providing insurance, investment company, or investment adviser), by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id95858382133a4aa39c49018a0d4f7d13"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a bank, the deposits of which are insured by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (other than a member of the Federal Reserve System), an insured State branch of a foreign bank, or any subsidiary thereof (other than a broker, dealer, person providing insurance, investment company, or investment adviser), by the Board of Directors of the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idea526ae9f5454e8589c4797cc6fa9e2e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Federal Credit Union Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1751">12 U.S.C. 1751 et seq.</external-xref>), by the National Credit Union Administration Board with respect to any federally insured credit union;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id8d0c63c3c49e445bb4fa238ebfbe1201"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78a">15 U.S.C. 78a et seq.</external-xref>), by the Securities and Exchange Commission with respect to any broker or dealer;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id1ae973fcf8b242d1a104ccf77cd11801"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the Investment Company Act of 1940 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/80a-1">15 U.S.C. 80a–1 et seq.</external-xref>), by the Securities and Exchange Commission with respect to any investment company;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id68c5f7d18303469baaa9aed55ed57d26"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the Investment Advisers Act of 1940 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/80b-1">15 U.S.C. 80b–1 et seq.</external-xref>), by the Securities and Exchange Commission with respect to any investment adviser registered with the Securities and Exchange Commission under that Act;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id6f3d3005cd5249c9b7263e7aa9fc4249"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the Commodity Exchange Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1">7 U.S.C. 1 et seq.</external-xref>), by the Commodity Futures Trading Commission with respect to any futures commission merchant, commodity trading advisor, commodity pool operator, or introducing broker;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idcd0f3e03613942b8be74cb6bde4ab331"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the provisions of title XIII of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1992 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/4501">12 U.S.C. 4501 et seq.</external-xref>), by the Director of Federal Housing Enterprise Oversight (and any successor to the functional regulatory agency) with respect to the Federal National Mortgage Association, the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation, and any other entity or enterprise (as defined in that title) subject to the jurisdiction of the functional regulatory agency under that title, including any affiliate of any the enterprise;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id6e4e7291abdc446ab74c5c03be6c479c"><enum>(8)</enum><text>State insurance law, in the case of any person engaged in providing insurance, by the applicable State insurance authority of the State in which the person is domiciled; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id2bf5bc1d71f443248a9753ebe2ec764b"><enum>(9)</enum><text>the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>), by the Commission for any other covered entity that is not subject to the jurisdiction of any agency or authority described under paragraphs (1) through (8), including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id449f7773b86044daa15c3c45415b02ee"><enum>(A)</enum><text>notwithstanding section 5(a)(2) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/45">15 U.S.C. 45(a)(2)</external-xref>), common carriers subject to the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/151">47 U.S.C. 151 et seq.</external-xref>);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id24b5ac8de846484f94ea3724f2dc34ef"><enum>(B)</enum><text>notwithstanding the Federal Aviation Act of 1958 (49 U.S.C. App. 1301 et seq.), include the authority to enforce compliance by air carriers and foreign air carriers; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id592e3a80a58f4404b1252ead801ef35d"><enum>(C)</enum><text>notwithstanding the Packers and Stockyards Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/181">7 U.S.C. 181 et seq.</external-xref>), include the authority to enforce compliance by persons, partnerships, and corporations subject to the provisions of that Act.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id6305be68756c48f68e2301db58cb372e"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application to cable operators, satellite operators, and telecommunications carriers</header>
 <paragraph id="id76b2234ada8f49a6ae1b09a25375b46f"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Data security and breach notification</header><text>Sections 201, 202, 222, 338, and 631 of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/201">47 U.S.C. 201</external-xref>, 202, 222, 338, and 551), and any regulations promulgated in accordance with those sections, shall not apply with respect to the information security practices, including practices relating to the notification of unauthorized access to data in electronic form, of any covered entity otherwise subject to those sections.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idde991395db8c4f6b93d2f16c5b95caca"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this subsection otherwise limits authority of the Federal Communication Commission with respect to sections 201, 202, 222, 338, and 631 of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/201">47 U.S.C. 201</external-xref>, 202, 222, 338, and 551).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id208f44b834f94d5fa8b04d19aa30fea0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>No private right of action</header>
 <paragraph id="id720f8ffcc4ad4a119831dd5e040c4ca7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>This Act may not be construed to provide a private right of action, including a class action with respect to any Act or practice regulated under this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idafa3c216668b4074bfe66718bc03856f"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>A consumer or entity that suffers financial harm as a result of a covered entity’s violation of this Act may bring an action in a district court of the United States for the judicial district in which the consumer or entity suffered the harm against the covered entity to recover—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id7bddd35ecd7d4f08b7b1b3e072781934"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of a negligent violation of this Act, actual financial damages, court costs allowed by the rules of the court, and reasonable attorney’s fees; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida058c14e1a0d430aa69949fe8d74ca89"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of a knowing violation of this Act, the damages, costs, and attorney’s fees described in subparagraph (A) of this subsection and punitive damages.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idf5d7afe5db62473fb7e86a23ac1c32dd"><enum>6.</enum><header>Relation to State law</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No requirement or prohibition may be imposed under the laws of any State with respect to the responsibilities of any person to—</text>
 <paragraph id="idb8330a3f2ab94d98a6824f88a6e9e4ad"><enum>(1)</enum><text>protect the security of information relating to consumers that is maintained, communicated, or otherwise handled by, or on behalf of, the person;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idf65c2b00e57a41dc966c1c96ea292f71"><enum>(2)</enum><text>safeguard information relating to consumers from—</text> <subparagraph id="idfff6dccce62140fc8fd2722efe208e64"><enum>(A)</enum><text>unauthorized access; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1e9662239db14708a37a896e6c7963de"><enum>(B)</enum><text>unauthorized acquisition;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idf975038224f446d0bb1fa2765bcd37f1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>investigate or provide notice of the unauthorized acquisition of, or access to, information relating to consumers, or the potential misuse of the information, for fraudulent, illegal, or other purposes; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id01f422b4dd74491ebbc8c141634956c7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>mitigate any potential or actual loss or harm resulting from the unauthorized acquisition of, or access to, information relating to consumers.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="ida0e6f677ec194041a3ce9e6bc050f717"><enum>7.</enum><header>Delayed effective date for certain provisions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Sections 4 and 6 shall take effect 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act.</text> </section></legis-body></bill> 

