<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S46 IS: To reduce the amount of financial assistance provided to the Government of Mexico in response to the illegal border crossings from Mexico into the United States, which serve to dissipate the political discontent with the higher unemployment rate within Mexico.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 46</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150107">January 7, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S299">Mr. Vitter</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To reduce the amount of financial assistance provided to the Government of Mexico in response to
			 the illegal border crossings from Mexico into the United States, which
			 serve to dissipate the political discontent with the higher unemployment
			 rate within Mexico.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="idAEC2033B673347E0B1CD5E46CF6BDEAB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Border crossing
			 accountability</header><subsection id="idBF3FB8096ADC47358F5E0A22F6F8BC90"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Estimation of
 annual illegal border crossings</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the end of each fiscal year, the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of Homeland Security, shall estimate the number of illegal border crossings that occurred during such fiscal year along the southern land border of the United States.</text></subsection><subsection id="id52E5B94E37E74EED9EAEFCD7F8514A7B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reduction of
			 foreign assistance</header><paragraph id="id04211FB30C1E4F288FC3EFE0F7E72CA0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>Except as provided under paragraph (2), the Secretary of State, shall proportionately reduce the amount of financial assistance provided to the Government of Mexico for each fiscal year by a total of $1,000 for each illegal border crossing from Mexico to the United States during the previous fiscal year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idA844A8F904F24AB0A6B88344F94E3898"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Notwithstanding paragraph (1), the Secretary of State may decide not to reduce the amounts appropriated for the Government of Mexico from the International Military Education and Training Fund, the International Narcotics Control and Law Enforcement Fund, and the fund to carry out nonproliferation, anti-terrorism, demining, and related programs and activities.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


