<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S555 IS: Bringing Terrorists to Justice Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 555</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150305">February 25, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S350">Mr. Rubio</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S282">Mr. Nelson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S212">Mr. Coats</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S197">Mr. McCain</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S358">Mr. Flake</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S356">Mr. Donnelly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S355">Mr. Cruz</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S340">Ms. Ayotte</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Secretary of State to offer rewards for information on the kidnapping and murder of
			 James Foley, Peter Kassig, Steven Sotloff, Kayla Mueller, or
			 any other United States citizen by a foreign terrorist organization.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body>
 <section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Bringing Terrorists to Justice Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="idF46EEEFBC0264F43A04295162023CB9E" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Rewards authorized</header> <subsection id="id4107192A93424D5EA4F4972D947EAB25"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In accordance with the Rewards for Justice program authorized under section 36(b) of the State Department Basic Authorities Act of 1956 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2708">22 U.S.C. 2708(b)</external-xref>), the Secretary of State shall offer a reward to any individual who furnishes information leading to the arrest or conviction in any country of any individual for committing, conspiring or attempting to commit, or aiding or abetting in the commission of—</text>
 <paragraph id="id8b98a92c96b64917bf793c15683fd24a"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the kidnapping and murder of James Foley, Peter Kassig, Steven Sotloff, or Kayla Mueller; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id6e8d100fda7e477291928ea3b70b42f3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the kidnapping and murder, on or after the date of the enactment of this Act, of any other citizen of the United States by a foreign terrorist organization.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id83f8015debd64fd2b5e603e4bfe73977"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitations</header>
 <paragraph id="id89de74cf0a5e407c9a6872b0553e6eae"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Affiliates of foreign terrorist organizations</header><text>The Secretary of State shall not offer a reward under subsection (a) in connection with the kidnapping and murder of a citizen of the United States described in subsection (a)(2) who the Secretary of State determines was affiliated with or supportive of a foreign terrorist organization.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ide88befdf019f4ceb976d83b72fc613da"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Total awards for an individual</header><text>The total amount of rewards offered under subsection (a) in connection with the kidnapping and murder of any one of the individuals named in such subsection or any other citizen of the United States described in such subsection may not exceed $5,000,000.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idcf5fbe896c4148f1884418fd97a73da1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Foreign terrorist organization</header><text>The term <term>foreign terrorist organization</term> means an organization designated by the Secretary of State as a foreign terrorist organization in accordance with section 219 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1189">8 U.S.C. 1189</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


