<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1359 IS: E-Warranty Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>S. 1359</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150514">May 14, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S357">Mrs. Fischer</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S282">Mr. Nelson</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To allow manufacturers to meet warranty and labeling requirements for consumer products by displaying the terms of warranties on Internet websites, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H585F6ECF525D4713B984B4960C710912"> 
<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>E-Warranty Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="idc112e979231448edbd44074756f3b9a3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text> 
<paragraph id="id4b72f570e72e401d84569fa6cf8f610a"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Many manufacturers and consumers prefer to have the option to provide or receive warranty information online.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="id4ae5429f8ea742a4ac80dac4e2ba00b5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Modernizing warranty notification rules is necessary to allow the United States to continue to compete globally in manufacturing, trade, and the development of consumer products connected to the Internet.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="id6276c37bcbda451a8c08880bddc05e15"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Allowing an electronic warranty option would expand consumer access to relevant consumer information in an environmentally friendly way, and would provide additional flexibility to manufacturers to meet their labeling and warranty requirements.</text> </paragraph></section> <section id="id39fd24c17b50435985b7b5d0cdacfd7f"><enum>3.</enum><header>Electronic display of terms of written warranty for consumer products</header> <subsection id="id4CA01107F039411A9FB30D3D05B91C0A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 102(b) of the Magnuson-Moss Warranty—Federal Trade Commission Improvement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/2302">15 U.S.C. 2302(b)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idBA0092131342419CBF7758ABFD057EC0" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="id1B9ED37F413A418E87A1EBDB56752F73" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id27FA5DC287DF4417A7E53F0E8DFE95F4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the rules prescribed under this subsection shall allow for the satisfaction of all requirements concerning the availability of terms of a written warranty on a consumer product under this subsection by—</text> <clause id="id928FEB328BC94B0B98E98D32F63DDBEA" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>making available such terms in an accessible digital format on the Internet website of the manufacturer of the consumer product in a clear and conspicuous manner; and</text> </clause>
<clause id="id8AEB8FD9645D4D2B85824C26C170BE25" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>providing to the consumer (or prospective consumer) information with respect to how to obtain and review such terms by indicating on the product or product packaging or in the product manual—</text> <subclause id="idFFB1D5AF1BF14D43AF9E18CE198C173B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the Internet website of the manufacturer where such terms can be obtained and reviewed; and</text> </subclause>
<subclause id="idB5CAAF70083C45119638F40A503304F5"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the phone number of the manufacturer, the postal mailing address of the manufacturer, or another reasonable non-Internet based means of contacting the manufacturer to obtain and review such terms.</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id406603763282482386E14E3FA5947089" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>With respect to any requirement that the terms of any written warranty on a consumer product be made available to the consumer (or prospective consumer) prior to sale of the product, in a case in which a consumer product is offered for sale in a retail location, by catalog, or through door-to-door sales, subparagraph (A) shall only apply if the seller makes available at the location of the sale to the consumer purchasing the consumer product the terms of the warranty on the consumer product before the purchase.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection>
<subsection id="id5286F4EAD28144FBA97ED119A310D7C5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Revision of rules</header> 
<paragraph id="id282855D7BCFF42ACAD9EBA43267A6C28"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Federal Trade Commission shall revise the rules prescribed under such section to comply with the requirements of paragraph (4) of such section, as added by subsection (a) of this section.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="idA93E77AC483642AC976E223AF6E1C36F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authority to waive requirement for oral presentation</header><text>In revising rules under paragraph (1), the Federal Trade Commission may waive the requirement of section 109(a) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/2309">15 U.S.C. 2309(a)</external-xref>) to give interested persons an opportunity for oral presentation if the Commission determines that giving interested persons such opportunity would interfere with the ability of the Commission to revise rules under paragraph (1) in a timely manner.</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
</legis-body> 
</bill> 


