<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S81 IS: Nepal Trade Preferences Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 81</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150107">January 7, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S221">Mrs. Feinstein</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To authorize preferential treatment for certain imports from Nepal, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="id1CEC8F67998E45A394BFED7E8E22D203" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Nepal Trade Preferences Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="ID20203F026E4C42909836C945197C33C5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Eligibility
			 requirements</header><subsection id="id1CF3AFEC5DB045D5AEC413553AA1B946"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may authorize the provision of preferential treatment under this Act to articles that are imported directly from Nepal into the customs territory of the United States pursuant to section 3 if the President determines—</text><paragraph id="ID4EBD024455C24B24908CAD73FF70BADD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>that Nepal meets the requirements set forth in paragraphs (1), (2), and (3) of section 104(a) of the African Growth and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/3703">19 U.S.C. 3703(a)</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="ID3F218201BB804651834C6EA6298877C5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>after taking into account the factors set forth in paragraphs (1) through (7) of subsection (c) of section 502 of the <act-name parsable-cite="TA74">Trade Act of 1974</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/2462">19 U.S.C. 2462</external-xref>), that Nepal meets the eligibility requirements of such section 502.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="id136904FF95EB47F784831EAC8DD49017"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Withdrawal,
			 suspension, or limitation of preferential treatment; mandatory
 graduation</header><text>The provisions of subsections (d) and (e) of section 502 of the Trade Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/2462">19 U.S.C. 2462</external-xref>) shall apply with respect to Nepal to the same extent and in the same manner as such provisions apply with respect to beneficiary developing countries under title V of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/2461">19 U.S.C. 2461 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section><section id="ID767590BA1CDA46C28F401558EF2AD479"><enum>3.</enum><header>Eligible
			 articles</header><subsection id="IDBC6383761075477FB901FCB59AFF6825"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Certain
			 manufactured and other articles</header><paragraph id="IDEEECF22A8AB24E939CFEAFB4316FFC35"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>An article described in paragraph (2) may enter the customs territory of the United States free of duty.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id12403FE95A3744EEBC027A0D0D82D37A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Articles
			 described</header><subparagraph id="id849A6FF990EB4B57B090A1B5651A7771"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>An article is described in this paragraph if—</text><clause id="id5018147BACE14D548C0030A327DD24D5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the article is the growth, product, or manufacture of Nepal;</text></clause><clause id="id72E7D7F76CE44283A7E15C66840F64A0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the article is imported directly from Nepal into the customs territory of the United States;</text></clause><clause id="idEEDB886247B947AF90DE09CC5F026D17"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the article is described in subparagraphs (B) through (G) of subsection (b)(1) of section 503 of the <act-name parsable-cite="TA74">Trade Act of 1974</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/2463">19 U.S.C. 2463</external-xref>);</text></clause><clause id="id07CCB1A2489B42E089D01424D6798F16"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the President determines, after receiving the advice of the United States International Trade Commission in accordance with subsection (e) of that section, that the article is not import-sensitive in the context of imports from Nepal; and</text></clause><clause id="ID5D8FD61CE98C4CF5813293FD08F13DE4"><enum>(v)</enum><text>subject to subparagraph (C), the sum of the cost or value of the materials produced in, and the direct costs of processing operations performed in, Nepal or the customs territory of the United States is not less than 35 percent of the appraised value of the article at the time it is entered.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID5A2FB43D0DB14241A58B2403C491E5D2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusions</header><text>An article shall not be treated as the growth, product, or manufacture of Nepal for purposes of subparagraph (A)(i) by virtue of having merely undergone—</text><clause id="ID9F9FA8426C6A49AD8E7F8366A35DF787"><enum>(i)</enum><text>simple combining or packaging operations; or</text></clause><clause id="ID6A5E1B837A134AAF972D6A230A8AD65F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>mere dilution with water or mere dilution with another substance that does not materially alter the characteristics of the article.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8724EDC4EA444D93854709BA7563E26A"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Limitation on
 United States cost</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A)(v), the cost or value of materials produced in, and the direct costs of processing operations performed in, the customs territory of the United States and attributed to the 35-percent requirement under that subparagraph may not exceed 15 percent of the appraised value of the article at the time it is entered.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID2437027F0B0841BDAB439D1432FF1BCF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Textile and
			 apparel articles</header><paragraph id="idAA0B379CBCD5458FA3349302B7381ADD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>A textile or apparel article described in paragraph (2) or (3) may enter the customs territory of the United States free of duty.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ID78052FC7A65C445C9685ECBDF6FBE1B2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Textile and
			 apparel articles wholly assembled in Nepal</header><subparagraph id="ID856EC3C4105B4EEF996AC14946BA4904"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>A textile or apparel article is described in this paragraph if the textile or apparel article is—</text><clause id="idF32E7F0798264358A3063CF53E83BA4E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>wholly assembled in Nepal, without regard to the country of origin of the yarn or fabric used to make the articles; and</text></clause><clause id="id6604B0B0963D44ABA0EBC2BEB23D6B5A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>imported directly from Nepal into the customs territory of the United States.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="ID83D1B9C889B64605942398A9FB6ACC23"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitations</header><clause commented="no" id="ID632EC3E0FF834E57B50444011717BF44"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Low volume of
 imports</header><text>If, during a calendar year, imports of textile and apparel articles described in subparagraph (A) from Nepal are less than 1 percent of the aggregate square meter equivalents of all textile and apparel articles imported into the customs territory of the United States during that calendar year, such imports from Nepal may be increased to an amount that is equal to not more than 1.5 percent of the aggregate square meter equivalents of all textile and apparel articles imported into the customs territory of the United States during that calendar year for the succeeding calendar year.</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="ID873C63CE65AA4424A89CF0BF80ABCA91"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Higher volume
 of imports</header><text>If, during a calendar year, imports of textile and apparel articles described in subparagraph (A) from Nepal are at least 1 percent of the aggregate square meter equivalents of all textile and apparel articles imported into the customs territory of the United States during that calendar year, such imports from Nepal may be increased by an amount that is equal to not more than <fraction>1/3</fraction> of 1 percent of the aggregate square meter equivalents of all textile and apparel articles imported into the customs territory of the United States during that calendar year for the succeeding calendar year.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="IDA686EEBAE9DB4265BCB117E62ADFC254"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Aggregate
 country limit</header><text>In no case may the aggregate quantity of textile and apparel articles described in subparagraph (A) imported into the customs territory of the United States from Nepal during a calendar year under this subsection exceed the applicable percentage set forth in paragraph (4)(B) for that calendar year.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="IDFA720735361146BDB7698355117F4212"><enum>(3)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Handloomed, handmade, folklore articles and
			 ethnic printed fabrics</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID7D0B0AEC356E425A8BF7285ABB897452"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>A textile or apparel article is described in this paragraph if the textile or apparel article is—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idBD54B6DD545C432596A5FCD9B2235A23"><enum>(i)</enum><text>imported directly from Nepal into the customs territory of the United States;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id96723408155D411793345B4662ADAB6F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>on a list of textile and apparel articles determined by the President, after consultation with the Government of Nepal, to be handloomed, handmade, folklore articles or ethnic printed fabrics of Nepal; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id350F297AC3FC41FFB161E205FDF77ADA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>certified as a handloomed, handmade, folklore article or an ethnic printed fabric of Nepal by the competent authority of Nepal.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="IDEA93A3E2CC264BF0A53ABF2324BF1CA2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Ethnic printed
 fabric</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A), an ethnic printed fabric of Nepal is fabric—</text><clause id="ID0688AA7A642F488890DF1DAB78A12F82"><enum>(i)</enum><text>containing a selvedge on both edges and having a width of less than 50 inches;</text></clause><clause id="id5D0EF22A881B488A93B5AC4C71F44989"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>classifiable under subheading 5208.52.30 or 5208.52.40 of the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States;</text></clause><clause id="ID368278ADF0614211BC4A090A30B2CA39"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>of a type that contains designs, symbols, and other characteristics of Nepal—</text><subclause id="ID83E15D91B7004DB9898688AB7C409145"><enum>(I)</enum><text>normally produced for and sold in indigenous markets in Nepal; and</text></subclause><subclause id="ID92FB11D373984FFEA16A1A04438DB337"><enum>(II)</enum><text>normally sold in Nepal by the piece as opposed to being tailored into garments before being sold in indigenous markets in Nepal;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="ID61BF2E2D4AFC42A2B8AA46820E7E71D4"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>printed, including waxed, in Nepal; and</text></clause><clause id="ID78DB34BA06034C4392DAE391814E8A18"><enum>(v)</enum><text>formed in the United States from yarns formed in the United States or formed in Nepal from yarns originating in either the United States or Nepal.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="IDC624DC280273450FBA82634F22F6BBDF"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Limitations on
			 benefits</header><subparagraph id="ID72E694D15013483781DE8731AF1D418D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>Preferential treatment under this subsection shall be extended in the 1-year period beginning January 1, 2016, and in each of the succeeding 10 1-year periods, to imports of textile and apparel articles from Nepal under this subsection in an amount not to exceed the applicable percentage of the aggregate square meter equivalents of all textile and apparel articles imported into the customs territory of the United States in the most recent 12-month period for which data are available.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID1C7566E55D7E4F108BCC8778EE308A88"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Applicable
 percentage</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>applicable percentage</term> means 1.5 percent for the 1-year period beginning January 1, 2016, increased in each of the 10 succeeding 1-year periods by equal increments, so that for the 1-year period beginning January 1, 2025, the applicable percentage does not exceed 3.5 percent.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id690DE477467E40759A86E5A17FE60CC9"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Surge
 mechanism</header><text>The provisions of subparagraph (B) of section 112(b)(3) of the African Growth and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/3721">19 U.S.C. 3721(b)(3)</external-xref>) shall apply to textile and apparel articles imported from Nepal to which preferential treatment is extended under this subsection to the same extent and in the same manner that such provisions apply to textile and apparel articles described in such section 112(b)(3) and imported from a beneficiary sub-Saharan African country.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id12BEE941FB5440A69AFB9027AAFBA159"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Special
 eligibility rules; protections against transshipment</header><text>The provisions of subsection (e) of section 112 and section 113 of the African Growth and Opportunity Act (19 U.S.C. 3721 and 3722) shall apply to textile and apparel articles imported from Nepal to which preferential treatment is extended under this subsection to the same extent and in the same manner that such provisions apply to textile and apparel articles imported from beneficiary sub-Saharan countries to which preferential treatment is extended under such section 112.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ID95143B883BD946B2AE6B370D7ECE109D"><enum>4.</enum><header>Reporting
 requirement</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The President shall monitor, review, and report to Congress, not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, on the implementation of this Act and on the trade and investment policy of the United States with respect to Nepal.</text></section><section id="IDFB24827D5BAD498BB82E4E24D909B294"><enum>5.</enum><header>Termination of
 preferential treatment</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No preferential treatment extended under this Act shall remain in effect after December 31, 2025.</text></section><section id="ID516CD0B3941E46A5AEA065E3BB160AFA"><enum>6.</enum><header>Effective
 date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The provisions of this Act shall take effect on January 1, 2016.</text></section></legis-body></bill>


