<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S263 IS: To protect the right of individuals to bear arms at water resources development projects.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 263</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150127">January 27, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S266">Mr. Crapo</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S323">Mr. Risch</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEV00">Committee on Environment and Public Works</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To protect the right of individuals to bear arms at water resources development projects.</official-title>
	</form>
 <legis-body><section id="idD8AD9A2FA0844F72BCD65E0296BB2E69" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Protecting the Right of Individuals To Bear Arms at Water Resources Development Projects</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of the Army shall not promulgate or enforce any regulation that prohibits an individual from possessing a firearm, including an assembled or functional firearm, in any area open to the public (other than a Federal facility as defined in section 930(g) of title 18, United States Code) at a water resources development project covered under section 327.0 of title 36, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act), if—</text><paragraph id="id43d2c9178b624eee8e4c13172dd2bc31"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the individual is not otherwise prohibited by law from possessing the firearm; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0935c19cb038484da42d5382c7c1b0f8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the possession of the firearm is in compliance with the law of the State in which the water resources development project is located.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body>
</bill>


