<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S717 IS: Community Provider Readiness Recognition Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 717</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150311">March 11, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S356">Mr. Donnelly</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S376">Mrs. Ernst</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSVA00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To designate certain non-Department mental health care providers who treat members of the Armed
			 Forces and veterans as providers who have particular knowledge relating to
			 the provision of mental health care to members of the Armed Forces and
			 veterans, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Community Provider Readiness Recognition Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="id32B596943DFE4B39BC5F1CBC53561B37"><enum>2.</enum><header>Designation of certain non-Department mental health care providers with knowledge
			 relating to treatment of members of the Armed Forces and veterans</header>
			<subsection id="id18DC5ACFEA4C412AB583F459BCEAC466"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Mental health provider readiness designation</header>
 <paragraph id="id3EE5F66662634286B92C85F2A8B9CF62"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall jointly develop a system by which any non-Department mental health care provider that meets eligibility criteria jointly established by such Secretaries relating to the knowledge described in paragraph (2) receives a mental health provider readiness designation from the Department of Defense and the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id8A512BCC53614FD3970E719078373FAA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Knowledge</header><text>The knowledge described in this paragraph is the following:</text> <subparagraph id="id1D2B7C7827B6458F8022B3304658669F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Knowledge, comfort, and understanding with respect to the culture of members of the Armed Forces, veterans, and family members and caregivers of members of the Armed Forces and veterans.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7F616F83BE3D434092E29A6518497003"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Knowledge with respect to evidence-based treatments that have been approved by the Department of Defense and the Department of Veterans Affairs for the treatment of mental health issues among members of the Armed Forces and veterans.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idE77D1EECA4944CDCB497C0259E001171"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Availability of information on designation</header>
 <paragraph id="idBB2C5D9D03734989BF127E795304C8DC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Registry</header><text>The Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall jointly establish and update a registry that is available to the public of all non-Department mental health care providers that are currently designated under subsection (a)(1).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id6C747330E5CC480B93711F0CEFED0676"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Provider list</header><text>The Secretary concerned shall update all lists maintained by such Secretary of non-Department mental health care providers that provide mental health care under the laws administered by such Secretary by indicating the providers that are currently designated under subsection (a)(1); and</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idD4CF9B851BAE4E5CA9ACF1C56B86CC4D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idCDF4C92E359843DB8671970B6434CF4B"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Non-Department mental health care provider</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>non-Department mental health care provider</term>—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5C4C00EE48424C4AA15127AEE1F62BD7"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means a health care provider that—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF70AC1AD78AA40819386B340CD072CE5"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">specializes in mental health;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idEA9AB83719FB49298B21F33C00C75838"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is not a health care provider of the Department of Defense or the Department of Veterans Affairs; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id92DE2C6CBBD64224858F4159FF9EF0AA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provides health care to members of the Armed Forces or veterans; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idAB08104074104DDA8A0809D180A5BE1B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes psychiatrists, psychologists, psychiatric nurses, social workers, mental health counselors, marriage and family therapists, and other mental health care providers designated by the Secretary of Defense and Secretary of Veterans Affairs.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id836E6692ED754C7A9E5DFABF8EA4D35B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary concerned</header><text>The term <term>Secretary concerned</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="id04A102B3BFD6431CBE4BFDF45AB122C4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary of Defense with respect to matters concerning the Department of Defense; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idCBC043C98AA74D1EAFAA05556392FB44"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary of Veterans Affairs with respect to matters concerning the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


