<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1154 IS: Subsistence Access Management Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 1154</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150430">April 30, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S288">Ms. Murkowski</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To reverse the designation by the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture of
			 certain communities in the State of
			 Alaska as nonrural.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Subsistence Access Management Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </section><section id="idDE4672AB6128488C862D5BDC249841F4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definition of Secretaries</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <term>Secretaries</term> means the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture.</text> </section><section id="id4780EADAB40F44E59DD1FB33C976EBA2"><enum>3.</enum><header>Redesignation not authorized</header> <subsection id="idA53F53589A144DD4A47E72BCC06FF110"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, including any regulation, order, or policy, for purposes of administering the Federal Subsistence Management Program on public lands within the State of Alaska pursuant to the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/3101">16 U.S.C. 3101 et seq.</external-xref>), with respect to a community or area designated as rural by the Secretaries by regulation effective on or before May 6, 2007, the Secretaries may not, except pursuant to Act of Congress—</text>
 <paragraph id="id3DFD97C14F3F4BF8B57D28B7D017ADAB"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">redesignate the community or area as nonrural; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id3D8C6204151E4665A482194275894284"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">adjust the boundaries of a community or area to render some or all of that community or area nonrural.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idE20F9BA53E0E40F98A854E96F2FAC8DB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reinstatement of list</header>
 <paragraph id="idADA22F199C2643FEBAB58D2781C56A58"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The list of communities and areas designated rural (including the boundaries of those communities and areas) in effect on May 6, 2007, is reinstated.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id509304B0EA24492FBBB97089BEE4DB31"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effect</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as modified by Act of Congress, with respect to those communities and areas designated as rural, the list described in paragraph (1) shall be in effect as if the final rule entitled <quote>Subsistence Management Regulations for Public Lands in Alaska, Subpart C; Nonrural Determinations</quote> (72 Fed. Reg. 25688 (<added-phrase reported-display-style="italic"></added-phrase>May 7, 2007)) had not been issued.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id6E59BA245D694D32BC0A1DF0CD14CE62"><enum>4.</enum><header>Effect</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act prohibits the Secretaries from determining that, in accordance with regulations duly promulgated by the Secretaries—</text>
 <paragraph id="idC080E6098A3545F389975885629AAE95"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a community or area designated nonrural by the Secretaries should be redesignated as rural; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id32D089B301F740C388D70A80ABDBC7F7"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the boundaries of a community or area designated nonrural should be adjusted by the Secretaries to render some or all of that community or area rural.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="id56A57C58228B42C1981C6C4AB99D19B4"><enum>5.</enum><header>Publication of interim final rule, list</header>
 <subsection id="idD45C8644BD914C6EA2A1F9327D7220CD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Publication of interim final rule</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretaries shall publish an interim final rule amending any regulations inconsistent with this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id6919A9D2F1034D009D54032594214C00"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Publication of list</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Once each year after the publication under subsection (a), the Secretaries shall publish in the Federal Register a list of communities and areas (including the boundaries of those communities and areas) designated rural and nonrural in accordance with this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


