<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1421 IS: Orphan Product Extensions Now Accelerating Cures and Treatments Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1421</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150521">May 21, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S118">Mr. Hatch</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to authorize a 6-month extension of certain
			 exclusivity periods in the case of approved drugs that are subsequently
			 approved for a new indication to prevent, diagnose, or treat a rare
			 disease or condition, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H2FCC993E5CE9402CA82E15D6C15BB2DD" style="OLC">
 <section id="H983AD783F5C445AC96721C92A95252D4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Orphan Product Extensions Now Accelerating Cures and Treatments Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H34A6E0C5962046D3AF076237D7C0BF72"><enum>2.</enum><header>Extension of exclusivity periods for a drug approved for a new indication for a rare disease or condition</header> <subsection id="HC8D12657FF4847C5BDCD29EDF10CBE54"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Chapter V of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act is amended by inserting after section 505E the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H971E0CA019FE427C8F9957EA72FAEAD6" style="OLC">
					<section id="HCF607B784573413C8D6A80D62A896C91"><enum>505F.</enum><header>Extension of exclusivity periods for a drug approved for a new indication for a rare disease or
			 condition</header>
						<subsection id="H45B459E3AEA5467284C9437548825300"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation</header>
 <paragraph id="H9C63F60F8EB04506908560EFB0CA35B4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall designate a drug as a drug approved for a new indication to prevent, diagnose, or treat a rare disease or condition for purposes of granting the extensions under subsection (b) if—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H88DD8AD6EE0E4068853FF4AE87FBF387"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prior to approval of an application or supplemental application for the new indication, the drug was approved or licensed for marketing under section 505(c) of this Act or section 351(a) of the Public Health Service Act, but was not so approved or licensed for the new indication;</text>
								</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6098F963EFCD43018EA2C13185AB1B39"><enum>(B)</enum>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H0121A326B0074299A316CC04CCECF903"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the sponsor of the approved or licensed drug files an application or a supplemental application for approval of the new indication for use of the drug to prevent, diagnose, or treat the rare disease or condition; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HE09827231D434FD5ABAB24A616DAC02B" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Secretary approves the application or supplemental application; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3E3F6DA0F7D84CAB97C98701A9592789"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the application or supplemental application for the new indication contains the consent of the applicant to notice being given by the Secretary under paragraph (4) respecting the designation of the drug.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H115F02AAC0BA46A98BEA42CFBE38C499"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Revocation of designation</header>
 <subparagraph id="H653AD465777A4741B19154503125874B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), a designation under this subsection shall not be revoked for any reason.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEEE1F8A2AA87413E92C27F8473964747"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The Secretary may revoke a designation of a drug under paragraph (1) if the Secretary finds that the application or supplemental application resulting in such designation contained an untrue statement of material fact.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF3D906F7327148999E9582DFBD7FF360"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Notification prior to discontinuance of production for solely commercial reasons</header><text>A designation of a drug under paragraph (1) shall be subject to the condition that the sponsor of the drug will notify the Secretary of any discontinuance of the production of the drug for solely commercial reasons at least one year before such discontinuance.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H50AF3B3F09D546B18B6B64F963995463"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Notice to public</header><text>Notice respecting the designation of a drug under paragraph (1) shall be made available to the public.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC4BB40ECB2A742468DA708A14B5F388F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Extension</header><text>If the Secretary designates a drug as a drug approved for a new indication for a rare disease or condition, as described in subsection (a)(1)—</text>
							<paragraph id="H3473EEEB9693442898B0A5F156DE868C"><enum>(1)</enum>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HE9DACB807DBE493BAA13EF55AE82A6DF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the 4-, 5-, and 7<fraction>½</fraction>-year periods described in subsections (c)(3)(E)(ii) and (j)(5)(F)(ii) of section 505, the 3-year periods described in clauses (iii) and (iv) of subsection (c)(3)(E) and clauses (iii) and (iv) of subsection (j)(5)(F) of section 505, and the 7-year period described in section 527, as applicable, shall be extended by 6 months; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA00BA50C7E354581A28236F8A16CDB07" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the 4- and 12-year periods described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of section 351(k)(7) of the Public Health Service Act and the 7-year period described in section 527, as applicable, shall be extended by 6 months; and</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0E8E7D5FE25948AC9269001046F05CA5"><enum>(2)</enum>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H7E95EC3DA6214F52A2D6F6347957EE1C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>if the drug is the subject of a listed patent for which a certification has been submitted under subsection (b)(2)(A)(ii) or (j)(2)(A)(vii)(II) of section 505 or a listed patent for which a certification has been submitted under subsections (b)(2)(A)(iii) or (j)(2)(A)(vii)(III) of section 505, the period during which an application may not be approved under section 505(c)(3) or section 505(j)(5)(B) shall be extended by a period of 6 months after the date the patent expires (including any patent extensions); or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H39959FD479D343548937A76EE24368C8" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if the drug is the subject of a listed patent for which a certification has been submitted under subsection (b)(2)(A)(iv) or (j)(2)(A)(vii)(IV) of section 505, and in the patent infringement litigation resulting from the certification the court determines that the patent is valid and would be infringed, the period during which an application may not be approved under section 505(c)(3) or section 505(j)(5)(B) shall be extended by a period of 6 months after the date the patent expires (including any patent extensions).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HED83CE773C624083A33F54C3D683F39B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Relation to pediatric and qualified infectious disease product exclusivity</header><text>Any extension under subsection (b) of a period shall be in addition to any extension of the periods under sections 505A and 505E of this Act and section 351(m) of the Public Health Service Act, as applicable, with respect to the drug.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2447C40A6AEF461FAF388ACBADC66071"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitations</header><text>The extension described in subsection (b) shall not apply if the drug designated under subsection (a)(1) has previously received an extension by operation of subsection (b).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H67D5E4E2953243B2AED5EB78C6D3706C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <term>rare disease or condition</term> has the meaning given to such term in section 526(a)(2).</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="H61E07429A90443569A05AEA09D542964"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 505F of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act, as added by subsection (a), applies only with respect to a drug for which an application or supplemental application described in subsection (a)(1)(B)(i) of such section 505F is first approved under section 505(c) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355">21 U.S.C. 355(c)</external-xref>) or section 351(a) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/262">42 U.S.C. 262(a)</external-xref>) on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H7F29BB10676D41F2AF7DF3A138EC5BB1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header>
 <paragraph id="H4A79320A21104AF3AE17466AFCFFAD3D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Relation to pediatric exclusivity for drugs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 505A of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355a">21 U.S.C. 355a</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H192CDAF830284F2C974725B3EBD0AE73"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (b), by adding at the end the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3C641A26B36E46989DD0C3698CBBEC3F" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H5B05A0A336D9484C898FC0C5C7158013"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Relation to exclusivity for a drug approved for a new indication for a rare disease or condition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding the references in subsection (b)(1) to the lengths of the exclusivity periods after application of pediatric exclusivity, the 6-month extensions described in subsection (b)(1) shall be in addition to any extensions under section 505F.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBE1BE9CC352D4389BCB377E4BC936781"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (c), by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0B458B1205244F1094DF6BC9BC294B91" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H47FBDF1F10F1422BAF8543797BC876F5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Relation to exclusivity for a drug approved for a new indication for a rare disease or condition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding the references in subsection (c)(1) to the lengths of the exclusivity periods after application of pediatric exclusivity, the 6-month extensions described in subsection (c)(1) shall be in addition to any extensions under section 505F.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2B142B37D42E495DA75E47ABE022A2D2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Relation to exclusivity for new qualified infectious disease products that are drugs</header><text>Subsection (b) of section 505E of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355f">21 U.S.C. 355f</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H337BCBFE8A6C4CE298C5B4C99BCA2EC6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by amending the subsection heading to read as follows: <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Relation to pediatric exclusivity and exclusivity for a drug approved for a new indication for a rare disease or condition</header-in-text></quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7C28EE1C8D084B159A4EAD0E94D7B99E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>any extension of the period under section 505A</quote> and inserting <quote>any extension of the periods under sections 505A and 505F, as applicable,</quote>.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H00D2DCC0A70A4168AC7D6E4B31DF8B01"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Relation to pediatric exclusivity for biological products</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 351(m) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/262">42 U.S.C. 262(m)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3D0B57ADBEB74BC4A3FB63593F8AE5F1" style="OLC">
						<paragraph id="H15C409330F4C4376A291A4DF99BF0497"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Relation to exclusivity for a biological product approved for a new indication for a rare disease
 or condition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding the references in paragraphs (2)(A), (2)(B), (3)(A), and (3)(B) to the lengths of the exclusivity periods after application of pediatric exclusivity, the 6-month extensions described in such paragraphs shall be in addition to any extensions under section 505F.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


