<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1945 IS: Mental Health Reform Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-08-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 1945</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150805">August 5, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S373">Mr. Cassidy</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S364">Mr. Murphy</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S252">Ms. Collins</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To make available needed psychiatric, psychological, and supportive services for individuals with
			 mental illness and families in mental health crisis, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header>
 <subsection id="id09C27259770B4EE49109484083FF1346"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text>This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Mental Health Reform Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id7DBB8ACD6885472E9DA0DC25F9ECC9F1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents of this Act is as follows:</text><toc><toc-entry idref="S1" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="idf003af47c9184b71aa9f38184b853912" level="section">Sec. 2. Definitions.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id5cebced9c04a4442bf4c9779bb014f09" level="title">TITLE I—Assistant secretary for mental health and substance use disorders</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id72a8881cfa7d498aa40e21944c24b419" level="section">Sec. 101. Assistant Secretary for mental health and substance use disorders.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id30545323e5714347b3b7e01a36ca0490" level="section">Sec. 102. Reports.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="ida0b6024200f14229b71d0a0ec340b405" level="section">Sec. 103. Advisory Council on graduate medical education.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id61b2ac7dd7fd4999943ef68a7f213f86" level="title">TITLE II—Grants</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id3735092ed5b74482b9a249851b966cdf" level="section">Sec. 201. National Mental Health Policy Laboratory.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id3d52bb34b4ca4124b3bc8fa96fd1a7ec" level="section">Sec. 202. Innovation grants.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id7183d52c0cd64d41bc57d28f9bc646e7" level="section">Sec. 203. Demonstration grants.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id55b78f6e6abf4167898d03957ec195d5" level="section">Sec. 204. Early childhood intervention and treatment.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id22721271b5144c29b78f901d17e6cc3f" level="section">Sec. 205. Extension of assisted outpatient treatment grant program for individuals with serious mental illness.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id60fd309f96d1421a95b5254c6ef8f16c" level="section">Sec. 206. Block grants.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id9134326ab85140bc81dff07f82971bba" level="section">Sec. 207. Telehealth child psychiatry access grants.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="ide35d7b3faadf41499e5ee0e38f3e5fa9" level="section">Sec. 208. Liability protections for health care professional volunteers at community health centers and community mental health centers.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id69ad84197df14ba1aef3e6ff656e5237" level="section">Sec. 209. Minority fellowship program.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="idc4d7277873764ca5aa39bb56d3460cbd" level="section">Sec. 210. National health service corps.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="idf709008319ec41e0b068bd5f08b7bc04" level="section">Sec. 211. Reauthorization of mental and behavioral health education training grant.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id9441DCD4B4FB4B3AB8BFE8CBFCACAF0A" level="section">Sec. 212. National suicide prevention lifeline program.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id7EEC5D77C2034FABA9166998E79BE3DA" level="title">TITLE III—Integration</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="idB4D82A82D2464DA8976B493B13CF72CD" level="section">Sec. 301. Primary and behavioral health care integration grant programs.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id028d1c5ad81048ddbcb0cc1d9f689ac1" level="title">TITLE IV—Interagency Serious Mental Illness Coordinating Committee</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id070f7536d6fd40358c98515bb5c8d4cc" level="section">Sec. 401. Interagency Serious Mental Illness Coordinating Committee.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id3c4b405089064847b26a80e419fa76f4" level="title">TITLE V—HIPAA clarification</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id36252dd681f04c889eab709f37ec3974" level="section">Sec. 501. Findings.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id89d20b2b5ba5435cb77fb93434bab1d7" level="section">Sec. 502. Modifications to HIPAA.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id01d38e7509b34f4d8740766e0937591f" level="section">Sec. 503. Development and dissemination of model training programs.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id4ba115d9fb14490ba3c3c15bc94d31c3" level="section">Sec. 504. Confidentiality of records.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="idbccd2865c58b4ea0995586c34baebca5" level="title">TITLE VI—Medicare and Medicaid Reforms</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id14dda1811fb44234a9403cd6057f67aa" level="section">Sec. 601. Enhanced Medicaid coverage relating to certain mental health services.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id3bbb7baca82943788a58a8759773984c" level="section">Sec. 602. Modifications to Medicare discharge planning requirements.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id494a8e8791e24a1ba7c189fa9dad3290" level="title">TITLE VII—Research by National Institute of Mental Health</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id7d85ae30c3b740ea9f118c29b0e19e86" level="section">Sec. 701. Increase in funding for certain research.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id7900a7b90ad445669976d98a9e521a42" level="title">TITLE VIII—SAMHSA reauthorization and reforms</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="ide047b912c6044389b01146b7ce564587" level="subtitle">Subtitle A—Organization and general authorities</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="idd86b7d618d9a4afe8bd12bc30a84a935" level="section">Sec. 801. Peer review.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="idb080460b50144c93891a73e6444a3054" level="section">Sec. 802. Advisory councils.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="idc62cda6ad5f64b9288a0cb42c9a05397" level="section">Sec. 803. Grants for jail diversion programs reauthorization.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id4eba022032d840eb92c332525de2e8f2" level="section">Sec. 804. Projects for assistance in transition from homelessness.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id8f9c29e0777b4e7b8794b76d78ebecea" level="section">Sec. 805. Comprehensive community mental health services for children with serious emotional disturbances.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="ide1c0053de9284f35a6e02e2700fda6af" level="section">Sec. 806. Reauthorization of priority mental health needs of regional and national significance.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="ida421aa4b4470423fb9886bb03e82c2f2" level="title">TITLE IX—Mental health parity</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id591a7739c81548da96b46f84ccae8e0e" level="section">Sec. 901. GAO study on preventing discriminatory coverage limitations for individuals with serious mental illness and substance use disorders.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="iddf9ba573651d41259c6b0a3a543637e1" level="section">Sec. 902. Report on investigations regarding parity in mental health and substance use disorder benefits.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="idA3F7DA383FFF4393BC60C8DF5C2A6CF3" level="section">Sec. 903. Strengthening parity in mental health and substance use disorder benefits.</toc-entry> </toc> </subsection></section><section id="idf003af47c9184b71aa9f38184b853912"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
 <paragraph id="idbcc1dcafc4b04302ac2dae972b6feabb"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Assistant Secretary</header><text>Except as otherwise specified, the term <term>Assistant Secretary</term> means the Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use Disorders.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idc9f8304deaf34f18af2698e01c42e0dc"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Evidence-based</header><text>The term <term>evidence-based</term> means the conscientious, systematic, explicit, and judicious appraisal and use of external, current, reliable, and valid research findings as the basis for making decisions about the effectiveness and efficacy of a program, intervention, or treatment.</text>
			</paragraph></section><title id="id5cebced9c04a4442bf4c9779bb014f09"><enum>I</enum><header>Assistant secretary for mental health and substance use disorders</header>
			<section id="id72a8881cfa7d498aa40e21944c24b419"><enum>101.</enum><header>Assistant Secretary for mental health and substance use disorders</header>
 <subsection id="idebc2f1e3d10d48bead2f6b99b14fd69c"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There shall be in the Department of Health and Human Services an official to be known as the Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use Disorders, who shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="idf236c227a67e439a886178a0f23f5767"><enum>(1)</enum><text>report directly to the Secretary;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idc57fae7a571041618693eb7ed9af21c7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idc17e3e3cccc847749d8e3adbf163c874"><enum>(3)</enum><text>be selected from among individuals who—</text> <subparagraph id="idc4d9959bc7bd43e3b892697568cf873b"><enum>(A)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idC76B0A2F7F364A1A80AE89C16F32A42E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>have a doctoral degree in medicine or osteopathic medicine;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idBEF0FF36BD374F148F60F3368D1B8AEE" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>have clinical, research, and policy experience in psychiatry;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idF8A8AE5C51544B69A89097C26B1FD418" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>graduated from an Accreditation Council for Graduate Medical Education-accredited psychiatric residency program; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id3A0C775452A64286851F3D9AE9D57075" indent="up1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>have an understanding of biological, psychosocial, and pharmaceutical treatments of mental illness and substance use disorders;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0af27af284d249f8b6c553cad13d4795"><enum>(B)</enum><text>have a doctoral degree in psychology and—</text> <clause id="idfacb1cbb3313474485c4a9feb324c51c"><enum>(i)</enum><text>clinical, research, and policy experience regarding mental illness and substance use disorders;</text>
 </clause><clause id="ida625511bd2fc4100b758b02d4f80f2ab"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>have completed an internship with an organization that is a member of the Association of Psychology Post-doctoral and Internship Centers as part of doctoral degree completion; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id8308bbaa37b543b388d59af073dc1359"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an understanding of biological, psychosocial, and pharmaceutical treatments of mental illness and substance use disorders; or</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida4a246207c1244ef958cc86d558f3569"><enum>(C)</enum><text>have a doctoral degree in social work and—</text> <clause id="id5f0f2348aa2f4fa4b618ca84d701074b"><enum>(i)</enum><text>clinical, research, and policy experience regarding mental illness and substance use disorders; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="ide421061cbe904de7ba18a4c87831fedf"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an understanding of biological, psychosocial, and pharmaceutical treatments of mental illness and substance use disorders.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id2d93bbe3712c4a58bc97780a8568a304"><enum>(b)</enum><header>SAMHSA Administrator</header><text>Section 501(c)(1) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290aa">42 U.S.C. 290aa(c)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate</quote> and inserting <quote>, and serve under, the Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use Disorders</quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="id0512a558646a455fb18d9bcdae99277d"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Assistant Secretary shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="id929ecda22b4949729831c37f1cf2f386"><enum>(1)</enum><text>promote, evaluate, organize, integrate, and coordinate research, treatment, and services across departments, agencies, organizations, and individuals with respect to the problems of individuals suffering from substance use disorders or mental illness;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id518227ec78694f87b9a7e75020637eb9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>carry out any functions within the Department of Health and Human Services—</text> <subparagraph id="idff49aa2c7ace48e2a7ac56f33c0ee58f"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to improve services for individuals with substance use disorders or mental illness, including services related to the prevention of, diagnosis of, intervention in, and treatment and rehabilitation of, substance use disorders or mental illness;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id06cf99c129fd4b10832c4419757d4fa1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to ensure access to effective, evidence-based diagnosis, prevention, intervention, treatment and rehabilitation for individuals with mental illnesses and individuals with a substance use disorder;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id94c5a5f501a74fa982bf7fa589762b4b"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to ensure that all grants with respect to serious mental illness or substance use disorders, are consistent with the grant management standards set forth by the Department, and that such grants are evidence-based, have scientific merit and avoid duplication;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8c79f93fff5b4d9aa7b161f32c99e0c6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to develop and implement initiatives to encourage individuals to pursue careers (especially in underserved areas and populations) as psychiatrists, psychologists, psychiatric nurse practitioners, clinical social workers, and other licensed mental health professionals specializing in the diagnosis, evaluation, and treatment of individuals with severe mental illness;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfc97eea352634a52b16d3bc2fba3397b"><enum>(E)</enum><text>to consult, coordinate with, facilitate joint efforts among, and support State, local, and tribal governments, nongovernmental entities, and individuals with a mental illness, particularly individuals with a serious mental illness and children and adolescents with a serious emotional disturbance, with respect to improving community-based and other mental health services;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id92c2df0428a54e90b1eeb8df1ff676b8"><enum>(F)</enum><text>to disseminate evidenced-based and promising best practices developed by the National Mental Health Policy Lab established under section 201 and other qualified research organizations that are culturally and linguistically indicated treatment and prevention services related to a mental illness, particularly individuals with a serious mental illness and children and adolescents with a serious emotional disturbance; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idFB5BFDCD05EF459E811B020A14D2CD0D"><enum>(G)</enum><text>to develop criteria for the application of best practices within the mental health and substance use disorder service delivery system;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id89ce66938c1a4d598fedae1c6a0b551f"><enum>(3)</enum><text>within the Department of Health and Human Services, oversee and coordinate all programs and activities relating to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idf53b399404a04a608c72d72a83372b04"><enum>(A)</enum><text>diagnosis, prevention, intervention, treatment, rehabilitation with respect to mental health or substance use disorders;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddcf6a134f6fa411b9e966e425a1cbb56"><enum>(B)</enum><text>parity in health insurance benefits and conditions relating to mental health and substance use disorders; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id60ea0a893f414a71b45e6073aef16a70"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the reduction of homelessness and incarceration among individuals with mental health and substance use disorders;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5609920bc14f44a2adb5e7824d0e983b"><enum>(4)</enum><text>make recommendations to the Secretary of Health and Human Services regarding public participation in decisions relating to mental health, including serious mental illness, and serious emotional disturbances across the lifespan;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id90678b3c1bc74ad0a47a09479f7c389c"><enum>(5)</enum><text>review and make recommendations with respect to the Department of Health and Human Services budget to ensure the adequacy of such budget;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id277e334427ea46f39fa31e94bb0960c8"><enum>(6)</enum><text>across the Federal Government, in conjunction with the Interagency Serious Mental Illness Coordinating Committee under section 501A of the Public Health Service Act (as added by section 401)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="ida2cdd77774b747369fa365788adbff58"><enum>(A)</enum><text>review all programs and activities relating to the diagnosis or prevention of, or treatment or rehabilitation for, mental illness or substance use disorders;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddac4c22950a44ba9832591d2408cf330"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identify any such programs and activities that are duplicative;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide3f7db71503f491d91466f2c5f7cde5e"><enum>(C)</enum><text>identify any such programs and activities that are not evidence-based, effective, or efficient; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide5c3ed4724e241f0910676ec671ebf5e"><enum>(D)</enum><text>formulate recommendations for expanding, coordinating, eliminating, and improving programs and activities identified pursuant to subparagraphs (B) and (C) and merging such programs and activities into other, successful programs and activities;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id2d836c21a32b457aa973a552f5abcdac"><enum>(7)</enum><text>identify evidence-based and promising best practices across the Federal Government for treatment and services for individuals with mental health and substance use disorders by reviewing practices for efficiency, effectiveness, quality, coordination, and cost effectiveness; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id248dd40d52f34a66a6d7f7cc54a03061"><enum>(8)</enum><text>not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act and every 2 years thereafter, submit to Congress a report containing a nationwide strategy to recruit, train, and increase the mental health workforce for the treatment of individuals with mental illness, serious mental illness, substance use disorders, and co-occurring disorders.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id64bb5389c2f24480bfced87e988d0d1a"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Nationwide strategy</header><text>The Assistant Secretary shall ensure that the nationwide strategy in the report under subsection (c)(8) is designed—</text>
 <paragraph id="id67f74b82b9f54bd396d8a53116a31d3a"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to encourage and incentivize students enrolled in an accredited medical or osteopathic school, or nursing, psychology, or social work graduate program, to specialize in the mental health field;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id847af4c0b4004b9fbe56f70b9c3bf13b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to promote greater research-oriented psychiatric, psychological, nursing, and social work training on evidence-based service delivery models for individuals with mental illness or substance use disorders, including models with family participation;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id8898e6f5c27343b2aa80bcb7b5725810"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to promote appropriate Federal administrative and fiscal mechanisms that support—</text> <subparagraph id="id71a5665320cc475c8d1d6dd051e2039a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>evidence-based collaborative care models; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf29047325ddf4cd09c718fc5938ea6d0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the necessary mental health workforce capacity for the models under subparagraph (A), including psychiatrists, child and adolescent psychiatrists, psychologists, psychiatric nurse practitioners, clinical social workers, and mental health, peer-support specialists;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5f6edbbf40d74b49bd2d55a8cc48a21f"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to increase access to child and adolescent psychiatric services in order to promote early intervention for prevention and mitigation of mental illness;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id27e7cc0caa534c199874cfb25bac4ee4"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to identify populations and locations that are the most underserved by mental health professionals, including psychiatrists, child and adolescent psychiatrists, psychologists, psychiatric nurse practitioners, clinical social workers, other licensed mental health professionals, and peer-support specialists; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idF23EF8B593C04A8491DFC393A39E6C05"><enum>(6)</enum><text>to identify means of alleviating the strain on the budgets of the criminal justice and correctional systems and the capacity of such systems with respect to mental health and substance use disorders.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id854b1415adcc438ca5154b0b4e9acf4f"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Prioritization of integration of services, early diagnosis, intervention, and workforce development</header><text>In carrying out the duties described in subsection (c), the Assistant Secretary—</text> <paragraph id="id646313086E3A4E34BD762DA42592ACAE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall prioritize—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id2ce14abb132f454484a5aea8a1d09ab4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the integration of mental health, substance use, and physical health services for the purpose of diagnosing, preventing, treating, and providing rehabilitation for mental illness or substance use disorders, including any such services provided through the justice system (including departments of correction) or entities other than the Department of Health and Human Services;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbd0baf0e521c4c129dd4832a94877880"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the early diagnosis and intervention services for the prevention of, or crisis intervention for, and treatment or rehabilitation for, serious mental health disorders or substance use disorders, in selecting evidence-based practices and service delivery models for evaluation and dissemination under section 201(a)(2)(C); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idef5227b4776f47198b93eb9cdc45d791"><enum>(C)</enum><text>workforce development for—</text> <clause id="id5990d20957ac4791bceaf0c62c91b07d"><enum>(i)</enum><text>appropriate treatment of serious mental illness or substance use disorders;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id21249ddb59fb4598802bea7374a9bfa6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>research activities that advance scientific and clinical understandings of serious mental illness or substance use disorders; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idD30F4C01E343410687859AADD5A2646F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>increasing the number of mental health professionals, including psychiatrists, child and adolescent psychiatrists, psychologists, psychiatric nurse practitioners, clinical social workers, and mental health peer support specialists;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id64d63623923246c3a826e78852d2b841"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall give preference to models that improve the coordination, quality, and efficiency of health care services furnished to individuals with serious mental illness; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idabb88d111ca949c5979e680dbee9f66a"><enum>(3)</enum><text>may include clinical protocols and practices used in the Recovery After an Initial Schizophrenia Episode project of the National Institute of Mental Health or similar models, such as the Specialized Treatment Early in Psychosis program.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id30545323e5714347b3b7e01a36ca0490"><enum>102.</enum><header>Reports</header>
				<subsection id="id09b0ad7ee6a64cf78800350343a84a17"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report on best practices for peer-Support specialist programs, training, and certification</header>
 <paragraph id="ida2fe12a6f99044968e4a7c9ce3ea0ed0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, and biannually thereafter, the Assistant Secretary shall submit to Congress and make publicly available a report on best practices and professional standards in States for—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idea00b99faac5462b9852beba871dba0b"><enum>(A)</enum><text>establishing and operating health care programs using peer-support specialists; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7f711e6441b6455cbdc6df8fde6e439c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>training and certifying peer-support specialists.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idc913af0a602c4db3a744f62fb81ad013"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Peer-support specialist defined</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>peer-support specialist</term> means an individual who—</text> <subparagraph id="ide102235b44534721a7dd2572d1c576ab"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is credentialed by the State in which the individual practices;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idAB24E57B5DDB4BE1A753E7FDFC29AD50"><enum>(B)</enum><text>uses his or her lived experience of recovery from mental illness or substance abuse, plus skills learned in formal training, to facilitate support groups, and to work on a one-on-one basis, with individuals with a serious mental illness or a substance use disorder, in consultation with, and under the supervision of, a licensed mental health or substance use treatment professional;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id763929f8de7249fb8b6cdbb99e9eb916"><enum>(C)</enum><text>has been an active participant in mental health or substance use treatment for at least the preceding year;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2394af90a4c24dc2bdd87ecc47a09364"><enum>(D)</enum><text>provides non-medical services; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide3479735ed2f439fb8254db1147173cc"><enum>(E)</enum><text>performs services only within his or her area of training, expertise, competence, or scope of practice.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9edc706810d24eb3a1382bb15f4d3340"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Each report under this subsection shall include information on best practices and standards with regard to the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="id27aa29c8d42f4ac3b6db9d6c3e7c28f3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Hours of formal work or volunteer experience related to mental health and substance use issues.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8c9f08e8d5f84cdd8b0d3fa6a1dcf6f0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Types of peer specialist exams required.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8a291f9c0fba4e1b9d22af1dc788fe36"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Code of ethics.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id16d66f9d8b874da6a0821c08ae0be855"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Additional training required prior to certification, including in areas such as—</text>
 <clause id="id302ac2f3d6be4c63bdc2d6b17f5efdae"><enum>(i)</enum><text>ethics;</text> </clause><clause id="id899af435a49e471c89cb27da61ab5cbc"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>scope of practice;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id094f7271ed764bc8be78b57d9aa94091"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>crisis intervention;</text> </clause><clause id="idf2be9c9203b846aa9ccecdda86183504"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>State confidentiality laws;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idc394b6ff441c4a8e98cbddc124f6c4f1"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Federal privacy protections, including under the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/191">Public Law 104–191</external-xref>); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id4a515ed8201343989023b0b43af21cdf"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>other areas, as determined by the Assistant Secretary.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide786359df019454fb4eaa2adf93bbdf5"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Requirements to explain what, where, when, and how to accurately complete all required documentation activities.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida1a7640dad66455b8426aa9db6b2ff61"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Required or recommended skill sets, including knowledge of—</text> <clause id="id5d7e119398014350b23859113ac687a5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>risk indicators and responding appropriately to individual stressors, triggers, and indicators of pre-crisis symptoms;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id4be60ba00dff48f688cf6f0f3b3cec41"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>basic crisis avoidance techniques;</text> </clause><clause id="id40bb72c73aec4415becff13799792dd2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>basic suicide prevention concepts and techniques;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idc6a53e6357574c499586526fbe51ef1b"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>indicators that an individual may be experiencing abuse or neglect;</text> </clause><clause id="idbaa80458b3274f3ebbaccbe7b773d05a"><enum>(v)</enum><text>stages of change or recovery;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id44ff06ae2e0c4df49ca3f29d63202f5e"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the typical process that should be followed to access or participate in community mental health and related services; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id42d546cd0ff34183b78a91ee5f084328"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>circumstances when it is appropriate to request assistance from other professionals to help meet the individual's recovery goals.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2fc9145a103c4a8f9d031475269a368f"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Annual requirements for continuing education credits.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idc56fc1aa65194437861ae5d7c455c130"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report on mental health and substance use treatment in the States</header> <paragraph id="id8865687bf1bf4c7e8d0283972496bd9a"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, and not less than every 18 months thereafter, the Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use Disorders, in collaboration with the Director of the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality and Director of the National Institutes of Health, shall submit to Congress and make available to the public a report on mental health and substance use treatment in the States, including the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="idd8c532df559c420c946a41462ff0aaa2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A detailed report on how Federal mental health and substance use treatment funds are used in each State, including:</text>
 <clause id="id563a8f5f77294cf0b30335fe5221886e"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The numbers of individuals with mental illness, serious mental illness, substance use disorders, or co-occurring disorders who are served with Federal funds.</text>
 </clause><clause id="idc9af277150554e00ba5853156a5edf4e"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The types of programs made available to individuals with mental illness, serious mental illness, substance use disorders, or co-occurring disorders.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd386c270e9bd4d49a59f60e0b105d8ac"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A summary of best practice models in the States highlighting programs that are cost effective, provide evidence-based care, increase access to care, integrate physical, psychiatric, psychological, and behavioral medicine, and improve outcomes for individuals with serious mental illness or substance use disorders.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida0322bda07cb40938a8c982d253a9717"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A statistical report of outcome measures in each State for individuals with mental illness, serious mental illness, substance use disorders, or co-occurring disorders, including rates of suicide, suicide attempts, substance abuse, overdose, overdose deaths, health outcomes, emergency psychiatric hospitalizations and emergency room boarding, arrests, incarcerations, homelessness, joblessness, employment, and enrollment in educational or vocational programs.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id31285A28C8914B0C92FE56C19533DCA4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A comparative effectiveness research study analyzing outcomes for different models of outpatient treatment programs for the seriously mentally ill that include outpatient mental health services that are court ordered or voluntary, including—</text>
 <clause id="idb2aafb911d924ca5a358c5b3b59fc825"><enum>(i)</enum><text>rates of keeping treatment appointments and compliance with prescribed medications;</text> </clause><clause id="ide6b70ebb0a3e4220a816dbf943a345b5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>participants’ perceived effectiveness of the program;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id8e330c755c4d4a049e41abe7ae45182c"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>rates of the programs helping individuals with serious mental illness gain control over their lives;</text>
 </clause><clause id="ide065b217102b4e8ca1e6147bbd104a1b"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>alcohol and drug abuse rates;</text> </clause><clause id="idb40a29d4275046abab0db0671b4b9507"><enum>(v)</enum><text>incarceration and arrest rates;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id5ed8f1366a6548dba4710b9a2e80e82a"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>violence against persons or property;</text> </clause><clause id="idcc45ad6690334cddb0e5c194f3bbdccd"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>homelessness;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idb5fca260103443908fb51a0d36070291"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>total treatment costs for compliance with program; and</text> </clause><clause id="id67c56e60a2764e3d91f61adf10b04b8a"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>health outcomes.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idE65CC15F21B7472D8AE53E916C0601CD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>emergency room boarding</term> means the practice of admitting patients to an emergency department and holding such patients in the department until inpatient psychiatric beds become available.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idce88e1e733fa43bca0d62cc7cf22db94"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reporting compliance study</header>
 <paragraph id="idc11ac91ab80a4945a07ba4abfc578e9c"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use Disorders shall enter into an arrangement with the National Academy of Medicine (or, if the National Academy of Medicine declines, another appropriate entity) under which, not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the National Academy of Medicine will submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report that evaluates the combined paperwork burden of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id6e80fa5146b545ea9aa49a5f2c6f632a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>community mental health centers meeting the criteria specified in section 1913(c) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300x-2">42 U.S.C. 300x–2(c)</external-xref>), including such centers meeting such criteria as in effect on the day before the date of enactment of this Act; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb4c8ec9f63ed47c4a01189e652230dbe"><enum>(B)</enum><text>community mental health centers, as defined in section 1861(ff)(3)(B) of the Social Security Act.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id7d8e14e4d747429c81765dd4891136dc"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Scope</header><text>In preparing the report under subsection (a), the National Academy of Medicine (or, if applicable, other appropriate entity) shall examine licensing, certification, service definitions, claims payment, billing codes, and financial auditing requirements used by the Office of Management and Budget, the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services, the Health Resources and Services Administration, the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration, the Office of the Inspector General of the Department of Health and Human Services, State Medicaid agencies, State departments of health, State departments of education, and State and local juvenile justice and social service agencies to make administrative and statutory recommendations to Congress (which recommendations may include a uniform methodology) to reduce the paperwork burden experienced by centers and clinics described in paragraph (1).</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ida0b6024200f14229b71d0a0ec340b405"><enum>103.</enum><header>Advisory Council on graduate medical education</header>
 <subsection id="id167E34D03C7C4878BC52ED3EEDDCBCB2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 762(b) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/294o">42 U.S.C. 294o(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="id9940749cc34f4ebaaabab44488f01743"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (4) through (6) as paragraphs (5) through (7), respectively; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idb290faef45e54ef18b237a666706fc8a"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (3) the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id96179FF784A74D969CF41674CE0B69B6" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="id66283ce1a6b84e03a76f4c70652e5224"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use Disorders;</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id70D29010A3F844C8B697D424892650AA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 762(c) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/294o">42 U.S.C. 294o(c)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>paragraphs (4), (5), and (6)</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>paragraphs (5), (6), and (7)</quote>.</text> </subsection></section></title><title id="id61b2ac7dd7fd4999943ef68a7f213f86"><enum>II</enum><header>Grants</header> <section id="id3735092ed5b74482b9a249851b966cdf"><enum>201.</enum><header>National Mental Health Policy Laboratory</header> <subsection id="id50e0938916794239b175ea5624049725"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header> <paragraph id="id604774d9d9d84c5aa4a265948e63a27f"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use Disorders shall establish, within the Office of the Assistant Secretary, the National Mental Health Policy Laboratory (in this section referred to as the <quote>NMHPL</quote>), to be headed by a Director.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ide7bca403c4ca4a41869d665b7a2dc317"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Director of the NMHPL shall—</text> <subparagraph id="idd4116213c942488b81f4c1a5e3ef9736"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identify, coordinate, and implement policy changes and other trends likely to have the most significant impact on mental health services and monitor their impact;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0402a8d6cd5843b5a0d8db223839a0c2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>collect information from grantees under programs established or amended by this Act and under other mental health programs under the Public Health Service Act, including grantees that are States receiving funds under a block grant under part B of title XIX of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300x">42 U.S.C. 300x et seq.</external-xref>);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8f6abf4be040419b863dbe51ed625fac"><enum>(C)</enum><text>evaluate and disseminate to such grantees evidence-based practices and service delivery models using the best available science shown to be cost-effective while enhancing the quality of care furnished to individuals; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5b28664ac9f14aee8eeba9984d7cc89b"><enum>(D)</enum><text>establish standards for the appointment of scientific peer-review panels to evaluate grant applications.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id4795aab691c54c4495d858c20f74256f"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Evidence-based practices and service delivery models</header><text>In selecting evidence-based best practices and service delivery models for evaluation and dissemination under paragraph (2)(C), the Director of the NMHPL—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id6a1bd0fd3c1a4d29be75e99a7ffe4ec2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall give preference to models that—</text> <clause id="id46bbeae4d77f453e9d87943757590a8a"><enum>(i)</enum><text>improve the coordination between mental health and physical health providers;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idb3d6a932c6014ef6bcc448941b9e6ed8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>improve the coordination among such providers and the justice and corrections system;</text> </clause><clause id="id31ba0e7676484cd38c3a0b7a6b1d7b80"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>improve the cost effectiveness, quality, effectiveness, and efficiency of health care services furnished to individuals with serious mental illness, in mental health crisis, or at risk to themselves, their families, and the general public; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="ide6cb7543ae954c3a9b71eb3995d21522"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>recognize the importance of family participation in recovery; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida97f2fddd9d5404eac4d2332c4e0f3af"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may include clinical protocols and practices used in the Recovery After Initial Schizophrenia Episode project of the National Institute of Mental Health and the Specialized Treatment Early in Psychosis program.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idff18c5e51be54c02ab1e7ae205642bc2"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Deadline for beginning implementation</header><text>The Director of the NMHPL shall begin implementation of the duties described in this subsection not later than January 1, 2018.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id4d052e5385d24f4492778bbc635056b2"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In carrying out the duties under this subsection, the Director of the NMHPL may consult with—</text> <subparagraph id="id249f7c5f7d54485cbd31f85390136ff4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>representatives of the National Institute of Mental Health on organizational and operational issues;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb10124bdf9c64f2e9564836fdf383f97"><enum>(B)</enum><text>other appropriate Federal agencies;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idea4c478fbab24709b53ec5ac7588e3c5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>clinical and analytical experts with expertise in medicine, psychiatric and clinical psychological care, health care management, education, corrections health care, social services, and mental health court systems; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0a3725600204421a8dd2c686192b83d5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>other individuals and agencies as the Assistant Secretary determines appropriate.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id94f587884af24df8956eafe53589de5e"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Staffing</header> <paragraph id="id50ceec03ae7b47b9ba3a1697fd0d1e41"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Composition</header><text>In selecting the staff of the NMHPL, the Director of the NMHPL, in consultation with the Director of the National Institute of Mental Health, shall include individuals with advanced degrees and clinical and research experience, and who have an understanding of biological, psychosocial, and pharmaceutical treatments of mental illness and substance use disorders, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idc197a21e7ad04cb690330e27f0b7a88f"><enum>(A)</enum><text>individuals with a medical degree or doctoral degree from an accredited program in—</text> <clause id="idA23265F3C4F5433390C3FCE827AB8225"><enum>(i)</enum><text>allopathic or osteopathic medicine, and who have specialized training in psychiatry;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idB812AE5A0A974A27AFC13FBF8E604142"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>psychology; or</text> </clause><clause id="idFE0067DA6B3045029B0ADAF3C4E47A63"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>social work;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc250e1e1f263457d9ec160f5b69e5514"><enum>(B)</enum><text>professionals or academics with clinical or research expertise in substance use disorders and treatment; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide6ed4614214d46b39ae8c6d65bbe2516"><enum>(C)</enum><text>professionals or academics with expertise in research design and methodologies.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idc09e3c2435b5462cab3b496426904128"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report on quality of care</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, and every 2 years thereafter, the Director of the NMHPL shall submit to Congress a report on the quality of care furnished through grant programs administered by the Assistant Secretary under the respective services delivery models, including measurement of patient-level outcomes and public health outcomes, such as—</text>
 <paragraph id="id65d692c0341d479e8b04e4d47d345625"><enum>(1)</enum><text>reduced rates of suicide, suicide attempts, substance abuse, overdose, overdose deaths, emergency psychiatric hospitalizations, emergency room boarding, incarceration, crime, arrest, homelessness, and joblessness;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id470ffdaac48449babe2cd5578ed01069"><enum>(2)</enum><text>rates of employment and enrollment in educational and vocational programs; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id614875ebefc546b1bdaa86989d7d3c68"><enum>(3)</enum><text>such other criteria as the Director may determine.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id119166109eb749908c9e0fd494ddbca7"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <term>emergency room boarding</term> means the practice of admitting patients to an emergency department and holding such patients in the department until inpatient psychiatric beds become available.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="id3d52bb34b4ca4124b3bc8fa96fd1a7ec"><enum>202.</enum><header>Innovation grants</header>
 <subsection id="id2b2fadc1a52d420db48798eac7aa8216"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Assistant Secretary shall award grants to State and local governments, educational institutions, and nonprofit organizations for expanding a model that has been scientifically demonstrated to show promise, but would benefit from further applied research, for—</text>
 <paragraph id="idfebaa8c9ab1743a3ad9c7de112156061"><enum>(1)</enum><text>enhancing the prevention, diagnosis, intervention, treatment, and rehabilitation of mental illness, serious emotional disorder, substance use disorder, and co-occurring disorders; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id4468ab2750ad4e538b29b6b0354ce573"><enum>(2)</enum><text>integrating or coordinating physical health, mental health, and substance use services.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ida2d6add9e38146b795ef836d3591ca68"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>A grant under this section shall be for a period of not more than 3 years.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id73e5ca4b656c47d4935d9cd1ea888e6c"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Limitations</header><text>Of the amounts made available for carrying out this section for a fiscal year—</text> <paragraph id="iddb352f556dac41e49b9d1a6acc3e5584"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not more than one-third shall be awarded for use for prevention; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id5f8f7f70555740dbb765b6b728a38599"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not less than one-third shall be awarded for screening, diagnosis, treatment, or services, as described in subsection (a), for individuals (or subpopulations of individuals) who are below the age of 18 when activities funded through the grant award are initiated.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4a871e9821724f48a057f51cb56968cf"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Guidelines</header><text>As a condition on receipt of an award under this section, an applicant shall agree to adhere to guidelines issued by the National Mental Health Policy Laboratory on research designs and data collection.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id574a6f040cfa4a31b5743840ea46b2f9"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>To carry out this section, there are authorized to be appropriated $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2017 through 2021.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="id7183d52c0cd64d41bc57d28f9bc646e7"><enum>203.</enum><header>Demonstration grants</header>
 <subsection id="idbbf2fb8f7a364ce88c7f0a3adf42b637"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grants</header><text>The Assistant Secretary shall award grants to States, counties, local governments, educational institutions, and private nonprofit organizations for the expansion, replication, or scaling of evidence-based programs across a wider area to enhance effective screening, early diagnosis, intervention, and treatment with respect to mental illness and serious mental illness, primarily by—</text>
 <paragraph id="id314d0940ae7c47539a2a6891ee5be452"><enum>(1)</enum><text>applied delivery of care, including training staff in effective evidence-based treatment; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idc9511cabadbf47fa9fe50029f8052368"><enum>(2)</enum><text>integrating models of care across specialties and jurisdictions.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id222533d6c2304b9691cf99f5b367ac4d"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>A grant under this section shall be for a period of not less than 2 years and not more than 5 years.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id16dfcf0d722a43d9bc9d7acc6d94ade9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Limitations</header><text>Of the amounts made available for carrying out this section for a fiscal year—</text> <paragraph id="ide76af6e85a1f48168ea5c6b19e5528f2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not less than half shall be awarded for screening, diagnosis, intervention, and treatment, as described in subsection (a), for individuals (or subpopulations of individuals) who are below the age of 26 when activities funded through the grant award are initiated;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id84825818d12448c1b428e6451f6fd40e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>no amounts shall be made available for any program or project that is not evidence-based;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idc46c7f0cbadf4f39a9fc646eb21bf883"><enum>(3)</enum><text>no amounts shall be made available for primary prevention; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id1228f1123f294b6f8156740c41f17ce8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>no amounts shall be made available solely for the purpose of expanding facilities or increasing staff at an existing program.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id782bbc3542bd4acd9d1798ef8ffba966"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Guidelines</header><text>As a condition on receipt of an award under this section, an applicant shall agree to adhere to guidelines issued by the National Mental Health Policy Laboratory (established under section 201) on research designs and data collection.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idfcd1f77df1ea4477abfe36c575ccc36f"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text>As a condition on receipt of an award under this section, an applicant shall agree—</text> <paragraph id="id59af6520fe7444f1a94316fa26d10325"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to report to the National Mental Health Policy Laboratory and the Assistant Secretary the results of programs and activities funded through the award; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id176aa8cb99f441239fab2b6982509ada"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to include in such reporting any relevant data requested by the National Mental Health Policy Laboratory and the Assistant Secretary.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ide0080d299e7841a5bdf70727ec3a1102"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>To carry out this section, there are authorized to be appropriated $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2017 through 2021.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="id55b78f6e6abf4167898d03957ec195d5"><enum>204.</enum><header>Early childhood intervention and treatment</header>
 <subsection id="idabeb22a993cc4c71bd60926283e0be3e"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grants</header><text>The Director of the National Mental Health Policy Laboratory (in this section referred to as the <quote>NMHPL</quote>) shall—</text> <paragraph id="id58ffc2a4677547cf8ec6a2fd9fcdd8a5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>award grants to eligible entities to initiate and undertake early childhood intervention and treatment programs, and specialized programs for preschool- and elementary school-aged children at significant risk or who show early signs of social or emotional disability (in addition to any learning disability); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id442b567c7dc3417b85efcbfb0070655a"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ensure that programs funded through grants under this section are based on promising or evidence-based models and methods that are culturally and linguistically relevant and can be replicated in other settings.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id9dbeb03a5af043e7876eb7059d64123b"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible entities and children</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="idd4f8e6df4f604c13a4566991e994ecba"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means a nonprofit institution that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idb1d2764a8fe14a0aad90d23a3aba68cd"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is accredited by a State mental health or education agency, as applicable, for the intervention, treatment, or education of children from 3 to 12 years of age; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddb31bd3df491490f80b7db01c41768cf"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provides services that include early intervention and treatment or specialized programs for preschool- and elementary school-aged children whose primary need is a social or emotional disability (in addition to any learning disability).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idaa44ea5d29a1461e854b667b0b46468c"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible child</header><text>The term <term>eligible child</term> means a child who is at least 3 years old and not more than 12 years old—</text> <subparagraph id="idfa8c8709593f4a09b956ac9349823c1e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>whose primary need is a social or emotional disability (in addition to any learning disability); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id05135535215d46af8b659149c3d40753"><enum>(B)</enum><text>who could benefit from early childhood intervention and specialized preschool or elementary school programs with the goal of intervening or treating social or emotional disabilities.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4a2df57d03184e7c802d0e0a5a056ce3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header><text>An eligible entity seeking a grant under subsection (a) shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="ideace23089ab944d383d52dd12af55ce1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Use of funds for early intervention and treatment programs</header><text>An eligible entity shall use amounts awarded under a grant under subsection (a)(1) to carry out the following activities:</text>
 <paragraph id="idc104dab5d4db4bda96e0dc7253f950f5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Deliver for eligible children mental health education and treatment, early childhood education and intervention, and specialized programs for preschool- and elementary school-aged children at significant risk or who show early signs of social or emotional disability (in addition to any learning disability), including the provision of day treatment and social-emotional and behavioral services.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idb3d75c94406043668ee7466568defcd8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Treat and educate eligible children, including by providing funding for—</text> <subparagraph id="idF18927F0DFAA42418AE5ECFE7AED190A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>program and curricula development;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id68B1CA8B56F7429B960A10BBA5B87BF2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>staff;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idBA2426F1CB654F5FA56D2A69DFC3A114"><enum>(C)</enum><text>assessment, intervention, and treatment services;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8C0FA1177DCD4A49B76D5C3096E4060F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>administrative costs, including operating costs, capital needs, and equipment;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2EBB4C0BF1D349D68D8D3A64F0B62EB6"><enum>(E)</enum><text>enrollment costs;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9459697F71164B66AA7575AA67D314E4"><enum>(F)</enum><text>collaboration with primary care physicians, psychiatrists, and clinical services of psychologists of other related mental health specialists;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB23BB4E9E21F4293B9DF18AF67CFAAEE"><enum>(G)</enum><text>services to meet emergency needs of children; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8B728C47818F4E36AF74495FA0CD3971"><enum>(H)</enum><text>communication with families and physical and mental health professionals concerning the children.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idb5b15c9921914608b9fd727425eb7a01"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Develop and implement other strategies to address identified intervention, treatment, and educational needs of eligible children that incorporate reliable and valid evaluation modalities into the program to ensure outcomes based on sound scientific metrics as determined by the NMHPL.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="id541541e657ab44d99f2f308e6c2c998b"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Amount of awards</header>
 <text>The amount of an award to an eligible entity under subsection (a)(1) shall be not more than $600,000 per fiscal year.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="id8b62ad65487e456484b8df44150c42fe"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Project terms</header><text>The period of a grant for awards under subsection (a)(1), shall be not less than 3 fiscal years and not more than 10 fiscal years.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id729b9cda1f5e483baa972832419f6991"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Matching funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the NMHPL may not award a grant under this section to an eligible entity unless the eligible entity agrees, with respect to the costs to be incurred by the eligible entity in carrying out the activities described in subsection (d), to make available non-Federal contributions (in cash or in kind) toward such costs in an amount that is not less than 10 percent of Federal funds provided in the grant.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idf321b708357446c5869214ee5adc1731"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>To carry out this section, there are authorized to be appropriated $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2017 through 2021.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="id22721271b5144c29b78f901d17e6cc3f"><enum>205.</enum><header>Extension of assisted outpatient treatment grant program for individuals with serious mental
 illness</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 224 of the Protecting Access to Medicare Act of 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290aa">42 U.S.C. 290aa</external-xref> note) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="id4d13ce586b2346c9ad2e94c5a6ded327"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>4-year</quote> and inserting <quote>6-year</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id463C22FD716C457FBD5D8C1E44F5D4A3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (e), by striking <quote>and 2018</quote> and inserting <quote>2018, 2019, and 2020</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id0595f3c2472f40798350964dc22c0472"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (g)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id114b68432d01497f8c47ac5af49228f9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>2018</quote> and inserting <quote>2020</quote>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4ae1371bb7cd488aa9d34c007086f678"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2) by striking <quote>2018</quote> and inserting <quote>2020</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5AA255977E1D467D942A87D561CEF1A5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking <quote>$15,000,000</quote> and inserting <quote>$20,000,000</quote>.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="id60fd309f96d1421a95b5254c6ef8f16c"><enum>206.</enum><header>Block grants</header> <subsection commented="no" id="id71c4f6c172a040a0bd01fd69e04572b4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reauthorization of block grant</header><text>Section 1920(a) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300x-9">42 U.S.C. 300x–9(a)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>$450,000,000 for fiscal year 2001, and such sums as may be necessary for each of the fiscal years 2002 and 2003</quote> and inserting <quote>$483,000,000 for fiscal year 2017 and such sums as may be necessary for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2019</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id6bdf4ae46e0e4a628607702b3007977f"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Best practices in clinical care models</header><text>Section 1920 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300x-9">42 U.S.C. 300x–9</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id381046ECC1B14D50895D9100A1D9E71F" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="id66c5aa0c8d604259a263d0639b4b8d0f"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Best Practices in Clinical Care Models</header><text>The Assistant Secretary, acting through the Administrator of the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services and in collaboration with the Director of the National Institute of Mental Health, shall obligate 5 percent of the amounts appropriated for a fiscal year under subsection (a) for translating evidence-based (as defined in section 2 of the <short-title>Mental Health Reform Act of 2015</short-title>) interventions and best available science into systems of care, such as through models including the Recovery After an Initial Schizophrenia Episode research project of the National Institute of Mental Health.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</subsection><subsection id="id2793a9acbf934b6cad4b545d504da54e"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Additional program requirements</header>
 <paragraph id="id674e844a18c5406f817534260f7ac91a"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Integrated services</header><text>Subsection (b)(1) of section 1912 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300x-1">42 U.S.C. 300x–1(b)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id05b6a63806d14ce48bf5f1bd37cc34da"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>The plan provides</quote> and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idC3C8F25C33A94CAD8E350A83140BA44B" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="id6ea39e608df4453cb3c826b21cc8d6fc"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The plan provides</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id68824ba71b8f41d59b7688efb7237c2a"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the second sentence, by striking <quote>health and mental health services</quote> and inserting <quote>integrated physical and mental health services</quote>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9c0da0dee3d344179449137ef85e31b5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking <quote>The plan shall include</quote> and all that follows through the period at the end and inserting <quote>The plan shall integrate and coordinate services to maximize the efficiency, effectiveness, quality, coordination, and cost effectiveness of those services and programs to produce the best possible outcomes for individuals with serious mental illness.</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc3c563149357428bb188904a2f6166ed"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id65990AF9953445D6BB695F0F2D84E8EE" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="idf359535b9bcf431e9635b7ed319f2d5f"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Additional requirements</header><text>The plan shall include a separate description of case management services and provide for activities leading to reduction of rates of suicides, suicide attempts, substance abuse, overdose deaths, emergency hospitalizations, incarceration, crimes, arrest, homelessness, joblessness, medication nonadherence, and education and vocational programs drop outs. The plan shall include a detailed list of services available for eligible patients in each county or county equivalent.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
						</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idec2e2d9dfe3d4fb5b3864c75342287f4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Data collection system</header>
 <subparagraph id="id4F1A4042CAC34834860CE2F735F5C05A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Subsection (b)(1)(A) (as so designated by paragraph (1)) of section 1912 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300x-1">42 U.S.C. 300x–1(b)(1)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>legal services, and</quote> before <quote>other support services</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id0b3d9fb4c4d148cc91425d55b385be5f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Subsection (b)(2) of section 1912 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300x-1">42 U.S.C. 300x–1(b)(2)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>and outcome measures for services and resources</quote> before the period.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide10d01743a9a4aab99ac02bc2ca57c82"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Implementation of plan</header><text>Subsection (d) of section 1912 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300x-1">42 U.S.C. 300x–1(d)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="id9f8b32cf33874a54964c242ec4755591"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text>
 <clause id="id5b9e84717c8a4e9ca05547bd5e03c2bf"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Except as provided</quote> and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1641335CE34B4A65B1731BDF597D01BF" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="id3bacfd422173410e8c89324688be60c9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </clause><clause id="idd4c8d9ad8c8643678b0dd4937a2de2fd"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB70DBA91F9EE4C6DB91CEAC35E232142" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="id50e24a4845bf4ce993c76f898b6dd619"><enum>(B)</enum><header>De-identified reports</header><text>For eligible patients receiving treatment through funds awarded under a grant under section 1911, a State shall include in the State plan for the first year beginning after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Mental Health Reform Act of 2015</short-title> and each subsequent year, a de-identified report, containing information that is open source and de-identified, on the outcomes measures collected in subsection (b)(2) of section 1912 of the Public Health Service Act and the overall cost of such treatment provided.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id311bd8db6fc4445fa60c8a7af3f5b846"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Incentives for State-based outcome measures</header><text>Section 1920 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300x-9">42 U.S.C. 300x–9</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2615F065068045ADA3FFDE42384AFF97" style="OLC">
							<subsection commented="no" id="id5F70A114A9D7449B80FAA2E84BE4A191"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Incentives for State-Based outcome measures</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="idE51EE390EA374520AA3A1B54E9DF49FD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In addition to the amounts made available under subsection (a) for fiscal year 2019, the Secretary shall provide to each State that meets the conditions under paragraph (2) for fiscal year 2019, an amount equal to 2 percent of the formula grant amount described in section 1911 and section 1921.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id2BFE3756771E4652A62DA74D7FC39F6A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conditions</header><text>The Secretary shall define the conditions under which a State is eligible to receive the additional amount under paragraph (1), based on the report on mental health and substance use treatment in the States under section 102(b) of the <short-title>Mental Health Reform Act of 2015</short-title>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idA00AD5787A99466AAE5DE82298A7FD77"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Clarification</header><text>Any amounts made available under paragraph (1) shall be in addition to the State’s block grant allocation and shall be made to a State for a fiscal year, as a single payment, not later than the last day of the first calendar quarter of fiscal year 2020.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id7BF404165FF347BBABC4D6E8FE989898"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Evidence-based services delivery models</header><text>Section 1912 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300x-1">42 U.S.C. 300x–1</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4CF4A8E64EE44E64B980E178D2AF8EC7" style="OLC">
							<subsection id="id234c9f1fcbd14bfabafac4b5eed17b4a"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Expansion of models</header>
 <paragraph id="id6716c84057f54cde952ee4f2a21a8156"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Taking into account the results of evaluations under section 201(a)(2)(C) of the <short-title>Mental Health Reform Act of 2015</short-title>, the Assistant Secretary may, by rule, as part of the program of block grants under this subpart, provide for expanded use across the Nation of evidence-based service delivery models by providers funded under such block grants, so long as—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id64c17771c59045fba099ec83672f9987"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use Disorders (in this subsection referred to as the <quote>Assistant Secretary</quote>) determines that such expansion will—</text>
 <clause id="ide5292e3b0dae4dedbc45c6dcebf957f6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>result in more effective use of funds under such block grants without reducing the quality of care; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="id7fc8e4a76f16401cbfb7684424329d0a"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>improve the quality of patient care without significantly increasing spending;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id98bc15dcb7744680afcf3ee0742cfc45"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Director of the National Institute of Mental Health determines that such expansion would improve the quality of patient care; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb6e9c484b4934c2dab6939c13b1e5ba9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Assistant Secretary determines that the change will—</text> <clause id="ide97f886403984b3e945d258e9af80ce8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>significantly reduce severity and duration of symptoms of mental illness;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id4c724e0b3e1742da8387e98c1c5ce963"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>reduce rates of suicide, suicide attempts, substance abuse, overdose, emergency hospitalizations, emergency room boarding, incarceration, crime, arrest, homelessness, or joblessness; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="idcccdc9f319e44fca9b41b4385d967d06"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>significantly improve the quality of patient care and mental health crisis outcomes without significantly increasing spending.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5317d608f8924bb5a70f6fd27795ea86"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this subsection, the term <quote>emergency room boarding</quote> means the practice of admitting patients to an emergency department and holding such patients in the department until inpatient psychiatric beds become available.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4488718a546c43b8a8ba9ab01e142d70"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Period for expenditure of grant funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1913 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300x-2">42 U.S.C. 300x–2</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE2E5DC6A9F5C427989945B49804BF39F" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="idc45e7a16bef74e2d9b64e13f72a9a9ca"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Period for expenditure of grant funds</header><text>In implementing a plan submitted under section 1912(a), a State receiving a grant under section 1911 may make such funds available to providers of services described in subsection (b) for the provision of services without fiscal year limitation.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="id48d396fc555244ea9a4047c0d88cda7b"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Active outreach and engagement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1915 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300x-4">42 U.S.C. 300x–4</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end of the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9DD7FB24490842C7ACD5131334BB3CDA" style="OLC">
						<subsection id="id5f1d33b0974e4f4dae355a786c5d7b9a"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Active outreach and engagement to persons with serious mental illness</header>
 <paragraph id="idfbcd351392f24b9b837bf84dbaf10a65"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A funding agreement for a grant under section 1911 is that the State involved has in effect active programs that seek to engage individuals with serious mental illness in comprehensive services in order to avert relapse, repeated hospitalizations, arrest, incarceration, suicide, and to provide the patient with the opportunity to live in the least restrictive setting, through a comprehensive program of evidence-based and culturally relevant assertive outreach and engagement services focusing on individuals who are homeless, have co-occurring disorders, are at risk for incarceration or re-incarceration, or have a history of treatment failure, including repeated hospitalizations or emergency room usage.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="id918174725e9540b0b469eacb9471cfb3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Evidence-based assertive outreach and engagement services</header>
 <subparagraph id="ida5637b7c59654c04848d9e9ee42ec1e7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>SAMHSA</header><text>The Administrator of the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration, in cooperation with the Director of the National Institute of Mental Health, shall develop—</text>
 <clause id="id68e575ab175f4e67a3ad59e21d523ea4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a list of evidence-based culturally and linguistically relevant assertive outreach and engagement services; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id41b8d706079c435e9174cef873a49c7a"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>criteria to be used to assess the scope and effectiveness of the approaches taken by such services, such as the ability to provide same-day appointments for emergent situations.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id15b4fe9f90124596aebda13cc9336271"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Types of assertive outreach and engagement services</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1), appropriate programs of evidence-based assertive outreach and engagement services may include peer support programs; the Wellness Recovery Action Plan, Assertive Community Treatment, and Forensic Assertive Community Treatment of the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration; assisted outpatient treatment, appropriate supportive housing programs incorporating a Housing First model; and intensive, evidence-based approaches to early intervention in psychosis, such as the Recovery After an Initial Schizophrenia Episode model of the National Institute of Mental Health and the Specialized Treatment Early in Psychosis program.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="id659324a7ba3f4780a795a201e6c90263"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Psychiatric advanced directives</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A funding agreement for a grant under section 1911 is that the State involved has in effect active programs that seek to engage individuals with serious mental illness in proactively making their own health care decisions and enhancing communication between themselves, their families, and their treatment providers by allowing for early intervention and reducing legal proceedings related to involuntary treatment by developing psychiatric advanced directives through a comprehensive program—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="id0d39403ad7a6413ebaab2d504dd8b4b0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>of assertive outreach and engagement services focusing on individuals diagnosed with serious mental illness or self-identifying as in recovery from serious mental illness to obtain a psychiatric advanced directive; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id68e6b7882474404b82062c5378254a94"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to support States in providing accessible legal counsel to individuals diagnosed with serious mental illness.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</subsection></section><section id="id9134326ab85140bc81dff07f82971bba"><enum>207.</enum><header>Telehealth child psychiatry access grants</header>
 <subsection id="idcb1c44c2639b49159bcf217152d827fe"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, shall award grants to States and Indian tribes or tribal organizations (as defined in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act) to promote behavioral health integration in pediatric primary care by—</text>
 <paragraph id="id52911beaf26c45aea09dffc423872e9f"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supporting the creation of statewide child psychiatry access programs; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id6f1e324c3f324fa6bb08054c183d9637"><enum>(2)</enum><text>supporting the expansion of existing statewide or regional child psychiatry access programs.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5d3d15a25ca34f41a3c9b2f6d1698ced"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Program requirements</header>
 <paragraph id="id797aa6f9dab94b98a7c43ffee9a32627"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To be eligible for funding under subsection (a), a child psychiatry access program shall—</text> <subparagraph id="id650ec75668674590bcd9f174bc42e0bc"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be a statewide network of pediatric mental health teams that provide support to pediatric primary care sites as an integrated team;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9a971fc0f6f2413bbbd4b46095ba611c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>support and further develop organized State networks of child and adolescent psychiatrists to provide consultative support to pediatric primary care sites;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id22505b7d03e442609d7cc06a48a02038"><enum>(C)</enum><text>conduct an assessment of critical behavioral consultation needs among pediatric providers and such providers' preferred mechanisms for receiving consultation and training and technical assistance;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id84fcb59e89214fe991634a7c77ac1f73"><enum>(D)</enum><text>develop an online database and communication mechanisms, including telehealth, to facilitate consultation support to pediatric practices;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3489835c5ed84b1fa32eec06ed805fff"><enum>(E)</enum><text>provide rapid (within 30 minutes) statewide clinical telephone consultations when requested between the pediatric mental health teams and pediatric primary care providers;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id27cf5be989384e8b8d9bc2693b890bc2"><enum>(F)</enum><text>conduct training and provide technical assistance to pediatric primary care providers to support the early identification, diagnosis, treatment, and referral of children with behavioral health conditions;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf278ac309b2a4a0ebd5869dae2bc3282"><enum>(G)</enum><text>inform and assist pediatric providers in accessing child psychiatry consultations and in scheduling and conducting technical assistance;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfef62c20b0b74df0930e3a528b05fc44"><enum>(H)</enum><text>assist with referrals to specialty care and community and behavioral health resources; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id66d1a06655f64ade921f84bfda0c59d0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>establish mechanisms for measuring and monitoring increased access to child and adolescent psychiatric services by pediatric primary care providers and expanded capacity of pediatric primary care providers to identify, treat, and refer children with mental health problems.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id77F8ADB4881A43F49C30198D6EB9A550"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Pediatric mental health teams</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>pediatric mental health team</term> means a team of case coordinators, child and adolescent psychiatrists, and a licensed clinical mental health professional, such as a psychologist, social worker, or mental health counselor. Such a team may be regionally based, provided there is access to a pediatric mental health team across the State.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idc77f85ddb91d4e238e6b5b76d5e66888"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header><text>A State, political subdivision of a State, Indian tribe, or tribal organization that desires a grant under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require, including a plan for the rigorous evaluation of activities that are carried out with funds received under such grant.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="ida2087c98d6154ed28bfcaec919b60d89"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text>A State, political subdivision of a State, Indian tribe, or tribal organization that receives a grant under this section shall prepare and submit an evaluation to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may reasonably require, including an evaluation of activities carried out with funds received under such grant and a process and outcome evaluation.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id1ca0136967954d13b021f7f171938a27"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Matching requirement</header><text>The Secretary may not award a grant under the grant program unless the State involved agrees, with respect to the costs to be incurred by the State in carrying out the purpose described in this section, to make available non-Federal contributions (in cash or in kind) toward such costs in an amount that is not less than 20 percent of Federal funds provided in the grant.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idaf88eb1aa8c149ffb6b279e2aed93bbe"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>To carry out this section, there are authorized to be appropriated $25,000,000 for fiscal year 2017 and such sums as may be necessary for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2021.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="ide35d7b3faadf41499e5ee0e38f3e5fa9"><enum>208.</enum><header>Liability protections for health care professional volunteers at community health centers and
 community mental health centers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 224 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/233">42 U.S.C. 233</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB0EBE2CFC86A43D9BF00377C24999C57" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="id839D282650994DC18AD01BF9C529F80D"><enum>(q)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idCCD513A770D34D9A9D7DA6C78C45C4E7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the term <term>community mental health center</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="id3A721ED967294DCF8E23461FF44C9C62" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a community mental health center, as defined in section 1861(ff) of the Social Security Act; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id31D36F6C8A3C4C52BC5A88EA952DF5B9" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a community mental health center meeting the criteria specified in section 1913(c).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id58E7091525234A30811F2CD951ADD479" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, a health care professional volunteer at an entity described in subsection (g)(4) or a community mental health center shall, in providing health care services eligible for funding under section 330 or subpart I of part B of title XIX to an individual, be deemed to be an employee of the Public Health Service for a calendar year that begins during a fiscal year for which a transfer was made under paragraph (5)(C). The preceding sentence is subject to the provisions of this subsection.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id453F3DCB0F864F598DAADF7A1EE7B9C5" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In providing a health care service to an individual, a health care professional shall, for purposes of this subsection be considered to be a health professional volunteer at an entity described in subsection (g)(4) or at a community mental health center if the following conditions are met:</text>
 <subparagraph id="idFBB9AE5E4172434B8EC580D4A2EA6F68"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The service is provided to the individual at the facilities of an entity described in subsection (g)(4), at a federally qualified community behavioral health clinic, or through offsite programs or events carried out by the center.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2C19967AD69B4894BBA29429B3458FA3"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The center or entity is sponsoring the health care professional volunteer pursuant to paragraph (4)(B).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8C8748AAC1714850BA8A1C61A2C135B4"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The health care professional does not receive any compensation for the service from the individual or from any third-party payer (including reimbursement under any insurance policy or health plan, or under any Federal or State health benefits program), except that the health care professional may receive repayment from the entity described in subsection (g)(4) or the center for reasonable expenses incurred by the health care professional in the provision of the service to the individual.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id46824D6532D84AC3AEE2D012D794FBC7"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Before the service is provided, the health care professional or the center or entity described in subsection (g)(4) posts a clear and conspicuous notice at the site where the service is provided of the extent to which the legal liability of the health care professional is limited pursuant to this subsection.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id383B4C104EF4437DAF0BBCD075B092B3"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At the time the service is provided, the health care professional is licensed or certified in accordance with applicable law regarding the provision of the service.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id069B73BAD68A4D9682204C15C37074D6" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (g) (other than paragraphs (3) and (5)) and subsections (h), (i), and (l) apply to a health care professional for purposes of this subsection to the same extent and in the same manner as such subsections apply to an officer, governing board member, employee, or contractor of an entity described in subsection (g)(4), subject to paragraph (5) and subject to the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="id58CC5C033B924F689300643D0DADD9D5"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The first sentence of paragraph (2) applies in lieu of the first sentence of subsection (g)(1)(A).</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7A20E3564ACA430B826A727B6D20063C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to an entity described in subsection (g)(4) or a federally qualified community behavioral health clinic, a health care professional is not a health professional volunteer at such center unless the center sponsors the health care professional. For purposes of this subsection, the center shall be considered to be sponsoring the health care professional if—</text>
 <clause id="id2F6C99D44F364A0FBC328C0ACD6EEBF9"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to the health care professional, the center submits to the Secretary an application meeting the requirements of subsection (g)(1)(D); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id340696E79D2D4409ACE0E8E3889F9D55"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary, pursuant to subsection (g)(1)(E), determines that the health care professional is deemed to be an employee of the Public Health Service.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2C6A36F01D024F41AE25BC30EA15970E"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a health care professional who is determined by the Secretary pursuant to subsection (g)(1)(E) to be a health professional volunteer at such center, this subsection applies to the health care professional (with respect to services described in paragraph (2)) for any cause of action arising from an act or omission of the health care professional occurring on or after the date on which the Secretary makes such determination.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idABA273CF8A8E40769DC2843E44737589"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (g)(1)(F) applies to a health professional volunteer for purposes of this subsection only to the extent that, in providing health services to an individual, each of the conditions specified in paragraph (3) is met.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idAFF75281877248C0873679F391E2996C" indent="up1"><enum>(5)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id870130EE030540D7947F2AF8D28D0EFA"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts in the fund established under subsection (k)(2) shall be available for transfer under subparagraph (C) for purposes of carrying out this subsection for health professional volunteers at entities described in subsection (g)(4).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id93A405CA2C714521B10F1BDBD82449DD" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than May 1 of each fiscal year, the Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary, shall submit to Congress a report providing an estimate of the amount of claims (together with related fees and expenses of witnesses) that, by reason of the acts or omissions of health care professional volunteers, will be paid pursuant to this subsection during the calendar year that begins in the following fiscal year. Subsection (k)(1)(B) applies to the estimate under the preceding sentence regarding health care professional volunteers to the same extent and in the same manner as such subsection applies to the estimate under such subsection regarding officers, governing board members, employees, and contractors of entities described in subsection (g)(4).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id177A0F39A9BD4582B05B0265BEC98593" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than December 31 of each fiscal year, the Secretary shall transfer from the fund under subsection (k)(2) to the appropriate accounts in the Treasury an amount equal to the estimate made under subparagraph (B) for the calendar year beginning in such fiscal year, subject to the extent of amounts in the fund.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idDAB5B36A11C543F184A832FACEC9E683" indent="up1"><enum>(6)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id6F708B8752764F55A4E9FA69B8FC7617"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This subsection takes effect on October 1, 2017, except as provided in subparagraph (B).</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idBAA5C2BC4E2C4BE7ACB366EF294F1377" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Effective on the date of the enactment of this subsection—</text>
 <clause id="idEE132FB261804E989E716C65066789C7"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary may issue regulations for carrying out this subsection, and the Secretary may accept and consider applications submitted pursuant to paragraph (4)(B); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id4C085238B630487BB212191FA5CC5E9F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reports under paragraph (5)(B) may be submitted to Congress.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </section><section id="id69ad84197df14ba1aef3e6ff656e5237"><enum>209.</enum><header>Minority fellowship program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title V of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290aa">42 U.S.C. 290aa et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="idF472E27AD75A4F61933CA8DF2A52EDB8"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating part G (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290kk">42 U.S.C. 290kk et seq.</external-xref>), relating to services provided through religious organizations and added by section 144 of the Community Renewal Tax Relief Act of 2000, as enacted into law by section 1(a)(7) of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/106/554">Public Law 106–554</external-xref>, as part J;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id417B84B802E1464EA531EEBB015B8066"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating sections 581 through 584 of part J, as so redesignated, as sections 596 through 596C, respectively; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id2E7F25D0DDD84E02AE4C3CC31495E11B"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id179369FE40124102912BA8A65F64D725" style="OLC"> <part id="id45A44DDFB4534A518FA6DB2D188A9013" style="OLC"><enum>K</enum><header>Minority fellowship program</header> <section id="id094B54E6D7894279B47143363E2DA6C2"><enum>597.</enum><header>Fellowships</header> <subsection id="id277B006C4B74411FAB96C24B6597A7B3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall maintain a program, to be known as the Minority Fellowship Program, under which the Secretary awards fellowships, which may include stipends, for the purposes of—</text>
 <paragraph id="idA60655513AD7411885BC5371115AD648"><enum>(1)</enum><text>increasing behavioral health practitioners' knowledge of issues related to prevention, treatment, and recovery support for mental and substance use disorders among racial and ethnic minority populations;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idC4B774F0B24B418684A1DA8852D447CE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>improving the quality of mental and substance use disorder prevention and treatment delivered to ethnic minorities; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id523A9DE0704F470899D6429FC8DDEC84"><enum>(3)</enum><text>increasing the number of culturally competent behavioral health professionals who teach, administer, conduct services research, and provide direct mental health or substance use services to underserved minority populations.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id81A5DE0EE0DE4BE396EDD43E17BF88BD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Training Covered</header><text>The fellowships under subsection (a) shall be for postbaccalaureate training (including for master's and doctoral degrees) for mental health professionals, including in the fields of psychiatry, nursing, social work, psychology, marriage and family therapy, and substance use and addiction counseling.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id9164764365DF4B0C88064173C54F7CBD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of Appropriations</header><text>To carry out this section, there are authorized to be appropriated $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2017 through 2021.</text></subsection></section></part><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></section><section id="idc4d7277873764ca5aa39bb56d3460cbd"><enum>210.</enum><header>National health service corps</header>
				<subsection id="idc477022888714457a4bf0e8698fc73fe"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header>
 <paragraph id="id6bb8526a689446ec8265bc5f1b88bbc3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Primary health services</header><text>Section 331(a)(3)(D) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/254d">42 U.S.C. 254d(a)(3)(D)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>(including pediatric mental health subspecialty services)</quote> after <quote>pediatrics</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idc9f9af328eee490c80c9e04a824d7d89"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Behavioral and mental health professionals</header><text>Clause (i) of section 331(a)(3)(E)(i) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/254d">42 U.S.C. 254d(a)(3)(E)(i)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>, including such professionals who are pediatric subspecialists</quote> before the period at the end.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id399f51fe0677429bb4dd5459f30debbf"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Health professional shortage area</header><text>Section 332(a)(1) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/254e">42 U.S.C. 254e(a)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>(which may be a group comprised of children and adolescents)</quote> after <quote>population group</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idd4d24e6b7d294e3fb96932c3a4771ee0"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Medical facility</header><text>Section 332(a)(2)(A) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/254e">42 U.S.C. 254e(a)(2)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>medical residency or fellowship training site for training in child and adolescent psychiatry,</quote> before <quote>facility operated by a city or county health department,</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id9e6c5a2007d14abd958a7e6b58d2b84b"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility To participate in loan repayment program</header><text>Section 338B(b)(1)(B) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/254l-1">42 U.S.C. 254l–1(b)(1)(B)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>, including any child and adolescent psychiatry medical residency or fellowship training program</quote> before the semicolon.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="idf709008319ec41e0b068bd5f08b7bc04"><enum>211.</enum><header>Reauthorization of mental and behavioral health education training grant</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 756 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/294e-1">42 U.S.C. 294e–1</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idD24174D0F20C4E81894CEACB9C6D03AF" style="OLC"> <section id="idCBEE847F5A4C4B6FA68A1F985BD6C575"><enum>756.</enum><header>Mental and behavioral health education and training grants</header> <subsection id="id71338DE2A54F4B6D9BE112DEB259F911"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grants authorized</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Administrators of the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Administration and the Health Resources and Services Administration, may award grants to eligible institutions to support the recruitment of students for, and education and clinical experience of the students in—</text>
 <paragraph id="id633431f24c0f4df2b0645f12e3c78c63"><enum>(1)</enum><text>accredited institutions of higher education or accredited professional training programs that are establishing or expanding internships or other field placement programs in mental health in psychiatry, psychology, school psychology, behavioral pediatrics, psychiatric nursing, social work, school social work, substance abuse prevention and treatment, marriage and family therapy, school counseling, or professional counseling, with a preference for programs addressing child and adolescent mental health, in particular transitional age youth between 16 to 25 years old;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ide07844cf4e9846ab8aff88bb3aeeddd4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>accredited doctoral, internship, and post-doctoral residency programs of health service psychology (which includes clinical psychology, counseling, and school psychology) for the development and implementation of interdisciplinary training of psychology graduate students for providing behavioral and mental health services, including substance abuse prevention and treatment services, as well as the development of faculty in health service psychology;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idee967f0a910743e38014a35f8b1dfa35"><enum>(3)</enum><text>accredited master’s and doctoral degree programs of social work for the development and implementation of interdisciplinary training of social work graduate students for providing behavioral and mental health services, including substance abuse prevention and treatment services, and the development of faculty in social work; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id274c9dd2936a417d8236105393c826c7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>paraprofessional certificate training programs offered by accredited community and technical colleges granting State licensure or certification in a behavioral health-related paraprofessional field, such as community health worker, outreach worker, social services aide, mental health worker, substance abuse or addictions worker, youth worker, promotora, or peer paraprofessional, with preference for pre-service or in-service training of paraprofessional child and adolescent mental health workers.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idE5320F0BE774453EA03B75B382C10B92"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility requirements</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, an institution shall demonstrate—</text> <paragraph id="idb7eb5171396d47a88b4e3016d9edc57e"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an ability to recruit and place psychiatrists, psychologists, social workers, or paraprofessionals in areas with a high need and high demand population;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id6f59cfa6cf384ff3a61a59aab1805f8e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>participation of individuals and groups from different racial, ethnic, cultural, geographic, religious, linguistic, and class backgrounds, and different genders and orientations in the institution’s programs;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idd76c613f9d874353b018f28654178dfa"><enum>(3)</enum><text>knowledge and understanding of the concerns of the individuals and groups described in paragraph (2), especially individuals with mental health symptoms or diagnoses, particularly children and adolescents, with a special emphasis on transitional-aged persons 16 to 25 years old;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id69551d61937e4d28baf11e946e6d28df"><enum>(4)</enum><text>prioritization of cultural and linguistic competency in training professionals and paraprofessionals in any academic program, field placement, internship, or post-doctoral position; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id30280bd324cd4b4eb43c694445645073"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the willingness to provide to the Secretary such data, assurances, and information as the Secretary may require.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idF56B2B46EF224131B6C1DCE240F68899"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In selecting grant recipients the Secretary shall give priority to—</text> <paragraph id="id7BA14A2486CD40508477B5210EEDA187"><enum>(1)</enum><text>programs that have demonstrated the ability to train psychology and social work professionals to work in integrated care settings; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id7CA81FCF2A76436AA9C5C67B4C166536"><enum>(2)</enum><text>programs for paraprofessionals that offer curriculum with an emphasis on the role of the family and the lived experience of the consumer and family-paraprofessional partnerships.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id6C94EA51244F464DBED226655A7A9668"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Institutional requirement</header><text>Of the grants awarded under paragraphs (2) and (3) of subsection (a), at least 4 of the grant recipients shall be historically black colleges or other minority serving institutions.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id6C00A5A195F14E988DD3235DD59EA9DF"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Mental Health Reform Act of 2015</short-title>, and annually thereafter, the Secretary, acting through the Administrators of the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration and the Health Resources Services Administration, shall submit to Congress a report on the effectiveness of—</text>
 <paragraph id="idD048DC02AD2645E8B89C642286D07DFE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>providing graduate students support for experiential training (internship or field placement);</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id0C2FA65A587A44BFABF378544839268B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recruitment of students interested in behavioral health practice;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idDF6C48B9E82E4CB4B18270D975BADF7A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>development and implementation of interprofessional training and integration within primary care;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id6071BBAEEA0F449FB27E71D52C969CA0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>development and implementation of accredited field placements and internships; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idFD6824469A3843F5B4693A0A6AC720E6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>data collected on the number of students trained in mental health and the number of available accredited internships and field placements.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5D42A58237CF48BEA0A20B4287685A9F"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>For each of fiscal years 2017 through 2021, there are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $44,000,000, to be allocated as follows:</text>
 <paragraph id="id93F4BD9AD4C743F8AA08B5DCCBB60149"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$15,000,000 shall be allocated to institutions to expand mental health internships or other field placement programs under subsection (a)(1).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idFAE2C8179C134E72AF59A3901DC79988"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$14,000,000 shall be allocated to training in graduate psychology under subsection (a)(2).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id13D08789069F4A22A8999D3D671CB0F2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>$10,000,000 shall be allocated to training in graduate social work under subsection (a)(3).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id867E91012F334EDA9613655C63D36BBE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>$5,000,000 shall be allocated to training paraprofessionals under subsection (a)(4).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </section><section id="id9441DCD4B4FB4B3AB8BFE8CBFCACAF0A"><enum>212.</enum><header>National suicide prevention lifeline program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subpart 3 of part B of title V of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290bb-31">42 U.S.C. 290bb–31 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 520E–2 the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idCFA9CEC4383343E7BDB36072C28C1BB7" style="OLC">
					<section id="id6F9647F5339E4EB6953F0A2EF4488253"><enum>520E–3.</enum><header>National suicide prevention lifeline program</header>
 <subsection id="id21BBA67822E04CB198EB4F51D561A35B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall maintain the National Suicide Prevention Lifeline program. The activities of the Secretary under such program shall include—</text>
 <paragraph id="id826754356d9a414f8fb282f60aa3ea6d"><enum>(1)</enum><text>coordinating a network of crisis centers across the Nation for providing suicide prevention and crisis intervention services to individuals seeking help at any time, day or night;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id70DAD339614D430492F1B1AD3040ED67"><enum>(2)</enum><text>maintaining a suicide prevention hotline to link callers to local emergency, mental health, and social services resources; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id097F550F462346FDA67913D5AB730277"><enum>(3)</enum><text>consulting with the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to ensure that veterans calling the suicide prevention hotline have access to a specialized veterans' suicide prevention hotline.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ide67b64a617db4855bf2f14c15ccbfeb3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorization of Appropriations</header><text>To carry out this section, there are authorized to be appropriated $5,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2016 through 2020.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</section></title><title id="id7EEC5D77C2034FABA9166998E79BE3DA" style="OLC"><enum>III</enum><header>Integration</header>
			<section id="idB4D82A82D2464DA8976B493B13CF72CD"><enum>301.</enum>
 <header>Primary and behavioral health care integration grant programs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 520K of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290bb-42">42 U.S.C. 290bb–42</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idAE2580D96F4C4CD3BE579E1ABE34C09D" style="OLC"> <section id="id575B374433424519B6AF210D4F757554"><enum>520K.</enum><header>Integration incentive grants</header> <subsection id="idde2a34495c304095acd79c331babe73c"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is established within the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration a primary and behavioral health care integration grant program. The Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use Disorders may award grants and cooperative agreements to eligible entities to expend funds for improvements in integrated settings with integrated practices.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id3D40ED3BBBBA44C890643377D428303A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="id42307EAB7D6245B7B1AED78283EF1F07"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Integrated care</header><text>The term <term>integrated care</term> means full collaboration in merged or transformed practices offering mental and physical health services within the same shared practice space in the same facility, where the entity—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id51F160B8257F42B29933D9F68FD07ED9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provides services in a shared space that ensures services will be available and accessible promptly and in a manner which preserves human dignity and assures continuity of care;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8E35212AF0EB4BE695144C5913E26030"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensures communication among the integrated care team that is consistent and team-based;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB6EC228CED0C4721A73E2F61117D58F9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>ensures shared decisionmaking between mental health and primary care providers;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8A00FFF8A3B44C20A5139A7DFE40063D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>provides evidence-based services in a mode of service delivery appropriate for the target population;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida9f76ac47d7c42f4abd86f7b183ed04c"><enum>(E)</enum><text>employs staff who are multidisciplinary and culturally and linguistically competent;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcc43a696486748309e0b7b27f17ab3e6"><enum>(F)</enum><text>provides integrated services related to screening, diagnosis, and treatment of mental illness and co-occurring primary care conditions and chronic diseases; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id19a803044f0c43daa460f73ac0b83176"><enum>(G)</enum><text>provides targeted case management, including services to assist individuals gaining access to needed medical, social, educational, and other services and applying for income security, housing, employment, and other benefits to which they may be entitled.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id93852FED45E0470F9CB91EB2F3ED834D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Integrated care team</header><text>The term <term>integrated care team</term> means a team that includes—</text> <subparagraph id="id76ABBED9E2E64173B63760A08F4DE294"><enum>(A)</enum><text>allopathic or osteopathic medical doctors, including a primary care physician and a board certified psychiatrist;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id13C576B03DEF4F1AB6E1DA9BAFDAEC58"><enum>(B)</enum><text>licensed clinical mental health professionals, such as psychologists or social workers;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC71698077C62452997115E5B75EF0B35"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a case manager; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idBB1C6F0AD33B434389A9BED9EE39FBE3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>other members, which may include psychiatric advanced practice nurses and other allied health professionals, such as mental health counselors, or others as appropriate.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id28880B98F0634F96862A81FEB8CA1E8E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Special population</header><text>The term <term>special population</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="id239D9C338F0F43108F5E7C7FF4241D94"><enum>(A)</enum><text>adults with mental illnesses who have co-occurring primary care conditions with chronic diseases;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0c038376db81414e865f18bcd939e4ad"><enum>(B)</enum><text>adults with serious mental illnesses who have co-occurring primary care conditions with chronic diseases;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA0BD9F46646E461B847AC1D0C479A538"><enum>(C)</enum><text>children and adolescents with serious emotional disorders with co-occurring primary care conditions and chronic diseases; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF4E1390DB3D24AD4A8FADB0252CB4956"><enum>(D)</enum><text>individuals with substance use disorder.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id9749CCBE21304F80A2FFABF50ADBED4B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The grant program under this section shall be designed to lead to full collaboration between primary and behavioral health in an integrated practice model at a statewide level, to ensure that—</text>
 <paragraph id="id03031FD9CD2D42AA85023865391FAF32"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the overall wellness and physical health status of individuals with serious mental illness and co-occurring substance use disorders is supported through integration of primary care into community mental health centers meeting the criteria specified in section 1913(c) of the Social Security Act or certified community behavioral health clinics described in section 223 of the Protecting Access to Medicare Act of 2014; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id04F02A6499674E54BA213589994A2F5A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the mental health status of individuals with significant co-occurring psychiatric and physical conditions will be supported through integration of behavioral health into primary care settings.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1305dcab0c604002932314edefcec64a"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Eligible entities</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant or cooperative agreement under this section, an entity shall be a State department of health, State mental health or addiction agency, or State Medicaid agency. The Administrator shall give preference to States that have existing integrated care models, such as those authorized by section 1945 of the Social Security Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idE8E1259AF4C54F7A9C5EA476AD588FAC"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Application</header><text>An eligible entity desiring a grant or cooperative agreement under this section shall submit an application to the Administrator at such time, in such manner, and accompanied by such information as the Administrator may require, including a description of a plan to achieve fully collaborative agreements to provide services to special populations and—</text>
 <paragraph id="idf796a2ee358445219a8451c58d762311"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a document that summarizes the State-specific policies that inhibit the provision of integrated care, and the specific steps that will be taken to address such barriers, such as through licensing and billing procedures; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ide2eb471464604576af5b137b7c2f3cdd"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a plan to develop and share a de-identified patient registry to track treatment implementation and clinical outcomes to inform clinical interventions, patient education, and engagement with merged or transformed integrated practices in compliance with applicable national and State health information privacy laws.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idbfe65bef0bcc4572892cf97e9736268f"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Grant amounts</header><text>The maximum annual grant amount under this section shall be $2,000,000, of which not more than 10 percent may be allocated to State administrative functions, and the remaining amounts shall be allocated to health facilities that provide integrated care.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idD137159C95784B1E8997F3C723A3FDB5"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>A grant under this section shall be for a period of 5 years.</text> </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="idc611c9a67ed3433890c4f5e61c45995c"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Report on program outcomes</header><text>An entity receiving a grant or cooperative agreement under this section shall submit an annual report to the Administrator that includes—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="idDA0C1FA9A9EA4FBAA5AE60E1B401D14F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the progress to reduce barriers to integrated care, including regulatory and billing barriers, as described in the entity's application under subsection (d); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id4eb78f275d9444b3833025cc712b2cfb"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of functional outcomes of special populations, including—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="id3AB8B7A1A3A345E896D1977D9F9D1EA8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with respect to individuals with serious mental illness, participation in supportive housing or independent living programs, attendance in social and rehabilitative programs, participation in job training opportunities, satisfactory performance in work settings, attendance at scheduled medical and mental health appointments, and compliance with prescribed medication regimes;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id8FB3E4C10CB546138711C3C1FEDA3B6E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to individuals with co-occurring mental illness and primary care conditions and chronic diseases, attendance at scheduled medical and mental health appointments, compliance with prescribed medication regimes, and participation in learning opportunities related to improved health and lifestyle practice; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id4AB27EE9F4EE44BBA13C1295F8E04F78"><enum>(C)</enum><text>with respect to children and adolescents with serious emotional disorders who have co-occurring primary care conditions and chronic diseases, attendance at scheduled medical and mental health appointments, compliance with prescribed medication regimes, and participation in learning opportunities at school and extracurricular activities.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="id5217E2AD54C24D54A86A2FCBF5B6C439"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Technical assistance center for primary-Behavioral health care integration</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="id11B6B34096A14051AF5AE3C610AD512F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use Disorders shall establish a program through which such Assistant Secretary shall provide appropriate information, training, and technical assistance to eligible entities that receive a grant or cooperative agreement under this section, in order to help such entities to meet the requirements of this section, including assistance with—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id7caf70b7906741ad85882a8bd1d9d9d4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>development and selection of integrated care models;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc5aba2c07bd7451e87af2e72d6042b53"><enum>(B)</enum><text>dissemination of evidence-based interventions in integrated care;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd5032847bc4146f2a5966f7100c1b687"><enum>(C)</enum><text>establishment of organizational practices to support operational and administrative success; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id80c1152994014e9db1bbd578018c4c85"><enum>(D)</enum><text>other activities, as the Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use Disorders determines appropriate.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id880A29B7C3444C64B2AB09DD786149CD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional dissemination of technical information</header><text>The information and resources provided by the technical assistance program established under paragraph (1) shall be made available to States, political subdivisions of a State, Indian tribes or tribal organizations (as defined in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act), outpatient mental health and addiction treatment centers, community mental health centers that meet the criteria under section 1913(c), certified community behavioral health clinics described in section 223 of the Protecting Access to Medicare Act of 2014, primary care organizations such as Federally qualified health centers or rural health centers, other community-based organizations, or other entities engaging in integrated care activities, as the Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use Disorders determines appropriate.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idE6458929155C4DFDBA502F14006C9E9D"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>To carry out this section, there are authorized to be appropriated $50,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2017 through 2021, of which $2,000,000 shall be available to the technical assistance program under subsection (i).</text>
						</subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</section></title><title id="id028d1c5ad81048ddbcb0cc1d9f689ac1"><enum>IV</enum><header>Interagency Serious Mental Illness Coordinating Committee</header>
 <section id="id070f7536d6fd40358c98515bb5c8d4cc"><enum>401.</enum><header>Interagency Serious Mental Illness Coordinating Committee</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title V of the Public Health Service Act is amended by inserting after section 501 the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id914E60F6F0A448E0AEF6B8737A1C48CC" style="OLC">
					<section id="id24E8D070691942FE919393345256E032"><enum>501A.</enum><header>Interagency Serious Mental Illness Coordinating Committee</header>
 <subsection id="idA526FD99E5B44A31B29D6FE0DF4DB3F4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use Disorders (in this section referred to as the <quote>Assistant Secretary</quote>) shall establish a committee, to be known as the Interagency Serious Mental Illness Coordinating Committee (in this section referred to as the <quote>Committee</quote>), to assist the Assistant Secretary in carrying out the Assistant Secretary's duties.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idC2610A33F8B942AE854EB2B7E2969D48"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Committee shall—</text> <paragraph id="idC2D82BED54754FD5800B20456D0972F7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop and annually update a summary of advances in serious mental illness research related to prevention of, diagnosis of, intervention in, and treatment and rehabilitation of, serious mental illness, and access to services and supports for individuals with serious mental illness;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id8AA8D2E4BEA64A1EAE3006AEFEB4EA5C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">monitor Federal programs and activities with respect to serious mental illness;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idEA4766FA7FE14EACA0EA7C8A609E706A"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">make recommendations to the Assistant Secretary regarding any appropriate changes to such activities, including recommendations to the Director of NIH with respect to the strategic plan developed under paragraph (5);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id0BE26B98C1E14DE6B677A067F49B31D4"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">make recommendations to the Assistant Secretary regarding public participation in decisions relating to serious mental illness;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id87CC0245E7BB4828A8D31A8672C04F37"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop and update every 3 years a strategic plan for the conduct and support of programs and services to assist individuals with serious mental illness, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id3476513dd7ed47a0977a1ab1b99e3154"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a summary of the advances in serious mental illness research developed in under paragraph (1);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfa22794033724e75babd653461d11492"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a list of the Federal programs and activities identified in paragraph (2);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9841f76945d34afdb914211e64c584da"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an analysis of the efficiency, effectiveness, quality, coordination, and cost-effectiveness of Federal programs and activities relating to the prevention, diagnosis, treatment, or rehabilitation of serious mental illness, including an accounting of the costs of such programs and activities with administrative costs disaggregated from the costs of services and care; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8c0069b7377b46faa95fd9fc867dbb35"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a plan with recommendations—</text> <clause id="id21ef733ef7d14912bbc10583412606ee"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for the coordination and improvement of Federal programs and activities related to serious mental illness, including budgetary requirements;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id1c96bbb5449641e4835061b5ccd71f06"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for improving outcomes for individuals with a serious mental illness including appropriate benchmarks to measure progress on achieving improvements;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id128de7358d86436e8c7e35f5e35f9d8b"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>for the mental health workforce;</text> </clause><clause id="id3c34df6ae05543e48416958e694ee3c4"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>to disseminate relevant information developed by the coordinating committee to the public, health care providers, social service providers, public health officials, courts, law enforcement, and other relevant groups;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idAA92ED5FE33F4BB7984A7544AE0CF9E3"><enum>(v)</enum><text>to identify research needs, including longitudinal studies of pediatric populations; and</text> </clause><clause id="idA441D80542354401B889FCFE2CD2266F"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>for vulnerable and underserved populations, including pediatric and geriatric populations; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id70c50350f69f47a8942970548df03203"><enum>(6)</enum><text>submit to Congress such strategic plan and any updates to such plan.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id467a908bd65441bbbf9b505ea05eb81e"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Membership</header> <paragraph id="idbb686b79a1d042d49f2d5892910356c1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Committee shall be composed of not more than 9 Federal representatives including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="ide9d97d98f9084bf69d03c74bb8b0a5c4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use Disorders (or the Assistant Secretary's designee), who shall serve as the Chair of the Committee;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id341d08f731c7417a929ff10612125c3b"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Director of the National Institute of Mental Health (or the Director's designee);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8b11c3eafc5c4f809b32dab5e6b733f2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Attorney General of the United States (or the Attorney General's designee);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id69f9b8d8bad24300a5c6e0648431bf1b"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (or the Director's designee);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9d422f44e5db4dd1bc285a213ac8f36f"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Director of the National Institutes of Health (or the Director's designee);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd1295f48212b453990f06cb0be7aae3e"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a member of the United States Interagency Council on Homelessness;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7876d8a554314c5896ad44fbff7f93b0"><enum>(G)</enum><text>representatives, appointed by the Assistant Secretary, of Federal agencies that serve individuals with serious mental illness, including representatives of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services, the Administration on Community Living, the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality, the Bureau of Indian Affairs, the Department of Defense, the Department of Education, the Department of Housing and Urban Development, the Department of Labor, the Department of Veterans Affairs, and the Social Security Administration; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb73378f9775b4aaa94291e62eadd3381"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the additional members appointed under paragraph (2).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id90b6226f871147859e25df3e693b60c4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional members</header><text>At least 14 members of the Committee shall be non-Federal public members appointed by the Assistant Secretary, of which—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idd13f387be8704ee29cd36dbc084b03f1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>at least 1 member shall be an individual in recovery from a diagnosis of serious mental illness who has benefitted from and is receiving medical treatment under the care of a licensed mental health professional;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfb2f32f14ad34e74a1dc9a48c4ade4cb"><enum>(B)</enum><text>at least 1 member shall be a parent or legal guardian of an individual with a history of serious mental illness who has either attempted suicide or is incarcerated for violence committed while experiencing a serious mental illness;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9bcf79a1b6f44215b221e85a8da572c7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>at least 1 member shall be a representative of a leading research, advocacy, and service organization for individuals with serious mental illness;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9cd855a78ad145d183baa1884a098e1f"><enum>(D)</enum><text>at least 2 members shall be—</text> <clause id="ida6102f1ed03e41b0aae00eff1e9c8461"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a licensed psychiatrist with experience treating serious mental illness;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id847ccda2764e4703a618fe056e924591"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a licensed psychologist with experience treating serious mental illness;</text> </clause><clause id="idb5eb78308f9b485cbfb5b2be224db265"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a licensed clinical social worker; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="id1656dcddd9b746c69e8a003b1a51992a"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a licensed psychiatric nurse or nurse practitioner;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id590d5e1fd2374d7b869c209286e6abdc"><enum>(E)</enum><text>at least 1 member shall be a mental health professional with a significant focus in his or her practice on working with children and adolescents;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc1e7ee58817a42a3b9fb1fa56f573a64"><enum>(F)</enum><text>at least 1 member shall be a mental health professional who has demonstrated cultural competencies and has research or clinical mental health experience working with minorities;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id490368314c2d41c6952631fc1c091e9d"><enum>(G)</enum><text>at least 1 member shall be a State certified mental health peer specialist;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1b43e73d25cf499a9bca6d38573e8c66"><enum>(H)</enum><text>at least 1 member shall be a judge with experience adjudicating cases related to criminal justice and serious mental illness;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idacf761a18d314c8e88613c43d75bb496"><enum>(I)</enum><text>at least 1 member shall be a law enforcement officer or corrections officer with extensive experience in interfacing with psychiatric and psychological disorders or individuals in mental health crisis; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida7dd7b5b27454a1cb771c61c2c7d2074"><enum>(J)</enum><text>4 members, of which—</text> <clause id="idef291da919b0413fb6f8ac2fb901900d"><enum>(i)</enum><text>1 shall be appointed by the majority leader of the Senate;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id206851136c794fa7ac470be2361079f8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>1 shall be appointed by the minority leader of the Senate;</text> </clause><clause id="id969bd0871ddf42e68188ca44b4d11e3a"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>1 shall be appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id3d19c68298274fd8be6f29cab1395523"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>1 shall be appointed by the minority leader of the House of Representatives.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id3552df2d139d4ec7a98345f8205fb43b"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reports to congress</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of release of the first strategic plan under subsection (b)(5) and annually thereafter, the Committee shall submit a report to Congress—</text>
 <paragraph id="id6d7d8152e00a4958bb9993c0b7352e95"><enum>(1)</enum><text>evaluating the impact on public health of projects addressing priority mental health needs of regional and national significance under sections 501, 509, 516, and 520A, including measurement of public health outcomes such as—</text>
 <subparagraph id="ida2eebae3823849208de7c0ba6d5fd4a0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>reduced rates of suicide, suicide attempts, substance abuse, overdose, overdose deaths, emergency hospitalizations, emergency room boarding (as defined in section 1912(e)), incarceration, crime, arrest, homelessness, and joblessness;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idec1cc6f79ef5426baf63546eee4d0040"><enum>(B)</enum><text>increased rates of employment and enrollment in educational and vocational programs; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8345f9a32850414f9ea9b8d0ee47469c"><enum>(C)</enum><text>such other criteria as may be determined by the Assistant Secretary;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id011490e56bab4278b2a35498a13e66b8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>formulating recommendations for the coordination and improvement of Federal programs and activities described in paragraph (2);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id88a08f66fbdd47fe910152a639232401"><enum>(3)</enum><text>identifying any such programs and activities that are duplicative; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id363102546051406c8085a44b842e1361"><enum>(4)</enum><text>summarizing all recommendations made, activities carried out, and results achieved pursuant to the workforce development strategy under section 101(c)(8) of the <short-title>Mental Health Reform Act of 2015</short-title>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id52c5e8c5fa9448faab92e55d3f751abe"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Administrative support; terms of service; other provisions</header><text>The following provisions shall apply with respect to the Committee:</text>
 <paragraph id="id68aaeeefa6a9474a80fb157ec86b3d8e"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Assistant Secretary shall provide such administrative support to the Committee as may be necessary for the Committee to carry out its responsibilities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idab5b841e178a429dacb3318226971483"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Members of the Committee appointed under subsection (c)(2) shall serve for a term of 4 years, and may be reappointed for one or more additional 4-year terms. Any member appointed to fill a vacancy for an unexpired term shall be appointed for the remainder of such term. A member may serve after the expiration of the member's term until a successor has taken office.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id1be60e6a1ee6490a91dc9d1b2c8a2e2f"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Committee shall meet at the call of the chair or upon the request of the Assistant Secretary. The Committee shall meet not fewer than 2 times each year.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idc3c3b963e70247cd9177c337096aa320"><enum>(4)</enum><text>All meetings of the Committee shall be public and shall include appropriate time periods for questions and presentations by the public.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id33d209cbc1354870a7121f527925beee"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Subcommittees; establishment and membership</header><text>In carrying out its functions, the Committee may establish subcommittees and convene workshops and conferences. Such subcommittees shall be composed of Committee members and may hold such meetings as are necessary to enable the subcommittees to carry out their duties.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</section></title><title id="id3c4b405089064847b26a80e419fa76f4"><enum>V</enum><header>HIPAA clarification</header>
 <section id="id36252dd681f04c889eab709f37ec3974"><enum>501.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Senate makes the following findings:</text> <paragraph id="ideed3568a1a4b4c3faf4a56db55749656"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The privacy regulations promulgated under section 264(c) of the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1320d-2">42 U.S.C. 1320d–2</external-xref> note) recognize the value of family members in the health and well-being of individuals experiencing temporary psychosis. However, a lack of understanding by health professionals has been a barrier to many family members assisting in the treatment of an individual with serious mental illness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id1a9ef912dd9b4c9e9947a639622627ff"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The privacy rule under section 164.510(b)(2) of title 45, Code of Federal Regulations allows for the disclosure of protected health information in the event that a covered entity receives the individual’s agreement provides an opportunity for an individual to object, and the individual does not express an objection or the covered entity reasonably infers that the individual does not object.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idc4ea62eb9d7b4e7db88e518efe4bf306"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The privacy rule under section 164.510(b)(3) of title 45, Code of Federal Regulations allows for the disclosure of protected health information if an individual is not present or is otherwise incapacitated if the medical provider determines that the disclosure is in the best interests of the individual.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id11739892da4c4a54813d84f671f696d9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Engagement by family members has been shown to help individuals with serious mental illness adhere to a treatment plan and improved outcomes.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id5c3224acbc044c16ad587447835c19d0"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Whenever possible, an individual who is the subject of protected health information shall be given advanced notice of the desire to share information with family members or other caregivers. This notice should include an explanation of what information is to be shared and why it is clinically desirable to share such information.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idc9b78575eab04076828e5be791b42f38"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The use of psychiatric advance directives should be encouraged for individuals with serious mental illness.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="id89d20b2b5ba5435cb77fb93434bab1d7"><enum>502.</enum><header> Modifications to HIPAA</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In applying section 164.510(b)(3) of title 45, Code of Federal Regulations, for the purposes of assisting health professionals to determine the best interests of the individual, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall consider the following factors:</text>
 <paragraph id="ide3e65d978487442884161dd9c8d4be42"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Timely intervention for treatment of a serious mental or general medical illness.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id4a387f8f23ee498eb17052abbd37f8f1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Safe and stable housing for the individual.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id7192bfb0307b451798aee009dee56532"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Increased daily living skills that are likely to allow the individual to live within the community.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id84b0ae4aba7946b3b45faffeb781dfb2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An increased capacity of caregivers to support the patient to live within the community.</text>
				</paragraph></section><section id="id01d38e7509b34f4d8740766e0937591f"><enum>503.</enum><header>Development and dissemination of model training programs</header>
 <subsection id="id8cfc85489b9f4fab9e970d587669c6e5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Initial Programs and Materials</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services (in this section referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>), in consultation with appropriate experts, shall develop and disseminate—</text>
 <paragraph id="idd8f0f2bbd6e34289b0f97dd1e36170d6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a model program and materials for training health care providers (including physicians, emergency medical personnel, psychiatrists, psychologists, counselors, therapists, behavioral health facilities and clinics, care managers, and hospitals) regarding the circumstances under which, consistent with the standards governing the privacy and security of individually identifiable health information promulgated by the Secretary under section 264 of the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1320d-2">42 U.S.C. 1320d–2</external-xref> note) and part C of title XI of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1320d">42 U.S.C. 1320d et seq.</external-xref>), the protected health information of patients with a mental illness may be disclosed with and without patient consent;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idddb8e7915c5447888ee82b2401f23e7f"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a model program and materials for training lawyers and others in the legal profession on such circumstances; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idb5dc4226056d4868a3fb78e12300cdc5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a model program and materials for training patients and their families regarding their rights to protect and obtain information under the standards specified in paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id43f2cae6a81d4d0abb6376ebe1b5389b"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Periodic updates</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text> <paragraph id="id05a0794a8bc64b10a6c6a4320fb7cecc"><enum>(1)</enum><text>periodically review, evaluate, and update the model programs and materials developed under subsection (a); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id4cef09b36a8e4dd38aae3e53f9195554"><enum>(2)</enum><text>disseminate the updated model programs and materials.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id3674b6aeffce410a9d0bef9c2c0e5b03"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The programs and materials developed under subsection (a) shall address the guidance entitled <quote>HIPAA Privacy Rule and Sharing Information Related to Mental Health</quote>, issued by the Department of Health and Human Services on February 20, 2014.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id32ac357fdcdf4c9f9b48a6f985328bfd"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>The Secretary shall carry out this section in coordination with the Director of the Office for Civil Rights within the Department of Health and Human Services, the Administrator of the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration, the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, and the heads of other relevant agencies within the Department of Health and Human Services.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id0c72d923384b4378b03df206e27ad062"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Input of Certain Entities</header><text>In developing the model programs and materials required under subsections (a) and (b), the Secretary shall solicit the input of relevant national, State, and local associations, medical societies, and licensing boards.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idb05607ca886045788a115e73e97f6665"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $5,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2017 through 2022.</text>
 </subsection></section><section commented="no" id="id4ba115d9fb14490ba3c3c15bc94d31c3"><enum>504.</enum><header>Confidentiality of records</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 543 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290dd-2">42 U.S.C. 290dd–2</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after subsection (h) the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id29C082858D444A7E97B8A000E9CECDDF" style="OLC">
					<subsection commented="no" id="id5ca9de2b00e746e386c1340fff71466f"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Streamlined consent in integrated care settings</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="ida1256c639f8949ecb4dee129a9296493"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For the sharing of records described in subsection (a) involving the interchange of electronic health records (as defined in section 13400 of division A of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/5">Public Law 111–5</external-xref>) solely for the purposes of improving the provision of health care and health care coordination solely within accountable care organizations described in section 1899 of the Social Security Act, health information exchanges (as defined for purposes of section 3013), health homes (as defined in section 1945(h)(3) of the Social Security Act), or other integrated care arrangements (in existence before, on, or after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Mental Health Reform Act of 2015</short-title>), a patient’s prior written or electronic consent for disclosure and re-disclosure of records may be provided annually in a generalized and revocable format to and for all of the health care providers in the accountable care organization, health information exchange, health home, or other integrated care arrangement, who are involved in the patient’s care.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id6463457452e54ffdb2b93151f6aa76fb"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Disclosure required</header><text>For all other disclosures or re-disclosures of the records described in subsection (a), except those expressly proscribed in paragraph 1, patient consent is required to be obtained in accordance with the procedures described in part 2 of title 42, Code of Federal Regulations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id7b9efb574eca4be18f219b8c488ece2f"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Prohibitions</header><text>It shall be unlawful for any health plan or health insurance program to use the records described in subsection (a) or this subsection to deny or condition the issuance of a plan, policy, or coverage on the basis of the contents of such records, or for a health care provider to use the records described in subsection (a) and this section to discriminate in the provision of medically necessary health care services to an individual who is the subject of such records.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</section></title><title id="idbccd2865c58b4ea0995586c34baebca5"><enum>VI</enum><header>Medicare and Medicaid Reforms</header>
			<section id="id14dda1811fb44234a9403cd6057f67aa"><enum>601.</enum><header>Enhanced Medicaid coverage relating to certain mental health services</header>
				<subsection id="idae96912c65674061919b41a669d4276f"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Medicaid coverage of mental health services and primary care services furnished on the same day</header>
 <paragraph id="id4e5f506c83de43918e65cbaf95b54f9a"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1902(a) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396a">42 U.S.C. 1396a(a)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after paragraph (77) the following new paragraph:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id088A0D61A6D94D90A39A638A098BA1B8" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="id4e2a16e34c4c49e0abb39a25d87d5314"><enum>(78)</enum><text>not prohibit payment under the plan for a mental health service or primary care service furnished to an individual at a community mental health center meeting the criteria specified in section 1913(c) of the Public Health Service Act or a Federally qualified health center (as defined in section 1861(aa)(4)) for which payment would otherwise be payable under the plan, with respect to such individual, if such service were not a same-day qualifying service (as defined in subsection (ll)).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idca5c65f929924359b057b2486e5ab7c8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Same-day qualifying services defined</header><text>Section 1902 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396a">42 U.S.C. 1396a</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5E7E400EB3B646BEA2F815E07CF4AAA6" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="id05569b072c8b4999ace09f6b9e090fef"><enum>(ll)</enum><header>Same-Day qualifying services defined</header><text>For purposes of subsection (a)(78), the term <term>same-day qualifying service</term> means—</text>
 <paragraph id="idf006701087fa4e0f804f4865afddda85"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a primary care service furnished to an individual by a provider at a facility on the same day a mental health service is furnished to such individual by such provider (or another provider) at the facility; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id12fe32708a844d8fbc2c6153fc90bb1a"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a mental health service furnished to an individual by a provider at a facility on the same day a primary care service is furnished to such individual by such provider (or another provider) at the facility.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id744cbcfa95fe4eba96d20f0d7aa3a24b"><enum>(b)</enum><header>State option To provide medical assistance for certain inpatient psychiatric services to nonelderly
 adults</header><text>Section 1905 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396d">42 U.S.C. 1396d</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="idde3ccda76bcd4133bb22db7ffe8784bf"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text> <subparagraph id="id216e9e109169442e830bf0a176859b91"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (16)—</text>
 <clause id="id25c2df8d2ae94943beb2964d06a6ba36"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>effective</quote> and inserting <quote>(A) effective</quote>; and</text> </clause><clause id="idc578058c727e4dc783cf490b57b8e451"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by inserting before the semicolon at the end the following: <quote>, and (B) qualified inpatient psychiatric hospital services (as defined in subsection (h)(3)) for individuals over 21 years of age and under 65 years of age</quote>; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd86b871112474d6394c64700bd907f07"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the subdivision (B) that follows paragraph (29), by inserting <quote>(other than services described in subparagraph (B) of paragraph (16) for individuals described in such subparagraph)</quote> after <quote>patient in an institution for mental diseases</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idf1a4eae403dd4ddba5ccf77082cd235b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (h), by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9D74DF58A2774511914AEA043D0F6664" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="id370e43e30e36493a8d3c2103a191e0c1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>For purposes of subsection (a)(16)(B), the term <term>qualified inpatient psychiatric hospital services</term>' means, with respect to individuals described in such subsection, services described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (1) that are furnished in an acute care psychiatric unit in a State-operated psychiatric hospital or a psychiatric hospital (as defined section 1861(f)) if such unit or hospital, as applicable, has a facility-wide average (determined on an annual basis) length of stay of less than 20 days.</text>
							</paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id91c5b542535e4e6d9c238703251d3093"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Study and report</header>
 <paragraph id="id4c591cbd7ef844358cb5f29f179eb884"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Study</header><text>The Secretary shall conduct a study to determine the impact of the amendments made by this section on the Medicaid IMD exclusion.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id664e84de038b4439b60efceda2c0fbe1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report containing the results of the study conducted under paragraph (1). The report shall include the following information:</text>
 <subparagraph id="id2f54076e9982489cb15c1771d13ff280"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An assessment of the level of State expenditures on short-term acute inpatient psychiatric hospital care for which no Federal financial participation is provided for the most recent State fiscal year ending prior to the effective date of the amendments made by this section and an analysis of the impact of the changes to the Medicaid IMD exclusion made by such amendments on State expenditures for such care.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf0e5aa6f25484ebbb37e3cb89b960c18"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An assessment of the extent to which States used disproportionate share hospital payment adjustments described in section 1923 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396r-4">42 U.S.C. 1396r–4</external-xref>) to fund short-term acute inpatient psychiatric hospital care prior to the effective date of the amendments made by this section and an analysis of the impact of the changes to the Medicaid IMD exclusion made by such amendments on the use of such payment adjustments to fund such care.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id536b0bc08917494abf5260f1795e94b9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The total amount by which State expenditures and the extent to which States use disproportionate share hospital payment adjustments for short-term acute inpatient psychiatric hospital care have been reduced due to the changes to the Medicaid IMD exclusion made by the amendments made by this section.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id79ee9559c667462898ed4c522b1a4fe4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Recommendations for strategies to encourage States to reinvest savings in State expenditures and disproportionate share hospital payment adjustments that result from the changes to the Medicaid IMD exclusion made by the amendments made by this section in community-based mental health services.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idAEB35F69421143F880971C8C5CEE046F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this subsection:</text> <subparagraph id="id0800D8EABFC8438F93F49362BFF656EB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Medicaid IMD exclusion</header><text>The term <term>Medicaid IMD exclusion</term> means the prohibition on Federal matching payments under Medicaid for care or services provided to patients who have attained age 22, but have not attained age 65, in an institution for mental diseases under subdivision (B) of the matter following paragraph (29) of section 1905(a) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396d">42 U.S.C. 1396d(a)</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id67112ED4DC4A479FBD582458002A12DF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6D62BFCC16F2420E847AB829D8998E31"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Short-term acute inpatient psychiatric hospital care</header><text>The term <term>short-term acute inpatient psychiatric hospital care</term> means care provided in either—</text>
 <clause id="idEB2D5B559CF34726A4C1FB0D2FBA19B3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an acute-care psychiatric unit with an average annual length of stay of fewer than 20 days that is operated within a State-operated psychiatric hospital; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="idD7321D5F2932439E95B74463ECB35F86"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a psychiatric hospital with an average length of stay of fewer than 20 days on an annual basis.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id08fffe4bd6c3471d9f689400154d9db4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header> <paragraph id="id1e2bdd106cf249a9b427d72a135d060b"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraphs (2) and (3), the amendments made by this section shall apply to items and services furnished after the first day of the first calendar year that begins after the date of the enactment of this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id6823db1ff335434badb60174b72e2c62"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Certification of no increased spending</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall not be effective unless the Chief Actuary of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services certifies that the inclusion of qualified inpatient psychiatric hospital services (as defined by paragraph (3) of section 1905(h) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396d">42 U.S.C. 1396d(h)</external-xref>), as added by subsection (b)) furnished to nonelderly adults as medical assistance under section 1905(a) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396d">42 U.S.C. 1396d(a)</external-xref>), as amended by subsection (b), would not result in any increase in net program spending under title XIX of such Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5ba717cbc2d24c9ba1644027d8529f4d"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exception for State legislation</header><text>In the case of a State plan under title XIX of the Social Security Act, which the Secretary of Health and Human Services determines requires State legislation in order for the respective plan to meet any requirement imposed by amendments made by this section, the respective plan shall not be regarded as failing to comply with the requirements of such title solely on the basis of its failure to meet such an additional requirement before the first day of the first calendar quarter beginning after the close of the first regular session of the State legislature that begins after the date of enactment of this section. For purposes of the previous sentence, in the case of a State that has a 2-year legislative session, each year of the session shall be considered to be a separate regular session of the State legislature.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id3bbb7baca82943788a58a8759773984c"><enum>602.</enum><header>Modifications to Medicare discharge planning requirements</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1861(ee) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x(ee)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="id4c2a5e8c2cac46b1ac00525dd5618f6f"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by inserting <quote>and, in the case of a psychiatric hospital or a psychiatric unit (as described in the matter following clause (v) of section 1886(d)(1)(B)), if it also meets the guidelines and standards established by the Secretary under paragraph (4)</quote> before the period at the end; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idd23b21f2fa5e44c8bef9b803aa780189"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id988492E663C84E5A8A79BD9E6CBD13FC" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="ida6208e5db846464f9bc36ea0b88a2d3e"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Secretary shall develop guidelines and standards, in addition to those developed under paragraph (2), for the discharge planning process of a psychiatric hospital or a psychiatric unit (as described in the matter following clause (v) of section 1886(d)(1)(B)) in order to ensure a timely and smooth transition to the most appropriate type of, and setting for, posthospital or rehabilitative care. The Secretary shall issue final regulations implementing such guidelines and standards not later than 24 months after the date of the enactment of this paragraph. The guidelines and standards shall include the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="ide3c2115aea954d88a9f711205b65c041"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The hospital or unit must identify the types of services needed upon discharge by a patient being treated by the hospital or unit.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id042389351ed84422897995c46883b765"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The hospital or unit must—</text> <clause id="id12ebf72f82f24ac3b0557e3742798b7b"><enum>(i)</enum><text>identify organizations that offer community services to the community that is served by the hospital or unit and the types of services provided by the organizations; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id04af9d9ca17d494588bcea3c06cd1b5b"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>make demonstrated efforts to establish connections, relationships, and partnerships with such organizations.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida39e95c4670e4a72903b1e8091c95618"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The hospital or unit must arrange (with the participation of the patient and of any other individuals selected by the patient for such purpose) for the development and implementation of a discharge plan for the patient as part of the patient's overall treatment plan from admission to discharge. Such discharge plan shall meet the requirements described in subparagraphs (G) and (H) of paragraph (2).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf812cac349eb47c282e97153859c3efe"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The hospital or unit shall coordinate with the patient (or assist the patient with) the referral for posthospital or rehabilitative care and as part of that referral the hospital or unit shall include transmitting to the receiving organization, in a timely manner, appropriate information about the care furnished to the patient by the hospital or unit and recommendations for posthospital or rehabilitative care to be furnished to the patient by the organization.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></section></title><title id="id494a8e8791e24a1ba7c189fa9dad3290"><enum>VII</enum><header>Research by National Institute of Mental Health</header>
 <section id="id7d85ae30c3b740ea9f118c29b0e19e86"><enum>701.</enum><header>Increase in funding for certain research</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 402A(a) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/282a">42 U.S.C. 282a(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idC732F3D84A564F55A72E3C4C9E76FE78" style="OLC">
					<paragraph id="id6F36243C7CEE41C6AC8C9BA78F9E31FC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Funding for the brain initiative at the national
			 institute of mental health</header>
 <subparagraph id="id1BDDC55E325B4B53B642236ED1962F74"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to amounts made available pursuant to paragraphs (1) and (2), there are authorized to be appropriated to the National Institute of Mental Health for the purposes described in subparagraph (B) $40,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2017 through 2021.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id46DE3E66AC594A718019784A78054D5F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts appropriated pursuant to subparagraph (A) shall be used exclusively for the purpose of conducting or supporting—</text>
 <clause id="idE005811BD39E4BA09F9401318B8708CC"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">research on the determinants of self- and other directed-violence in mental illness, including studies directed at reducing the risk of self harm, suicide, and interpersonal violence; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="id80060B93A0714FCAABC9C1D972F5EAA1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">brain research through the Brain Research through Advancing Innovative Neurotechnologies Initiative.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</section></title><title id="id7900a7b90ad445669976d98a9e521a42"><enum>VIII</enum><header>SAMHSA reauthorization and reforms</header>
			<subtitle id="ide047b912c6044389b01146b7ce564587"><enum>A</enum><header>Organization and general authorities</header>
				<section id="idd86b7d618d9a4afe8bd12bc30a84a935"><enum>801.</enum><header>Peer review</header>
 <subsection id="idA701A3D2A2224CD5A9EE86F66B7D7D4A"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 501(h) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290aa">42 U.S.C. 290aa(h)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting at the end the following: <quote>In the case of any such peer-review group that is reviewing a proposal or grant related to mental illness, no fewer than half of the members of the group shall have a medical degree, a doctoral degree in psychology, or advanced degree in nursing or social work from an accredited graduate school, and shall specialize in the mental health field.</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idf65ec7d78e2648f38c36402c0fdd1a0a"><enum>(b)</enum><text>Section 504 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290aa-3">42 U.S.C. 290aa–3</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end of subsection (b) the following: <quote>At least half of the members of any peer-review group established under subsection (a) shall have a medical degree, a doctoral degree in psychology, or advanced degree in nursing or social work from an accredited graduate school, and shall specialize in the mental health field.</quote>.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="idb080460b50144c93891a73e6444a3054"><enum>802.</enum><header>Advisory councils</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Paragraph (3) of section 502(b) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290aa-1">42 U.S.C. 290aa–1(b)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id96D3647BA8B74DD3A228C1298D6091E4" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="idB655E1B690DB49B3A53701DEBEBD1300"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not fewer than half of the members of the group shall have a medical degree, a doctoral degree in psychology, or advanced degree in nursing or social work from an accredited graduate school and shall specialize in the mental health field.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0F0055F36E6B4202975AFE1F8F66D046"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each advisory committee shall include at least one member of the National Institute of Mental Health and 1 member from any Federal agency that has a program serving a similar population.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="idc62cda6ad5f64b9288a0cb42c9a05397"><enum>803.</enum><header>Grants for jail diversion programs reauthorization</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 520G(i) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290bb-38">42 U.S.C. 290bb–38(i)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>$10,000,000 for fiscal year 2001, and such sums as may be necessary for fiscal years 2002 through 2003</quote> and inserting <quote>$5,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2017 through 2021</quote>.</text>
 </section><section id="id4eba022032d840eb92c332525de2e8f2"><enum>804.</enum><header>Projects for assistance in transition from homelessness</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 535(a) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290cc-35">42 U.S.C. 290cc–35(a)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>$75,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2001 through 2003</quote> and inserting <quote>$65,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2017 through 2021</quote>.</text>
 </section><section id="id8f9c29e0777b4e7b8794b76d78ebecea"><enum>805.</enum><header>Comprehensive community mental health services for children with serious emotional disturbances</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 565 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290ff-4">42 U.S.C. 290ff–4</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="idf9115171c2694996a129316839dfaeeb"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(1), by striking <quote>receiving a grant under section 561(a)</quote> and inserting <quote>(irrespective of whether the public entity is in receipt of a grant under section 561(a))</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idf83efed249c246b9b0b62f8268666383"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(1)(B), by striking <quote>pursuant to section 562</quote> and inserting <quote>described in section 562</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id30793968628f46eda113cb8610360790"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (f)(1), by striking <quote>$100,000,000 for fiscal year 2001, and such sums as may be necessary for each of the fiscal years 2002 and 2003</quote> and inserting <quote>$117,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2017 through 2021</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="ide1c0053de9284f35a6e02e2700fda6af"><enum>806.</enum><header>Reauthorization of priority mental health needs of regional and national significance</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 520A(f)(1) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290bb-32">42 U.S.C. 290bb–32(f)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>$300,000,000 for fiscal year 2001, and such sums as may be necessary for each of the fiscal years 2002 and 2003</quote> and inserting <quote>$370,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2017 through 2021</quote>.</text>
				</section></subtitle></title><title id="ida421aa4b4470423fb9886bb03e82c2f2"><enum>IX</enum><header>Mental health parity</header>
			<section id="id591a7739c81548da96b46f84ccae8e0e"><enum>901.</enum><header>GAO study on preventing discriminatory coverage limitations for individuals with serious mental
 illness and substance use disorders</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States, in consultation with the Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use Disorders, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Secretary of Labor, and the Secretary of the Treasury, shall submit to Congress a report detailing the extent to which covered group health plans (or health insurance coverage offered in connection with such plans), including Medicaid managed care plans under section 1903 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396b">42 U.S.C. 1396b</external-xref>), comply with the Paul Wellstone and Pete Domenici Mental Health Parity and Addiction Equity Act of 2008 (subtitle B of title V of division C of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/343">Public Law 110–343</external-xref>) (in this section referred to as the <quote>law</quote>), including—</text>
 <paragraph id="id946fcb515cc14b299132cdb86ba9789d"><enum>(1)</enum><text>how nonquantitative treatment limitations, including medical necessity criteria, of covered group health plans comply with the law;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id8a78eb4f221d4cde88c881cc5cfaf9fa"><enum>(2)</enum><text>how the responsible Federal departments and agencies ensure that plans comply with the law; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="ideddd2035db6848d081ee406af8e6d9ef"><enum>(3)</enum><text>how proper enforcement, education, and coordination activities within responsible Federal departments and agencies can be used to ensure full compliance with the law, including educational activities directed to State insurance commissioners.</text>
				</paragraph></section><section id="iddf9ba573651d41259c6b0a3a543637e1"><enum>902.</enum><header>Report on investigations regarding parity in mental health and substance use disorder benefits</header>
 <subsection id="idf77cb1101ac24cfea13b9f1bc876d796"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Administrator of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services, in collaboration with the Assistant Secretary of Labor of the Employee Benefits Security Administration and the Secretary of the Treasury, and in consultation with the Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use Disorders, shall submit to Congress a report—</text>
 <paragraph id="id884cad4f05b7408cbf94f5f3db5a0a16"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identifying Federal investigations conducted or completed during the preceding 12-month period regarding compliance with parity in mental health and substance use disorder benefits, including benefits provided to persons with serious mental illness and substance use disorders, under the Paul Wellstone and Pete Domenici Mental Health Parity and Addiction Equity Act of 2008 (subtitle B of title V of division C of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/343">Public Law 110–343</external-xref>); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="iddeaad5f9554f46abb97096cb9bd371c7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>summarizing the results of such investigations.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idf905e313f5e04966aaf023e533a8bda0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Subject to subsection (c), each report under subsection (a) shall include the following information:</text>
 <paragraph id="id0b4006c951e14ad4b0f0b0b35af0f4e7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The number of investigations opened and closed during the covered reporting period.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id0f5281baaa574649a942148c70ece83e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The benefit classification or classifications examined by each investigation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id4866893d03ef4ff2a87933fb21c419f4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The subject matter or subject matters of each investigation, including quantitative and nonquantitative treatment limitations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id6939a12e4a614a0d8b066685aab732e4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A summary of the basis of the final decision rendered for each investigation.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4fe65fb198fa4b41bbb20f5a3cf7b1e8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Individually identifiable information shall be excluded from reports under subsection (a) consistent with Federal privacy protections.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="idA3F7DA383FFF4393BC60C8DF5C2A6CF3"><enum>903.</enum><header>Strengthening parity in mental health and substance use disorder benefits</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2726(a) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg-26">42 U.S.C. 300gg–26(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id680922fad7c447a9b33c1afd3c3294e2" style="OLC">
					<paragraph id="idD079D1C8C9B64F9186C3A4D8B2E7328F"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Disclosure and enforcement requirements</header>
						<subparagraph id="id720cb9e11f994f05a4a00da98b5eae7c"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Disclosure requirements</header>
 <clause id="id63cd7dfb8a8d4d84bab4733a663f92a4"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>Not later than March 1, 2016, the Secretary, in cooperation with the Secretary of Labor and the Secretary of the Treasury shall issue additional regulations or sub-regulatory guidance for carrying out this section, including an explanation of documents that are required to be disclosed, and analyses that are required to be conducted, including how non-quantitative treatment limitations are applied to mental health or substance use disorder benefits and medical or surgical benefits covered under the plan, by a group health plan (or health insurance issuer) offering health insurance coverage in the group or individual market in order for such plan or issuer to demonstrate compliance with the provisions of this section. The disclosure requirements shall include a report detailing the specific analyses performed to develop a compliance review of the requirements of the Paul Wellstone and Pete Domenici Mental Health Parity and Addiction Equity Act of 2008, including the amendments made by such Act. With respect to non-quantitative treatment limitations, this report shall—</text>
 <subclause id="id32f15da900864ba3b9db090fd62a82cd"><enum>(I)</enum><text>identify the specific factors used by the plan in performing its non-quantitative treatment limitations analysis;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id54a0e4ca59d944aeb0319b2166432b62"><enum>(II)</enum><text>identify and define the specific evidentiary standards relied on to evaluate the factors;</text> </subclause><subclause id="iddaa55b5d53ac4235913c25b50d8f4549"><enum>(III)</enum><text>describe how the evidentiary standards were applied to each service category;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idca1c018297c544fe993375551515d7ad"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>disclose the results of the analyses of the specific evidentiary standards in each service category; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idd1685cdd3ffc421a84832a7f876e8b3d"><enum>(V)</enum><text>disclose the plan’s specific findings in each service category and the conclusions reached with respect to compliance with comparability and stringency of application tests under the non-quantitative treatment limitations rule.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="id661a03a0c0f94ef0965cd4df77501212"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Guidance</header><text>The Secretary, in cooperation with the Secretary of Labor and the Secretary of the Treasury shall issue guidance to group health plans and health insurance issuers offering health insurance coverage in the group or individual markets on how to satisfy the requirements of this section with respect to making information, including certificate of coverage documents and instruments under which the plan is administered and operated that specify, include, or refer to procedures, formulas, and methodologies applied to determine a participant or beneficiary’s benefit under the plan, regardless of whether such information is contained in a document designated as the <quote>plan document</quote> available to current and potential participants and beneficiaries. This guidance shall include plan disclosure of how the plan has met the 2-part test under the non-quantitative treatment limitations rule of comparability and stringency in application.</text>
							</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id86162b5c9e8149868bb4a65490a550fa"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Enforcement</header>
 <clause id="idfc94087fff6940bd8f2f62768db2c981"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Process for complaints</header><text>The Secretary, in cooperation with the Secretary of Labor and the Secretary of the Treasury, as appropriate, shall, with respect to group health plans and health insurance issuers offering health insurance coverage in the group or individual market, issue guidance to clarify the process and timeline for current and potential participants and beneficiaries and their authorized representatives and providers with respect to such plans and coverage to file formal complaints of such plans or issuers being in violation of this section, including guidance on the relevant individual State, regional, and national offices with which such claims should be filed by plan type.</text>
 </clause><clause id="id4ff723bdb36d47c09e7e1a8b3a3fa492"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Authority for public enforcement</header><text>The Secretary shall make available to the public de-identified information on audits and investigations of group health plans and health insurance issuers conducted under this section.</text>
							</clause><clause id="idfa2452a1677e4f289bfb2fa4e439ffb7"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Audits</header>
 <subclause id="ide88a9a6d8dd948d99ad0260c1d5c4ffa"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Randomized audits</header><text>The Secretary is authorized to conduct randomized audits of group health plans and health insurance issuers offering health insurance coverage in the group or individual market to determine compliance with this section. Such audits shall be conducted on no fewer than 12 plans and issuers per plan year. The information shall be made plainly available on the public Internet websites of the Department of Health and Human Services and the Department of Labor.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id9ce092f70e0b4e52a1be24d4b97e7686"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Additional audits</header><text>In the case of a group health plan or health insurance issuer offering health insurance coverage in the group or individual market with respect to which at least 5 substantiated claims of the same type of non-compliance with this section have been filed during a plan year, the Secretary shall audit plan documents to determine compliance with this section. Information detailing the results of the audit shall be made available on the public Internet website of the Department of Health and Human Services.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></title></legis-body>
</bill>


