<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1462 IS: Eliminating Dangerous Oil Cars and Ensuring Community Safety Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 1462</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150522">May 22, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S270">Mr. Schumer</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S331">Mrs. Gillibrand</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S223">Mrs. Boxer</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S221">Mrs. Feinstein</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To improve the safety of oil shipments by rail and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Eliminating Dangerous Oil Cars and Ensuring Community Safety Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </section><section id="id60B6BE77E1BF4D1C801105D277B85503"><enum>2.</enum><header>Retrofitting or phasing-out certain tank cars</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 20155 of title 49, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2FC8B4C675D34F77B49F1688C5604C3E" style="USC"> <section id="id34C754AE404E439B81A0C07265FA55EC"><enum>20155.</enum><header>Tank cars</header> <subsection id="idE7B91C67D17C406CA40712780F361E69"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Retrofitting requirement</header><text>A rail carrier may not ship any hazardous material in any DOT–111 or non-jacketed CPC–1232 tank car on or after the applicable deadline set forth in subsection (b) unless the tank car has been retrofitted in accordance with the DOT–117 specification design established by the May 2015 final rule for the safe transportation of flammable liquids by rail.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id64AAA14AB56347AD9D7F4F0480FF096F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Deadlines</header><text>The deadlines set forth in this subsection are as follows:</text> <paragraph id="id86C0D75C797C4D779738715E5CA1BEF6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>For non-jacketed DOT–111 tank cars carrying materials in Packing Group I, January 1, 2017.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idC81DB5C7120545A9A9B44E152EAB5164"><enum>(2)</enum><text>For jacketed DOT–111 tank cars carrying materials in Packing Group I or II and non-jacketed DOT–111 tank cars carrying materials in Packing Group II, May, 1, 2017.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id7B952397812C45D6927C0105181C5A57"><enum>(3)</enum><text>For non-jacketed CPC–1232 tank cars carrying materials in Packing Group I, May 1, 2018.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idF9AA71EA4F7A407C93671374F497065E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>For non-jacketed CPC–1232 tank cars carrying materials in Packing Group II, May 1, 2019.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id744DCBB69EB846DB8050BFBF2DB8958B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>For jacketed CPC–1232 tank cars carrying materials in Packing Group I or II and all tank cars carrying materials in Packing Group III, May 1, 2020.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id7A9D6FEE25A7442A887F40AFA58EB882"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section, the terms <term>Packing Group I</term>, <term>Packing Group II</term>, and <term>Packing Group III</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 173.127(b) of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </section><section id="id63DCC0DD7DF8413BBAEE0AF7C655A26A"><enum>3.</enum><header>Crude oil stability requirement</header> <subsection id="idB90A2F77642C4B2F82299D13365793F8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/51">Chapter 51</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/5110">section 5110</external-xref> the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id21451AC70E9A4E16AC8F7DB2E2A89F5D" style="USC">
 <section id="id9BA8DD7693654C4A951AEE8B8EEB335C"><enum>5111.</enum><header>Crude oil volatility standard</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Eliminating Dangerous Oil Cars and Ensuring Community Safety Act</short-title>, the Secretary of Transportation, in consultation with the Administrator of the Pipeline and Hazardous Materials Safety Administration, shall establish and begin enforcing a national maximum volatility standard for the transport of crude oil by rail or by barge.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="id0FCCC8E1BC034B8490821DD4071BCAE8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>Chapter 51 of such title is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 5110 the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="id5a2cd8f9-ebf3-4d40-b6da-8fe3dd7abe90" style="USC"><toc><toc-entry idref="id9BA8DD7693654C4A951AEE8B8EEB335C" level="section">5111. Crude oil volatility standard.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section id="id81DEA685E1E8454CA3A1130E9588C185"><enum>4.</enum><header>Speed restrictions for trains with tank cars that do not comply with Federal safety standards</header>
 <subsection id="id147DAFBBA18C4CC2856E7A784ECEA75E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>DOT–111 tank cars</header><text>Any train carrying more than 10 cars, including at least 1 DOT–111 tank car carrying a hazardous material that has not been retrofitted in accordance with the DOT–117 specification design established by the May 2015 final rule for the safe transportation of flammable liquids by rail, may not be operated at a speed greater than 40 miles per hour while traveling through a county (or county equivalent) that has a population density of greater than 20 persons per square mile, as determined in the most recent decennial census.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idE6FC7C896C9449C79B9CFA4CE38CFB4D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Unjacketed CPC–1232 tank cars</header><text>Beginning on the date that is 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, any train carrying more than 10 cars, including at least 1 non-jacketed CPC–1232 tank car carrying a hazardous material that has not been retrofitted in accordance with the DOT–117 specification design established by the May 2015 final rule for the safe transportation of flammable liquids by rail, may not be operated at a speed greater than 40 miles per hour while traveling through a county (or county equivalent) that has a population density of greater than 20 persons per square mile, as determined in the most recent decennial census.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="idC4845F6432F946E2B25466DD9F916897"><enum>5.</enum><header>Inspections</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In addition to the track inspections required under sections 213.233 and 213.237 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, as of the date of the enactment of this Act, each rail carrier shall conduct, on main line routes that the rail carrier owns or has been assigned maintenance responsibility under section 213.5 of such title, and over which 1 or more high-hazard flammable trains are operated—</text>
 <paragraph id="id66639E5D6CD647568E18FEDD0E928ED1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">2 additional inspections for internal defects of all rail in Classes 3, 4, and 5 for every 40,000,000 gross tons transported on such lines, or annually, whichever interval is shorter; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id642AD815F23E485193336CD132B9B4F4"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">4 track geometry inspections each calendar year.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="id20A30D57F2AD486586DAF61CB701555A"><enum>6.</enum><header>Positive train control requirement</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/201">Chapter 201</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="idDA4D1BC4654749AA9DCC24AF0EB47077"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking section 20150; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id6833E7AC82EF476DBA35DFB061EC3008"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 20157—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id7892E0E3916242C589E7CA18F2397BF1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating subsection (i) as subsection (j); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id970DA8EE4B7940EBBA3DD4AFAA3FD432"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (h) the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id01B73DB91C1642F9A1A601505958B82E" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="id523755DD2234409FB760B112F46789DD"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Trains that carry crude oil or ethanol</header><text>Beginning on December 1, 2018, each rail line over which tank cars carrying crude oil or ethanol travel shall be equipped with a positive train control system.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="idA380471B613D46D89106E84D3DFAE63D"><enum>7.</enum><header>Oil spill response plans</header>
 <subsection id="id93464ADAB7DC46FAA65D102B225BAEB7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/209">Chapter 209</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id86E5E55F09D84FDF9E87D61BB1521F6A" style="USC"> <section id="idF10B0E3EF521417599B9FC39127FB6AB"><enum>20904.</enum><header>Oil spill response plans</header> <subsection id="id21A0BE06820B42CF99B4063BB240109B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Comprehensive oil spill response plans</header><text>Each rail carrier that transports crude oil, petroleum, or other hazardous products by rail shall develop comprehensive oil spill response plans, in accordance with part 130 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idCCF2B58A433641BE9419AB4064B041D8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Response plan audit program</header><text>The Administrator of the Federal Railroad Administration shall develop a program to audit response plans for rail carriers of crude oil, petroleum, and other hazardous products to ensure that such plans include comprehensive procedures for—</text>
 <paragraph id="id124C81572B9242628AF1625369388560"><enum>(1)</enum><text>preventing or mitigating a substantial threat of a worst-case discharge of such products resulting from a rail accident or incident; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id99BA702C00EE47319332881CF6B71C49"><enum>(2)</enum><text>responding to and cleaning up such a discharge.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="id9BB707900ACE4BD69CD74B5AF631C91D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text>The Administrator of the Pipeline and Hazardous Materials Safety Administration, in consultation with the Administrator of the Federal Railroad Administration, shall update the regulations contained in part 130 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, by revising the spill response planning thresholds to require comprehensive response plans to effectively provide for the carrier’s ability to respond to worst-case discharges resulting from accidents involving unit trains or blocks of tank cars transporting oil and petroleum products.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id10895DB245784FAB9C46E70ACB520D8E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections in <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/209">chapter 209</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="idbd0f53f9-3173-4c65-9615-0e7c38a750d3" style="USC"><toc><toc-entry idref="idF10B0E3EF521417599B9FC39127FB6AB" level="section">20904. Oil spill response plans.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section id="id05EBC1EBEEB54923B09C8D7404D34365"><enum>8.</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header>
 <subsection id="idD838279FD8CB4D76BC4980F2FFEEED29"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Close call reporting systems</header><text>Section 20901 of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE0256671360F4A2895B1B092709F36C1" style="OLC"> <subsection id="idA38AA97FE73D4F9AA16D70BEC216274D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Close call reporting system</header><text>Each rail carrier shall establish a system through which employees may anonymously report circumstances or incidents that endanger the safety of railroad operations.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="id72963A73DCEF45419C5F8A50629E1ED1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Derailment reporting requirement</header><text>Section 20901 of such title, as amended by subsection (a), is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idCA17897596E14681BFBB3A9D5B1D7F83" style="USC">
					<subsection id="id264e8189f4af44abbda8a1109de16da9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Derailment reporting requirements</header>
 <paragraph id="idA9173237918C4B7BA6BF413731FE3886"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Defined term</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>high hazard flammable train</term> means a train comprised of more than 10 loaded tank cars of a Class 3 flammable liquid.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id55A0A6B311F74D0A801F338F4ADEC236"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Immediate notification</header><text>Immediately after the derailment of any high hazard flammable train operated by a rail carrier, the rail carrier shall provide the Federal Railroad Administration and the county emergency management contact (or equivalent) in the county in which the train derailed with—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id5b943b77c4844dfa9a4ad934a3dee50a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>information about the train, including—</text> <clause id="id57453AA3A7B64FB3AA0B22BD8CF5CBDD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the train number;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id4EB464629F964A7EB646D33857F468AC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the models of locomotive attached to the train;</text> </clause><clause id="idFCAA1AA0B2B14C93B5897A536ABBB529"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>end-of-train device information;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id4FB0D7DC41B748649857937DF79D111D"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the number and position of tank cars in the train;</text> </clause><clause id="idEA0E8E8916994C539421D5CE4BB9D821"><enum>(v)</enum><text>tank car reporting marks; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idC8049D29F21B40368CA83462A641DFB1"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>tank car specifications and relevant attributes, including information related to thermal protection, shell and head thickness, steel specification and grade, head shield, and pressure relief valve setting;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcc260877d89f4f54aeaf88b5905751af"><enum>(B)</enum><text>information contained on the waybill, including the origin and destination of the train, the goods being transported, and the name and contact information for consignors of such goods;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id68d835aa05534c97baba4e4ca8c6db1d"><enum>(C)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idB4E15322E946427B803438775A87C4E5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the safety data sheet for each hazardous chemical being transported by the train, as required under section 1910.1200(g) of title 29, Code of Federal Regulations; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="id1C8B2A27A58443C6BD0E96979940E27B" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any other documents used to provide comprehensive emergency response and incident mitigation information for Class 3 flammable liquids.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id70f923d7011a495ca21fcb5f3c41fd93"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Subsequent notification</header><text>Not later than 90 minutes after the derailment of any high hazard flammable train operated by a rail carrier, the rail carrier shall provide the Federal Railroad Administration with—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id733888e4fde7471ab3053f85373e1d57"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the results of any product testing undertaken before transportation that was used to properly characterize the Class 3 flammable liquids for transportation;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id37ce31fd1db94140a55a2d4b424dda69"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the results from any analysis of product samples taken before being offered into transportation from tank cars involved in the derailment;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id68379b0f04b540ccb2fc4e29a2e900a4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>if a flammable liquid is involved in the derailment, the type of liquid and the name and location of the company extracting the material;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id788f9ee9d2c34e49b85844662d5d2a5d"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the identification of the company that conducted the initial testing of the material, including sampling and analysis;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb7c95e46e7a74854996ccaf960b4f96a"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the name and location of the company transporting the material from the well head to the loading facility or terminal;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfa8012cf8caa4e9784603a715e6a5655"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the name and location of the company that owns and that operates the terminal or loading facility that loaded the product for rail transportation;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idadb4aede85004b9b9602227f55415577"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the name of the railroads handling the tank cars at any time from point of origin to destination; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC6308947DFE647BA82A833D9E5B58479"><enum>(H)</enum><text>a timeline of handling changes between railroads.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body> </bill> 

