<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1821 IS: Armed Forces Self-Defense Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 1821</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150721">July 21, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S345">Mr. Johnson</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To permit service members to carry firearms on military installations, including
			 reserve centers and recruitment offices.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Armed Forces Self-Defense Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="id8a2e1005b63b42b9a5c160bdeb365acc"><enum>2.</enum><header>Statement of policy</header>
 <subsection id="id998b1850259d44b88e85a8269c46dc80"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>It is the policy of the United States that Department of Defense personnel shall be appropriately armed and have the inherent right to self-defense.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id967dfe34d3df49a181573303507accf8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Department of Defense policy</header><text>It shall be the policy of the Department of Defense to permit trained military personnel to carry, open or concealed, certain personal firearms while on military installations in the United States.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id9237138FC620427BACA3ED71CE904E28"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This section shall take effect not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text> </subsection></section><section id="id2d92884d98654656a8046eca8bf6d72e"><enum>3.</enum><header>Repeal of portions of regulations and directives prohibiting service members trained in the use of firearms from carrying a personal firearm on a military installation</header> <subsection id="id9ae0eb3dd7044baba2829f7904638214"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Termination of force and effect of current regulations and directives</header><text>Effective not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the following regulations, directives, and rules shall have no further force or effect:</text>
 <paragraph id="id9e13be26959543c2b2a681b64f5345f7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Section 4.b. of the Department of Defense Directive Number 5210.56, issued on November 1, 2001, and modified on January 24, 2002, and on April 1, 2011.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idb4e33a43bde3472a8b3a74ee3963e454"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Army Regulation 190–14, issued on March 12, 1993.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idbe3731e990e04f92994ef4a6e1a62ea2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Other firearm bans</header><text>Effective not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, any provision in any other rule, regulation, or Executive order that prohibits military personnel trained in firearms from carrying personal firearms on United States military installations shall have no further force or effect with regard to such military personnel, and such military personnel shall not be prohibited from carrying personal firearms on United States military installations.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="idcb734ad2b1dc42e88672bb2f856929bb"><enum>4.</enum><header>Process by which service members may carry a personal firearm on a
			 military installation</header>
 <subsection id="ida66b4e9d1730458c8e095a0be114a292"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Process required</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense, taking into consideration the views of senior leadership of military installations in the United States, shall establish a process by which the commander of a military installation in the United States may authorize a member of the Armed Forces who is assigned to duty at the installation to carry a personal firearm on the installation if the commander determines it to be necessary as a personal- or force-protection measure.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id15fd3f00841b4045b4f2ccd42de25a78"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Relation to State and local law</header><text>In establishing the process under subsection (a) for a military installation, the commander of the installation shall consult with elected officials of the State and local jurisdictions in which the installation is located and take into consideration the law of the State and such jurisdictions regarding carrying a personal firearm.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id3da01bc518654a358cbcc486e8b1036f"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Member qualifications</header><text>To be eligible to be authorized to carry a personal firearm on a military installation pursuant to the process established under subsection (a), a member of the Armed Forces—</text>
 <paragraph id="id070c48e54bb74bcf98fe8d14052864b5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>must complete any training and certification required by any State in which the installation is located that would permit the member to carry in that State;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idb37c50ff67304ebdb5a77752409230e1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>must not be subject to disciplinary action under the Uniform Code of Military Justice for any offense that could result in incarceration or separation from the Armed Forces; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id9d03a45319304e39aac7477163f7d7bb"><enum>(3)</enum><text>must not be prohibited from possessing a firearm because of conviction of a crime of domestic violence.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id9be7928502ce4ef5866f5dc775890e91"><enum>(d)</enum><header>State defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>State</term> includes the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and any territory or possession of the United States.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="iddf5479621f0740ec97e38f75b48a9a92"><enum>5.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="id75FE33A12AD3415288E44833446BCAEE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Military installation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>military installation</term> means a base, camp, post, station, yard, center, or other activity, including a reserve center and a recruitment office, under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of a military department.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idE3053ABBCC284A3D8E90E7171042EB05"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Firearm</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>firearm</term> means a handgun, specifically, a gun designed for use in one hand such as a pistol or a revolver.</text> </paragraph></section></legis-body> </bill> 

