<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S471 IS: Women Veterans Access to Quality Care Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 471</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150212">February 12, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S352">Mr. Heller</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S229">Mrs. Murray</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSVA00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To improve the provision of health care for women veterans by the Department of Veterans Affairs,
			 and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body>
 <section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Women Veterans Access to Quality Care Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="ida44f644a9d1646c18999b6613a0216c2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Establishment of structural standards to meet gender-specific health care needs in medical
			 facilities  of Department of Veterans Affairs</header>
			<subsection id="id5ac4346fa70740d0ac63587875472cab"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header>
 <paragraph id="id55B619A415794A989E5C8130B31DD68D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall establish standards to ensure that all medical facilities of the Department of Veterans Affairs have the structural characteristics necessary to adequately meet the gender-specific health care needs of veterans at such facilities, including privacy, safety, and dignity.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idf92dfcd6bbc0466395265eeecf5f2891"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall promulgate regulations to carry out paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idb3bf536c37da4db6bf1df0bfc0fcec2f"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Integration into prioritization methodology</header><text>Not later than 270 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall integrate the standards established under subsection (a)(1) into the prioritization methodology used by the Department under paragraph (5) of section 8104(b) of title 38, United States Code, with respect to requests for the funding of major medical facility projects and major medical facility leases under such section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idf3bc955573d14454b4cba164ea934d39"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 450 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on the standards established under subsection (a)(1) that includes the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="id2b4f29d1a9784b3384d53bc27017a5ff"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A list of the medical facilities of the Department that fail to meet such standards.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="iddf5c34fd3a7d4cf68e82da3568e0c8cd"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The minimum total cost of the projects or leases that would be required to ensure that all medical facilities of the Department meet such standards.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id81b13c40ac90417dad509a8555ca5ca0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The number of such projects or leases that qualify as a major medical facility project or major medical facility lease under section 8104(a)(3).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id72d83250c2e249699fc2266f265babb9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Where each such project or lease is located in the current project prioritization of the Department.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idBA5246B2EA1E409283A536A0BE01FA92"><enum>3.</enum><header>Use of health outcomes for women veterans in evaluating the
			 performance of directors of medical centers of Department and disclosure
			 of health outcomes</header>
 <subsection id="idF7762447F8A34EA7BDB6F280B8DBDB33"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Evaluation of directors</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall use health outcomes for women veterans furnished hospital care, medical services, and other health care by the Department of Veterans Affairs in evaluating the performance of directors of medical centers of the Department.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="idA70CD0703654446D81B799E0B36A0050"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Public availability</header>
 <paragraph id="idA34BC83E75FD441F8B0A7661EF1F7767"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall publish on an Internet website of the Department available to the public information on the performance of directors of medical centers of the Department with respect to health outcomes for women veterans.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idE4189EFABEAD4480911994B5378DF777"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Data on health outcomes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall publish on an Internet website that is available to the public of each medical facility of the Department the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="id14FA649126164C058AD37122FC5E8658"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Data on health outcomes pursuant to key health outcome metrics at such facility for veterans who are women.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE0247C055B1149078DC8E9B0003F060F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A comparison of how such data compares to data on health outcomes pursuant to key health outcome metrics at such facility for veterans who are men.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE4620A572BCE4A58A94E0FFF8848D1DD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Explanatory or clarifying information necessary for members of the public to understand the data under subparagraphs (A) and (B).</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idC64A79D86AE64131A7DB293C9C1A3DFE"><enum>4.</enum><header>Increase in number of obstetricians and gynecologists of Department of Veterans Affairs</header>
 <subsection id="idDE5721E011B4436392D1DF2CB2F08FCD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 540 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall ensure that every medical center of the Department of Veterans Affairs has a full-time obstetrician or gynecologist.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id67118A9BA5B14589B50A92ECE679062E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Pilot program on increase of residency and medical education positions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall carry out a pilot program to increase the number of residency program positions and graduate medical education positions for obstetricians and gynecologists at medical facilities of the Department of Veterans Affairs in not less than three Veterans Integrated Service Networks of the Department.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="idD787E8142BE7451AAEE122B09437FC0B"><enum>5.</enum><header>Procedures for provision of certain information to State veterans agencies to facilitate the
			 furnishing of assistance and benefits to veterans</header>
 <subsection id="id59A42B019C8840BBAB1525F957508F98"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Procedures required</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall develop procedures to share the information described in subsection (b) regarding veterans with State veterans agencies in electronic data format as a means of facilitating the furnishing of assistance and benefits to veterans.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id5DCC39757CA74CE19EE4F8054701D17B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Covered information</header><text>The information shared with State veterans agencies under subsection (a) regarding a veteran shall include the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="id15c7456b3992453ca56e0aca0dca9abc"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Military service and separation data.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idcb12cc7b6a334a11abbef2b3fed0dd33"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A personal email address.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idb96a69edb5d6493f85924e99a50c4d49"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A personal telephone number.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idcb8911b44e8d460fbad80b2d462d82a6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A mailing address.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="iddced4f3993e7416891a496b864ea1f57"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Opt-Out election</header><text>A veteran may elect to prevent their information from being shared with State veterans agencies under subsection (a) pursuant to a process that the Secretary shall establish for purposes of this subsection.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbc7ac08d06ea4cb481814acb355ee83f"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Use of information</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that the information shared with State veterans agencies in accordance with the procedures developed under subsection (a) is only shared by such agencies with county government veterans service offices for such purposes as the Secretary shall specify for the administration and delivery of assistance and benefits.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="id2022089FDB32499DB30CD1ABDCE8FFC2"><enum>6.</enum><header>Comptroller General report on ability of medical centers of Department of Veterans Affairs to meet
			 health care needs of women veterans</header>
 <subsection id="id5D01B730A5C24C708BF95FABAC1B197C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Comptroller General of the United States shall carry out an examination of whether the medical centers of the Department of Veterans Affairs are able to meet the health care needs of women veterans.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id02C701BF88AF44978400310850332966"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The examination under subsection (a) shall address, with respect to each medical center of the Department, at a minimum, the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="idC124E2D2FA0C43B6A9107A05FAF351E4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The wait times for women veterans for appointments for the receipt of hospital care, medical services, or other health care.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id9FBF690C0E2642DB95FC3A03814E670B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Whether the medical center has a clinic that specializes in the treatment of women.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id07DBDB32E54547CF8F341D6D5DA310CD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The number of full-time obstetricians or gynecologists.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id44A1DBF64A98426C8F3B3327D0E19F5C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The number of health professionals trained in women's health.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idB4EA2204AA11488DAD152113A20183A5"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The extent to which the medical center conducts regular—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id475304FD4427430E8F8D6ADA8D23326C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>training on issues specific to women's health; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id49E0AA8AE4324E0998316AAD7E2E0EEA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>sensitivity training.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idE49D4281CBF8476D8372BC551F3B6F65"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The differences in health outcomes between men and women.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id1C1C8640DF5E4575907395025095EBF4"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The security and privacy measures used in registration, clinical, and diagnostic areas.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id7FC3DCA80B0345F3921B0130C91205C4"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The availability of gender-specific equipment or procedures.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idC57E017E4DDA45C18555FB5237FFEB13"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The extent to which the Center for Women Veterans of the Department advises and engages with the medical center with respect to providing health care to women veterans.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id775513597C324A8DA34EB59C52AD58D2"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The extent to which the medical center implements directives from the Center for Women Veterans.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idFBA8E5A10B3B404FA1DAEBFE132AB0E0"><enum>(11)</enum><text>The outreach conducted by the Department to women veterans in the community served by the medical center.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id627348DEB8304F2C8BE68212317DF3F2"><enum>(12)</enum><text>The collaboration between the medical center and non-Department entities, including veterans service organizations, to meet the health care needs of women veterans.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id73314968645943C2B5FF9D3FC74AA219"><enum>(13)</enum><text>The effectiveness of Patient Aligned Care Teams in meeting the health care needs of women veterans.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id299CDD4E1A234EF1B114B7E857E91DE7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 270 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on the examination carried out under subsection (a).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id384EAFBDD59640B2A5E3508B9FB9E07E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Veterans service organization defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>veterans service organization</term> means an organization recognized by the Secretary for the representation of veterans under section 5902 of title 38, United States Code.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


