<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1502 IS: To authorize the award of the Medal of Honor to James Megellas, formerly of Fond du Lac, Wisconsin, and currently of Colleyville, Texas, for acts of valor on January 28, 1945, during the Battle of the Bulge in World War II.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-06-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 1502</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150604">June 4, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S345">Mr. Johnson</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S287">Mr. Cornyn</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S354">Ms. Baldwin</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To authorize the award of the Medal of Honor to James Megellas, formerly of
			 Fond du Lac, Wisconsin, and currently of Colleyville, Texas, for acts of
			 valor on January 28, 1945, during the Battle of the Bulge in World War II.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Authorization for award of Medal of Honor to James Megellas for acts of valor during
			 Battle of the Bulge</header>
 <subsection id="id2ba567ccca554337930c51a17991ca73"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text>The President may award the Medal of Honor under section 3741 of title 10, United States Code, to James Megellas, formerly of Fond du Lac, Wisconsin, and currently of Colleyville, Texas, for the acts of valor described in subsection (b).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id5a58d502b4b24adeba56a09acb950bcb"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Action described</header><text>The acts of valor referred to in subsection (a) are the actions of James Megellas on January 28, 1945, in Herresbach, Belgium, during the Battle of the Bulge, during World War II, when, as a first lieutenant in the 82d Airborne Division, he led a surprise and devastating attack on a much larger advancing enemy force, killing and capturing a large number and causing others to flee, single-handedly destroying an attacking German Mark V tank with two hand-held grenades, and then leading his men in clearing and seizing Herresbach.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idcc5077188fb949ae9dc0f375e6b3fbb5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Waiver of time limitations</header><text>The award under subsection (a) may be made without regard to the time limitations specified in section 3744(b) of title 10, United States Code, or any other time limitation established by law or regulation with respect to the awarding of certain medals to persons who served in the Army.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


