<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S2076 IS: Super Pollutants Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-09-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2076</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150924">September 24, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S364">Mr. Murphy</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S252">Ms. Collins</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEV00">Committee on Environment and Public Works</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To establish a task force to review policies and measures to promote, and to develop best practices
			 for, reduction of short-lived climate pollutants, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body>
 <section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Super Pollutants Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </section><section id="id93B07CC1BFC44AC789F64894187EB518"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text> <paragraph id="id47695058df82490c84121f13f19bd386"><enum>(1)</enum><text>short-lived climate pollutants account for 40 percent of global warming impacting the atmosphere, even though those pollutants account for a much smaller percentage of warming agents, by weight;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id65be46bc371b4c22ba03830d427ad810"><enum>(2)</enum><text>reducing short-lived climate pollutant emissions could—</text> <subparagraph id="id85998B4C25AA42EEA8A8BA75E99B437A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>prevent more than 2,000,000 premature deaths each year, according to the United Nations Environment Programme (UNEP);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8E2B72C7AA5C4F4FA46FA12673195301"><enum>(B)</enum><text>prevent more than 30,000,000 tons of crop losses each year, according to UNEP;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7537F15699F549C1B866C30803CA8143"><enum>(C)</enum><text>cut the rate of sea-level rise by 25 percent, according to the National Center for Atmospheric Research and the Scripps Institution of Oceanography;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4EAFC61956454ECB81ACDD5EC83F68FC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>cut the rate of warming by up to 0.6 degrees Celsius by 2050, according to UNEP; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8AE9A1C07648401EA19D20BB9A71CAFD"><enum>(E)</enum><text>significantly contribute toward the overall global target of holding increased warming below 2 degrees Celsius;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idb9a3f40f05004362bf8af26e74d0a47f"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the United States is—</text> <subparagraph id="id7CB57791B55546E5912D27F678AB346B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>1 of the largest consumers of hydrofluorocarbons in the world; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4A420B58629148A2B9D0E57E020B2647"><enum>(B)</enum><text>providing significant innovation in the development of low global warming potential (low-GWP) alternatives;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id60F024F54A0247A39D723F24C169AFB6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the United States could serve as a leader and exemplar of responsibly phasing down hydrofluorocarbon production and consumption;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id8C40827D32114D879726BE3F0271D016"><enum>(5)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id7902C8D743D540D292C025A6F1CFA13E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Montreal Protocol on Substances that Deplete the Ozone Layer has been an extraordinarily successful model for protecting the stratospheric ozone layer and achieving significant climate protection cobenefits; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id77D65717C52F415587BAE29D611815E1" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>since that treaty was signed in 1987, there has been a 98-percent reduction in ozone-depleting substances; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id72E5890864FE4C90A2B1DF162D15301E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the interagency Strategy to Reduce Methane Emissions, released in March 2014, outlines a proactive agenda for reducing methane leakage and waste throughout the United States economy.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="idCFFF6962A12546E0AFAB79C2BA81DDD6"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="id29AEC38B93B54B52B2A2E587D84F9E0E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Short-lived climate pollutant</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>short-lived climate pollutant</term> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idC873A74B68B44EDF8FF1E86723B43859"><enum>(A)</enum><text>black carbon;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2D08E4E8E15A49B6AE44664A443AECF2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>methane; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3C592C59A2D94873B7AF6D815D5ADFE9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>high global warming potential hydrofluorocarbons (referred to in this Act as <quote>high-GWP HFC</quote>).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id51A508A04E0F43CC929151337381F52B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Task Force</header><text>The term <term>Task Force</term> means the Interagency Task Force on Short-Lived Climate Pollutant Mitigation established under section 4(a).</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="id03D60D6E4AF34C17BE39A0ABA2C58A1D"><enum>4.</enum><header>Interagency Task Force on Short-Lived Climate Pollutant Mitigation</header>
 <subsection id="id7522958699FA43FF8B81C901A99BF23A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the President shall establish a task force, to be known as the <quote>Interagency Task Force on Short-Lived Climate Pollutant Mitigation</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idBCBE366F622D431785EC6712112BE293"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>The members of the Task Force shall include the head of each relevant Federal department or agency (or a designee), including the Department of Agriculture, the Department of Commerce, the Department of Defense, the Department of Energy, the Department of the Interior, the Department of State, the Department of Transportation, the Environmental Protection Agency, the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, and the United States Agency for International Development.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idc161d940d73346b3a3715ff9713808e8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Task Force shall—</text> <paragraph id="id3BAA3A30141A44B1B286D012265225F9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that includes—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id705318095FB9468E86A97BA6BC9F3879"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the plans of the relevant departments or agencies for meeting the goals established in section 2 of Executive Order 13514 (October 5, 2009) (74 Fed. Reg. 52117) to reduce hydrofluorocarbons, methane, and related indirect emissions (including tropospheric ozone) by the Federal Government; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idBEB09AF572E446709683E6594310FAA1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>specific plans of the relevant departments or agencies—</text> <clause id="idF12CD84164DA41E8BF5EAD962A07E10B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to purchase cleaner alternatives to high-GWP HFC whenever feasible; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idD560BCA3A4EB488DB519DC8A77E5D007"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to transition over time to equipment that uses safer and more sustainable alternatives to high-GWP HFC;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id2EDD451F7E55432A8A5542216FB7DD08"><enum>(2)</enum><text>review the policy recommendations made by—</text> <subparagraph id="id379CECEBEB224DEC9A7400F40576D66E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Interagency Climate Change Adaptation Task Force;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD3211A66E02840919BCBA27F5C7EDAF2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Interagency Strategy to Reduce Methane Emissions;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id027CC76DFF5B4F0BB0B8F8E53DC629C5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the report to Congress regarding black carbon dated March 2012; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB7178D2AEA1C437CAC7AD7996CE5AE04"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Council on Climate Preparedness and Resilience;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idD4D7E934C6FC47B79DB01ED848EEE1A6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>incorporate into the action plan of the Task Force any appropriate proposals or recommendations made by the entities or reports referred to in paragraph (2) that are relevant to short-lived climate pollutants;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id64FAF0D7684C43B0A71052DC8B6082E1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>identify relevant Federal programs that are or could be addressing the reduction of short-lived climate pollutants in the United States and worldwide;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id2ef8d16ec84044a9875e188bf4a4ce5e"><enum>(5)</enum><text>identify overlapping and duplicative programs addressing short-lived climate pollutants that would benefit from consolidation and streamlining;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id7abfa1a313934853ad9013f5bba7cdb2"><enum>(6)</enum><text>identify gaps and serious deficiencies in United States programs targeted at short-lived climate pollutants, including those that can be achieved through a combination of assessment, scientific research, monitoring, and technological development activities, with an emphasis on industry standards and public-private partnerships;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id41AB7FE36BE249249FD5125E05645208"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in developing recommendations, consult with affected stakeholders in private industry; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id9bb479e1af1b430c948635ccda0778c7"><enum>(8)</enum><text>not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report describing the findings and recommendations resulting from the activities described in paragraphs (2) through (7).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idAFAC9600268F4316A1CE3EEE1FE9529F"><enum>5.</enum><header>Reduction of black carbon emissions</header>
			<subsection id="id246548676b044e18958fb567a6be8024"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Comprehensive plan</header>
 <paragraph id="id6C498159A953464790F800AAA5075666"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Through the membership of the United States in the International Maritime Organization, the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of Transportation, the Secretary of Commerce, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, and the Commandant of the Coast Guard, shall develop a comprehensive plan to reduce black carbon emissions, based on appropriate emission data from oceangoing vessels provided on a voluntary basis, from international shipping through—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id57A5B091297B428DBA5B76DF34E66113"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a clean freight partnership;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idDE894E0E49444043BFC96AA22E47A0F7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the inclusion of limits on black carbon; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id6BDCDD76B11043A4A8E3B0D2BCB35387"><enum>(C)</enum><text>efforts that include protection of access to critical fuel shipments and emergency needs of coastal communities.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0584b06cb5a242c39b59e43d7316085d"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Roadmap</header><text>A principal objective of the plan developed pursuant to paragraph (1) shall be the establishment, in coordination with the Department of Transportation, of a roadmap toward helping countries reduce fine-particle emissions (PM<subscript>2.5</subscript>) in the shipping sector through—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="id58326E9DC24241CD85917EDFD95063B0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the installation of advanced emissions controls; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idFA6E5B0ACE644348AB1185887CD6D491"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the reduction of sulfur content in fuels.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idbeb531ac3526431d8099475d6a7635b1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Black carbon emissions reduction goals</header><text>Acting as chairperson of the Arctic Council, the Secretary of State shall—</text> <paragraph id="idAAD95224C3F64D4EBBD3A3EF38819B52"><enum>(1)</enum><text>lead an effort to reduce black carbon through an Arctic-wide aspirational black carbon goal; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idFDB93DC1595F4FD5A48C953794300BC2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>encourage observers of the Arctic Council (including India and China) to adopt national black carbon emissions reduction goals and mitigation plans.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0cb4255ff52848948dca2d61beeb41be"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Climate and Clean Air Coalition</header><text>Through the membership of the United States in the Climate and Clean Air Coalition to Reduce Short-Lived Climate Pollutants, the Secretary of State is encouraged—</text>
 <paragraph id="id1452B4253E7640ABB969712A69F0A488"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to work with the Coalition to craft specific financing mechanisms for the incremental cost of international black carbon mitigation activities; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id81CCF02D47E046A98199F8FCC7B0386C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to request that the Coalition produce a report describing black carbon mitigation financing options.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ida342e44b4ec24de1bd340d2184bd080e"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Black carbon mitigation activities</header>
 <paragraph id="idFD259B7F54CE4D978AA8851E33E28ABE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Prioritization</header><text>The Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, in cooperation with the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idE8E81CF0355244F88558D7309C4A79FA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>prioritize black carbon mitigation activities as part of official development assistance and programmatic activities;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8947DE46071645B8A715EB34F2B3C689"><enum>(B)</enum><text>give special emphasis to projects that produce substantial environmental, gender, livelihood, and public health benefits, including support for clean-burning cookstoves and fuels; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5e07704e4dfb4371954207b2822e47af"><enum>(C)</enum><text>work with the Global Alliance for Clean Cookstoves to help developing nations establish thriving markets for clean and efficient cooking solutions.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id49b3c5b681794e0cbfae6fe06954a450"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Emissions reductions</header><text>The Secretary of State, in collaboration with the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency and the Secretary of Transportation, shall provide additional aid to international efforts to reduce black carbon emissions from diesel trucks, 2-stroke engines, diesel generators, and industrial processes by providing technical assistance—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idDEB17013467E42E882C381325727EBC8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to help developing nations lower the sulfur content of diesel fuels;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1AAB8AA7B7F545CA80CC335302AC9609"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to expand access to diesel particulate filters;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id18C3396DEB384ACA8FC59461E766FC25"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to provide vehicle manufacturers with low-emission engine designs; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id608f9fd04a254b0fbad72b2ca372821a"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to develop other mitigation activities, including energy efficiency alternatives for generators and industrial processes.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idB02276002982496896D923BEE7D6DD7E"><enum>6.</enum><header>Global reductions in high-GWP fluorinated gases</header>
			<subsection id="idA894701472574359BECDF70E6CB047EB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header>
 <paragraph id="idEF3D36FE81264865881B98AC809A34A3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Actions by Environmental Protection Agency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency should—</text> <subparagraph id="id309292D09823437C9AF764964B6EDB0C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>amend any regulations issued under section 608 of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7671g">42 U.S.C. 7671g</external-xref>)—</text>
 <clause id="idFFB4D956835D4F899ED3983387B2A917"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to include hydrofluorocarbons; and</text> </clause><clause id="id24358A5189AF4711A361B3D34AFC7587"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to expand initiatives relating to the recovery and reclamation of hydrofluorocarbons;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB0E678E6B358459BBF481450C9769A58"><enum>(B)</enum><text>cooperate with the Secretary of Energy in considering modifications to the Energy Star program established under section 324A of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6294a">42 U.S.C. 6294a</external-xref>) to include refrigerant systems that—</text>
 <clause id="idE62F684B5B3B40BBB322D23AFF376990"><enum>(i)</enum><text>achieve best-in-class energy efficiency savings; and</text> </clause><clause id="idFCE41AD850B44DBAA181A32F82FB0C5B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>use low global warming potential refrigerants and foam-blowing agents; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9C88E83370A343FE93C8B743E838B24B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>remove high-GWP HFC from the Significant New Alternatives Policy Program authorized under section 612(c) of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7671k">42 U.S.C. 7671k(c)</external-xref>) for applications in which the Administrator has identified other alternatives that—</text>
 <clause id="id260910FE5B6B411C8E5EF219BCC69F18"><enum>(i)</enum><text>are currently or potentially available;</text> </clause><clause id="id8B5A879EEB854471B5AD38D7245BD489"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>reduce the overall risk to human health and the environment; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id837200ead1cc4952ab9bc1d56292e922"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>take into consideration cost-effectiveness.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5B0B2A552F4E4351A2A95012B73A7266"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sense of Senate</header><text>It is the sense of the Senate that United States leadership and full support of an amendment to the Montreal Protocol on Substances that Deplete the Ozone Layer, done at Montreal September 16, 1987, should ensure a smooth, technically feasible global transition away from high-GWP HFC.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id9BBF36FB354947488DA0FDF9BDAFF0AD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Study on high-GWP HFC alternatives</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Energy and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, in collaboration with the National Institute of Standards and Technology, shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="id317ED1541197411FB9E2B187F19113D1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>evaluate the availability of high-GWP HFC alternatives; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id43D94BF2F09C4CB78A0058FB45424D83"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submit to Congress a report that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id2B05279F12C94470AED785831A8ABEFA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identifies—</text> <clause id="id9378B867A38145AAA968A836B3FD07D5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the standards or regulatory barriers that are preventing the use of alternatives to high-GWP HFC in the United States that are in widespread use in other countries;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idDD2519B2A6EE4FDD8D09C6304E6A2081"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any standards or regulations requiring revision; and</text> </clause><clause id="id1261561542DB418C9887EF84D60E229E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any actions necessary to revise those standards or regulations; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id383EFAAE25A0493D8474759364DC59E5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>establishes a plan for revising the standards referred to in paragraph (1) in the shortest practicable timeframe.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idB68D64ED97C4497C92646A4E0412C240"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Prohibition of HCFC–22 air conditioning condensing equipment</header>
 <paragraph id="idC20EDB05096E4FC2A54192AE4D02A559"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 605 of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7671d">42 U.S.C. 7671d</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idA29049C46E21491B922172DE1E5DDD6D" style="OLC"> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID358518A0512D487C8617B02F74ADF337"><enum>(e)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">HCFC–22 air conditioning condensing equipment</header><text>Effective 1 year after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Super Pollutants Act of 2015</short-title>, it shall be unlawful for any person to manufacture any uncharged hydrochlorofluorocarbon–22 air conditioning condensing equipment for residential use.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idE909B48C86EF40208DA89DCA799CDEC7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency shall promulgate regulations—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id848DF3FF3DEA40A1AA4B80446F510100"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to carry out the amendment made by paragraph (1); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id93AE261EEBC3438DAA484613241E8784"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to reduce the allocation of HCFC–22 consumption allowances commensurate with anticipated decreased demand resulting from the prohibition of uncharged condensing equipment under subsection (e) of section 605 of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7671d">42 U.S.C. 7671d</external-xref>) (as added by paragraph (1)).</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idc0f57d8111ac4db188531c494c050538"><enum>(d)</enum><header>R–134a automotive air conditioning recharge kits</header>
 <paragraph id="id04EF922978FC4B5DA05264103D3CB58C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Study</header><text>The Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency shall conduct a study to determine the most effective method to minimize the inadvertent release of HFC–134a from automotive air conditioning recharge kits at any time during which the recharge container is not being used.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id3b257e981620412aa50c48e2ad2e5e6a"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall submit to Congress a report that contains the results of the study conducted pursuant to paragraph (1).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id7047AE52E49542C98ECF7077F70CAF2A"><enum>7.</enum><header>Reduction of methane emissions</header>
 <subsection id="id4885a1014ebb49e5ac7ee282a843461a"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Technical guidance</header><text>The Secretary of State, the Secretary of Energy, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, and the Secretary of Commerce shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="idEC9C6C90496847269F15E9099C4249FD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide to other countries technical guidance regarding containment of emissions from gas drilling, landfills, coal mining, and agriculture in engaging with other governments, including trade delegations, under the auspices of international initiatives, such as the Global Shale Gas Initiative of the Department of State and the Global Methane Initiative; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idA72623702984444BB7CFF587B30B2A79"><enum>(2)</enum><text>collaborate with—</text> <subparagraph id="id6348FB12A5994E20A736DA7449E89DED"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Global Gas Flaring Reduction Partnership of the World Bank; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2C5F26B622764306A71C3A675DE6C8CA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Global Methane Initiative, Natural Gas STAR Program, the Climate and Clean Air Coalition Oil and Gas Methane Partnership, and other voluntary reduction programs of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id180fbcdab9a4461494a122491d9d93de"><enum>(b)</enum><header>GAO report</header>
 <paragraph id="id57cb88eb33004d4791b893b23c7a44bc"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study that identifies—</text> <subparagraph id="id5f1177455d8d4b4cb48d0cb9874083d0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the types of equipment throughout the production value chain that are most likely to have high leak rates; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idad7a9b9ae3c545809e8dcaa62041fcff"><enum>(B)</enum><text>voluntary efforts on replacing or monitoring those types of equipment.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id96bc26cc7f1542608a7b3b4dc4e682b9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report that contains the results of the examination conducted pursuant to paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ide897f161499342659622eb602f0866c7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Sense of Congress regarding financing conditions</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that, in evaluating gas and oil-related projects for financial support, the heads of the United States Export-Import Bank and the Overseas Private Investment Corporation should condition financing for those projects on—</text>
 <paragraph id="id9d30c01a833a4b0b9c8c9c7e449bee5e"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the deployment of the best technology, methods, and management practices for detecting and repairing leaks of methane throughout the oil and gas production, processing, transportation, and distribution system;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idebd0142634784a9e846985d8c2278370"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the minimization of venting and inefficient or unnecessary flaring; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id96b4dfcbcf3549d4be6c90abcef6fc48"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the deployment of best technology, methods, and management practices for reducing emissions of other air pollution, especially—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id7FFD7119217D40018446C10970D9E1E3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>volatile organic compounds; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idDA05D5285EFB442584922FFDF1D28C05"><enum>(B)</enum><text>hazardous air pollutants.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


