<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1199 IS: To authorize Federal agencies to provide alternative fuel to Federal employees on a reimbursable basis, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1199</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150505">May 5, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S229">Mrs. Murray</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To authorize Federal agencies to provide alternative fuel to Federal employees on a reimbursable
			 basis, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="id492273725032411397BADC7D9EEE7344" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Alternative fuel infrastructure</header>
 <subsection id="id5360F412C5184F32BC341093D9A8322C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text>
				<paragraph id="idC8F77F7B029848609CBE317B1BF2C955"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Alternative
 fuel</header><text>The term <term>alternative fuel</term> has the meaning given the term in section 400AA(g) of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6374">42 U.S.C. 6374(g)</external-xref>).</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="id658634e654ca4771af9e15daf78f7643"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Alternative
 fuel infrastructure</header><text>The term <term>alternative fuel infrastructure</term> means any ancillary equipment necessary to provide alternative fuel to vehicles.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="idFD4521669E414634BA4E188A6BFCBAE5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered
 individual</header><text>The term <term>covered individual</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="id6E9B70D415854BAEB8122307705598CD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any employee (as defined in section 2105 of title 5, United States Code);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7ae6a389954148aeb7f2d4af2d35802f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a member of a uniformed service;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idCBB3FDFE87444ABF8F2B9E71FC4F1FE2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any other individual who performs services for or on behalf of a Federal agency under a contract or subcontract with a Federal agency; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfa1c5e56135545ec9e4cf3073c0868bf"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a visitor to a Federal agency or facility.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID556A7CAAFE604DD99B1924E95D74F759"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Federal agency</header> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5DD6244A1DF04C2AA504209AEDF227F4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Federal agency</term> has the meaning given the term in section 1004 of the <act-name parsable-cite="SWDA">Solid Waste Disposal Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6903">42 U.S.C. 6903</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1AC6B7A220394E72968B119D57FEC449"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusion</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Federal agency</term> includes the Executive Office of the President.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="id9BE63E19D0AB408396FFAB508C38A166"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authority</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="id1D40AB1B053F40358AF2459F83FB6331"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to the availability of appropriations and paragraph (2), the head of a Federal agency may—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="idD3DAA459656D4E10A66C77F624FE1FAA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>construct, operate, and maintain alternative fuel infrastructure on property under the jurisdiction of the Federal agency; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id5B4858348F014F27B2C5B8993A47A4C5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide alternative fuel on a reimbursable basis on property under the jurisdiction of the Federal agency for use by privately owned vehicles used by covered individuals.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idC5C6FC7606AC42F89958F564C525DF2C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>A Federal agency may not provide compensation, benefits, or any other payment to a covered individual for the purpose of purchasing alternative fuel under paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idB5F92F77150D41DCB2637788E84B6091"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Fees</header><text>The head of a Federal agency shall charge fees for alternative fuel provided to covered individuals sufficient to cover the costs of only the alternative fuel provided under this section.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="id785F43878A4749008A96CC37792145EF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Deposit and
 availability of fees and commissions</header><text>Any fees or commissions collected by the head of a Federal agency under this section—</text>
 <paragraph id="idB4D978818FAB4D3EA5839F1C2F4C965D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall be—</text> <subparagraph id="id226622574FD34B868A2360165E7A5765"><enum>(A)</enum><text>deposited monthly into the account of the Treasury from which the amounts were made available to carry out this section, notwithstanding section 3302(b) of title 31, United States Code; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB3EE8DC4BFE041CBB4EC7F0F328F8465"><enum>(B)</enum><text>transferred from the Treasury to an appropriate account of the agency if the agency operates with a budget outside of the Treasury; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id27FCBEE99609433A84D87C9B505786FA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall be available for obligation by the head of the Federal agency without further appropriation during—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id9696B861A431410F8311F264BA9E8C82"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the fiscal year collected; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD55169E030B84920BE14C5EAE833ED80"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the fiscal year following the fiscal year collected.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id37AFCF86A2DE49CF9033A1AA54B12621"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reports</header>
				<paragraph id="idD2101EE6E5C04C1CA613C0DF141EB847"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the end of each fiscal year, the head of each Federal agency participating in the activities authorized by subsection (b) shall submit to the Administrator of General Services a report on the financial administration of activities carried out under this section with respect to that fiscal year.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="idFBE8E7E62CB84A4D81C567F0E4B967CF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report to
 Congress</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act and every 5 years thereafter, the Administrator of General Services, in consultation with the Secretary, shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress, including the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives, a report that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id34FC1C3BF3AA473C96C356C0959ED905"><enum>(A)</enum><text>aggregates the information provided by the heads of Federal agencies in the annual reports under paragraph (1); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6E72FB1BB0624EC68088E8E93D35B3A2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provides information on whether the fees collected under subsection (c) are sufficient to cover the cost to the head of a Federal agency of carrying out this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


