<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S2274 IS: To provide for rental assistance for homeless or at-risk Indian veterans. </dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-11-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2274</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20151110">November 10, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S314">Mr. Tester</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S275">Ms. Cantwell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S326">Mr. Udall</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S332">Mr. Franken</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S375">Mr. Daines</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SLIA00">Committee on Indian Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To provide for rental assistance for homeless or at-risk Indian veterans. </official-title></form>
	<legis-body>
 <section id="id3B485A4D2A644E3C964A0623CC1D51F8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Rental assistance for homeless or at-risk Indian veterans</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 8(o)(19) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437f">42 U.S.C. 1437f(o)(19)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide2b87a9198b24f6f973e8d1fb6bb2aca" style="OLC">
				<subparagraph id="idd97ea6be0d874203973617bda03b2d61"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Indian veterans housing rental assistance program</header>
 <clause id="id9717b3936ec34021b2903d2fdeb41fd2"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subparagraph:</text> <subclause id="id72448c622aa14f5f9288bf826a407770"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Indian</header><text>The term <term>Indian</term> has the meaning given the term in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/450b">25 U.S.C. 450b</external-xref>).</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id11af463cdb0242dd8e50122cefa8c85f"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Indian area</header><text>The term <term>Indian area</term> has the meaning given the term in section 4 of the Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/4103">25 U.S.C. 4103</external-xref>).</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idaa939d5aefbb4458ae20878ab594bd91"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Tribal organization</header><text>The term <term>tribal organization</term> has the meaning given the term in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/450b">25 U.S.C. 450b</external-xref>).</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="id07383979cd2a44df9eb3fb06f82e0f4b"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Authorization of program</header><text>The Secretary may use not more than 5 percent of the amounts made available for rental assistance under this subsection to carry out a rental assistance and supportive housing program, in conjunction with the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, for the benefit of Indian veterans who are homeless or at risk of homelessness and who are residing on or near an Indian area.</text>
 </clause><clause id="id00a482d9d0c044df85e557f299df681c"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Model</header><text>The program described in clause (ii) shall be modeled on the rental assistance and supportive housing program authorized under this section and applicable appropriations Acts, including administration in conjunction with the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, except that the Secretary may make necessary and appropriate modifications to facilitate the use of the program by Indian grant recipients to serve eligible Indian veterans.</text>
 </clause><clause id="id49e5e4c24ffe4e118255eecb0a6c64c2"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Eligible recipients</header><text>Amounts for rental assistance and associated administrative costs under clause (ii) shall be made available to recipients eligible to receive grants under section 101 of the Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/4111">25 U.S.C. 4111</external-xref>).</text>
 </clause><clause id="idbe6218bd3ffb4e08835cc50d232e5aae"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Funding criteria</header><text>Rental assistance under clause (ii) shall be awarded based on—</text> <subclause id="id63028db02a9d4a0bb2fd8058ad8ca7fa"><enum>(I)</enum><text>need;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idfd6cb09fa83f4a4a97b3c92ad51ebb4a"><enum>(II)</enum><text>administrative capacity; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="id0b5346146f60486394a1677ef1c04b6a"><enum>(III)</enum><text>any other funding criteria established by the Secretary in a notice published in the Federal Register after consulting with the Secretary of Veterans Affairs.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="id490430648e5a48d5b9e1db3dd299db67"><enum>(vi)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>Rental assistance made available under clause (ii) shall be administered in accordance with the Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/4101">25 U.S.C. 4101 et seq.</external-xref>), except that grantees shall—</text>
 <subclause id="id914914d5440642178a27ab31d9c9ddc0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>submit to the Secretary, in a manner prescribed by the Secretary, reports on the utilization of rental assistance provided under the program; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id41bbdd27fbb84bbab6a81a2fbb139883"><enum>(II)</enum><text>provide to the Secretary information specified by the Secretary to assess the effectiveness of the program in serving eligible veterans.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="id95bc8b7b982e46cab32f9da02bbb3201"><enum>(vii)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>The Secretary, in coordination with the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, shall consult with recipients of grants under section 101 of the Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/4111">25 U.S.C. 4111</external-xref>) and any other appropriate tribal organization on the design of the program to ensure the effective delivery of rental assistance and supportive services to persons eligible to receive assistance under this subparagraph.</text>
					</clause><clause id="ide0536473635f416c96dd9608bae2d8d0"><enum>(viii)</enum><header>Waiver</header>
 <subclause id="id3e61072dc7c54897b9ff3c0818f2e707"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subclause (II), the Secretary may waive or specify alternative requirements for any provision of law (including regulations) that the Secretary administers in connection with the use of rental assistance made available under this subparagraph if the Secretary finds that the waiver or alternative requirement is necessary for the effective delivery and administration of rental assistance made available under this subparagraph to Indian veterans.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id34c58b94e7b8457c893c8dc90b804a6b"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The Secretary shall not waive or specify alternative requirements under subclause (I) for any provision of law (including regulations) relating to labor standards or the environment.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill>


