<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S963 IS: Small Business Innovation Impact Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 963</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150415">April 15, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSSB00">Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To require the Chief Counsel for Advocacy of the Small Business Administration to submit a report
			 on small
			 business innovation.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Small Business Innovation Impact Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="id4F050CE38B7B422583C92D7048268715"><enum>2.</enum><header>Report on small business innovation</header>
 <subsection id="id736f4af269d24f1586a5050448cb638e"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <term>small business concern</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/632">15 U.S.C. 632</external-xref>).</text> </subsection><subsection id="id035318c7a2e343f2b4bcf00a6340c75f"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Small business administration report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Chief Counsel for Advocacy of the Small Business Administration shall, using existing resources, submit to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship of the Senate and the Committee on Small Business of the House of Representatives a report analyzing—</text>
 <paragraph id="idd47003ea8bf6491db2598d76eb779b96"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the investment of small business concerns in developing new and useful inventions and obtaining patents on those inventions;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id06d71710480c41f184220ca29bbc7970"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the importance of university technology transfer to small business concerns;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id8c4f8b4b35a444f2b5b317e43494427c"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the use of patent licensing arrangements by small business concerns;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id8fc54cee748a464d9c65ab41660f0b9a"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the impact of patent ownership for small business concerns on attracting outside investment, creating new jobs, protecting against foreign infringing goods, and competing against larger businesses; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id5611b92a368f477db0b200426cf1280a"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the impact on small business concerns from patent-related demand letters and civil actions arising under title 35, United States Code, relating to patent infringement.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


