<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1931 IS: To reaffirm that certain land has been taken into trust for the benefit of certain Indian tribes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-08-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1931</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150804">August 4, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S347">Mr. Moran</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S314">Mr. Tester</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SLIA00">Committee on Indian Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To reaffirm that certain land has been taken into trust for the benefit of certain Indian tribes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HACA685BEE9854CA2B207090B298D9A8E" style="OLC">
		<section id="idC7F82E480537443B9232102513AF03C6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Ratification of existing trust land</header>
 <subsection id="id0fa50c7254464d20ac2df822f8ba7f69"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any land taken into trust by the United States prior to the date of enactment of this Act for an Indian tribe that was federally recognized on the date the land was taken into trust is reaffirmed as trust land, and any action of the Secretary of the Interior in acquiring and taking into trust land under the Act of June 18, 1934 (commonly known as the <quote>Indian Reorganization Act</quote>) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/461">25 U.S.C. 461 et seq.</external-xref>), is ratified and confirmed as fully and to all intents and purposes as if the action had, by prior Act of Congress, been specifically authorized and directed.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idc4b73dc73128470ea7d768a335f15cc7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Indian country</header><text>Any land taken into trust that has been ratified and confirmed by this Act shall remain Indian country in accordance with section 1151 of title 18, United States Code.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idf2fab48a2f234e1fa63451259c79c793"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Additional land</header><text>Nothing in this Act alters or diminishes the right of any federally recognized Indian tribe or the authority of the Secretary of the Interior with respect to taking additional land into trust for the benefit of the Indian tribe.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id53fce733f55c4c94930d710e9bf37bd7"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Application</header><text>This Act shall apply to all claims, including claims challenging the validity of title or the effectiveness of any action of the Secretary of the Interior acquiring and taking into trust land, that are—</text>
 <paragraph id="id262E4D773F4145DFAD04A0A6A468F5D1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>pending on the date of enactment of this Act; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idC3B834D76FD047FCA9A6AC50B0B9BC8D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>filed on or after that date.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


