<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1862 IS: Veterans Entrepreneurial Transition Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 1862</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150726">July 26, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S347">Mr. Moran</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S314">Mr. Tester</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSVA00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To require the Administrator of the Small Business Administration to carry out a pilot program on
			 issuing grants to eligible veterans to start or
			 acquire qualifying businesses, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Veterans Entrepreneurial Transition Act of 2015</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>VET Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="id46971e9042434c58ac519a4b5501eec1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Veterans small business entrepreneurship pilot program</header>
			<subsection id="idf607724f5c2f44358c2058929f6841b4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Pilot program required</header>
 <paragraph id="id4F83772A7F3F4A17A9C26E03876A947C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator, in consultation with the Advisory Committee, shall begin carrying out a pilot program to assess the feasibility and advisability of making grants to eligible veterans to start or acquire a qualifying business enterprise.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id16FB356667EB4B768B0EE66ED2043264"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Promotion of efficiency</header><text>In carrying out the pilot program, the Administrator shall ensure, to the maximum extent practicable, that the pilot program promotes efficiency, accountability, and competition.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ide508ca84d4c84126b2c7b87fdc8d1279"><enum>(3)</enum><header>List of categories of business enterprises</header><text>The Administrator, in consultation with the Advisory Committee, shall by rule establish a list of categories of business enterprises that the Administrator determines to be qualifying business enterprises for purposes of the pilot program, which shall include—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id54102a19a6bf43378c55c610c5322d23"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a small business concern (as the term is defined in section 3(a) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/632">15 U.S.C. 632(a)</external-xref>));</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide630f7cf5d5a43dc94437a8703aacf46"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a franchise business enterprise; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id20a93157fabb4e93ba7e2776cf451b81"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any other category of business enterprise that the Administrator, in consultation with the Advisory Committee, determines is appropriate and in accordance with the purposes of the pilot program.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idA0E6C6DA50294305AE2263D364E8C8EA"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Number of grants</header><text>Under the pilot program, the Administrator may make grants in accordance with subsection (d) to not more than 250 eligible veterans to start or acquire a qualifying business enterprise.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id7596883D74A9422B9320D20806EEE221"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Geographic diversity</header><text>In making grants under the pilot program, the Administrator shall ensure geographic diversity among the veterans who receive the grants.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id85D9264949A9402E862B763717692A1E"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>The Administrator shall carry out the pilot program during the 3-year period beginning on the date on which the Administrator begins carrying out the pilot program.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0399ED55CDF74688BEB8B75ADB88370F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2bf498a48d614faaabec7ba108577895"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An eligible veteran desiring a grant under the pilot program shall submit an application—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idD20D4A22AD4641B2A25326A4ACB2947F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to the Administrator in the form and containing the information as the Administrator may require, including the information described in paragraph (2); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5726C786E83045F1860B2C9384BC47B6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not later than 1 year before the date on which the pilot program terminates under subsection (a)(6).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id801D351E82554D8C80AD9128098B89AA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Documentation requirements</header><text>The Administrator, in considering an application from an eligible veteran for a grant under the pilot program, may not approve the application unless the application includes the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="idec103e678d124a65b263e044105b5769"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A description of the use of the grant amount, including an identification and description of the qualifying business enterprise.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE1364FF557464BF58EBF260B90B6AE71"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A description of the expected return on investment resulting from the grant amounts.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id189e4d970b7d4013907766bce2e60125"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A certification that the eligible veteran applying for the grant—</text>
 <clause id="id350E6DD12693499B9A019D6B126A52EC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall complete the education and training relevant to the ownership and operation of the qualifying business enterprise described in subsections (c)(1) and (c)(2); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id0A55041FD7B348ECA1D5C5EC9C057543"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>understands that the eligible veteran may not receive amounts under a grant under the pilot program until after the eligible veteran has completed the required education and training relevant to the ownership and operation of the qualifying business enterprise described in subsections (c)(1) and (c)(2).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idee668a63385d4cf1b1536ac5303e4faa"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Such certifications as the Administrator, in consultation with the Advisory Committee, shall by rule require, including—</text>
 <clause id="iddcf07951a93946af83d1dd04c72365cf"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for a business enterprise in operation on the date of the application, evidence that the Administrator, in consultation with the Advisory Committee, determines appropriate of—</text>
 <subclause id="idf8e523a78d0746339dfdc841e1948918"><enum>(I)</enum><text>good standing;</text> </subclause><subclause id="ide4339c1ee3574c57ab440f3febab243e"><enum>(II)</enum><text>profitable operation; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id49000abfd38248f1a2a6c8c780673503"><enum>(III)</enum><text>guarantees relating to the purchase of the enterprise;</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="id10bc8bb0b5524cd181395cd9b359ee2b"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for a franchise business enterprise, evidence that the Administrator, in consultation with the Advisory Committee, determines appropriate of—</text>
 <subclause id="idd0f901d23d3049a3a420e28ab3aa0d89"><enum>(I)</enum><text>compliance with applicable State and Federal laws on franchises; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="id3b6d63cb1eaf4fdb9ed7ea193e0a5dc5"><enum>(II)</enum><text>training in conformation with the industry standard; and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="id4f4abaaa21ca4c71843a8a99bdbdfc7a"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>for a startup, or an enterprise that is otherwise not in operation at the time of the application, a proposal for the operation of that enterprise that leads to profitable operation within a reasonable timeframe.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idD5B6CE2074B048A2968CBE5F2337EF1C"><enum>(E)</enum><text>A certification that the eligible veteran applying for the grant understands that the eligible veteran may not receive amounts under the grant until after the business plan of the eligible veteran has been approved under the procedures described in subsection (c)(3)(B).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id068A29644D78499CAAB7819A6A6BD2C9"><enum>(F)</enum><text>A certification that the eligible veteran—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id68C3233C61AD41508D6600E4D4A1645F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has been truthful about the employment status of the eligible veteran; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB7033EA235CE4C10AE9BC8795DF8B7C0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>understands that the eligible veteran will be prohibited from participating in the pilot program if the certification described in clause (i) is determined to be untrue.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id646D347FF97C4E6DB37672ED9E6FAC34"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Group applications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator may authorize a group of eligible veterans to apply as a group under the pilot program. The group shall be treated as a single eligible veteran under the pilot program, except that the maximum amount of the grant shall be calculated by multiplying the maximum amount under subsection (d)(1) by the number of members of the group.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id17f8298207244042adfb28a7f725fc2b"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Entrepreneurship training</header>
 <paragraph id="id951f2e0f384a4df1809863fa5cc36ed9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each eligible veteran receiving a grant under the pilot program shall complete an entrepreneurship readiness program approved by the Administrator that is designed to prepare the eligible veteran for, and lead to the immediate subsequent ownership and management by the eligible veteran of, a qualifying business enterprise.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id64956DC4FFD248FCAB9D3335EF40DC73"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Approved programs</header><text>An approved program described in paragraph (1) may include a program—</text> <subparagraph id="id23E57EEAEBF74D40A137F260F39CEE51"><enum>(A)</enum><text>available through a small business development center, as described in section 21 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/648">15 U.S.C. 648</external-xref>);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idDA7717A9621D4EDB9AAC5706E4E843EA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>approved by the Administrator for entrepreneurship training;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idDF1C8F95D50A46F1BF4EDDAE4B781B9F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>approved by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs for entrepreneurship training;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idBF3D968369694FB4994BB947A0D4903D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>available through the Transition Assistance Program of the Department of Defense;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id796439DEF15F471F82338459C900604F"><enum>(E)</enum><text>available through a women’s business center, as described in section 29 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/656">15 U.S.C. 656</external-xref>);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5F6746E58BFD4F468668A7E8E9149880"><enum>(F)</enum><text>available through a Veterans Business Outreach Center, as described in section 32 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/657b">15 U.S.C. 657b</external-xref>);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4426953ABED245A2A17799C6D8DD44E4"><enum>(G)</enum><text>available through the SCORE program authorized by section 8(b)(1) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/637">15 U.S.C. 637(b)(1)</external-xref>); or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id18E23418748B4A0EA8FDF1345556C899"><enum>(H)</enum><text>approved by the Administrator, in consultation with the Advisory Committee, as appropriate because of the expertise the program offers relating to a certain type of business enterprise.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idee3035a240894670972bda9b97cc949d"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Business plan</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id210C147E238849679415FC25F29BC119"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>An eligible veteran receiving a grant under the pilot program shall prepare a business plan, which shall include—</text>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3255910314B84986A7A76F38BA1F6048"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a description of how the qualifying business enterprise will achieve profitable operation within a reasonable timeframe;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id815F40ED2A8146DB9E82A99BE29EA87E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an assessment of relevant—</text> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF6891578E9524CA1959FEFFCCC65762E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>economic indicators;</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8CA2E92E205B40D2802D03E6F264768A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>consumer data;</text> </subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id71FF247ECB364669A81CA4E587373DF2"><enum>(III)</enum><text>production and sales data; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id42FCC96AF3CA4F02AFD0E4D469224D7E"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>market or industry analysis; and</text> </subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF143B0F33EFD4B9194FADD909125823B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>other information that the Administrator, in consultation with the Advisory Committee, determines is appropriate.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3C4A029B668743D1882B9AC05D36B45A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Approval procedure</header>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF471796DC7714542B6419883DD0C5B55"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Approval by advisor</header><text>If an advisor approves the business plan prepared by the eligible veteran, the Associate Administrator for Veterans Business Development of the Small Business Administration—</text>
 <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3FDE89BBF11C4206BB92C3A1986E943B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>shall review the business plan; and</text> </subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id40551C69319A456F97A131D15C6014B3"><enum>(II)</enum><text>may reverse the approval of the business plan and require that the eligible veteran continue to consult with the advisor to develop and resubmit the business plan.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE10CDCF351DC457388904C1B33D40A18"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Disapproval by advisor</header><text>If an advisor does not approve the business plan prepared by an eligible veteran, the Associate Administrator for Veterans Business Development of the Small Business Administration, upon appeal by the eligible veteran, may reverse the decision of the advisor and approve the business plan.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idfd50faf8cc1748d0970d6045ac855668"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Grant terms and conditions</header>
				<paragraph id="id89DC3C32CF974B1CB84A04EA1C936553"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Maximum grant amount and additional assistance</header>
 <subparagraph id="idFE436E8846F2487CA2918ABB312A1104"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subsection (b)(3), the maximum amount that an eligible veteran may receive under the pilot program shall not exceed an amount equal to the sum of—</text>
 <clause id="id5A62A0EDB0644EB1A665181460F8D9DC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the maximum grant amount specified in subparagraph (B);</text>
 </clause><clause id="idCA8BF086D9FE4490995BD4DEB3ACFA35"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the amount equal to the product obtained by multiplying—</text> <subclause id="id41ACDC39EDA243948F712487A1E3E666"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the amount of additional assistance to which the eligible veteran is entitled under subparagraph (C)(ii); by</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id13525A4CF24C4955A7183A579A0E67A9"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the number of months that the eligible veteran participates in the pilot program; and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="id059C32AA60D442E288C66701537BF386"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the amount of training assistance received by the eligible veteran in subparagraph (D).</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id13DD8C25ED2E4222BE31B56CF9121268"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Maximum grant amount</header><text>The maximum grant amount specified in this subparagraph is the following:</text>
 <clause id="idF4702B65DE5245DB8818554EDF0D05DD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>In the case of an eligible veteran entitled to educational assistance under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/33">chapter 33</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, the amount equal to the product obtained by multiplying—</text>
 <subclause id="id2BB32023A3D04AEA809CA548B46B2FB1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the number of months of educational assistance to which the eligible veteran is entitled on the date that the eligible veteran submits an application; by</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idD5DD516226C24DF19C325215B9324131"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the pro rata monthly rate of the amount that the eligible veteran is entitled to under paragraph (1)(A)(ii)(II) of section 3313(c) of that title, subject to paragraphs (2) through (7) of that section.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idAAA82EF6858E4931B4EE9DCB0F75E268"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>In the case of an eligible veteran entitled to educational assistance under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/30">chapter 30</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, the amount equal to the product obtained by multiplying—</text>
 <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7EDB3614E0534FC6BEADD4817251D3C9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the number of months of educational assistance to which the eligible veteran is entitled on the date that the eligible veteran submits an application; by</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB8B998A879974D2A9EB8A3B51A45FE83"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the rate in effect under section 3015(a)(1) of that title.</text>
							</subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9B013A02F72140EF83523DFB37875B05"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Additional assistance</header>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2BCC38BBB6FD4B6C9CFE44348B7D43B1"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Period of eligibility</header><text>An eligible veteran shall receive the amount described in clause (ii) for each month that the eligible veteran participates in the pilot program.</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idCB03F71D330B439085BA4886C3D6620C"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Amount</header><text>The amount of the additional assistance specified in this clause is an amount, paid to the eligible veteran on a monthly basis, equal to the product obtained by multiplying—</text>
 <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4C25358BA5A54725A86FC35BB7946129"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the monthly amount of the basic allowance for housing payable under section 403 of title 37, United States Code, for a member with dependents in pay grade E–5 residing in the military housing area that encompasses all or the majority portion of the ZIP code area in which is located the residence of the eligible veteran (similar to the calculation made under section 3313(c)(1)(B)(i)(I) of title 38, United States Code); by—</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idCE965CD564F6423CACA84216C56E0768"><enum>(II)</enum><item commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idC596E26077BC4D32BFFC497E39C17CE2"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>in the case of an eligible veteran who, as of the date on which the eligible veteran applies for a grant under this section, has no employment other than the qualifying business enterprise for which the eligible veteran seeks a grant under this section, 1; or</text>
 </item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idC4BC4C550BED4763819A9331322D7753" indent="up1"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>in the case of an eligible veteran who is not described in item (aa), 0.5.</text> </item></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id56A635AA5C8E4ABE9C8424443B1657F5"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Training assistance</header><text>Upon application by an eligible veteran receiving a grant under the pilot program, the Administrator may pay for the cost, if applicable, of an approved program described in subsection (c)(2)(H).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide35a0447c62a402d951e74de1ae23546"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Disbursement</header><text>The amount of a grant made under the pilot program shall be disbursed to an eligible veteran—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id1694CFC1B16B42F18ADC4723758302C3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in installments, in accordance with the procedures described in paragraph (3);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1A03BFB62F2542D3BBE128542750A8B4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>only after the eligible veteran presents documentation proving that the eligible veteran has completed the required entrepreneurship training described in subsections (c)(1) and (c)(2); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1EFD4B44F121435A9B43B5CE0B027CBE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>only after the business plan of the eligible veteran has been approved under the procedures described in subsection (c)(3)(B).</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id94B33084CE374297B1740CE360F78EDE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Installment payments</header>
 <text>The amount described in paragraph (1)(B) shall be paid to the eligible veteran in installments on a pro rata basis with each installment being paid to the eligible veteran—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idC32A330D179A4F108F1E686290098E88"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not earlier than 3 months after the date of the payment of the most recent installment to the eligible veteran;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0DDBE0AD04CF46D89002960F92F260EF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not later than 12 months after the date of the payment of the most recent installment to the eligible veteran; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE5271114F6BD437480828A097BCFA218"><enum>(C)</enum><text>only after the eligible veteran has met milestones established in the business plan of the eligible veteran.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idb2d9bb8dcc4740daa645f70bddbc5747"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Impact on entitlement to educational assistance</header><text>An eligible veteran who receives a grant under the pilot program shall be deemed to have received an amount of educational assistance under chapter 30 or 33, of title 38, United States Code, as the case may be, that is equal to the amount of the grant.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ida65cc237b7094552a07b422d2e8fb796"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Use of grant amounts</header><text>An eligible veteran who receives a grant under the pilot program may use the amount of the grant—</text> <paragraph id="idDE83F2ECC1F34FD59E723C08DDFC9878"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in accordance with the limitations that the Administrator, in consultation with the Advisory Committee, may by rule establish; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idC77B46F003064CB0AC0EBF497B101B7F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for purposes related to starting or acquiring a qualifying business enterprise that the Administrator, in consultation with the Advisory Committee, determines are appropriate, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id92d208fa339b468f9e75102c102c641c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>purchasing goods or services necessary for the creation or operation of a qualifying business enterprise;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf578bac49e6c4a848b603d1d42be3f18"><enum>(B)</enum><text>funding a project that is directed toward any economic development objective described under section 501(d) of the Small Business Investment Act of 1958 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/695">15 U.S.C. 695(d)</external-xref>); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id97b4e44eb1e74c05973ccecb249f5af6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>acquiring a qualifying business enterprise.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idF60BEB75085C41CDB7851CEBB1919D16"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Report</header> <paragraph id="id6487B9068BE3452385016506A67097DC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date on which the pilot program is commenced, the Administrator shall submit to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Small Business and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a report analyzing the feasibility and effectiveness of the pilot program.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id74168BC457C944618440EF862B29D5C7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report submitted under paragraph (1) shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="id64A311B893554AC88393C47F8E6EB698"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an assessment of the pilot program;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idAAF2C4AAC94A47BAA84A43245F5137EB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a survey containing—</text> <clause id="id387777599B7B452BB88FE4B7A2894407"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number of grantees under the pilot program; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idE2A336AD83BA4FE882F6EF2D8EB33479"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the number of the grantees under the pilot program that participated in each of the training programs described in paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (c);</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3C465D996B2B4D14B640C3196F12AB0B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>recommendations regarding whether any aspect of the pilot program should be made a permanent authority, and, if so, the means to ensure—</text>
 <clause id="idFC8FD267080C4B34BADDB88F77613BE3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>geographic and demographic diversity among the eligible veterans who receive the grants under the permanent authority; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id7D4101A3E7DF41EF91B04D7EF28D5102"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>diversity in the types of qualifying business enterprises for which eligible veterans may receive grants under the pilot program;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id29B5659EEAB0464BA7814F13BA93F08B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an assessment regarding whether the grants distributed under the pilot program should continue to be made in installments or with a one-time, lump sum payment;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id37115932974F48E9AECF5AE5EBE6B11A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>an assessment of the additional assistance made available under the pilot program, including the accountability surrounding the availability of additional assistance;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE5AD731350DE4273BC99C5097E2593C0"><enum>(F)</enum><text>an analysis of the procedures for approving a business plan and a recommendation regarding ways, if necessary, to improve the procedures; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idEAE737EB58714910A348A654A497DA45"><enum>(G)</enum><text>a recommendation regarding ways, if necessary, to improve the accountability of advisors.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0640235D4CC84EC0885DCF4CCDAFABAD"><enum>(g)</enum><header>No effect on time limitation for use of entitlement to educational assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed to modify any time limitation or period during which an individual is entitled to educational assistance under chapter 30 or 33 of title 38, United States Code.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="id9C729D55024A4D42A2B1E6C95412FA35"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Funding</header>
 <paragraph id="id12D63B96B2464C2AA01C6C44609F4164"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall transfer to the Administrator from funds appropriated to the Secretary to carry out chapters 30 and 33 of title 38, United States Code, an amount equal to the amount necessary for the Administrator to carry out the pilot program.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id7FB48CD02ECA486FB991F9D8612FC7A3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>Amounts transferred to the Administrator under paragraph (1) shall remain available until the date on which the pilot program terminates under subsection (a)(5).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id2E3A6CE2E1FB41F2AFF8C10F5C988E70"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> <paragraph id="id9F363596561545C88CF3C9FC55F9B7E2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Small Business Administration.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id4CA5BA246BFD46B48E6C1E4A4D55A70E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Advisor</header><text>The term <term>advisor</term> means a person—</text> <subparagraph id="idC43E1A2C2B8C4E12A84581A95914EB14"><enum>(A)</enum><text>affiliated with an entrepreneurship or training and curricula program described in subsections (c)(1) and (c)(2);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF4ABFE53AAC545F1AAAFF839C27657CA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>who may assist an eligible veteran with the preparation and approval of a business plan; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7FC5234FBB934B06A711EE532A85D370"><enum>(C)</enum><text>who is approved to serve as an advisor by the Administrator, in consultation with the Advisory Committee.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id01DB70EC81BC4A42942E84F627AD14AC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Advisory committee</header><text>The term <term>Advisory Committee</term> means the Advisory Committee on Veterans Business Affairs established under section 203 of the Veterans Entrepreneurship and Small Business Development Act of 1999 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/657b">15 U.S.C. 657b</external-xref> note).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idE3E5814FA7F245D9B1ED76E076B9D91D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Business plan</header><text>The term <term>business plan</term> means a plan prepared by an eligible veteran for the operation of a qualifying business enterprise that shall be—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id1E41AD3E92464653A861A805478D4283"><enum>(A)</enum><text>prepared—</text> <clause id="idBD7ADA2299B946838E5D78F500642E31"><enum>(i)</enum><text>while the eligible veteran participates in an approved training program described in subsections (c)(1) and (c)(2); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id800E8542AB6049EEBEC4175ED4008CF9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>with the assistance of an advisor; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id363E774A7B394355B3A8C6BCFB8EA3D7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>consistent with the guidelines and recommendations provided by the Business Plan Tool of the Small Business Administration.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id10F4E5EFEDA44B30A07BBA75ABC75EBF"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Eligible veteran</header><text>The term <term>eligible veteran</term> means an individual who—</text> <subparagraph id="id49B8EB02F98C4BE58AB5C5003197FE46"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is—</text>
 <clause id="id10B04D322C9E4BD5B256EFF44B42C21B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a veteran; or</text> </clause><clause id="idB100666F3BD741788C3AD4151278D288"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a member of the Armed Forces who—</text>
 <subclause id="id31D160FF114647C1AA6F69A1A625702C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is currently retiring or separating from the Armed Forces and has a service approved retirement or separation packet; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idD5C0B66A22D949ABA6CBC9468DA13180"><enum>(II)</enum><text>has last been honorably discharged from active duty service in the Armed Forces;</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcb57336ee7b64027a3273d1507f818a5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has completed not less than—</text>
 <clause id="id6faf83a9a5b64da3a18c3acab09a6205"><enum>(i)</enum><text>36 months of active duty service in the Armed Forces (other than active duty service for training); or</text>
 </clause><clause id="id7f7a7accf72a4fb19c1a3868760f66c7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>24 months of active duty service in the Armed Forces (other than active duty service for training) before being discharged or separated for a service-connected disability, as that term is defined in section 101 of title 38, United States Code; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbb245694fefc4179aca850ce72279331"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is entitled to educational assistance under chapter 30 or 33 of title 38, United States Code.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idAEFCB154DF1941D8B24EC9A167287395"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Franchise business enterprise</header><text>The term <term>franchise business enterprise</term> means any continuing commercial relationship or arrangement, regardless of the title given the relationship or arrangement, under which the terms of the offer or contract specify, or the franchise seller promises or represents, orally or in writing, that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idDDB2B7442EEE4A0EBA00A7118C26CD9D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the franchisee will obtain the right to—</text> <clause id="id651A0E7082304B39854807D5B52E5EEF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>operate a business that is identified or associated with the trademark of the franchisor; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="idEBEEFF148EF444C1B56AECE16F38D7A3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>offer, sell, or distribute goods, services, or commodities that are identified or associated with the trademark of the franchisor;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idBD9EBDEBD982401E8DE2694BD94928B1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the franchisor may—</text> <clause id="idF3C726F7F13E41F3AA8072EE56081365"><enum>(i)</enum><text>exert, or has authority to exert, a significant degree of control over the method of operation of the franchisee; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="id6001860B05914EDBA3887D9CF4097530"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provide significant assistance in the method of operation of the franchisee; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3DF8EF45A4074DD28E3BBF889CA242BD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>as a condition of obtaining or commencing operation of the franchise business enterprise, the franchisee makes a required payment or commits to make a required payment to the franchisor or the affiliate of the franchisor.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id427D946C9A18465B81CF3082B8857BEA"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Franchisee</header><text>The term <term>franchisee</term> means any person who is granted a franchise business enterprise.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id86300835D8EB4B23A01138357AD10D43"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Franchisor</header><text>The term <term>franchisor</term>—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id30145A24EB6644E6B7275EF998063111"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means any person who grants a franchise business enterprise and participates in the franchise relationship; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF398B1AC61AE432489837855CD83F65F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes subfranchisors.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id700EB730D03B40D3B0A0B3D087946A0A"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Pilot program</header><text>The term <term>pilot program</term> means the pilot program established under subsection (a)(1).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id6E1BF68342B44963B9C9DC0421621EBE"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Qualifying business enterprise</header><text>The term <term>qualifying business enterprise</term> means a business included in the list of categories of business enterprises established under subsection (a)(3).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id836D3526D67F4A2C9F2B19D1D9F8184D"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Startup</header><text>The term <term>startup</term> means a business enterprise that—</text> <subparagraph id="id149C9FEFD2CF4D88920E343C802AAB3F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is not yet in existence; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idDCFE6C0B8DC140B29420E232F40C311D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has been in existence for not more than 5 years.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idE15E7611D36342F4BC665DCEF8846D6D"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Subfranchisor</header><text>The term <term>subfranchisor</term> means a person who functions as a franchisor by engaging in both pre-sale activities and post-sale performance.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB0C574CE0BB144C2B5B7275238C8352C"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Veteran</header><text>The term <term>veteran</term> has the meaning given the term in section 101 of title 38, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body> </bill> 

