<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1583 IS: To authorize the expansion of an existing hydroelectric project. </dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-06-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 1583</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150616">June 16, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S288">Ms. Murkowski</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To authorize the expansion of an existing hydroelectric project. </official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="id21B420E9D4BA4C21B6FED4E1AB6D2CA3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Kodiak Electric Association Upper Hidden Basin Diversion authorization</header>
			<subsection id="idD5ADBB0524274004B601EDF573D976C0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The special-use permit for the Terror Lake Hydroelectric Project (Federal Energy Regulatory Commission project No. 2743) described in section 1325 of the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/3212">16 U.S.C. 3212</external-xref>) is amended as depicted on the map entitled <quote>Upper Hidden Basin Diversion Project</quote> and dated May 18, 2015, for the construction, operation, and maintenance of a tunnel and associated facilities and activities for the Upper Hidden Basin Diversion.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idE46B83C41C6A4FF19575222240D0997C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The tunnel and associated facilities and activities described in subsection (a) shall be subject to appropriate terms and conditions included in an amendment to a license issued by the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission pursuant to the Federal Power Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/791a">16 U.S.C. 791a et seq.</external-xref>), including section 4(e) of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/797">16 U.S.C. 797(e)</external-xref>).</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


