<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1477 IS: Long Range Strike Aircraft Mix Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-06-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 1477</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150602">June 2, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S381">Mr. Rounds</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To require a report on the future mix of aircraft platforms for the Armed Forces. </official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Long Range Strike Aircraft Mix Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="idDE70C9E5D4974AA6828EB5DCD00F1EC6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Report on future mix of aircraft platforms for the Armed Forces</header>
 <subsection id="idB7739E716F54478D8F88424D156F25C8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report on study required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense shall submit to Congress a report setting forth the results of a study, to be performed by an organization or entity independent of the Department of Defense selected by the Secretary for purposes of this section, that determines the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="id8E419B48C90A4CD8B4838270EE7ECF2A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An optimized future mix of shorter range fighter-class strike aircraft and long-range strike aircraft platforms for the Armed Forces.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id95A8BDD7A6574BBC8E23E64226B1D549"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An appropriate future mix of manned aerial platforms and unmanned aerial platforms for the Armed Forces.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idB4DF505A4EFE4FC19F4785F887875D42"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Considerations in determining mix</header><text>The mixes determined pursuant to the study shall be determined taking into account relevant portions of the defense strategy, critical assumptions, priorities, force-sizing construct, and cost.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id596AB20A942B43C5A95C407C4987655B"><enum>(c)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nonduplication of effort</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If any information required under subsection (a) has been included in another report or notification previously submitted to Congress by law, the Secretary may provide a list of such reports and notifications at the time of submitting the report required by subsection (a) in lieu of including such information in the report required by subsection (a).</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


