<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1967 IS: To provide for the conveyance of land of the Illiana Health Care System of the Department of Veterans Affairs in Danville, Illinois.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-08-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1967</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150805">August 5, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S339">Mr. Kirk</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSVA00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To provide for the conveyance of land of the Illiana Health Care System of the Department of
			 Veterans Affairs in Danville, Illinois.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H1440FCED3D4342B4A405198CF69052C4" style="OLC">
		<section id="HE1B5456F637745F3A261D1B2738FA06F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Land conveyance, Danville, Illinois</header>
			<subsection id="H4840B07928DA432589F60630D703B83F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Conveyance authorized</header>
 <paragraph id="id7C2BE4E234CF4CC5BF47EE91E9D0BB5F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs may convey to the Danville Area Community College of Danville, Illinois, all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to certain real property, including any improvements thereon, consisting of approximately 0.6 acres known as <quote>Building Number 48</quote>, which is part of the Illiana Health Care System of the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H82A137E07570496A984DEB6BA306F3FB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Condition of conveyance</header><text>The conveyance under paragraph (1) shall be subject to the condition that the recipient accept the conveyed real property in its condition at the time of the conveyance.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6FF11964C3B6468AA0A52F6D89C023F9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consideration for conveyance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As consideration for the conveyance under subsection (a), the Secretary shall require the Danville Area Community College to convey to the United States all right, title, and interest of the Danville Area Community College in and to certain real property, including any improvements thereon, consisting of approximately 1.06 acres with a gazebo located approximately 293 feet south of the Danville Area Community College Library Building, which is part of the Danville Area Community College.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H724238A9BE7344308AD466151E3A0BF6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Description of property</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The exact acreage and legal description of the parcels of real property to be conveyed under subsections (a) and (b) shall be determined by surveys satisfactory to the Secretary.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H936D8EC3BB59480C8BF7AAF4CE4A6FD5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Additional terms and conditions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may require such additional terms and conditions in connection with the conveyances under subsections (a) and (b) as the Secretary considers appropriate to protect the interests of the United States.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


