<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S494 IS: Authorizing Alaska Production Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 494</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150212">February 12, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S288">Ms. Murkowski</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S383">Mr. Sullivan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To authorize the exploration, leasing, development, production, and economically feasible and
			 prudent transportation of oil and gas in and from the Coastal Plain in
			 Alaska.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short
 title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Authorizing Alaska Production Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </section><section id="ID4e9a796bf5e74177ad0fc81905906d2b"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="ID47b396edd4dc4e04a7eaf4138ea49707"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Coastal Plain</header><text>The term <term>Coastal Plain</term> means the area described in appendix I to part 37 of title 50, Code of Federal Regulations.</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="idA5ECCB29380B47D2AE423F4053A22DD7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federal
 agreement</header><text>The term <term>Federal Agreement</term> means the Federal Agreement and Grant Right-of-Way for the Trans-Alaska Pipeline issued on January 23, 1974, in accordance with section 28 of the Mineral Leasing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/185">30 U.S.C. 185</external-xref>) and the Trans-Alaska Pipeline Authorization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1651">43 U.S.C. 1651 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="idDBA4F7E2D7A84BD3BBC1FAB620F5F3A1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Final
 statement</header><text>The term <term>Final Statement</term> means the final legislative environmental impact statement on the Coastal Plain, dated April 1987, and prepared pursuant to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id5E6B4165B7F240DB86F8FD543434F233"><enum>(A)</enum><text>section 1002 of the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/3142">16 U.S.C. 3142</external-xref>); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idBCAA7A772E3445EA85260C9A7FE6EDAD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>section 102(2)(C) of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4332">42 U.S.C. 4332(2)(C)</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id966D90EBFCCD4E37814E12C3DFDC9FD9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Map</header><text>The term <term>map</term> means the map entitled <quote>Arctic National Wildlife Refuge</quote>, dated September 2005, and prepared by the United States Geological Survey.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ID4a7356c932ba4dc29bf5ec63b50279d2"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id75C16812E8CD44978A64869E02E6BB3D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary of the Interior; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1F2F934E860D45ABAC4C1C9EFF0B0B6C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the designee of the Secretary.</text>
				</subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="ID889aaf0072184e539931d49f86ba4518"><enum>3.</enum><header>Leasing program
			 for land within the Coastal Plain</header>
			<subsection id="ID2f98fdc0a24e49bab1df5890d8a6bfd0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In
			 general</header>
 <paragraph id="ID56ab21a606894a329255624c97cc4c04"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text>Congress authorizes the exploration, leasing, development, production, and economically feasible and prudent transportation of oil and gas in and from the Coastal Plain.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="IDd6b6a4fe40fa4f638363560177501b4c"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Actions</header><text>The Secretary shall take such actions as are necessary—</text>
 <subparagraph id="ID8a3afa33ba904f07a2be6609b373aea5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to establish and implement, in accordance with this Act, a competitive oil and gas leasing program that will result in an environmentally sound program for the exploration, development, and production of the oil and gas resources of the Coastal Plain; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID6be957b1e1a544debd11c2d7ad42c467"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to administer this Act through regulations, lease terms, conditions, restrictions, prohibitions, stipulations, and other provisions that—</text>
 <clause id="id0192541073494C31BEE6911C11AC0909"><enum>(i)</enum><text>ensure the oil and gas exploration, development, and production activities on the Coastal Plain will result in no significant adverse effect on fish and wildlife, fish and wildlife habitat, subsistence resources, and the environment; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id45C134A7F7B64600AD1A2AC129BEBBD0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>require the application of the best commercially available technology for oil and gas exploration, development, and production to all exploration, development, and production operations under this Act in a manner that ensures the receipt of fair market value by the public for the mineral resources to be leased.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="IDb8092d27dbc14ddbae4244978a8c99f0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Repeal</header>
 <paragraph id="ID545351343f064191b485df77b9dee607"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Repeal</header><text>Section 1003 of the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/3143">16 U.S.C. 3143</external-xref>) is repealed.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="IDcbeeb834f994455082c352d90d9dcb60"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming
 amendment</header><text>The table of contents contained in section 1 of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/3101">16 U.S.C. 3101</external-xref> note) is amended by striking the item relating to section 1003.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="IDf0d70ebf58d94376bdfedc23ec82fb1c"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Compliance with
			 requirements under certain other laws</header>
 <paragraph id="IDca7477988a3342069237ebf398829b6c"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Compatibility</header><text>For purposes of the National Wildlife Refuge System Administration Act of 1966 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/668dd">16 U.S.C. 668dd et seq.</external-xref>)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idCE8F08EBA973474394419C8EF11D4AFB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the oil and gas preleasing and leasing program, and activities authorized by this section in the Coastal Plain, shall be considered to be compatible with the purposes for which the Arctic National Wildlife Refuge was established; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0DD31ED74DF545AF94CD29203E6BE85E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>no further findings or decisions shall be required to implement that program and those activities.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID4fa05e559e734d1faa8825a4dde85c33"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Adequacy of the
			 Department of the Interior's legislative environmental impact
 statement</header><text>The Final Statement shall be considered to satisfy the requirements under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>) that apply with respect to preleasing, including exploration programs and actions authorized to be taken by the Secretary to develop and promulgate the regulations for the establishment of a leasing program authorized by this Act before the conduct of the first lease sale.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="IDc9c33801be56487ea69bb3d121ba170a"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Compliance with
			 NEPA for other actions</header>
					<subparagraph id="id58B4D63A74CD4B12B826D98F1EDD7B85"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>Before conducting the first lease sale under this Act, the Secretary shall prepare an environmental impact statement in accordance with the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>) with respect to the actions authorized by this Act that are not referred to in paragraph (2).</text>
					</subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE072FF63C9B04A1F86A81679413C7D3B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Identification
 and analysis</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, in carrying out this paragraph, the Secretary shall not—</text>
 <clause id="id32FC1DCC7290454BB571E2BED9C2B5AD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>identify nonleasing alternative courses of action; or</text> </clause><clause id="id54B6AAF2B8264C66AB16975798047C6A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>analyze the environmental effects of those courses of action.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC16C34F9411A4F729983001D4F5B5914"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Identification
 of preferred action</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall identify only a preferred action and a single leasing alternative for the first lease sale authorized under this Act.</text>
					</subparagraph><subparagraph id="idED29943597F84BBBA395A966C2D45BDF"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Effect of
 compliance</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, compliance with this paragraph shall be considered to satisfy all requirements for the analysis and consideration of the environmental effects of proposed leasing under this Act.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="IDf17426dfa4954f3f8d395b5a95226c8c"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Relationship to
 State and local authority</header><text>Nothing in this Act expands or limits any State or local regulatory authority.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="ID49ac219709474e86a2d7555bdaac5880"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Limitation on
 closed areas</header><text>The Secretary shall not close land within the Coastal Plain to oil and gas leasing or to exploration, development, or production except in accordance with this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idcc5720a24ad044d0a18ea797a04adcfb"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, in consultation with the State of Alaska, North Slope Borough, Alaska, the City of Kaktovik, Alaska, and the Arctic Slope Regional Corporation, the Secretary shall promulgate such regulations as are necessary to carry out this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="ID8f083be956fc419cbbb4ac31e61f5e17"><enum>4.</enum><header>Lease
			 sales</header>
			<subsection id="IDaf799b786e5941a090af9afe6dddc7a0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>Land may be leased pursuant to this Act to any person qualified to obtain a lease for deposits of oil and gas under the Mineral Leasing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/181">30 U.S.C. 181 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id5e3e914a337d405da4e41ea1d5abbe66"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Procedures</header><text>The Secretary shall, by regulation, establish procedures for—</text> <paragraph id="ideb93d89ee5b14730a92eacd1f02f2a90"><enum>(1)</enum><text>receipt and consideration of sealed nominations for any area in the Coastal Plain for inclusion in a lease sale;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id569f5f9bd4654900862a68c2d5a8005a"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the holding of lease sales after the nomination process described in paragraph (1); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idfeb3725014a7424b95065f4bf81dc097"><enum>(3)</enum><text>public notice of and comment on designation of areas to be included in, or excluded from, a lease sale.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0563d475cf3d4efcafecc15d92dc0650"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Lease sale bids</header><text>Bidding for leases under this Act shall be by sealed competitive cash bonus bids.</text> </subsection><subsection id="id852c6c6375eb413e8a9811eafc62a89c"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Acreage minimum in first sale</header><text>For the first lease sale under this Act, the Secretary shall offer for lease those tracts the Secretary considers to have the greatest potential for the discovery of hydrocarbons, taking into consideration nominations received pursuant to subsection (b)(1), but in no case less than 200,000 acres.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idae60bd74f7874823ab8c195cf2e5fef8"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Timing of lease sales</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text> <paragraph id="id80912c57983646a48fc101c88ab0d779"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, conduct the first lease sale under this Act;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id162f74d2016449848dd61612056e3ea0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not later than 1 year after the date on which the first lease sale is conducted under paragraph (1), conduct a second lease sale under this Act; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idda334bedc94f4a32a50e496e642b3ca0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>conduct additional sales at appropriate intervals if sufficient interest in exploration or development exists to warrant the conduct of the additional sales.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="IDb8b851cd962e49b6b39ccf738d779f00"><enum>5.</enum><header>Grant of leases
			 by the Secretary</header>
			<subsection id="ID5c0caed57f8c49d1acf56ef960755dfc"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>Upon payment by a lessee of such bonus as may be accepted by the Secretary, the Secretary shall grant to the highest responsible qualified bidder in a lease sale conducted pursuant to section 4 a lease for any land on the Coastal Plain.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="ID4b130bd6c66948f2bcb59274df4496b4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Subsequent
			 transfers</header>
				<paragraph id="id4F4FAB88EBA14631A3E84B15A23FFAED"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>No lease issued under this Act may be sold, exchanged, assigned, sublet, or otherwise transferred except with the approval of the Secretary.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="id0CB39DCA414F40BAB8539D8C50246114"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Condition for
 approval</header><text>Before granting any approval described in paragraph (1), the Secretary shall consult with and give due consideration to the opinion of the Attorney General.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="IDefd6e12ef8514bde89de0dc2fc2d109b"><enum>6.</enum><header>Lease terms and
			 conditions</header>
			<subsection id="ID2c4b6f82f115481b979d65e939387b27"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>An oil or gas lease issued pursuant to this Act shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="ID99a284cde5b3476da3759f9388b97e15"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide for the payment of a royalty of not less than 12<fraction>½</fraction> percent of the amount or value of the production removed or sold from the lease, as determined by the Secretary in accordance with regulations applicable to other Federal oil and gas leases;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ID7c352925494d4ded86a3241e04f725db"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide that the Secretary, after consultation with the State of Alaska, North Slope Borough, Alaska, the City of Kaktovik, Alaska, and the Arctic Slope Regional Corporation, may close, on a seasonal basis, such portions of the Coastal Plain to exploratory drilling activities as are necessary to protect caribou calving areas and other species of fish and wildlife;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ID12531e09e5e04d8484f5cb2304fcbe4d"><enum>(3)</enum><text>require that each lessee of land within the Coastal Plain shall be fully responsible and liable for the reclamation of land within the Coastal Plain and any other Federal land that is adversely affected in connection with exploration, development, production, or transportation activities within the Coastal Plain conducted by the lessee or by any of the subcontractors or agents of the lessee;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ID6c1f792c77c648b4b9840b87bd00a02a"><enum>(4)</enum><text>provide that the lessee may not delegate or convey, by contract or otherwise, the reclamation responsibility and liability described in paragraph (3) to another person without the express written approval of the Secretary;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ID3060d755055e46be8b211470f4046a8a"><enum>(5)</enum><text>provide that the standard of reclamation for land required to be reclaimed under this Act shall be, to the maximum extent practicable—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id6B5C33D881294161A937C4895D5B4881"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a condition capable of supporting the uses that the land was capable of supporting prior to any exploration, development, or production activities; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2021C7D1A56A4CAEB0EE43B9CCBFE588"><enum>(B)</enum><text>upon application by the lessee, to a higher or better standard, as approved by the Secretary;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID4560710656704623bde65435189c5ad6"><enum>(6)</enum><text>contain terms and conditions relating to protection of fish and wildlife, fish and wildlife habitat, subsistence resources, and the environment as required under section 3(a)(2); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ID69c6485d0e1745ea8568a456438bd671"><enum>(7)</enum><text>provide that each lessee, and each agent and contractor of a lessee, shall use their best efforts to provide a fair share of employment and contracting for Alaska Natives and Alaska Native Corporations from throughout the State of Alaska, as determined by the level of obligation previously agreed to in the Federal Agreement.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID6663471783d1446d833e06af08e1c06d"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Project labor
 agreements</header><text>The Secretary, as a term and condition of each lease under this Act, and in recognizing the proprietary interest of the Federal Government in labor stability and in the ability of construction labor and management to meet the particular needs and conditions of projects to be developed under the leases issued pursuant to this Act (including the special concerns of the parties to those leases), shall require that each lessee, and each agent and contractor of a lessee, under this Act negotiate to obtain a project labor agreement for the employment of laborers and mechanics on production, maintenance, and construction under the lease.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="IDb715d31383244a52b20e661ef6f5a528"><enum>7.</enum><header>Coastal plain
			 environmental protection</header>
			<subsection id="ID0ea79d2df5a34851aaa6e0778b4ab21e"><enum>(a)</enum><header>No significant
			 adverse effect standard To govern authorized coastal plain
 activities</header><text>In accordance with section 3, the Secretary shall administer this Act through regulations, lease terms, conditions, restrictions, prohibitions, stipulations, or other provisions that—</text>
 <paragraph id="ID711ba77b4f5849f9a88d98c077d75b28"><enum>(1)</enum><text>ensure, to the maximum extent practicable, that oil and gas exploration, development, and production activities on the Coastal Plain will result in no significant adverse effect on fish and wildlife, fish and wildlife habitat, subsistence resources, and the environment;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ID0b9f5988d7c04622883b4ab7be8a298e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>require the application of the best commercially available technology for oil and gas exploration, development, and production on all new exploration, development, and production operations; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="IDb38f9619683f4a55b58ac9ecdac562ed"><enum>(3)</enum><text>ensure that the maximum surface acreage covered in connection with the leasing program by production and support facilities, including airstrips and any areas covered by gravel berms or piers for support of pipelines, does not exceed 2,000 acres on the Coastal Plain.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="IDd4930e0ae9b74cf280455841be21b9d5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Site-Specific
 assessment and mitigation</header><text>The Secretary shall require, with respect to any proposed drilling and related activities on the Coastal Plain, that—</text>
 <paragraph id="ID789ea94bb3a94f6a9982ef42ec5cc4f6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a site-specific environmental analysis be made of the probable effects, if any, that the drilling or related activities will have on fish and wildlife, fish and wildlife habitat, subsistence resources, and the environment;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="IDc79d60d288384a7d869ead77d2952724"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a plan be implemented to avoid, minimize, and mitigate (in that order and to the maximum extent practicable) any significant adverse effect identified under paragraph (1); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ID9719dd88ca734f5ca4d9b2f5a6fbeab4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the development of the plan occur after consultation with—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id034C2CB7F6B44AA9928B076CAB3A662D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>each agency having jurisdiction over matters mitigated by the plan;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idEBEDC83241764C8D871E44EFEEF2FABF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the State of Alaska;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id38D2E4228E174E768B49CC152051E8BA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>North Slope Borough, Alaska;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1803E562270641B79F22829A34B1D533"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the City of Kaktovik, Alaska; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2E4A3F8839A34882B65538E7C1F8EFD9"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Arctic Slope Regional Corporation.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="IDa5193f629bb740ce9cb252e8b3b2f94d"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Regulations To
			 protect Coastal Plain fish and wildlife resources, subsistence users, and
			 the
 environment</header><text>Before implementing the leasing program authorized by this Act, the Secretary shall prepare and promulgate regulations, lease terms, conditions, restrictions, prohibitions, stipulations, or other measures designed to ensure, to the maximum extent practicable, that the activities carried out on the Coastal Plain under this Act are conducted in a manner consistent with the purposes and environmental requirements of this Act.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="ID3cc7a9ba70884dfdb094ea50e15ab9ab"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Compliance with
 Federal and State environmental laws and other requirements</header><text>The regulations, lease terms, conditions, restrictions, prohibitions, and stipulations for the leasing program under this Act shall require—</text>
 <paragraph id="id620EEE5785EF40D8850FDF89C4F1E19D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>compliance with all applicable provisions of Federal and State environmental law (including regulations); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ID8b865e509bf14068bd041ca997bda418"><enum>(2)</enum><text>implementation of and compliance with—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idCB8F04702D624A939D41FF8CAFADF5CF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>standards that are at least as effective as the safety and environmental mitigation measures, as described in items 1 through 29 on pages 167 through 169 of the Final Statement;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID4cc920810b6b4aa5b227414069803416"><enum>(B)</enum><text>reclamation and rehabilitation requirements in accordance with this Act for the removal from the Coastal Plain of all oil and gas development and production facilities, structures, and equipment on completion of oil and gas production operations, except in a case in which the Secretary determines that those facilities, structures, or equipment—</text>
 <clause id="id0EB7CBD2EC714E2182214043A940CF3D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>would assist in the management of the Arctic National Wildlife Refuge; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id23CF756FB8B447A785B3D256F11F9BC0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>are donated to the United States for that purpose; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6CE025E0CD404BF88027807155AF857F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>reasonable stipulations for protection of cultural and archaeological resources.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="IDad933e1fbdcd4744868fc25761e6ee9c"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Access to
 public land</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text> <paragraph id="IDe691d89c04c14d7a933450bcc88646c5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>manage public land in the Coastal Plain in accordance with subsections (a) and (b) of section 811 of the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/3121">16 U.S.C. 3121</external-xref>); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ID24114d61ed5e4b73bb7ca40db4e7bf28"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ensure that local residents shall have reasonable access to public land in the Coastal Plain for traditional uses.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="IDfb526f6f4f9845e1bc3339dea8f4b46b"><enum>8.</enum><header>Rights-of-way
 and easements across Coastal Plain</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For purposes of section 1102(4)(A) of the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/3162">16 U.S.C. 3162(4)(A)</external-xref>), any rights-of-way or easements across the Coastal Plain for the exploration, development, production, or transportation of oil and gas shall be considered to be established incident to the management of the Coastal Plain under this section.</text>
 </section><section id="ID39c37018eb834d63b4a3222d0df30589"><enum>9.</enum><header>Conveyance</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 1302(h)(2) of the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/3192">16 U.S.C. 3192(h)(2)</external-xref>), to remove any cloud on title to land, and to clarify land ownership patterns in the Coastal Plain, the Secretary shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="ID8b13eca8b9e4414c89ad2830a1bace2f"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to the extent necessary to fulfill the entitlement of the Kaktovik Inupiat Corporation under sections 12 and 14 of the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1611">43 U.S.C. 1611</external-xref>, 1613), as determined by the Secretary, convey to that Corporation the surface estate of the land described in paragraph (1) of Public Land Order 6959, in accordance with the terms and conditions of the agreement between the Secretary, the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, the Bureau of Land Management, and the Kaktovik Inupiat Corporation, dated January 22, 1993; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="IDf5a9b0ad60314024b710654412ee8daf"><enum>(2)</enum><text>convey to the Arctic Slope Regional Corporation the remaining subsurface estate to which that Corporation is entitled under the agreement between that corporation and the United States, dated August 9, 1983.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HC18B01F194ED4F1DAF978EF03DFEF300"><enum>10.</enum><header>Local government impact aid and community service assistance</header>
			<subsection id="H52CED88BED964602B0D3B4A778EC7B15"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of fund</header>
 <paragraph id="H70DE5AE58A454058AE02511616196BB5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is established in the Treasury a fund to be known as the <quote>Coastal Plain Local Government Impact Aid Assistance Fund</quote> (referred to in this section as the <quote>Fund</quote>).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC13BF3C16CF241F1BCA900BD02B7F4A8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use</header><text>Amounts in the Fund may be used only to provide financial assistance in accordance with subsection (b).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H473D5F54A7F64AB9A18112C621FAF76F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Deposits</header><text>Subject to paragraph (4), of amounts of revenues payable to the State of Alaska under section 35 of the Mineral Leasing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/191">30 U.S.C. 191</external-xref>) that are derived from rents, bonuses, and royalties from Federal leases and lease sales authorized under this Act—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id60E23D6FA7CE4F7BA57B5F65C8CF25F8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>$28,000,000 shall be deposited in the Fund for the first fiscal year for which amounts are received by the United States from Federal leases and lease sales authorized under this Act; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id76DCD861EA26401FA1562ECA9D3459DA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>$7,000,000 shall be deposited in the Fund for each fiscal year thereafter.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2C0236E419D04210A68910B2E54777B0"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Limitation on deposits</header><text>The total amount in the Fund may not exceed $28,000,000.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDC6AB2058AC549BEA2A8A14494E2015B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Investment of balances</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall invest amounts in the Fund in interest-bearing securities of the United States.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE6023E2520F04F1E8939A8AD6DBBADA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Financial assistance</header>
 <paragraph id="H387DE36F66C44C1FA56D4759315331A2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may use amounts available from the Fund to provide timely financial assistance to North Slope Borough, Alaska, the City of Kaktovik, Alaska, and any other borough, municipal subdivision, village, or other community in the State of Alaska that is directly impacted by exploration for, or the production of, oil or gas on the Coastal Plain under this Act, as determined by the Secretary.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H479F9528AB324BB1B7344CDA001DC081"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of assistance</header><text>Financial assistance provided under this subsection may be used only for—</text> <subparagraph id="H30114532BEF74A4C93B99CADC3B8E285"><enum>(A)</enum><text>planning for mitigation of the potential effects of oil and gas exploration and development on environmental, social, cultural, recreational, and subsistence values;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD04FFC54515C4B88B4DB58DC2B86487D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>implementing mitigation plans and maintaining mitigation projects;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H405618BD55D845D3A75E6E5F056715C3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>developing, carrying out, and maintaining projects and programs that provide new or expanded public facilities and services to address needs and problems associated with the effects described in subparagraph (A), including firefighting, police, water, waste treatment, medivac, and medical services; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFD1BFE8A355748BC85E3A14064CCD6E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the establishment by North Slope Borough, Alaska, of a coordination office in the City of Kaktovik, Alaska—</text>
 <clause id="H1FA3922155924F9C8BBF8A7FF00ECAC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to coordinate with and advise developers on local conditions of, impacts on, and the history of the areas utilized for development under this Act; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H457E1432B544455C98845B8EE64CE0F6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to provide to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate an annual report that describes the status of coordination between developers and the communities affected by development under this Act.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA9A1A266E3F94096A76BE79644B2AD15"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header>
 <paragraph id="H8DB037F1F75448A8BAD36049F8A52BAA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To receive assistance under subsection (b), a community described in subsection (b)(1) shall submit to the Secretary an application for assistance, in such form and under such procedures as the Secretary may prescribe by regulation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCCE6E65BAB264F3BB912F444F41016B4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>North Slope Borough communities</header><text>A community located in North Slope Borough, Alaska, may apply for assistance under this section either directly with the Secretary or through the North Slope Borough.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE63C570D76C8458CB887B121BDB35E23"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Application assistance</header><text>The Secretary shall work closely with and assist North Slope Borough, Alaska, and other communities eligible for assistance under this section in developing and submitting applications under this subsection.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7D0A8968250E4AD99D098700F00411CD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary from the Fund $7,000,000 for each fiscal year to provide financial assistance under this section.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


