<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1217 IS: Electric Transmission Infrastructure Permitting Improvement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 1217</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150506">May 6, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S288">Ms. Murkowski</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To establish an Interagency Rapid Response Team for Transmission, to establish an Office of
			 Transmission Ombudsperson, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Electric Transmission Infrastructure Permitting Improvement Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="id2A2A4A3856EC409F920E274A0BF0B2B4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Interagency Rapid Response Team for Transmission</header>
 <subsection id="id78966B480D054C419D44741A5AB1BD5E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established an interagency rapid response team, to be known as the <quote>Interagency Rapid Response Team for Transmission</quote> (referred to in this section as the <quote>Team</quote>), to expedite and improve the permitting process for electric transmission infrastructure on Federal land and non-Federal land.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id224FD9E48B6842D8808CE5B354719946"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Mission</header><text>The mission of the Team shall be—</text> <paragraph id="idA92D6B61B8C143D0B6A225AC03A531F1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to improve the timeliness and efficiency of electric transmission infrastructure permitting; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id8CA09670372C4D0E8B6D3B7172C29004"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to facilitate the performance of maintenance and upgrades to electric transmission lines on Federal land and non-Federal land.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0C4DBD90BFE44029BAEF29775611EB50"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>The Team shall be comprised of representatives of—</text> <paragraph id="idABAA1165E8A845DCBAF1C64FCAFEBEC7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id246094fb598b46e6a147ff485246b7fb"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Department of Energy;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id8C606B83E5C3406E947FEE23F0A2799C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Department of the Interior;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id2e9a65bc055e4ba48adb7e7f3da3f400"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the Department of Defense;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id09ad03266d09411f823ca17352acd485"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the Department of Agriculture;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id76D0C052D4E4417FBF439B8F862F1A8C"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the Council on Environmental Quality;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id0c038b86d3e84aaf89b7340dd058e7d7"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the Department of Commerce;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id3c452775bf0e4fd5baf85c460dcf3e07"><enum>(8)</enum><text>the Advisory Council on Historic Preservation; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id1c58cc548bbf466b9400b5809cdd531d"><enum>(9)</enum><text>the Environmental Protection Agency.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ide11e031e32e64ab1b2abac1a337a47b7"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Team shall—</text> <paragraph id="idaca915ac7f834bf88b26d38385974e4b"><enum>(1)</enum><text>facilitate coordination and unified environmental documentation among electric transmission infrastructure project applicants, Federal agencies, States, and Indian tribes involved in the siting and permitting process;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id245654180f5f42f4a842ae3d7c426cd2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>establish clear timelines for the review and coordination of electric transmission infrastructure projects by the applicable agencies;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idc037edcb8f1d4461ad458a3262aaaeb7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>ensure that each electric transmission infrastructure project is posted on the Federal permitting transmission tracking system known as <quote>e-Trans</quote>, including information on the status and anticipated completion date of each project; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id132cc4202bb74db88a1058201ba5a4ce"><enum>(4)</enum><text>regularly notify all participating members of the Team involved in any specific permit of—</text> <subparagraph id="id7BCC7E0724E14CB79E1F75433358605F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any outstanding agency action that is required with respect to the permit; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF4F3F24A9F7646D1907780D9C7FB4149"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any approval or required comment that has exceeded statutory or agency timelines for completion, including an identification of any Federal agency, department, or field office that has not met the applicable timeline.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id92BA6258635B40BE9593A540FB3CBE2D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Annual reports</header><text>Annually, the Team shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives a report that describes the average completion time for specific categories of regionally and nationally significant transmission projects, based on information obtained from the applicable Federal agencies.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idB22E8E8709A747F0B7EC00163814804D"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Use of data by OMB</header><text>Using data provided by the Team, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall prioritize inclusion of individual electric transmission infrastructure projects in the permit performance dashboard.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="id63C5F08FCEDD44279A786E334B3E759C"><enum>3.</enum><header>Transmission Ombudsperson</header>
 <subsection id="id50F71D5D33B74D9CB9EE12F916662050"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>To enhance and ensure the reliability of the electric grid, there is established within the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission the position of Transmission Ombudsperson (referred to in this section as the <quote>Ombudsperson</quote>), to provide a unified point of contact for—</text>
 <paragraph id="id3F6A05035AA44303A8554F50A9CD32F8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>resolving interagency or intra-agency issues or delays with respect to electric transmission infrastructure permits; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id974E5D0E8C654FEDB94D9B2D1C09C52C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>receiving and resolving complaints from parties with outstanding or in-process applications relating to electric transmission infrastructure.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id7B4A81AA6994499D95577E508E2456F2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Ombudsperson shall—</text> <paragraph id="idb4979d3b5e654add8b3c30913a77ba18"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establish a process for—</text>
 <subparagraph id="ide3cb4af36a104d81a5128809b1043b07"><enum>(A)</enum><text>facilitating the permitting process for performance of maintenance and upgrades to electric transmission lines on Federal land and non-Federal land, with a special emphasis on facilitating access for immediate maintenance, repair, and vegetation management needs;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC9B7081AACF941F98E1588EE1334A7DC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>resolving complaints filed with the Ombudsperson with respect to in-process electric transmission infrastructure permits; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF9F82D501E2D433E9665C1922A593A7F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>issuing recommended resolutions to address the complaints filed with the Ombudsperson; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id2fe074d7e1aa4bdc866c53f5f041cd5b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>hear, compile, and share any complaints filed with Ombudsperson relating to in-process electric transmission infrastructure permits.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id0CBF5F14884644B4960DCF0A18CC75C4"><enum>4.</enum><header>Rights-of-way for electric transmission systems</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 507 of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1767">43 U.S.C. 1767</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id90F9D921C5EC4701877FAEDF83748B2A" style="OLC">
				<subsection id="id56476EF745754C41BFF354AC2AAC7895"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rights-of-Way for electric transmission systems</header>
 <paragraph id="id83A70E073A334A1488465EF18AAACE7C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In a case in which a right-of-way has been reserved for the use of any Federal agency or department for an electric transmission system, the Secretary shall not take any of the actions described in paragraph (2) unless the head of the applicable Federal agency or department proposes to change the use of the right-of-way to support a function other than an electric transmission system.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idABA56EE7399B4133946105AD3D0F4F12"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered actions</header><text>An action referred to in paragraph (1) is an action—</text> <subparagraph id="idD4529C6258B84A00B4AFC6E5371265ED"><enum>(A)</enum><text>requiring a new grant, permit, or renewal of the grant or permit relating to the right-of-way;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4FBBF87EA87B459D8A270B013172DDFB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>requiring any other authorization or instrument relating to the right-of-way; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE15A18BA308E49DCA77509A9DA761229"><enum>(C)</enum><text>imposing new terms or conditions relating to the right-of-way or the use of the right-of-way, including any proposed changes to or additions of equipment, structures, or other electric transmission system facilities or appurtenances.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body>
</bill>


