<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Placed-on-Calendar-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S915 PCS: Real Estate Investment and Jobs Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><calendar>Calendar No. 48</calendar><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 915</legis-num><associated-doc>[Report No. 114–25]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150414">April 14, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S118">Mr. Hatch</sponsor>, from the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name>, reported the following original bill; which was read twice and placed on the calendar</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to exempt certain stock of real estate investment trusts
			 from the tax on foreign investments in United States real property
			 interests, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="id4AEF534283ED4405A015A505605DD48D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short
			 title; etc</header>
 <subsection id="id20D7C00D53FF4062B747A05E40324486"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Real Estate Investment and Jobs Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEE901218BF3F4CEAA58016BF2D58D382"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amendment of 1986 Code</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as otherwise expressly provided, whenever in this Act an amendment or repeal is expressed in terms of an amendment to, or repeal of, a section or other provision, the reference shall be considered to be made to a section or other provision of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="ID0e92309938ca463c9e66cab4aabbd409"><enum>2.</enum><header>Exception from
			 FIRPTA for certain stock of real estate investment trusts</header>
			<subsection id="idE35FFE92AA5A49EA9BE3C6496D775057"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Modifications of ownership rules</header>
 <paragraph id="idE9F1DDEB80A74735BF674874702E2220"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/897">Section 897</external-xref> is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id237D0F01F8334AB6BC858262CDD922EE" style="OLC"> <subsection id="id003584477C934E108D639F0A479D726C"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Special rules relating to real estate investment trusts</header> <paragraph id="id27421418A55646FF9BB44CAA16EDA832"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Increase in percentage ownership for exceptions for persons holding publicly traded stock</header> <subparagraph id="idB870F8108EF84B17A841CF224294DB14"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Dispositions</header><text>In the case of any disposition of stock in a real estate investment trust, paragraphs (3) and (6)(C) of subsection (c) shall each be applied by substituting <quote>more than 10 percent</quote> for <quote>more than 5 percent</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idCBEAD332802542BCAA0CEDA00A5843BA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Distributions</header><text>In the case of any distribution from a real estate investment trust, subsection (h)(1) shall be applied by substituting <quote>10 percent</quote> for <quote>5 percent</quote>.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idC52A4CE621514DD09C41D5F84E3E1D9A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Stock held by qualified shareholders not treated as USRPI</header>
 <subparagraph id="id4C37A591DEE84BE8B5992EA9659E5B59"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B)—</text> <clause id="idD12723DD43764EF197F4F756B227C258"><enum>(i)</enum><text>stock of a real estate investment trust which is held directly by a qualified shareholder shall not be treated as a United States real property interest, and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id7D7853E38A234218A24610405F046B7E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>notwithstanding subsection (h)(1), any distribution to a qualified shareholder shall not be treated as gain recognized from the sale or exchange of a United States real property interest to the extent the stock of the real estate investment trust held by such qualified shareholder is not treated as a United States real property interest under clause (i).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7A5C6EB936144972AB0D6232DCD15129"><enum>(B)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a qualified shareholder with 1 or more applicable investors—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idA71D4B3999754225AC2CF1A09665D0CD"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">subparagraph (A)(i) shall not apply to so much of the stock of a real estate investment trust held by a qualified shareholder as bears the same ratio to the amount of the interests (other than interests held solely as a creditor) held by such applicable investors in the qualified shareholder bears to all such interests in the qualified shareholder, and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1C7F8957EC3146778915E183C5915FF9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a percentage equal to the ratio determined under clause (i) of the amounts realized by the qualified shareholder with respect to any disposition of stock in the real estate investment trust or with respect to any distribution from the real estate investment trust attributable to gain from sales or exchanges of a United States real property interest shall be treated as amounts realized from the disposition of United States real property interests.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id83EB4F9E35BB4AB980B9ADAE8719E8C3"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Applicable investor</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph—</text> <clause commented="no" id="idEA9665A666754D46AF3646125920AAF6"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>applicable investor</term> means, with respect to any qualified shareholder holding stock in a real estate investment trust, a person (other than a qualified shareholder) which—</text>
 <subclause commented="no" id="id9C7E2599A95C4C5C9C4477419119CD6F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>holds an interest (other than an interest solely as a creditor) in such qualified shareholder, and</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="id08EC781C30E44CA19DF33FB54385F134"><enum>(II)</enum><text>holds more than 10 percent of the stock of such real estate investment trust (whether or not by reason of the person's ownership interest in the qualified shareholder).</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause commented="no" id="id8CE4D08839314467883831233CB7E714"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Constructive ownership rules</header><text>For purposes of this subparagraph, the constructive ownership rules under subsection (c)(6)(C) shall apply.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id59B00AEA1542417E9B05C675763423D6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Qualified shareholder</header><text>For purposes of this subsection—</text> <subparagraph id="id6306FB3784CE497182E8719877CB6638"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>qualified shareholder</term> means a foreign person—</text>
 <clause id="idA88ECE8004474C20B4EA2683496790BB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>which is eligible for benefits of a comprehensive income tax treaty with the United States which includes an exchange of information program,</text>
 </clause><clause id="id09EFC0616AFF478ABCBA872C42882A76"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>which is a qualified collective investment vehicle,</text>
 </clause><clause id="id9CB8BCFCEADE445A89C9F53BE5817F16"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the principal class of interests of which is listed and regularly traded on 1 or more recognized stock exchanges (as defined in such comprehensive income tax treaty), and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id4FFB6575315B4780ADEAB3F9B3EF24FB"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>which maintains records on the identity of each person who, at any time during the foreign person’s taxable year, holds directly more than 10 percent of the class of interest described in clause (iii).</text>
									</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3D214232ED914EF5BEF26830724D18D5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Qualified
 collective investment vehicle</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>qualified collective investment vehicle</term> means a foreign person—</text>
 <clause id="idB54F17B7F3EF4369A97FD71A4FB503F3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>which, under the comprehensive income tax treaty described in subparagraph (A)(i), is eligible for a reduced rate of withholding with respect to ordinary dividends paid by a real estate investment trust and continues to be so eligible even if such person holds more than 10 percent of the stock of such real estate investment trust,</text>
 </clause><clause id="id83B43943EA114CF38996C8E3E557A014"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>which, if such person were a United States person, would be classified as a United States real property holding corporation (determined without regard to paragraph (2)) at any time during the 5-year period ending on the date of any disposition of, or distribution with respect to, the person’s interests in a real estate investment trust, or</text>
 </clause><clause id="id80B62F0AAF4C488CBE91423B5925AE13"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>which is designated as a qualified collective investment vehicle by the Secretary and is either—</text>
 <subclause id="id759B05FD73DA418FAAFE07217E643E82"><enum>(I)</enum><text>fiscally transparent within the meaning of section 894, or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id67BED49F815C4FCF9B645DC27102FCB6"><enum>(II)</enum><text>required to include dividends in its gross income, but entitled to a deduction for distributions to persons holding interests (other than interests solely as a creditor) in such foreign person.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="id5ED194610F53440DB9DCFA81E520DAFD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header>
 <subparagraph id="id56A71B78525D42689724B12FFF3322AF"><enum>(A)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/897">Section 897(c)(1)(A)</external-xref> is amended by inserting <quote>or subsection (k)</quote> after <quote>subparagraph (B)</quote> in the matter preceding clause (i).</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id67313DCF4C4342D98B4B88DE42DEF844"><enum>(B)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/857">Section 857(b)(3)(F)</external-xref> is amended by inserting <quote>or section 897(k)(2)(A)(ii)</quote> after <quote>897(h)(1)</quote>.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF51AA050064D401CA93A21F05C0DF63D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Determination of domestic control</header>
				<paragraph id="id7D007F49562845CF9A3C8CD171D8E961"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Special ownership rules</header>
 <subparagraph id="id0DC813D83E5449C18867466F3F032C4B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/897">Section 897(h)(4)</external-xref> is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4AF0CE38615947CF805E881B514FCD69" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="id274A01A1280E4D6C94BD56FAB8492122"><enum>(E)</enum> <header>Special ownership rules</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of determining the holder of stock under subparagraphs (B) and (C)—</text>
 <clause id="idA23AAFA7723F4D3DB35F6C28345405E7"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of any class of stock of the qualified investment entity which is regularly traded on an established securities market in the United States, a person holding less than 5 percent of such class of stock at all times during the testing period shall be treated as a United States person unless the qualified investment entity has actual knowledge that such person is not a United States person,</text>
 </clause><clause id="HEF07CE61B34D4A1B8102C955D004D121"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any stock in the qualified investment entity held by another qualified investment entity—</text> <subclause id="HC07D0E7AFF594DAAA9FF5D363E4EBD12"><enum>(I)</enum><text>any class of stock of which is regularly traded on an established securities market, or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H6F05F0E18D30492D90C650E3419ED98D"><enum>(II)</enum><text>which is a regulated investment company which issues redeemable securities (within the meaning of section 2 of the Investment Company Act of 1940),</text>
									</subclause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="clause">shall be treated as held by a foreign person, except that if such other qualified investment entity
			 is
			 domestically controlled (determined after application of this
			 subparagraph), such stock shall be treated as held by a United States
 person, and</continuation-text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4F4BBB2929A34427B104D4EFB32419AF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any stock in the qualified investment entity held by any other qualified investment entity not described in subclause (I) or (II) of clause (ii) shall only be treated as held by a United States person in proportion to the stock of such other qualified investment entity which is (or is treated under clause (ii) or (iii) as) held by a United States person.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE773FAB5567E4150968886E13B4C4DC6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>The heading for paragraph (4) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/897">section 897(h)</external-xref> is amended by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">and special rules</header-in-text></quote> after <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">Definitions</header-in-text></quote>.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id350A9AD8D03E413F909BD806DB3D1617"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Technical amendment</header><text>Clause (ii) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/897">section 897(h)(4)(A)</external-xref> is amended by inserting <quote>and for purposes of determining whether a real estate investment trust is a domestically controlled qualified investment entity under this subsection</quote> after <quote>real estate investment trust</quote>.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idCC2175B2980545E7BB2608445D779594"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective
			 dates</header>
				<paragraph id="idEB46A513208F41B8A4C1CA0E95D579CE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>The amendments made by subsection (a) shall take effect on the date of enactment and shall apply to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id7C530155E2D04D969C8D23E6E99378DB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any disposition on and after the date of the enactment of this Act, and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD9541819E36648289AF3DE11AC871755"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any distribution by a real estate investment trust on or after the date of the enactment of this Act which is treated as a deduction for a taxable year of such trust ending after such date.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idBC58108A1C2343C3869271D0678DDF0D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Determination of domestic control</header><text>The amendments made by subsection (b)(1) shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id95DD418A2EAB490DB3679AF157E187A5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Technical amendment</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (b)(2) shall take effect on January 1, 2015.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HC8A88CC882C04BEB8C445D27D9B28E54"><enum>3.</enum><header>Increase in rate of withholding of tax on dispositions of United States real property interests</header> <subsection id="HD85907A27F0E474F821BA74B4F718BCA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsections (a), (e)(3), (e)(4), and (e)(5) of section 1445 are each amended by striking <quote>10 percent</quote> and inserting <quote>15 percent</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HFA1047D4E14646FC81F0368C3DFAC0F0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exception for certain residences</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/1445">Section 1445(c)</external-xref> is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCF84C20800A44B5D821443DF17E3729D" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HC99129E742924F5FB6A93AA5A74BF1B2"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Reduced rate of withholding for residence where amount realized does not exceed $1,000,000</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a disposition—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2FAEBE310034484FA908A85D898AB02A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">of property which is acquired by the transferee for use by the transferee as a residence,</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7209D762EF2946D98C266483AE42328F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to which the amount realized for such property does not exceed $1,000,000, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB5FED6F176C7487FA68FECE316F49C8D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to which subsection (b)(5) does not apply,</text> </subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">subsection (a) shall be applied by substituting <quote>10 percent</quote> for <quote>15 percent</quote>.</continuation-text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="H5AE894FD5FBF4E4D8AFF4AF172B23A2B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to dispositions after the date which is 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section><section commented="no" id="HD7A20D731C5842ADB9399B9CFF2AFFF6"><enum>4.</enum><header>Required notification of status as United States real property holding corporation</header>
			<subsection commented="no" id="H9B9BBD3DBAD74B008D7AACE4D41E99D4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Notification of status as United States real property holding corporation</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="id5F37447C71DF42B0939864429AF7C5CD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subpart A of part III of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/61">chapter 61</external-xref> is amended by inserting before section 6039C the following new section:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFB1FE09B47D74A01AADBE6F6F3839C57" style="OLC">
						<section commented="no" id="HA2CF9C63CD0F4491882BB4ABBC770391"><enum>6039B.</enum><header>Notification of status as United States real property holding corporation</header>
 <subsection commented="no" id="idF6BF8906B8844C8887B4486760665366"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any corporation which is a United States real property holding corporation shall make the following notifications:</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H76846BE73C8F47D58339CCEFC3019B77"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Disclosure to the Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than the due date for its return of tax (including extensions) for the taxable year, the corporation shall disclose the information described in subsection (b) to the Secretary in such form and manner as the Secretary may require.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id7B73639EB3DF44059F5785D1D12D85E2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Disclosure on payee statements</header><text>The corporation shall include on any statement required to be made under section 6042(c) the information described in subsection (b).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id8B90C3E0459A46AFAAFEE013D649A5EF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Disclosure to the public</header><text>The corporation shall disclose to the public the information described in subsection (b)—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="id55F41D6C47394C19B97A4ABECA725DF2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in any annual report made by such corporation, or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id0B9C34875CB442A3B7E33054B99FFF6F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of a corporation which does not file an annual report for any year, on its website or through such other media as determined appropriate by the Secretary in the interests of tax administration.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="idE67687120E2240F39F4E865AFE8835CE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Information described</header><text>The information described in this subsection is—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="idAA726DD28C2F44D3B96EB8BAA0AA78E9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a statement that such corporation is a United States real property holding corporation, and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id31907F7C22454B0DB74B32ADD1D7CE92"><enum>(2)</enum><text>such other information as may be required by the Secretary.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H230C6421CAE548ADB5A1797777B4FE1A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>United States real property holding corporation</header> <paragraph commented="no" id="idCA505AF4D0DA415699C7FB672FF4BF39"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of this section, a corporation is a United States real property holding corporation if—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="id95D55D27EA9445DC8C962B30756EFCA8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such corporation meets the requirements of section 897(c)(2) at any time during the applicable period, or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="idB0D523141483407F915ADE0D844DB7D2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any officer of such corporation has actual knowledge that such corporation meets such requirements at any time during the period beginning on the first day after the end of the applicable period and ending on the date the notification required under subsection (a) is made.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idAD7D9880FBE046DA9CA6249C921BBE4B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applicable period</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1), the applicable period is—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="id86E69F47F68D4E24B33A231FF995E0BC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of any notice required under subsection (a)(1), the 5-year period ending on the last day of the taxable year for which a disclosure was required to be made under such subsection,</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id9A02EDF70CC8490B9A8144BB7B24591F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of any notice required under subsection (a)(2), the 5-year period ending on the last day of the calendar year for which a disclosure was required to be made under such subsection, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id0E6AA4EED0F34BFB91BE7F34FB02C4BB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in the case of any notice required under subsection (a)(3), the 5-year period ending on the last day of the year for which a disclosure was required to be made under such subsection.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="id76E1B38BA72949DA82DCF49740229E8E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Application to publicly traded partnerships</header><text>Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, rules similar to the rules of subsection (a) shall apply to any publicly traded partnership (as defined in section 7704(b)) which—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="id67D291DC34914F418E219FB8F2C7463B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is not treated as a corporation under section 7704(a), and</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id8F225C464002427281E3B15A95492BF7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>would be a United States real property holding corporation if such publicly traded partnership were a corporation.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idE72466FE225A47E0A1393DD8DAB5DE38"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for subpart A of part III of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/61">chapter 61</external-xref> is amended by inserting before the item relating to section 6039C the following new item:</text>
					<quoted-block id="id9ea9b155-b931-4a97-8750-53199004c915" style="OLC"><toc><toc-entry idref="HA2CF9C63CD0F4491882BB4ABBC770391" level="section">Sec. 6039B. Notification of status as United States real property holding corporation.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H4DE76B13E6A846368F3D03AC1704E51B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Notification of domestic control</header><text>Subparagraph (B) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/897">section 897(h)(4)</external-xref> is amended by adding at the end the following new sentence: <quote>Notwithstanding the preceding sentence, a qualified investment entity shall not be treated as a domestically controlled qualified investment entity for any period unless such entity makes a disclosure that such entity is domestically controlled on any annual report made by such entity on or after January 1, 2016 (or, in the case of an entity which does not file an annual report for the year, on its website or through such other media as determined appropriate by the Secretary in the interests of tax administration).</quote>.</text>
			</subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H604A5A75712E4487AFD876E4E91F3EA3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Penalty for failure to make notification of status</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="idBD727D1794704382A1AC93E17E801EFE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Part I of subchapter B of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/68">chapter 68</external-xref> is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id257E8BAB8A7B4FC5A8EACAF1D36CAEF7" style="OLC"> <section commented="no" id="idA1D2F0D1DD3546C6A15DF3155317991A"><enum>6720D.</enum><header>Failure to make notification of status as United States real property holding company</header> <subsection commented="no" id="idC1B1C942040943A7BDA387B69A3F6922"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any person required to make a notification under section 6039B who—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="id19610E88994B48449D4D235C035E8631"><enum>(1)</enum><text>fails to disclose to the Secretary the information required under section 6039B(a)(1) for any taxable year,</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id7A2567051C704AC7ADD6D4A10DE780EC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>fails to substantially comply with the requirements of section 6039B(a)(2) for any calendar year, or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idACDB91459C334CC083480A18A790255A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>fails to make the disclosure required under section 6039B(a)(3) for any year,</text> </paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">shall pay a penalty with respect to each such failure in the amount determined under subsection (b).</continuation-text></subsection><subsection id="id4E9B0F259EE040E8914C2F3467C06AC1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Amount of penalty</header> <paragraph id="id36C07F1A3E8C471893A863207092847F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, the amount of the penalty under this subsection shall be $1,500,000.</text>
								</paragraph><paragraph id="id22E133720DC74D90A6E98C999BC14666"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Lower penalty for persons with gross receipts of not more than $5,000,000</header>
 <subparagraph id="idCDD2C7E21C5A45FA94A78530A3F64528"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of a person who meets the gross receipts test under subparagraph (B), the amount of the penalty under this subsection shall be $500,000.</text>
									</subparagraph><subparagraph id="id66936FE0B8434069A355E2B58434532B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Gross receipts test</header>
 <clause id="idc5619062d4a64244a379e22279699695"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A person meets the gross receipts test of this subparagraph for any calendar year if the average annual gross receipts of such person for the most recent 5 taxable years ending before such calendar year do not exceed $5,000,000.</text>
 </clause><clause id="id9eadf9fd864f4512ac790ec83c4844c0"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Certain rules made applicable</header><text>For purposes of clause (i), rules similar to the rules of paragraphs (2) and (3) of section 448(c) shall apply.</text>
										</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1BB541FF25024ACBA3C71283E2E1DE0B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Higher penalty for persons with large United States real property interests</header>
 <subparagraph id="idD1D2A7E006494FECBB385F4AFB0C6F4E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of a person described in subparagraph (C), the amount of the penalty under this subsection shall be $5,000,000.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id14777C8579684AAD94B59ED6B7C0E4D9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Intentional disregard</header><text>If a failure is due to intentional disregard, subparagraph (A) shall be applied by substituting <quote>$10,000,000</quote> for <quote>$5,000,000</quote>.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idEE77557E73584E8599AD1A7EAD20BB25"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Person described</header> <clause id="id73DB6EC6BC0A4BFCBE8D4E9D72D025C1"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A person is described in this subparagraph if such person has United States real property interests (as defined in section 897(c)) with a gross fair market value of $1,000,000,000 or more at any time during the applicable period (as defined in section 6039B(b)(2)).</text>
 </clause><clause id="id9c14ed9dcf1a4abfb7d48825b81a6250"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Aggregation rules</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, rules similar to the rules of paragraph (2) of section 448(c) shall apply.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id31AA5A10D2FD470F83EEC312863C84BE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Coordination with penalty for failure to file correct payee statements</header><text>No penalty shall be imposed under section 6722 with respect to any failure to comply with the requirements of section 6039B(a)(2) if a penalty is imposed under subsection (a)(2) with respect to such failure.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idC11846E0E05D4D8084B3299B4B1ED627"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reasonable cause waiver</header><text>No penalty shall be imposed under this section with respect to any failure if it is shown that such failure is due to reasonable cause and not to willful neglect.</text>
							</subsection><subsection id="idAF93963309144E0CBBE9E2941737551B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Inflation adjustment</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="idd31e47684c5846cbb56d950d4da1c29e"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of any failure relating to a notice required to be made in a calendar year beginning after 2016, each of the dollar amounts under subsection (b) shall be increased by such dollar amount multiplied by the cost-of-living adjustment determined under section 1(f)(3), determined by substituting <quote>calendar year 2015</quote> for <quote>calendar year 1992</quote> in subparagraph (B) thereof.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ide1cb1502cc484fcd8c3f8e72135fee51"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rounding</header><text>If any amount adjusted under paragraph (1) is not a multiple of $10,000, such amount shall be rounded to the next lowest multiple of $10,000.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idA73AF0B199F540E393CBC2B57A2CB165"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for part I of subchapter B of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/68">chapter 68</external-xref> is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text>
					<quoted-block id="id312c5cce-8ebf-458e-8efe-ed69672afe32" style="OLC"><toc><toc-entry idref="idA1D2F0D1DD3546C6A15DF3155317991A" level="section">Sec. 6720D. Failure to make notification of status as United States real property holding company.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H4C90500905064022BE0AD7E42EA834F8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective dates</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="id52438453623649DBB511636AACE9B888"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Notification</header><text>The amendments made by subsections (a) and (b) shall take effect on January 1, 2016.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idCA9395892DAA4E0CABD9ACA3E957C5DF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>The amendments made by subsection (c) shall apply to notifications required to be made on or after January 1, 2016.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H08F76290D0184C039D4AB8D26BF1FDBC"><enum>5.</enum><header>Required withholding by brokers on sales by shareholders owning a more than 5 percent
			 interest</header>
 <subsection id="H5F62A829FB964B3AA1E886FA8AF7FCAC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/1445">Section 1445(e)</external-xref> is amended by redesignating paragraph (7) as paragraph (8) and by inserting after paragraph (6) the following new paragraph:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H10763F10F0FC4AA2BC264C671CE8FF37" style="OLC">
					<paragraph id="HAF3FC67FD3A24E958EAA7C825239E127"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Broker withholding obligation on dispositions of certain interests in United States real property
			 holding corporations and publicly traded partnerships</header>
 <subparagraph id="H4FE1D006438645FD8B0160372FA3C339"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any disposition of stock of a United States real property holding corporation by a foreign person in which the disposition is made through a broker (as defined in section 6045(c)), such broker shall be required to deduct and withhold a tax equal to 15 percent of the amount realized on the disposition.</text>
						</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD447511F54444F57A21FC583F49F922C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exceptions</header>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id82796A9BFA4C400D99C943D07B59DACD"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Amounts withheld by transferee</header><text>Subparagraph (A) shall not apply to any disposition if—</text> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idD26A07F80AB94A9F8D8408C663D5D584"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the transferee is required to deduct and withhold tax under subsection (a), and</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9B6A77938B9D439E951604BFE8899184"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the transferee furnishes to the broker an affidavit, under penalty of perjury, that the transferee has deducted and withheld such tax.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAFB9ED91A4D64047936B51B3D1661973"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Interests regularly traded on an established securities market</header><text>Subparagraph (A) shall not apply to any disposition of any class of stock of a United States real property holding corporation which is regularly traded on an established securities market if the transferor, immediately prior to the disposition, holds 5 percent (10 percent in the case of a real estate investment trust) or less of such class of stock (determined under the rules of section 897(c)(6)(C)).</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HE67280D181B04A70A1A0479784CF3765"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Domestically controlled qualified investment entities and real estate investment trusts</header><text>Subparagraph (A) shall not apply to dispositions of stock of—</text> <subclause commented="no" id="id23907B93BEDF439A9372EFB1E3DCC2FA"><enum>(I)</enum><text>any domestically controlled qualified investment entity (as defined in section 897(h)(4)), or</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="idC68C9601E1924DA28FC94BCA639F6B4A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any real estate investment trust to the extent that such stock is not treated as a United States real property interest pursuant to section 897(k)(2).</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause commented="no" id="id3E8F63A9C6654DFAA161149F205193B7"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Interests in certain corporations</header><text>Subparagraph (A) shall not apply to any disposition of stock in a United States real property holding corporation if such stock is not treated as a United States real property interest by reason of section 897(c)(1)(B).</text>
							</clause><clause commented="no" id="HB14BDEC919CD464999F3E8752CD7C4CD"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Lack of broker knowledge</header>
 <subclause commented="no" id="id8686476C83A24CF1B533C93139CA3E8C"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subparagraph (A) shall not apply if the broker had no knowledge, and reasonably could not have been expected to have knowledge, that the disposition was of stock in a United States real property holding corporation.</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idC77EA441392F4D82BD3A8016229DEC08"><enum>(II)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Special rule</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subclause (I), a broker may rely on public statements made by a public company, including statements related to the status of the company as a United States real property holding corporation or as a domestically controlled qualified investment entity.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="idEBD8583912814535B3DA56E9786A1540"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Application to publicly traded partnerships</header><text>Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, rules similar to the rules of subparagraphs (A) and (B) shall apply to the disposition through a broker of any interest in a publicly traded partnership (as defined in section 7704(b)) which—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="id70E632FEF29B4E058CCFD6D45E17D0E7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is not treated as a corporation under section 7704(a), and</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="id1D79C3CF55BC4BB78A63F1B943460A48"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>would be a United States real property holding corporation if such publicly traded partnership were a corporation.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2DBE3508CC20411191E965705F5A641C"><enum>(D)</enum><header>United States real property holding corporation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>United States real property holding corporation</term> means any corporation which was a United States real property holding corporation (as defined in section 897(c)(2)) at any time during the 5-year period ending on the date of the disposition referred to in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE2284FCDE0144216AEC14501B4025B67"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/1445">Section 1445(b)(6)</external-xref> is amended by striking <quote>This paragraph</quote> and inserting <quote>Except as provided in subsection (e)(7), this paragraph</quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HEA8795C7C8104825BFD39015246802A2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to dispositions after December 31, 2015.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HF90531BD189C4AC19F8D4593246F5CB8"><enum>6.</enum><header>Interests in RICs and REITs not excluded from definition of United States real property interests</header>
 <subsection id="H71495701B0F947308BAB8F4734BD5176"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/897">Section 897(c)(1)(B)</external-xref> is amended by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of clause (i), by striking the period at the end of clause (ii)(II) and inserting <quote>, and</quote>, and by adding at the end the following new clause:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDC7FA609273B4AD9ADF7F590D146B846" style="OLC"> <clause id="H42871B529C554D02820145A57A90E743"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">neither such corporation nor any predecessor of such corporation was a regulated investment company or a real estate investment trust at any time during the shorter of the periods described in subparagraph (A)(ii).</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HCC0C4B7659994940998F2A4545E9E7A6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by this section shall apply to dispositions on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H8CE21C4CAAF84EBDAF0B55901EEF20C5"><enum>7.</enum><header>Dividends derived from RICs and REITs ineligible for deduction for United States source portion of
			 dividends from certain foreign corporations</header>
 <subsection id="HBD647FF340144769B172F2532775B792"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/245">Section 245(a)</external-xref> is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6DCFCF484AAC4F7CAB2FC7150BF5D166" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HFB32AD19BB0243D58EDF782D51B66AC5"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Dividends derived from RICs and REITs ineligible for deduction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Regulated investment companies and real estate investment trusts shall not be treated as domestic corporations for purposes of paragraph (5)(B).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H09513CC68DA84AC88A7E8AA45BAC7EF9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendment made by this section shall apply to dividends received from regulated investment companies and real estate investment trusts on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAF8497680FFA4E19A15CA322439D329F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>No inference</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing contained in this section or the amendments made by this section shall be construed to create any inference with respect to the proper treatment under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/245">section 245</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 of dividends received from regulated investment companies or real estate investment trusts before the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="id4410FC685B164F258EEC6D4FDE62BF55"><enum>8.</enum><header>Increase in continuous levy</header>
 <subsection id="idAB995DD90D08439B9B74EB037C7F4F1F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (3) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6331">section 6331(h)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking <quote>30 percent</quote> and inserting <quote>35 percent</quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF6F6F53C678449E0A058426BE40B1507"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by this section shall apply to payments made after 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement><action-date>April 14, 2015</action-date><action-desc>Read twice and placed on the calendar</action-desc></endorsement></bill>


