<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S2080 IS: Pipeline Improvement and Preventing Spills Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-09-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2080</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150924">September 24, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S380">Mr. Peters</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S284">Ms. Stabenow</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend title 49, United States Code, to enhance pipeline safety, to provide communities with
			 access to improved information concerning the equipment and operations of
			 pipeline facilities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header>
 <subsection id="id7A205FCC4D0C432296B5533E591C5F84"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Pipeline Improvement and Preventing Spills Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id9917ecfaa1954eafa42b56c16c9afcc1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text><toc><toc-entry idref="S1" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id30E819DE800447D495AD2E2B32506611" level="title">TITLE I—Information transparency</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="idd963f0f708ea46d0933a15e3e12c99c0" level="section">Sec. 101. References to title 49, United States Code.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id573ee7f55dd04e8fb1ac859830423484" level="section">Sec. 102. Notice to property owners and residents.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id7c633d65a24944fc805af05a08bd9d36" level="section">Sec. 103. Facility operation information standards.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id47977aba63e549c59db538763d77d9fa" level="section">Sec. 104. Availability of industry standards and procedures adopted in regulations by reference.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="iddb48191007844e6b95e12416720ee050" level="section">Sec. 105. Considerations for identification of high-consequence areas.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id98a85dd6ae4149f1ba0af4e6aa2e74f1" level="title">TITLE II—Pipeline spill prevention</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id44c6e352669441f5961820e2c31b9f6d" level="section">Sec. 201. Assessment of oil spill impacts and response in the Great Lakes.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id0E2DBCD6F8E94D818AD290632F42D755" level="section">Sec. 202. Great Lakes Basin water crossing study and alternatives assessment.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id076451D1D3EC4A569E41E9C7E74429D3" level="section">Sec. 203. Prohibition on transport of crude oil on Great Lakes.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="idFD0D2FD127D64115BD3C0E4A0BD2BB94" level="section">Sec. 204. Definition of worst case discharge.</toc-entry> </toc> </subsection></section><title id="id30E819DE800447D495AD2E2B32506611" style="OLC"><enum>I</enum><header>Information transparency</header> <section id="idd963f0f708ea46d0933a15e3e12c99c0"><enum>101.</enum><header>References to title 49, United States Code</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Except as otherwise expressly provided, whenever in this Act an amendment or repeal is expressed in terms of an amendment to, or a repeal of, a section or other provision, the reference shall be considered to be made to a section or other provision of title 49, United States Code.</text>
 </section><section id="id573ee7f55dd04e8fb1ac859830423484"><enum>102.</enum><header>Notice to property owners and residents</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/60102">Section 60102(c)(4)</external-xref> is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idA9C5B6513EF54D928C7598F3A15E6A32" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="id6c3a642760f2484c82516a7c21230f1b"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Notice to property owners and residents</header> <clause id="idf70cf986eeab4d74b6733933a31858d8"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this subparagraph, the Secretary shall prescribe minimum standards to require the owner or operator of a pipeline facility to notify all owners and residents of property located within 2,000 feet of a transmission line of the facility of—</text>
 <subclause id="id568d7f893d9d4d8598efc0df38226f13"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the proximity of the property to the transmission line; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="idd92f1ebae57c428f9986b16d71a6e312"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in the case of a transmission line located on private residential property, the specific location of the line on the property.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="id0f0c1af5cb0f49168cfc426555705286"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Required information</header><text>The notice under clause (i) shall include, at a minimum—</text> <subclause id="ida3f4b8439178438faa8962ac6b5e9196"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a method for electronic access to the information described in clause (i) through the Geospatial Platform or such other Federal data archive as the Secretary considers appropriate;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id674c1ebc2cba4a99b001545b60add728"><enum>(II)</enum><text>information on how to obtain a map of the pipeline system through the National Pipeline Mapping System; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id858f0184d79344bf823de44d3dd7b83a"><enum>(III)</enum><text>such other information as the Secretary considers appropriate.</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="id4338f9257c3140c98fb07f8270d2da7e"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Deadlines</header><text>The notice under clause (i) shall be provided not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this subparagraph and at least once every 3 years thereafter.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="id7c633d65a24944fc805af05a08bd9d36"><enum>103.</enum><header>Facility operation information standards</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/60102">Section 60102(d)</external-xref> is amended—</text> <paragraph id="id04F5EB9678404B43B7C5096D9103BC6D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (2), by redesignating subparagraphs (A) and (B) as clauses (i) and (ii), respectively, and indenting appropriately;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id34B273BBEE0146079A1AB43C68012D30"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (3), by redesignating subparagraphs (A) and (B) as clauses (i) and (ii), respectively, and indenting appropriately;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id2B3070B523C54226A5A0DCA1725E0212"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (5), by redesignating subparagraphs (A) through (C) as clauses (i) through (iii), respectively, and indenting appropriately;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id8F39A31DA68D4C7CB776D936431D9F7A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by designating paragraphs (1) through (6) as subparagraphs (A) through (F), respectively, and indenting appropriately; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id090050FB7E4949D8B771A15301ECE770"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>The Secretary</quote> and all that follows through <quote>shall include—</quote> and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE38E1DABAFEC4B11AFBA35E04EF8EA82" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="id721A241909CE4245BD2DD1AA77C92127"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to paragraph (2), not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Pipeline Improvement and Preventing Spills Act of 2015</short-title>, the Secretary shall prescribe minimum standards under this section requiring an operator of a pipeline facility subject to this chapter—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id4756C9B8800F4DBFA24FDA62AB1750E0"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to maintain information related to operating the facility as required by the standards prescribed under this chapter; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7938F339F800404FA29D815F947D1860"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to provide that information, including any updates and changes, to the Secretary, State regulatory officials, State and local emergency responders, and such other entities as the Secretary considers appropriate.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id4FDB2BD23BC2467B941677A89C15BAB1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Local emergency responders</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a local emergency responder, the Secretary shall provide the information described in subparagraphs (A), (B), (E), and (F) of paragraph (4) only to the extent applicable to the local district.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id6F0F40ABDA4044C6A7B654625DDA0F4F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Maintenance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall keep on file the information submitted to the Secretary under paragraphs (1) and (2).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idA200EF0873F14C798BD3506157C057AE"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The information shall include—</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></section><section id="id47977aba63e549c59db538763d77d9fa"><enum>104.</enum><header>Availability of industry standards and procedures adopted in regulations by reference</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/60102">Section 60102</external-xref> is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idD9C0D96616E247EA93FC2D002E5F5AF9" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="id7effc22ad0674d57a3fe138408aff8ca"><enum>(q)</enum><header>Availability of industry standards and procedures adopted in regulations by reference</header>
 <paragraph id="id1A965DF7FAA046E59A1FF61271AF6E76"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that industry standards and procedures adopted by reference as part of the Federal pipeline safety regulatory program under this chapter are easily available to the public free of charge.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idDC2FD165BB70480C943337F774E4D654"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application</header><text>This subsection shall apply to regulations issued before, on, or after the date of enactment of this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="iddb48191007844e6b95e12416720ee050"><enum>105.</enum><header>Considerations for identification of high-consequence areas</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/60109">Section 60109</external-xref> is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE963ACAB8D56428DB2C5FA83972A8E27" style="OLC"> <subsection id="id02b28f8c14094aaca974257ab4fe5343"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Considerations for identification of high-Consequence areas</header><text>In identifying high-consequence areas under this chapter, the Secretary shall consider—</text>
 <paragraph id="id7368b22a66434179bb9652d152087609"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the age of the pipe;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id078b5203ec40438a8e501a4c19549643"><enum>(2)</enum><text>whether the pipe at issue can be inspected using the most modern instrumented internal inspection devices;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id6a26a7c55b1646efaf1d7cb883c9d30f"><enum>(3)</enum><text>whether the pipe at issue crosses open waters of the Great Lakes; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id0f0734d860b847f085668f3f7430c252"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the type of commodity (including the type and grade of petroleum product) being transported through the pipe.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</section></title><title id="id98a85dd6ae4149f1ba0af4e6aa2e74f1"><enum>II</enum><header>Pipeline spill prevention</header>
			<section id="id44c6e352669441f5961820e2c31b9f6d"><enum>201.</enum><header>Assessment of oil spill impacts and response in the Great Lakes</header>
				<subsection id="id864b27e9a5b4461281eae530d0643bff"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Assessment</header>
 <paragraph id="idBE8E44A0BA284406A1F098E3AB453099"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Interagency Coordinating Committee on Oil Pollution Research, in consultation with the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, and the heads of other relevant agencies, shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idA9A0A64DB1BE47D18BB3C1B550B03612"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identify measures to respond to spills or leaks of oil in the Great Lakes; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idAD8BDFB3FEDE4A7C858FBA22F7AC8FB3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>conduct an assessment of the effectiveness of such measures in preventing significant or substantial harm to the public health or welfare, including fish, shellfish, wildlife, public and private property, shorelines, and beaches of the Great Lakes system.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idB5BD3056683E496A963E2E341B74EED4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The assessment required under paragraph (1) shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="id4bc00897957b448699da35c8636a3db0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>new scientific research on the impacts of a spill or leak of oil or a hazardous substance in fresh water under a wide range of meteorological and hydrological conditions, including an evaluation of the impacts of different types of petroleum, including synthetic oil from tar sands;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9ff50d8cccc8444a9ded5b92e9acc2a2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an evaluation of oil spill or leak prevention and response plans (including techniques to address submerged oil recovery and recovery in ice-choked waters) in order to identify vulnerabilities and existing threats to the Great Lakes system; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id77184fc82135495cbbcb6975212a1202"><enum>(C)</enum><text>recommendations to foster improvements to safety technologies, spill response planning, clean-up techniques, and environmental protection systems.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id09706d0592bf4056b7397ba658a0eb5d"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Interagency Coordinating Committee on Oil Pollution Research shall submit to Congress a report on the results of the assessment required under subsection (a).</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="id0E2DBCD6F8E94D818AD290632F42D755"><enum>202.</enum><header>Great Lakes Basin water crossing study and alternatives assessment</header>
 <subsection id="idF1573B38805F47A28C4F7DB7B57AA87A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Survey required</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation, working with pipeline facility owners, operators, and State governments, shall conduct a comprehensive water crossing survey of all intrastate and interstate hazardous liquid pipeline facilities that cross waterways in the Great Lakes Basin in the waters of the United States (as defined in the final rule of the Corps of Engineers and the Environmental Protection Agency entitled <quote>Clean Water Rule: Definition of <quote>Waters of the United States</quote></quote> (80 Fed. Reg. 37054; June 29, 2015)).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idB8680592AD7F4F4DA15855182ADA5229"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The survey required under subsection (a) shall—</text> <paragraph id="id6DC7963810A04BDAB28E2288BABED1A3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>produce a comprehensive map of all hazardous pipeline waterway crossings in the Great Lakes Basin, including lakes, rivers, and streams;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id355a4ebaf55b41f295ae0b7a1ae79303"><enum>(2)</enum><text>evaluate the condition and structural integrity of pipelines at each crossing, considering factors that include pipeline thickness, diameter, weld integrity, internal and external corrosion, age, pressure, control and shut-off valves, burial depths, water depths, currents, and ice cover;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id9f5dd15cc1a14cfd8d7dca8ef21ff908"><enum>(3)</enum><text>identify risks of leak and rupture resulting from pipeline integrity failures, or any other vulnerability at the pipeline water crossings;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id608f2dbee541442898a5073a5120aef2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>identify gaps in data and information that exist in the pipeline network in the Great Lakes Basin, and request information related to pipeline integrity or risks from owners and operators with facilities that cross lakes, rivers, and streams; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id2a3132cf06b54cffa04da24dc3d95dbb"><enum>(5)</enum><text>produce recommendations to prevent future leaks, ruptures, and failures that could result in damage to waterways and natural resources in the Great Lakes Basin.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5070B355666C4DEAA785F1FF03482476"><enum>(c)</enum><header>National Research Council study</header>
 <paragraph id="id699EA085E122494F9C5EC6C1FF290B23"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation shall enter into a joint agreement with the National Research Council of the National Academies of Sciences to conduct a study in connection with the survey under this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idA356DC56E3FA4FA78F28BD3DAA48EF14"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The study conducted under this subsection shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="id7F3434CE34BF4E96946EFFC7578811C9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a study covering the elements described under paragraphs (4) and (5) of subsection (b);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB863792F729C42DF9CF0C9F818F869A4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>consideration of ways in which review of facility response plans as required by the Oil Pollution Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/2701">33 U.S.C. 2701 et seq.</external-xref>) and approval of permits under section 404 of the <act-name parsable-cite="FWPCA">Federal Water Pollution Control Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1344">33 U.S.C. 1344</external-xref>) in accordance with the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>) of future and existing pipelines that cross waterways in the Great Lakes Basin would help prevent spills in the Great Lakes; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id66B1CC7417EC4475A38B82C1AEA2E39A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a risk assessment analysis for alternative transportation options to the hazardous liquid pipeline facility that crosses from the Upper Peninsula of Michigan to the Lower Peninsula of Michigan through the Straits of Mackinac, including—</text>
 <clause id="idE8DEF39553CB40218A260562F685BA7A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>no action (status quo);</text> </clause><clause id="id36BAF96619E444459A9E3D314A4BA73D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>rerouting;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id2089E127A84F4A208C92133632131158"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>decommissioning and abandoning;</text> </clause><clause id="id70023C473632427CB53560278A1BA170"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>replacing;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id403A9B5E3D5542B5AC9E7F50AE35B809"><enum>(v)</enum><text>modifying operations (such as limiting pipeline product transport to only natural gas liquids); and</text> </clause><clause id="id50A389A374B44963AA39B874BC622691"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>other transportation means.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id076451D1D3EC4A569E41E9C7E74429D3"><enum>203.</enum><header>Prohibition on transport of crude oil on Great Lakes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 108 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1258">33 U.S.C. 1258</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="id5A178538338E46B388E5C4B67CC70394"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating subsection (e) as subsection (f); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idE0B8F395D25B4DD8AEA6A4A6825868A1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting after subsection (d) the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE36F889C9E2C4A9B8719A172B3DAE429" style="OLC"> <subsection id="idc8467e2d1d97449e90bd01efea7c1176"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Prohibition on transport of crude oil on Great Lakes</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, effective beginning on the date of enactment of the <short-title>Pipeline Improvement and Preventing Spills Act of 2015</short-title>, crude oil (as that term is defined in section 2101 of title 46, United States Code) and crude oil derived from oil sands may not be transported on the Great Lakes by vessel (as that term is defined in section 3 of title 1, United States Code).</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></section><section id="idFD0D2FD127D64115BD3C0E4A0BD2BB94"><enum>204.</enum><header>Definition of worst case discharge</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 311(a)(24)(B) of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1321">33 U.S.C. 1321(a)(24)(B)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting before the semicolon at the end the following: <quote>, including conditions in which waters that may receive a discharge are covered in whole or in part by ice</quote>.</text></section></title></legis-body></bill>


