<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1131 IS: Medicare Diabetes Prevention Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1131</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150429">April 29, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S332">Mr. Franken</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S252">Ms. Collins</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S153">Mr. Grassley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S307">Mr. Brown</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S306">Mr. Menendez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S270">Mr. Schumer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S331">Mrs. Gillibrand</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to reduce the incidence of diabetes among Medicare
			 beneficiaries, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HC774F591F06E43B98F349048BBBB7F72" style="OLC">
 <section id="H2BB0B31F8343419793EE2BBF8FA0BF9F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Medicare Diabetes Prevention Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H16517FA7F84947549ED1B42102567582"><enum>2.</enum><header>Diabetes prevention under the Medicare program</header> <subsection id="H0B0A3B4ABDDA416D95E8BEDD84DBB805"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Coverage of diabetes prevention program services</header> <paragraph id="H476EFF8651DE41F6BCB90CD96E94DB22"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Coverage of services</header> <subparagraph id="HDE8257C271194127BDE5B588807C17ED"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1861(s)(2) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x(s)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <clause id="H8D9C266F3F1741E2B770812519BB9D6A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (EE), by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon at the end;</text> </clause><clause id="H12F96C25CCEA4563983A3946C6128B3D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (FF), by inserting <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon at the end; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HAADCF8FFD351470F830A3D6D4AF69E95"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1D2637CCC12542C391DD2205AF9807D7" style="OLC"> <subitem id="HC6DA027962A044C5809D39ED9FCEA60C" indent="up5"><enum>(GG)</enum><text>items and services furnished under a diabetes prevention program (as defined in subsection (iii)(1)) to an eligible diabetes prevention program individual (as defined in subsection (iii)(2));</text></subitem><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9CE4B99D96824A85AB7480419A09962E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>Section 1861 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9FB2FAE381F84A6C9B9DFB9966167ED0" other-style="archaic" style="other"><subsection id="H1E843B66F1F14BEDBD0F94E590501FD9"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Diabetes prevention program; eligible diabetes prevention program individual; qualified diabetes
 prevention program provider</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H77018F3B534F4C2FA7AFB0CF44A8E8FD"><enum>(1)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HE3C18D6DF02345B8B61BCCB6D433B35B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The term <term>diabetes prevention program</term> means a program that—</text> <clause id="H47DE77E6A0034530A97EF1192B8768C1" indent="up2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>meets the criteria described in subparagraph (B); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HDAF2AE2054AF4030B86DE2FCB431F0C9" indent="up2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is furnished by a qualified diabetes prevention program provider (as defined in paragraph (3)(A)).</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H72E31938C4E04F278E31771ED9B545D0" indent="up2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Secretary shall establish the criteria for a diabetes prevention program. Such criteria shall be in accordance with the standards under the National Diabetes Prevention Program, as established by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, and shall require that the program complies with the Federal regulations (concerning the privacy of individually identifiable health information) promulgated under section 264(c) of the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996. In establishing such criteria, the Secretary may also consider clinical evidence or other factors, such as the results of ongoing translational studies, as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H47B20613C5404052B980769089012F20" indent="up2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Items and services furnished under a diabetes prevention program may, as determined appropriate by the Secretary, be furnished—</text>
 <clause id="idC51586AD1ECA4B8E8759A0B7D7B0034C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in-person in a community setting;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idF50466E9B6F84722871265977890472B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>virtually; or</text> </clause><clause id="id7F23FE41909F4D7ABD0A39B4083340B0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>via one or more proven distance-learning modalities.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H59D1E60E069443CDBC8F729A2300E7FE" indent="up2"><enum>(D)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id0B5ABABEAFCF4879886E01778F7D30A5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The Secretary shall establish procedures under which a qualified diabetes prevention program provider may contract with a diabetes prevention program delivery partner to furnish the items and services under a diabetes prevention program. Such items and services may be furnished in one or some combination of the settings described in clauses (i) through (iii) of subparagraph (C).</text>
 </clause><clause id="id65F5E9C13EA44ED4B2C3B355B69CCCBB" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>diabetes prevention program delivery partner</term> means an entity, including non-profit organizations, public and private hospitals, State and local departments of public health, Federally qualified health centers, and any other entity the Secretary determines appropriate, that meets criteria established by the Secretary. Such criteria shall be in accordance with the standards under the National Diabetes Prevention Program, as established by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. In establishing such criteria, the Secretary may also consider other factors or clinical evidence as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD1AC92E62C5B4D89BB258E467E5BF3D5" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HDAD01CFE5E1C484AB9F6D7178EF835DC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The term <term>eligible diabetes prevention program individual</term> means an individual at risk for diabetes (as defined in subsection (yy)(2)) who would benefit from items and services under a diabetes prevention program, as determined based on criteria established by the Secretary.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H52D862C36A09427097C7ED3E013611E1" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The criteria established under subparagraph (A) shall be in accordance with the standards under the National Diabetes Prevention Program, as established by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. In establishing such criteria, the Secretary may also consider other factors or clinical evidence as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H293334E039194846AD42149FC398EBC0" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H3223B2C17A28432BAF02F26D6DB8BB06"><enum>(A)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H28F5089A260A44D5AB7599730E86AC38"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The term <term>qualified diabetes prevention program provider</term> means any entity, including a Federally qualified health center, that the Secretary determines—</text> <subclause id="H8EA97B197B99400CA0AA8975FFD8C52A" indent="up2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is appropriate to furnish items and services under a diabetes prevention program; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H5C5431F460AB4A6D85A68A1963E89736" indent="up2"><enum>(II)</enum><text>meets criteria established by the Secretary, in consultation with the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H599B6A50600A4D01B8549A9EDF82CCD7" indent="up2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A qualified diabetes prevention program provider may be, as determined appropriate by the Secretary, a supplier (as defined in subsection (d)), a provider of services (as defined in subsection (u)), a health insurance or services company, a community-based organization, or any other appropriate entity.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4A39CA49526B4C6CB10B18E96747BA68" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A qualified diabetes prevention program provider shall—</text> <clause id="H0DE1071BF2314405ACC5969859897C79"><enum>(i)</enum><text>furnish the items and services under the diabetes prevention program through a delivery partner (pursuant to paragraph (1)(D)) unless no such delivery partner is available;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8F70982FCD694162B89418914EA7C557"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>manage, track, and verify the outcomes of a diabetes prevention program (including attendance and observed weight loss of participating individuals) through defined systems which do not rely on data self-reported by participating individuals, including outcomes of programs furnished under contract with a diabetes prevention program delivery partner;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD4241CB40ACC473AA542A5FEE955459B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>implement business processes to manage program workflow, such as eligibility, reporting, claims billing, class scheduling, and enrollment;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4C19612143FD488EBD3FCC55B8D1BC6A"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>manage and verify billing accuracy and beneficiary eligibility (as described in paragraph (2));</text> </clause><clause id="HAA9E382D263F4DDCB1A5CCEA7C08183A"><enum>(v)</enum><text>comply with applicable laws and regulations and ensure such compliance by a diabetes prevention program delivery partner;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA3FF86AEE05F4F9AA8CC2DC6ADD93B83"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>perform various forms of engagement with, and outreach to, eligible diabetes prevention program individuals, including those participating in programs furnished under contract with a diabetes prevention program delivery partner;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H58B1E83FF0C64E208727290502E6B17B"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>comply with all program integrity requirements as established by the Secretary; and</text> </clause><clause id="H1289EEE698A34DDF98D980A0837A7E3F"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>perform such other functions as established by the Secretary.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6B68D07F37AE4582929002A1591755BD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Amount of payment</header><text>Section 1833(a)(1) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395l">42 U.S.C. 1395l(a)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="HD996502104A4465BA6BDF6CAFEEF7825"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and (Z)</quote> and inserting <quote>(Z)</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0874C8917BF243C2A5DD27944C8BA3E9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting before the semicolon at the end the following: <quote>, and (AA) with respect to items and services furnished under a diabetes prevention program (as defined in section 1861(iii)(1)), the amount paid shall be 100 percent of (i) except as provided in clause (ii), the lesser of the actual charge for the items and services or the amount determined under the fee schedule that applies to such items and services under this part, as determined by the Secretary, and (ii) in the case of such items and services that are covered OPD services (as defined in subsection (t)(1)(B)), the amount determined under subsection (t)</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H289DB825F0F2459190CC5B8A7AD0C0B4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Waiver of application of deductible</header><text>The first sentence of section 1833(b) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395l">42 U.S.C. 1395l(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="HED3CB61D19854F00B60D16BBEE0C8E2C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and</quote> before <quote>(10)</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB787910A0BC049658E70B64B49989295"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting before the period the following: <quote>, and (11) such deductible shall not apply with respect to items and services under a diabetes prevention program (as defined in section 1861(iii)(1))</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H86BB21B1E86A499187F9994276919361"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Assignment of claims</header><text>Section 1842(b)(18)(C) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395u">42 U.S.C. 1395u(b)(18)(C)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new clause:</text>
					<quoted-block act-name="Social" id="HDBA54CC6C55E4C3FA241FC987B28C00F" style="OLC">
 <clause commented="no" id="H89EE1BD88BC540808DA61B9C1A77CBF0" indent="up2"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>A qualified diabetes prevention program provider (as defined in section 1861(iii)(3)(A)).</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph id="H41F0377ACC804189B3AFA9689DC39CC6"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Exclusion of items and services under a diabetes prevention program from skilled nursing facility prospective payment system</header><text>Section 1888(e)(2)(A)(ii) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395yy">42 U.S.C. 1395yy(e)(2)(A)(ii)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>items and services under a diabetes prevention program (as defined in section 1861(iii)(1)),</quote> after <quote>qualified psychologist services,</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB42738E0D4BF480EA2B858996189B0F4"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Inclusion in Federally qualified health center services</header><text>Section 1861(aa)(3) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x(aa)(3)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H92F3CD246A7D434C855D24ACB3DE51FA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H770D1354019241B1A8A0E64587DA4F01"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking the comma at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB2D10E299E8E464098A5FDCA93D82344"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding after subparagraph (B) the following new subparagraph:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0C87D856BB6F404187F3CADFFD963903" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H032A81F168EB45D784DD672F2C921036" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>items and services under a diabetes prevention program (as defined in section 1861(iii)(1)),</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H90CDE12A700C4C989C05FFD8B407AF3F"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Special consideration for the dual eligible population</header><text>In implementing the amendments made by this subsection, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall give special consideration to the needs of individuals who are dually eligible for benefits under the Medicare and Medicaid programs.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HA1A87B3CA1B84415B9CA590287F4B88C"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Evaluation and report to congress</header>
 <subparagraph id="HCB1650F8D55D483A9C5E970D33FF2E39"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall conduct an evaluation on the coverage of items and services under a diabetes prevention program under the Medicare program, as added by the amendments made by this subsection. Such evaluation shall include an analysis of—</text>
 <clause id="HD1DC9BAD7EFC4690BD36D772023255DF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the impact of the provision of such coverage on Medicare beneficiaries, including the impact on various populations, such as individuals who are dually eligible for benefits under the Medicare and Medicaid programs and individuals living in rural or medically underserved areas, and the impact of the provision of such coverage on health disparities;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H80E7289B4047444485F3085F244BFB21"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the rate at which physicians refer eligible diabetes prevention program individuals to diabetes prevention programs under the Medicare program;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3AE046FA51CA415AA7BD2CA13BAB6683"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Medicare beneficiary participation levels in diabetes prevention programs under the Medicare program, including program completion rates, and the awareness of Medicare beneficiaries of the benefit;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF3EA4F1C9D524CF0BD4E2AF36F297AA1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the health outcomes resulting from completion of a diabetes prevention program under the Medicare program, including any measurable variations in outcome between the program settings described in clauses (i) through (iii) of section 1861(iii)(1)(C) of the Social Security Act, as added by paragraph (1);</text>
 </clause><clause id="H84ADD123526C40A98F093C8FB61A4E17"><enum>(v)</enum><text>program integrity protections important to diabetes prevention programs under the Medicare program; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8201D173C5AB4395B4BF4EE0C4CA82FC"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>other areas determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H888ADADCC18B418BBEDB69D83E702B90"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than January 1, 2021, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall submit to Congress a report on the evaluation conducted under subparagraph (A), together with recommendations for such legislation and administrative actions as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7E9AFE7F6AEF4BC6AA9E7281EB35FC4F"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by paragraphs (1) through (6) shall apply with respect to services furnished on or after January 1, 2017.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H002B84D367D14224BC79E645009B1C13"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Inclusion of referral rates to diabetes prevention programs in Medicare quality
 reporting requirements</header><text>Section 1848(k)(2)(C)(i) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-4">42 U.S.C. 1395w–4(k)(2)(C)(i)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new sentence: <quote>For purposes of reporting data on quality measures for covered professional services furnished during 2020 and each subsequent year, the quality measures specified under this paragraph shall include a measure with respect to referrals of eligible diabetes prevention program individuals (as defined in paragraph (2) of section 1861(iii)) to diabetes prevention programs (as defined in paragraph (1) of such section).</quote>.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HDC3940A2B41F434BB6FD26F4CF1B39B8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Inclusion of diabetes risk assessment in medicare personalized prevention plan</header>
 <paragraph id="HC39D0554EBB14523AAD614363514DBB1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1861(hhh)(2)(C) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x(hhh)(2)(C)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting before the period at the end the following: <quote>, and an assessment of whether the individual is an individual at risk for diabetes (as defined in subsection (yy)(2))</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAB4C9AA7155E4BDCAA6E9AE3D4928108"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this subsection shall apply to personalized prevention plans created or updated on or after January 1, 2017.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H8DD5BE2901F740B6A8729F12760DD3EA"><enum>3.</enum><header>Findings; sense of the Senate regarding diabetes prevention under the Medicaid
			 program</header>
 <subsection id="H6BBC2DFC2D4F4876A11DA2F8E8B0F12D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text> <paragraph id="HB51A3414E0924A43BBD3FABCEF03EA74"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The prevalence and cost of diabetes is a significant concern for State Medicaid programs. By 2021, the Medicaid program is expected to cover 13,000,000 people with diabetes and about 9,000,000 people who may have pre-diabetes. By 2021, States will spend an estimated $83,000,000,000 on individuals with diabetes or pre-diabetes.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3955C6E998114183BF65A0890EBBD868"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The National Diabetes Prevention Program, as established by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, has been proven to reduce the onset of diabetes in at-risk adults by 58 percent, using a cost-effective, community-based intervention.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF221FB10444D49A492A86131351F89EB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of the Senate</header><text>It is the sense of the Senate that the National Diabetes Prevention Program presents an opportunity for States to reduce the incidence of diabetes among individuals enrolled in their Medicaid programs.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


