<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1810 IS: No Exemption for Washington from Obamacare Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 1810</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150721">July 21, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S299">Mr. Vitter</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S355">Mr. Cruz</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To apply the provisions of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act to
			 Congressional members and members of the executive branch.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No Exemption for Washington from Obamacare Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="id76288F637C3840FCA2D59D516B8F1543" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Health insurance
			 coverage for certain Congressional members and members of the executive
			 branch</header>
 <subsection id="idE735D60B039A4F5D940D7F4287AC9C24"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 1312(d)(3)(D) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18032">42 U.S.C. 18032(d)(3)(D)</external-xref>), Members of Congress, the President, Vice President, and all other political appointees shall purchase health insurance coverage through a health exchange established under such Act and shall receive no Federal subsidy or contribution to the costs of such coverage that is not also otherwise available to individuals at a similar income level.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idB1C04C2FFB364464A8EC74A2B4AE07CB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> <paragraph id="id289E1DFA9021488DA3ABBE24AB10888D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Member of Congress</header><text>The term <term>Member of Congress</term> shall have the meaning given such term in section 1312(d)(3)(D)(ii)(I) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18032">42 U.S.C. 18032(d)(3)(D)(ii)(I)</external-xref>).</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="idF83FDF34B4E34AB894E3AE2016392EDB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Political
 appointee</header><text>The term <term>political appointee</term> means any individual who—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idC835E309D78D4C2F97C6E0CA2E5B6441"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is employed in a position described under sections 5312 through 5316 of title 5, United States Code (relating to the Executive Schedule);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idFC159DC0DB9348C4864D1EC0C485E641"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is a limited term appointee, limited emergency appointee, or noncareer appointee in the Senior Executive Service, as defined under paragraphs (5), (6), and (7), respectively, of section 3132(a) of title 5, United States Code;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2B28CADEC9CA4B72A329AF5E3265EFD5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is employed in a position in the executive branch of the Government of a confidential or policy-determining character under schedule C of subpart C of part 213 of title 5 of the Code of Federal Regulations; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbb4cc65fe8034b479d2ca0756949ab9a"><enum>(D)</enum><text>is employed in or under the Executive Office of the President in a position that is excluded from the competitive service by reason of its confidential, policy-determining, policy-making, or policy-advocating character.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


