<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S553 IS: End Modern Slavery Initiative Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 553</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150224">February 24, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S310">Mr. Corker</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S306">Mr. Menendez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S350">Mr. Rubio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S340">Ms. Ayotte</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S197">Mr. McCain</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S289">Mr. Alexander</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S349">Mr. Portman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S339">Mr. Kirk</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S308">Mr. Cardin</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To marshal resources to undertake a concerted, transformative effort that seeks to bring an end to
			 modern slavery, and for other purposes. </official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>End Modern Slavery Initiative Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </section><section id="id78f51fc458cc44bd94c539fcc91744a4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text> <paragraph id="id951de727aca047a3a3d993fdf5ba6490"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the United States has a long history of domestic and international engagement in preventing and responding to modern slavery;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idcd6ee995f98543f2bd5457e8020cde82"><enum>(2)</enum><text>modern slavery involves extensive criminal activity and demands the full attention and commitment of the United States;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idf31a10665ebf44c29c5825d85d38c694"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the United States Government should continue to coordinate across departments and agencies to prevent and respond to this heinous activity that involves over 21,000,000 people worldwide through sustained investment in integrated, interagency anti-trafficking initiatives;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id5b84f28df8994c568bb6c734f0d729d1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>while United States Government efforts continue to address many facets of modern slavery, there is an urgent need today for international public and private cooperation to increase resources available to programs that can make a measureable impact in reducing the prevalence of modern slavery by building the capacity of foreign governments to sustainably deter perpetrators of modern slavery through—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id2c1179e195344f13979e9df0943b093f"><enum>(A)</enum><text>establishing and enforcing the rule of law to hold perpetrators of modern slavery accountable, including—</text>
 <clause id="id0a1072e96dfd4ede8512d6affe4febe4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>those who enslave children and adults in the sex trade; and</text> </clause><clause id="id0a45c4e530cc425f82f6840f75f556e3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>those who enslave through forced labor and abusive labor recruitment practices and fees;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfec02d6cb5454cbf845cd3a704a244e3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>promoting justice for victims of modern slavery;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide6d0381f76994e5caa75661e09d7d824"><enum>(C)</enum><text>restoring and protecting survivors of modern slavery; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id65c14c38186741f49cfde2c9bfef3e32"><enum>(D)</enum><text>building partnerships between governments, civil society organizations, private sector entities and individuals, and survivors to seek to bring an end to modern slavery; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idaff8ca91bd824ccd9bd34410e0f4f382"><enum>(5)</enum><text>countries that fall within the first and second tiers of the United States Department of State’s annual Trafficking in Persons report could qualify as partner countries for the purposes of this Act, and many countries that fall within the Tier 2 watch list may also qualify, and therefore should be eligible for funding as partner countries under this Act, along with key jurisdictions of other countries, such as Tier 3 countries.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="id7e583a80e9d246d994d73a159da285c2"><enum>3.</enum><header>Policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States Government—</text> <paragraph id="id4e61cb2b8def44b68ab0c78d5a70221d"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to marshal resources to seek to bring to an end modern slavery through the provision of matching funds to a private grant-making institution, in partnership with private donors and other governments, that selects and supports innovative strategies with the aim of verifiably and sustainably reducing the prevalence of modern slavery by 50 percent in targeted populations within partner countries (or jurisdictions thereof) with a high prevalence of modern slavery;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id37c0e07c1198475b984835011cf8025a"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to allow such a private grant-making institution the flexibility to work in jurisdictions of other countries, where those jurisdictions have demonstrated the type of commitment and capabilities otherwise required of partner countries; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id390afa7158764d9dafb92b9081f4956b"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to engage other countries with a high prevalence of modern slavery through the full range of United States Government foreign assistance programs in order to help those countries become eligible as partner countries for the purposes of receiving additional assistance under the End Modern Slavery Initiative established by this Act.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="id5a719ba91a694fbcb71172ef51ca7a95"><enum>4.</enum><header>The end modern slavery initiative foundation</header>
 <subsection id="id1e431b55ded643b68672acd47bb379ac"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, there shall be established and incorporated under the laws of the District of Columbia an independent, private nonprofit corporation to be known as <quote>End Modern Slavery Initiative Foundation</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id5b736d100c7e432fa12c31a8ecc26ab2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of the End Modern Slavery Initiative Foundation shall be to work collaboratively with government, civil society, and private institutions in partner countries and key jurisdictions of other countries with a high prevalence of modern slavery to identify and fund successful strategies to combat modern slavery.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id0205f7123a344a07865cbe436a714d15"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Status of Foundation</header><text>The End Modern Slavery Initiative Foundation shall not be an agency or establishment of the United States Government.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id86de3fd126be4f6c95e62f19f650817d"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Status of board and officers and employees</header><text>The members of the Board of Directors of the End Modern Slavery Initiative Foundation shall not, by reason of such membership, be officers or employees of the United States, and the officers or employees of the End Modern Slavery Initiative Foundation shall not be officers or employees of the United States.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id4de22adf24e540b3ab28bcf687b95785"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Tax status eligibility</header><text>The End Modern Slavery Initiative Foundation shall be eligible to be treated as an organization described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 which is exempt from taxation under section 501(a) of such code and, if such treatment is conferred in accordance with the provisions of such code, shall be subject to all provisions of such code relevant to the conduct of organizations exempt from taxation.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id00ec37858158471f8256343065eac145"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>The End Modern Slavery Initiative Foundation shall seek to obtain a minimum of $1,500,000,000 in aggregate funding from foreign governments and private sector organizations and individuals over an initial seven year period, leveraging United States Government grants provided to the Foundation as seed funding and to complement the comprehensive foreign assistance programs of the United States Government.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id69181b5628a24519bbfd364ab5a89016"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Additional private sector funding plan</header><text>The Board of Directors shall, not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, submit to the appropriate congressional committees a plan to raise an additional $500,000,000 in commitments from private sector entities to fully fund the End Modern Slavery Initiative Foundation.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idbf56a983a93040e49d1755c2dd1c1a58"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Authorization for the receipt of funds</header><text>The End Modern Slavery Initiative Foundation may accept and utilize, consistent with the policies, priorities, and purposes of this Act, any gift, donation, bequest, or devise of real or personal property from any government or private sector individual or organization, including the provision of voluntary services or in-kind services or products.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="id64d855a341a24ed5915ce327c5c33127"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Governance</header>
				<paragraph id="id9bbac283d65a4c2e97d120e7bb4921a0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Board of directors</header>
 <subparagraph id="idd2318bc97cff4f3ca6278956fbdb5ef1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The End Modern Slavery Initiative Foundation shall be overseen by a Board of Directors—</text> <clause id="id7e21de94f4ad4203943986417948285b"><enum>(i)</enum><text>which shall include individuals with recognized relevant professional expertise and a survivor of modern slavery; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id45f05c32495948d8b32879e3b6439e44"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>not more than 11 of whom will be voting members.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id67fd5ada90a540ad8b974b6c16c1002c"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Non-voting advisory directors</header><text>The voting directors of the Board may appoint, at their discretion, non-voting advisory directors, which may include a representative of the Secretary of State such as the Ambassador-at-Large and Director of the Office to Monitor and Combat Trafficking in Persons.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1941fad2285c4fe3b52e9805ff280462"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Decisions of the board of directors</header><text>Decisions of the Board of Directors shall be made by a simple majority vote of voting directors present.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2a7281baad124e40b3cdce2d4f198222"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text>In addition to other specific responsibilities provided for in this Act, the voting directors of the Board of Directors shall—</text>
 <clause id="id3fb68b6bc8004a9087e81723d7ed0af3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>oversee the monitoring and evaluation of the End Modern Slavery Initiative Foundation efforts and supported projects; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idf15ca70d88dd4f4883a4d651e418b99d"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>make prioritized program funding decisions.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idaaef7cc9fcd943a1a46763dfcec788b7"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Quorum of the board of directors</header><text>In order to take official action, the Board shall require a quorum composed of a majority of its voting directors.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idde98c7b7e0d14027b6be145d0452e433"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Additional responsibilities of the board of directors</header><text>The Board of Directors shall—</text> <clause id="id0fe4deeb56f8478c921b83fe76bae658"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by majority vote of voting directors delegate relevant authorities to the Chief Executive Officer appointed pursuant to paragraph (2)(A) concerning agreements made with governments or private sector individuals or organizations, programmatic and monitoring and evaluation strategies of the End Modern Slavery Initiative Foundation, and other matters related to the End Modern Slavery Initiative Foundation, consistent with the policies, priorities, and purposes of this Act; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id1e1c6f875ea34fc7a47bd793186f991d"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>reserve the right of review and approval of major agreements as appropriate.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id84763a27721e4b829473b7d0eb44b175"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Long-term strategy review, approval, and submission</header><text>Not later than five years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Board of Directors shall review, approve, and submit to governments, entities, or individuals providing funding to the End Modern Slavery Initiative Foundation, as well as the appropriate congressional committees, the strategy required to be developed pursuant to paragraph (2)(D).</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="iddb7ac6dffa024c60a20b8a5ad5452865"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Chief executive officer</header>
 <subparagraph id="id228d78adc52440879e543b00c1a36ba6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The day-to-day operations of the End Modern Slavery Initiative Foundation shall be run by a Chief Executive Officer, who shall be a United States citizen and shall be employed at the exclusive discretion of the Board of Directors.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id42242341837c4e19bd95bf8779892bfd"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Authority of the chief executive officer</header><text>The Chief Executive Officer of the End Modern Slavery Initiative Foundation shall be authorized to take all actions authorized by the Board of Directors, consistent with the policies, priorities, and purposes of this Act, including the hiring and termination of any employees of the End Modern Slavery Initiative Foundation.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id19e3f184bb434106ac1bce008378b8a1"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Responsibilities of the chief executive officer</header><text>The Chief Executive Officer shall be responsible for—</text> <clause id="id79d00acd72a5459c9a96e863bda2427a"><enum>(i)</enum><text>ensuring matching funding requirements pursuant to this Act are met;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id1010f77bae0241eabc720c8dc2fd1d61"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ensuring that foreign government and private sector funding commitments are fully realized;</text> </clause><clause id="id0f0bf312bfe9404aad57d4abf8d55782"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>developing all necessary strategies and agreements for the End Modern Slavery Initiative Foundation;</text>
 </clause><clause id="ida15b00b0bc1346a3a1b60c680bc013e2"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>identifying funding requirements;</text> </clause><clause id="id3fd82bcdc8344d5dafd2f509a23af402"><enum>(v)</enum><text>preparing and presenting to the Board of Directors for approval a portfolio of priority projects to be funded;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id9f65db9cf0dd486db7866be2e86fa80f"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>administering the End Modern Slavery Initiative Foundation procurement processes;</text> </clause><clause id="idb4487815ba2b4c4484c0f4493375f92e"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>developing reliable baseline data and ensuring that such data and the process of obtaining such data are subject to outside, independent audits;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id5a3ace01a45449f4ab89a9b1d8bf7480"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>developing and administering the monitoring and evaluation of funded programs;</text> </clause><clause id="id0f937b9bd2ce40fb9b0f5d6db14affde"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>complying with all relevant auditing, accounting, taxation, and legal requirements;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id878efe4506394e0c870646b2ad510601"><enum>(x)</enum><text>preparing, publicly publishing, and submitting to each government, private individual, or corporation that has contributed funds an annual report of approximately 50 pages with appropriate annexes on the activities and results of the End Modern Slavery Initiative Foundation;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idaf14f56cddbb47fca57760a36012f201"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>ensuring the sharing, among appropriate governmental and nongovernmental partners and interested parties in the global anti-slavery community, of corporate and nonprofit best practices, including those developed or identified by the End Modern Slavery Initiative Foundation or others through its supported programs;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id39f5be3bd48048d68b2751297741f155"><enum>(xii)</enum><text>working to encourage partner countries to hold accountable those who enslave children and adults in the sex trade;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id4e262fae21514c5799cd4d9c38da8d9c"><enum>(xiii)</enum><text>working to develop best practices to help ensure that corporate supply chains do not involve the use of victims of modern slavery, including ending forced labor and addressing the role of abusive labor recruitment practices and fees; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id92b281b6981a4bf6b277d8471ff235c9"><enum>(xiv)</enum><text>undertaking consultations, as the Chief Executive Officer deems necessary or is directed by the Board of Directors, with appropriate governmental and nongovernmental partners with respect to End Modern Slavery Initiative Foundation strategies, programs, and projects.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idadcf1d99338647aaa0c6b8797f3988ab"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Long-term strategy development and consultations</header><text>Not later than four years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Chief Executive Officer, in consultation with the Board of Directors, shall initiate discussions with appropriate governmental and nongovernmental partners and begin development of a strategy that seeks to end modern slavery globally based on empirical evidence and best practices identified by the End Modern Slavery Initiative Foundation, including funding requirements to fully implement such a strategy.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="iddb85971e1ca94e749ccf63fef9845750"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Limitations and prohibitions</header>
 <paragraph id="id89d849c73d4e4de1bd6cc5c48576a3cb"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Issuance of stock and dividends</header><text>The End Modern Slavery Initiative Foundation may not issue any shares of stock or declare or pay dividends.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="id22eaac5f99f8473f9567d0804668a145"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conflicts of interest</header>
 <subparagraph id="id95cce7fac1324230b419f0c22d72a008"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Assets</header><text>No part of the assets of the End Modern Slavery Initiative Foundation shall inure to the benefit of any member of the Board of Directors, any officer or employee of the End Slavery Initiative Foundation, or any other individual, except as reasonable salary or compensation for services for officers and employees, reasonable reimbursement for expenses incurred in the course of such employment, or for other individuals, as specific beneficiaries of services provided pursuant to supported projects.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd7029b2bd0eb41139a133abc17ad8199"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Relationship to grantees</header><text>No voting director of the Board of Directors may be a member of the board of directors or an officer, employee, or consultant to, any grantee of the End Modern Slavery Initiative Foundation.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idec2072d1ada749d480e7c2292a8b1c72"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Compensation</header><text>No director of the Board of Directors may receive compensation for service on the Board of Directors, other than reasonable reimbursement for expenses incurred in the course of such service.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idf836d2f5f6e1408fae59e4bfce04dbdc"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Lobbying restriction</header><text>Any Federal funds provided to the End Modern Slavery Initiative Foundation or any other nonprofit organization pursuant to the authorization of funding provided under this Act shall be subject to the restrictions and prohibitions of section 1352 of title 31, United States Code.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id100530bfd3924f44a95709593e80f650"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Recordkeeping, auditing, oversight, and reporting requirements</header>
 <paragraph id="id0103cb149efe40e5ad5d5104dd1ab506"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The End Modern Slavery Initiative Foundation shall be subject to the same auditing, recordkeeping, and reporting obligations as required pursuant to subsections (e), (f), (g), and (i) of section 504 of the National Endowment for Democracy Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/4413">22 U.S.C. 4413</external-xref>).</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="ida6498c4076fa4245b69d670cf94ef46e"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Comptroller general audit authority</header>
 <subparagraph id="idafbd54098850455a8af347b1946cbd14"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Comptroller General of the United States may evaluate the financial transactions of the End Slavery Initiative Foundation as well as the programs or activities the End Slavery Initiative Foundation carries out pursuant to this Act.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7b2ef42d7f4a4a5f9f177f553fa7a1ac"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Access to records</header><text>The End Slavery Initiative Foundation shall provide the Comptroller General, or his duly authorized representatives, access to such records as the Comptroller General determines necessary to conduct evaluations authorized by this Act.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ide886cc7001804cbbb556d5e519280fa0"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to make the End Modern Slavery Initiative Foundation an agency or establishment of the United States Government or to make the members of the Board of Directors of the End Slavery Initiative Foundation, or the officers or employees of the End Slavery Initiative, officers or employees of the United States.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="id90995e96f5194b7bafc498b172aa482d"><enum>5.</enum><header>Authorization for grants to end modern slavery</header>
 <subsection id="idc10df09fe63d4f63bd4de4382a6795dc"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grant authorization</header><text>The Secretary of State is authorized, subject to the availability of appropriations and on an annual basis, to make grants of funding for purposes of this Act in the amounts authorized in subsection (b) to the End Modern Slavery Initiative Foundation or other nonprofit organization that—</text>
 <paragraph id="id324f50347feb4971a4cf4fb0f32d391b"><enum>(1)</enum><text>funds programs and projects in partner countries and key jurisdictions of other countries in order to seek to end modern slavery, including by funding programs and projects that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="iddb5cd9731e9341dbbabae7e7b607f926"><enum>(A)</enum><text>contribute to the freeing and sustainable recovery of victims of modern slavery;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc60f8bd22a524f07a43c17db72dabb10"><enum>(B)</enum><text>prevent individuals from being subject to modern slavery; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3204f0f45fc8466e8c39bdd9256c43e6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>enforce laws that punish both individuals and corporate entities that engage in modern slavery; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="iddb9b0513cfc94031aedd96e39808b1c6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>seeks to receive foreign government contributions in a ratio of two-to-one and private sector contributions in a ratio of three-to-one to United States Government funding.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id3d5cf8a8ff5b48f0b58212851a128770"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations for fiscal years 2015 through 2022</header><text>In addition to such sums as may otherwise be available for such purposes, there is authorized to be appropriated to the Department of State for the purpose of making the grants authorized under subsection (a)—</text>
 <paragraph id="id66d9e69d3a4543ed91aec60a16689346"><enum>(1)</enum><text>for fiscal year 2015, $1,000,000; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id2b95f48a1b59435aa2549665a8177eee"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for each fiscal year from 2016 through 2022, $35,714,285.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id7526c07a9b124873832a08d3bff5aa9d"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conditions for united states government funding</header>
 <paragraph id="id0523246f93824f45b51dbbd1a8523b86"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Matching government funding</header><text>Except as provided under paragraphs (4) and (5), funding provided pursuant to grants authorized under subsection (a) shall only be available for expenditure by the grantee during a fiscal year if matching funding equal to twice the total amount of such funding has been obtained from one or more other governments in such fiscal year.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id612e597bb5174c5a9ff4050ae7afbd3a"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Matching private sector funding</header><text>Except as provided under paragraphs (4) and (5), funding provided pursuant to grants authorized under subsection (a) shall only be available for expenditure by the grantee during a fiscal year if matching funding equal to the total amount of such funding has been obtained from private sector entities in such fiscal year.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idd5008708d45b4223a6675a93a8cf4431"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitation on administrative costs</header><text>Funding provided pursuant to the grants authorized under subsection (a) shall only be available for expenditure by the grantee for a fiscal year in which the prior fiscal year administrative costs are no more than 10 percent of modified total direct costs or otherwise meet the administrative cost requirements of section 200.414 of title 2, Code of Federal Regulations.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="idc727f2978f604fa096a4becfebf50244"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Initial exemption</header>
 <subparagraph id="idd95270fe973a465e8825f04392c0bde3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding the matching funding requirement in paragraphs (1) and (2), funding provided pursuant to grants authorized under subsection (a) shall be available for expenditure by a grantee in fiscal years 2015 and 2016.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7347c874aea241bea4ac10cfa2476ae7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Additional matching requirement</header><text>To the extent that matching funding is not obtained in fiscal years 2015 or 2016, as generally required by paragraphs (1) and (2), the grantee must obtain such funding no later than September 30, 2018.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7a5e2de506d741d9a31ab40d83fe6dba"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Limitation on funding</header><text>No funding provided pursuant to grants authorized under subsection (a) shall be available for expenditure by the grantee during any fiscal year after 2018 until the requirement in subparagraph (B) is met.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id8e94c25fb9e640ecabba1c650bee7aaf"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Additional exemptions</header>
 <subparagraph id="idc6a9bb6b112f4c72a6f23d93504cac66"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If during any fiscal year the matching requirement described in paragraph (1) or (2) is not achieved, the Secretary of State may provide a one-year exemption from fulfillment of such requirement provided that—</text>
 <clause id="ide814ce0f255f4ff1b08d171a5fa9cb12"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a plan is in place to make up the funding shortfall during the next fiscal year and to meet the matching requirements in future years;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idab90718414b24bbeaec62159dc3bb1b1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the plan is submitted to the appropriate congressional committees; and</text> </clause><clause id="id9b8498e4c59341b7baf6a2d2862480b5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the grantee has obtained matching funding, in the proportion required by such paragraphs, for the total amount of any prior year shortfalls.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id33ada6e60b0d400aa16dbdfa4125f0fd"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitation on funding</header><text>During an exemption provided pursuant to subparagraph (A), funding provided pursuant to grants authorized under subsection (a) shall only be available for expenditure by the grantee during a fiscal year in an amount that is equal in proportion to the proportion of matching funds secured in accordance with paragraphs (1) and (2).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id23a692a79f384c078e3a50881a74d989"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Limited quantity</header><text>The Secretary of State may provide no more than a total of two exemptions pursuant to subparagraph (A) during fiscal years 2017 through 2022.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id705830306f4b44cab21f1202c4f5ba54"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Availability of additional funds</header><text>In fiscal years in which the grantee obtains matching funding to address a shortfall of funding required by paragraph (1) or (2) from a prior year, the funds previously restricted as a result of such shortfall shall be available for expenditure by the grantee in such later fiscal year in an amount that is equal in proportion, pursuant to such paragraphs, to the amount obtained.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idb1c3ef3becf64d48b740915dee172912"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Funding additional to existing authorizations</header><text>Amounts authorized by this section are in addition to funds otherwise authorized to be appropriated for combatting trafficking in persons, forced labor, or related programs.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0a4d7185a579420c9295fc60ecf5a076"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Duration of funding</header><text>Funds appropriated pursuant to subsection (b) shall remain available until expended subject to the conditions on such funds described in subsection (c).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idc405685221374a8f87d57bbc682cd49a"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Implementation of policies, priorities, and purposes</header><text>No funds received pursuant to the provisions of this section may be obligated or expended by the Secretary of State or the End Modern Slavery Initiative Foundation or other nonprofit organization except to the extent that such obligation and expenditure is consistent with the policies, priorities, and purposes of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="id58120e4235354e4aa6aba83811ddcbad"><enum>6.</enum><header>Additional support from member governments</header>
 <subsection id="id0fb8373e79324a7caeadcf975c50b747"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The United States Government shall seek, and shall encourage other foreign governments providing support to the End Modern Slavery Initiative Foundation, consistent with the individual priorities and policies of such governments, to provide additional support for projects in partner countries and key jurisdictions of other countries supported by the End Modern Slavery Initiative Foundation through the commitment of new resources, or the redirection of existing resources, including funding and personnel as appropriate, to efforts that are consistent with the policies, priorities, and purposes of this Act, including the provision of economic, development, law enforcement, rule of law, and training assistance that is aimed, among other things, at strengthening government institutions and providing appropriate services to victims of modern slavery.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id366d64e805fb45288da113cafe1e9a97"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Diplomatic efforts</header><text>The United States Government shall also seek, and shall encourage other foreign governments providing support to the End Modern Slavery Initiative Foundation, consistent with the individual priorities and policies of such governments, to undertake diplomatic efforts in partner countries and key jurisdictions of other countries with a high prevalence of modern slavery that support the policies, priorities, and purposes of this Act and End Modern Slavery Initiative supported projects.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id5bdf7eeb3d9742fba5385c0051a5d72c"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Prioritization of additional efforts</header><text>The United States Government shall also seek, and shall encourage other foreign governments providing support to the End Modern Slavery Initiative Foundation, consistent with the individual priorities and policies of such governments, to undertake efforts to support partner countries and key jurisdictions of other countries in their efforts to address the areas of key concern highlighted by the Department of State’s annual Trafficking in Persons Report.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="id3a4617cdb18c4ccdb9edcf25db001c83"><enum>7.</enum><header>Priorities and policies of the end modern slavery initiative</header>
 <subsection id="ida85f743e827c4aa6bb37d99d87d0b302"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The key priorities of the End Modern Slavery Initiative shall be—</text> <paragraph id="id2ea1dbecbc954c94bf60c07b080ad249"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to select partner countries and key jurisdictions in other countries;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id797efb2473f248399a4b9843081781f5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to provide support for programs and projects that collectively or individually seek to achieve a measurable and sustainable reduction of modern slavery in targeted populations within partner countries (or jurisdictions thereof) and key jurisdictions of other countries of at least 50 percent in the prevalence of modern slavery over a seven year period and that are based on goals and outcomes that are capable of being empirically measured;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id24f26707e26b485b8eb6ba013165afee"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to prioritize programs and projects consistent with this Act;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id86e95ac3665b492cb2bf6eafc2565c20"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to work with partner countries and entities funded by the End Modern Slavery Initiative to collaboratively establish budgeted national plans that identify and leverage partner country public and private funding and institutions, and leverage current and expected outside assistance, including programs supported by the End Modern Slavery Initiative Foundation; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id608bde015b0846d6be69b641f0f60681"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to establish national coordinators and leadership councils in partner countries.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idb50115f7b9bc497faa0c6871a69790e2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Selection of partner countries</header><text>In selecting partner countries, the End Modern Slavery Initiative shall consider and prioritize the funding of projects and programs in countries and jurisdictions where there is—</text>
 <paragraph id="id84cc61e5d4334a02971a87af262b613a"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a documented high prevalence of modern slavery within the country as evidenced by assessments in the Department of State’s annual Trafficking in Persons Report; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ida9720e9923ad429f80b907bfd6556823"><enum>(2)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id0F2D3B3FA65D425E960EC00341CC9352"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a demonstrated political motivation and sustained commitment by government entities of such country to undertake meaningful measures to address severe forms of trafficking in persons, including prevention, protection of victims, and the enactment and enforcement of anti-trafficking laws against perpetrators; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id32AD44F332524C6DB3DA66A03CBE0152" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a demonstrated presence of an active and independent civil society that can and will support the efforts of the End Modern Slavery Initiative.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idc10df121a99b413c8cf43c4509a6fc74"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Selection of key jurisdictions of other countries</header><text>In selecting key jurisdictions of other countries, the End Modern Slavery Initiative shall consider and prioritize the funding of projects and programs in key jurisdictions where there is—</text>
 <paragraph id="idfe5d34c411194f2399a9112ca85aad97"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a documented high prevalence of modern slavery within the jurisdiction as evidenced by assessments in the Department of State’s annual Trafficking in Persons Report; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id94e3a0eec71f46eabbff0e2f7e7aa816"><enum>(2)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idB30E416CCD674910BD2B38742797E1BD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a demonstrated political motivation and sustained commitment by government entities of such jurisdiction to undertake meaningful measures to address severe forms of trafficking in persons, including prevention, protection of victims, and the enactment and enforcement of anti-trafficking laws against perpetrators; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7BBA20F6541040CA9887E3395E9D452D" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a demonstrated presence of an active and independent civil society that can and will support the efforts of the End Modern Slavery Initiative.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1eba3a262ee8467881103784bf03720a"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Policies for end modern slavery initiative operations and supported programs in partner countries</header><text>End Modern Slavery Initiative programs in partner programs shall include strategies that—</text> <paragraph id="id3e42d8ae84084c0b971fbebdccabba39"><enum>(1)</enum><text>develop the capacity of national and local government institutions to enforce the law, end impunity of perpetrators, and sustainably deter the crime;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id372802bbe2944543a140283325189cdb"><enum>(2)</enum><text>contribute to the freeing and sustainable recovery of victims of modern slavery, prevent individuals from being subject to modern slavery, or create and enforce laws that punish both individual and corporate perpetrators of modern slavery; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id44a11c6c1cff448b9496fa986ce1eb92"><enum>(3)</enum><text>set out clear, defined goals and outcomes that are capable of empirical measurement against baseline data.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idb0e1bd913ad744a281d2b1d8a8395fff"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Consultation with State department</header><text>In selecting partner countries and key jurisdictions of other countries and funding programs in such countries and jurisdictions, the End Modern Slavery Initiative should consult with the Department of State, including the Office to Monitor and Combat Trafficking in Persons.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id659e5e9df44d451aad041d1e4dcdb347"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Interagency consultation</header><text>In providing the views of the United States Government to the End Modern Slavery Initiative pursuant to subsection (e), the Department of State, including the Office to Monitor and Combat Trafficking in Persons, should consult with the United States Department of Justice, the United States Agency for International Development, the United States Department of Labor, and any other appropriate Federal departments and agencies.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="idbbf2e210d6e9402e82f4d81493f7bca1"><enum>8.</enum><header>Monitoring and evaluation of supported programs</header>
 <subsection id="idefe247609cde4ed69330264b16ca60b7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Board of Directors shall review, on a no less than annual basis, specific and detailed criteria for the monitoring and evaluation of End Modern Slavery Initiative supported projects.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id5c6d283b81f2473bbb577979bfee93b8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements for criteria</header><text>The criteria required to be established pursuant to subsection (a) shall be designed to measure progress against baseline data and shall be rigorously designed based on international corporate and nongovernmental best practices.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id740db74b8f2b4dcfb25414012251dad3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Supported project requirements</header><text>Each supported project shall be regularly and rigorously monitored and evaluated, on a not less than biennial basis, by an independent monitoring and evaluation entity, against the specific and detailed criteria established pursuant to subsection (a), and shall have its progress towards its stated goals measured by such entity against baseline data.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id5e78678a2249419f9289cc944413302b"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Survey methodology</header><text>The End Modern Slavery Initiative shall support the development of a scientifically sound, representative survey methodology for measuring prevalence with reference to existing research and experience and shall apply the methodology consistently to determine the baseline prevalence in target populations and outcomes in order to periodically assess progress in reducing prevalence.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="iddce4bf356fb44db19839635d084f15f8"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Suspension and termination of supported projects</header><text>The Board of Directors shall establish, and revise on a no less than annual basis, specific and detailed criteria for the suspension and termination, as appropriate, of projects supported by the End Modern Slavery Initiative Foundation that regularly or consistently fail to meet the criteria required by this section.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="iddb6fd540a4af440bb45989c719c2b7ca"><enum>9.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="ida8b5386b70c7417e83abc3207254975d"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id3eb15e4778fc422a9c04874d201c92b4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committees on Foreign Relations and Appropriations of the Senate; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3f0f5d54e58d4f6e9588fc67480d99b6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committees on Foreign Affairs and Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idad989031ee41444b84e535d13283e088"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Key jurisdictions of other countries</header><text>The term <term>key jurisdictions of other countries</term> means specific jurisdictions, located in countries that do not qualify to be partner countries, that have a demonstrated commitment to, and institutions capable of, achieving a significant reduction in the incidence of modern slavery within a period of seven years and have been determined to be appropriate to receive funds by the Board of Directors pursuant to the criteria and priorities set forth in this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id70b2ba3731034fe3bf41fa199a2877de"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Modern slavery</header><text>The term <term>modern slavery</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="id34a20f70f7bb4b0295ee557e08511348"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the recruitment, harboring, transportation, provision, or obtaining of a person for the purpose of a commercial sex act in which such commercial sex act is induced by force, fraud, or coercion, or in which the person induced to perform such act has not attained 18 years of age; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id00db720cd8e945ac892a5634bdbbdbc6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the recruitment, harboring, transportation, provision, or obtaining of a person for labor or services, through the use of force, fraud, or coercion for the purpose of subjection to involuntary servitude, peonage, debt bondage, or slavery.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idaca7ee1bebbf4912a7579ef28bb17372"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Partner countries</header><text>The term <term>partner countries</term> means countries that have a demonstrated commitment to, and institutions capable of, achieving a significant reduction in the incidence of modern slavery within a period of seven years and have been determined to be appropriate to receive funds by the Board of Directors pursuant to the criteria and priorities set forth in this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id743076f05d5747f5af4a192f0b24c84e"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Terms defined in title 18, United States Code</header><text>Terms defined in title 18, United States Code, and not otherwise defined in this section shall have the meaning provided in such title.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body>
</bill>


