<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S848 IS: Resolving Environmental and Grid Reliability Conflicts Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 848</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150324">March 24, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S312">Mrs. McCaskill</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S342">Mr. Blunt</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEV00">Committee on Environment and Public Works</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To clarify that compliance with an emergency order under the Federal Power Act may not be
			 considered a violation of any Federal, State, or local environmental law
			 or regulation, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H2B9FD5608B8E495C9D95DC4A11007AE9" style="OLC">
 <section id="H36038B23400F441B9F702FB46169EAB1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Resolving Environmental and Grid Reliability Conflicts Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H0FE894FE540F4A2894E6CBF76F672DB5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Amendments to the Federal Power Act</header> <subsection id="HFC3168FA8B124C77A7D8036E9C0D994D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Compliance with or violation of environmental laws while under emergency order</header><text>Section 202(c) of the Federal Power Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/824a">16 U.S.C. 824a(c)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HD32B93C4A4014A6989FAA87812A6CE7B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the first sentence, by striking <quote>(c) During</quote> and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id62465CD2D4D845EB87AF1F77768C826B" style="OLC"> <subsection id="id81FE136C9AF441CF9715A14FB343F930"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization during war or emergency</header> <paragraph id="idC71F0117E9BE47F58BF9E623B26AE666"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>During</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H504C241D6FDE4AF68C26ACEE80DAE9AA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idC980D65D03134374B99036859C4B61FF" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="id9FD46BD6CD8C4E85B6388E228A635FBF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation as result of conflict with environmental law</header><text>With respect to an order issued under this subsection that may result in a conflict with a requirement of any Federal, State, or local environmental law (including regulations), the Commission shall ensure that the order—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idDBD8425B17D44E96B63FC57A9E2076CF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>requires generation, delivery, interchange, or transmission of electric energy only during hours necessary to meet the emergency and serve the public interest; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idFB61BDF0809348F2A1D756104709E800"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to the maximum extent practicable—</text> <clause id="idD4CBF5888483416DB6A3DCC44B88A6A8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is consistent with any applicable Federal, State, or local environmental law (including regulations); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id447A016F25B24D51B9AC7644303F86A8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>minimizes any adverse environmental impacts.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idB371D49DA9A1463A89930B9834A0F3FC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Compliance not considered violation of other law</header><text>To the extent that any omission or action taken by a party that is necessary to comply with an order issued under this subsection, including any omission or action taken to voluntarily comply with the order, results in noncompliance with, or causes the party to not comply with, any Federal, State, or local environmental law (including regulations), the omission or action shall not—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id7A870523ED924A028C7427B78CDC1F02"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be considered a violation of that environmental law (including regulations); or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA8A67E62EDCD483B94FDF80BABB0F9A2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>subject the party to any requirement, civil or criminal liability, or a citizen suit under that environmental law or regulation.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idAFD28C8FDB6D42E1B32439CFCE668D1B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Expiration of order; renewal</header>
 <subparagraph id="id5E11256ECD5B468E83F6B687E26D400C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Expiration</header><text>An order issued under this subsection that may result in a conflict as described in paragraph (3) shall expire not later than 90 days after that order is issued.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD3D5195B2A3446119E104F0B212CAB31"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Renewal</header><text>The Commission may renew or reissue an order described in subparagraph (A) pursuant to paragraphs (1) and (2) for subsequent periods, not to exceed 90 days for each period, as the Commission determines necessary to meet the emergency and serve the public interest.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id685C985F287B487980406BF8BB7D13C3"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In renewing or reissuing an order under subparagraph (A) or (B), the Commission—</text> <clause id="id388E46000F6F4FC6BD594AEB7B50957B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall consult with the primary Federal agency with expertise in the environmental interest protected by the law or regulation in conflict; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idA20C79132D64452997C7E96D901C59A2"><enum>(ii)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id7B4DFE4A72F04F59A452D57B5DA418B3"><enum>(I)</enum><text>shall include in any renewed or reissued order such conditions as that Federal agency determines necessary to minimize any adverse environmental impacts to the maximum extent practicable; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idDA45BF3F91F94F8BA01338DDDC1BC0FE" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>may exclude from the renewed or reissued order any condition if the Commission—</text> <item id="id5A571174CF08497EA380848C61593ADB"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>determines the condition would prevent the order from adequately addressing the emergency necessitating the order; and</text>
 </item><item id="id45951146E0674DADA8AE4B0860B67D1B"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>provides in the order, or otherwise makes publicly available, an explanation of that determination.</text>
 </item></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idBD415FD69BF0464FB3D08ECF0622C93B"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>Any conditions submitted by the Federal agency under subparagraph (C)(ii) shall be made available to the public.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1005B6CAFD1A4A0F809D21376F53944B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Effect of court action</header><text>If an order issued under this subsection is subsequently stayed, modified, or set aside by a court pursuant to section 313 or any other provision of law, any omission or action previously taken by a party that was necessary to comply with the order while the order was in effect, including any omission or action taken to voluntarily comply with the order, shall remain subject to paragraph (3).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCC4CC727C76E48B19D6B4CB3426A9FA7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Temporary connection or construction by municipalities</header><text>Section 202(d) of the Federal Power Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/824a">16 U.S.C. 824a(d)</external-xref>) is amended in the matter preceding the first proviso by inserting <quote>or municipality</quote> before <quote>engaged in the transmission or sale of electric energy</quote>.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


