<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S800 IS: Enhancing the Stature and Visibility of Medical Rehabilitation Research at the NIH Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 800</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150319">March 19, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S339">Mr. Kirk</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S118">Mr. Hatch</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S288">Ms. Murkowski</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To improve, coordinate, and enhance rehabilitation
		  research at the National Institutes of Health.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
 <section id="id3DBBE4DEE317449DA54C2D724356678D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Enhancing the Stature and Visibility of Medical Rehabilitation Research at the NIH Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="id9128A74D937748F4970E6AE025AEFB21"><enum>2.</enum><header>Improving medical rehabilitation research at the National Institutes of Health</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 452 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/285g-4">42 U.S.C. 285g–4</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="id239b3ef8d72e454fa3475e735934bc78"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b), by striking <quote>conduct and support</quote> and inserting <quote>conduct, support, and coordination</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id8b017bc390c94290a099ac889e061cf1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (c)(1)(C), by striking <quote>of the Center</quote> and inserting <quote>within the Center</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id28577745afdc4c309bc94fa3e4766761"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (d)—</text> <subparagraph id="id80B299DDC88948899D4799B21F76AA10"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (1) and inserting the following: <quote>(1) The Director of the Center, on behalf of the Director of NIH and the Director of the Institute and in consultation with the coordinating committee established under subsection (e) and the advisory board established under subsection (f), shall develop a comprehensive plan (referred to in this section as the <quote>Research Plan</quote>) for the conduct, support, and coordination of medical rehabilitation research.</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfec98fb9d5774660a5ce74314e6d0e65"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text> <clause id="id98cf23a47777499cbe2ab0f1c7e8e4ff"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>and priorities for such research; and</quote> and inserting <quote>priorities for such research, and existing resources to support the purpose described in subsection (b);</quote>;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id2F08554E1BE846A3AEC2F3ADBCA25392"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking the period and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text> </clause><clause id="id3821e908bcef4bb5aeba617edc7d399e"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB78821A2BBFF48B19AA75EEB98C6ABC9" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="id7662EB3E9C314DCEBAE0DC3E78D3C334" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>include objectives, benchmarks, and guiding principles for conducting, supporting, and coordinating medical rehabilitation research, consistent with the purpose described in subsection (b).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id72b27cdca8e54f24990654eafd9021ba"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)—</text> <clause id="idD2E9F1EA6169436A830BAC01BD033E29"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking the first sentence and inserting the following: <quote>The Director of the Center, in consultation with the Director of the Institute, the coordinating committee established under subsection (e), and the advisory board established under subsection (f), shall periodically, or not less than every 5 years, revise and update the Research Plan, as appropriate. Not later than 30 days after the Research Plan is so revised and updated, the Director of the Center shall transmit the revised and updated Research Plan to the President and the appropriate committees of Congress.</quote>; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7ae1bdbe3a5449bcbd405e6ea987d515"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idadb61e9054844d328c946f197c7c33cb" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="id4499A62214454A8584913A48CE359765" indent="up1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Director of the Center, in consultation with the Director of the Institute, shall annually prepare a report for the coordinating committee established under subsection (e) and the advisory board established under subsection (f) that describes and analyzes the progress during the preceding fiscal year in achieving the objectives, benchmarks, and guiding principles described in paragraph (2)(C) and includes expenditures of the Center and other agencies of the National Institutes of Health for carrying out the Research Plan. The report shall include recommendations for revising and updating the Research Plan, and such initiatives as the Director of the Center and the Director of the Institute determine appropriate. In preparing the report, the Director of the Center and the Director of the Institute shall consult with the Director of NIH, and the report shall reflect an assessment of the Research Plan by the Director of NIH.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idb2636953999342ddafbda95d31b00561"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (e)—</text> <subparagraph id="idECE1E70C3299406085BC102CEAF50E26"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by inserting <quote>periodically, or not less than every 5 years, host a scientific conference or workshop on medical rehabilitation research and</quote> after <quote>The Coordinating Committee shall</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id832cbdc3e7eb4cc7b0db31228728d911"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by inserting <quote>the Director of the Division of Program Coordination, Planning, and Strategic Initiatives within the Office of the Director of NIH,</quote> after <quote>shall be composed of</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id479f4dab2f374ac2ba27112980a71a34"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by striking <quote>Director of the Center</quote> and inserting <quote>Director of the Center, acting in the capacity of a designee of the Director of NIH</quote>;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idCB06D502CAFE4252B470C197686A6FF0"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in subsection (f)(3)(B), by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB99759CA829145B2AA517E9282C335C3" style="OLC">
 <clause id="id634B48C293E64269B75EAD5660391AB7" indent="up2"><enum>(xii)</enum><text>The Director of the Division of Program Coordination, Planning, and Strategic Initiatives.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and </after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph id="id4a94378cf2a545dd962b63885c2b4e31"><enum>(6)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id349A7D9CF0D44CD7AD76ECC7479B7AD6" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="idb13289c528514aa49bf49bb89b0cbaad"><enum>(g)</enum><text>The Director of the Center, in consultation with the Director of the Institute, the Coordinating Committee, and the Advisory Board, shall develop guidelines governing the funding for medical rehabilitation research by the Center and other agencies of the National Institutes of Health. At a minimum, such guidelines shall reflect the purpose of the Center described in subsection (b) and be consistent with the Research Plan.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idb8070681b51246e8a3e578f037614f1a"><enum>(h)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id54FC6E648E234A21B1B77ADB1EA9D003"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary and the heads of other Federal agencies shall jointly review the programs carried out (or proposed to be carried out) by each such official with respect to medical rehabilitation research and, as appropriate, enter into agreements preventing duplication among such programs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idCA3F9484E0F9455AAC121E9A02544748" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Secretary shall enter into interagency agreements relating to the coordination of medical rehabilitation research conducted by agencies of the National Institutes of Health and other agencies of the Federal Government.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="iddcb1c16a51d34d649f2f84cbacb624ee"><enum>(i)</enum><text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>medical rehabilitation research</term> means the science of mechanisms and interventions that prevent, improve, restore, or replace lost, underdeveloped, or deteriorating function (defined at the level of impairment, activity, and participation, according to the World Health Organization in the International Classification of Functioning, Disability and Health (2001)).</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section><section id="id66CDA0F01FBB4BB8B41BA6D3BDE54F87"><enum>3.</enum><header>Requirements of certain agreements for enhancing coordination and preventing duplicative programs
 of medical rehabilitation research</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 3 of the National Institutes of Health Amendments of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/285g-4">42 U.S.C. 285g–4</external-xref> note) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="id2E173DF0778C4C1592BB9DCF0EBA2132"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>(a) <header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">In general</header-in-text>.—</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF3CC1ED7D6784748AE9929BCCAB1FEBA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking subsection (b).</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body>
</bill>


