<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1549 IS: Care Planning Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-06-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1549</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150610">June 10, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S327">Mr. Warner</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S305">Mr. Isakson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S354">Ms. Baldwin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S372">Mrs. Capito</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S252">Ms. Collins</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide for advanced illness care coordination
			 services for Medicare beneficiaries, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short
			 title; table of contents</header>
			<subsection id="idDD0C8E5645B84F10889292A954C6D3E3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short
 title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Care Planning Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="id3778012ED01B40FD8215B1395A10CBAA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of
 contents</header><text>The table of contents of this Act is as follows:</text><toc><toc-entry idref="S1" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="idA4372D97BDE0436FB2D82A689A269DC2" level="section">Sec. 2. Findings.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id9CDFA7CBFBA8466E882BF9C1EE5A7B3D" level="section">Sec. 3. Improvement of advanced illness planning and coordination.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id9843D98CDF884CCAADFE2D8DDB160915" level="section">Sec. 4. Quality measurement development.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id6CBC4EEF35C5407FBF008941B9D0C6A0" level="section">Sec. 5. Inclusion of advance care planning materials in the Medicare &amp; You handbook.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="IDD773C462BF734C3D8C0D9AAB226658D1" level="section">Sec. 6. Improvement of policies related to the use and portability of advance directives.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id1D6D3BAA05454981959EB715D7A4AAD2" level="section">Sec. 7. Additional requirements for facilities.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id2A059FAC6F214DBE8D99A0C28C6AE06C" level="section">Sec. 8. Grants for increasing public awareness of advance care planning and advanced illness care.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="idE88EC4FC08C74D0895827A4EC7AA5E27" level="section">Sec. 9. Rule of construction.</toc-entry> </toc> </subsection></section><section id="idA4372D97BDE0436FB2D82A689A269DC2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text>
 <paragraph id="id233c72a4a40743e4bb29f12e99701da4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The population of the United States is estimated to age rapidly, with the number of people over the age of 65 set to double to more than 72,000,000, or 1 in 5 Americans, over the next two decades.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id9953935bb0b84fe68301729107c5da76"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Americans today are living longer and healthier lives than ever before in the history of the United States yet are also facing increased incidence of multiple serious conditions as aging progresses.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idc99a4c8f6cf344d5b2fcf7d7b4b32ba1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Americans with advanced illness face a complicated and fragmented system of care delivery that puts them at risk for repeat hospitalizations, adverse drug reactions, and conflicting medical advice that may be overwhelming to individuals and families.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id022942b6daf14bc7be7572dadf2fdfec"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The progression of advanced illness leads to the need for increasingly intensive decision support, health care services, and support from family caregivers.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id34239606e1f3423eb3970e7ca595334e"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The complexity of care needed by individuals with advanced illness may result in uncoordinated care, adverse health outcomes, frustration, wasted time, and undue emotional burdens on individuals and their family caregivers.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id2a9d64a794fb4e9db7a2b4ff0d8c010b"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Numerous private sector leaders, including hospitals, health systems, home health agencies, hospice programs, long-term care providers, employers, and other entities, have put in place innovative solutions to provide more comprehensive and coordinated care for Americans living with advanced illness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id179c2b10b0ee40ffb14b21ddb8cecc57"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Hospice programs, as one of the longest standing Medicare care coordination benefits that offer a comprehensive set of services via an interdisciplinary team working to provide person- and family-centered care to the frailest and most vulnerable individuals in our communities, can serve as a model for advanced illness care delivery.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ide1d1ce4c5ec64305a8a1c1bf982e11b1"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Palliative care programs that serve patients beginning at diagnosis with advanced illness and provide care designed to reduce the symptom burden of illness can serve as a model for interdisciplinary team care planning based on the individual’s goals of care.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idcd2d409a5f6241b696c37f67cd5975a8"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The Government of the United States, as the Nation’s largest purchaser of health care services, must learn from these innovators and encourage health care providers to furnish more supportive and comprehensive advanced illness care to improve the efficacy and quality of health care delivered for generations of Americans to come.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id571A1F34D28C43FB8F43F15FA4444E7D"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Health care providers who serve individuals with advanced illness face complicated care systems and legal concerns that may result in over- or under-treatment of individuals with advanced illness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id504DE3E9C8E047BB87FBB6792134BD82"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Individuals have the well-established right to accept or reject medical treatment that is offered, as well as the well-established right to document their preferences for how treatment decisions should be made if, at some point in the future, they lose the ability to make health care decisions.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id2046D429BDE2445B8EFDC7CB24C4107C"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Too often, individuals with advanced illness do not understand the conditions they are facing or their treatment options, and they do not receive the information or support they need to evaluate treatment options in light of their personal goals and values and to document treatment plans in a manner that allows providers and facilities to follow their plans.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id968E30955C894143BFBF28D29BB82B40"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Providing quality services and planning support to individuals with advanced illness will protect and preserve their dignity.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="id9CDFA7CBFBA8466E882BF9C1EE5A7B3D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Improvement of
			 advanced illness planning and coordination</header>
			<subsection id="id6AF858AC982241BD8E568D3CFC596135"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Medicare
			 coverage of planning services</header>
 <paragraph id="idBD5C2048B01C4EA4A6BF733531DB0080"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Coverage</header><text>Section 1861(s)(2) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x(s)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H0E20A9D10CA54ECF9C8693DE63BB3A53"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (EE), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB054EC4D865248D0ADF9746F7D95A4AE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (FF), by inserting <quote>and</quote> at the end; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H07E8BFEDC5C8444E84FE1FCB4C0EFAB6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (FF) the following new paragraph:</text>
						<quoted-block id="H1E21350E25884A4F9DD974F5CF57F150" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H918F4FF92A2D4B63BCB457EC56593B32"><enum>(GG)</enum><text>planning services (as defined in subsection (iii));</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idDBD19A426C324FBDA0F118EAB23DB6F2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Services
 described</header><text>Section 1861 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
 <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB54635B29AC447A6BACB51425DB6532E" other-style="archaic" style="other"><subsection id="id17C404EF8FEE4055866702AC0C4EFF63"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Planning services</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idBCAB4124FAD240C3B1B357A8BC2C54A4"><enum>(1)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idEEF1C6C9D8D145F1B8F5E708DEF0C55D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The term <term>planning services</term> means a voluntary decisionmaking process that includes the elements described in paragraph (2) and is furnished to a planning services eligible individual by an applicable provider through an interdisciplinary team.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id855386311C3E419AAD29CA07E0CCAC05" indent="up2"><enum>(B)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idB34AC6F19E8448A1B8DDFAA0C8F05EC4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Except as provided in clause (ii), planning services may only be furnished to a planning services eligible individual under this title once in each 12-month period.</text>
 </clause><clause id="id2DC07243EB354C8F84B57EC57B7DF875" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The Secretary shall establish appropriate exceptions to the frequency limitation under clause (i), such as when there is a change in the individual's medical condition.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1A81E561E8C64A40967DD2CF39B97FA7" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id800C21927E104A0086A3873D59B5D7BD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The elements described in this paragraph are the following:</text>
 <clause id="idA440F33746FF474787F3DDA4B369FF1D" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>One or more face-to-face encounters between one or more members of the interdisciplinary team and the individual and, at the individual’s discretion, family caregivers, or, for an individual who lacks decisionmaking capacity under State law, the individual’s legally authorized representative.</text>
 </clause><clause id="id671E11FCE0B3452386122D2F369E8A3E" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The provision of information about the typical trajectory of illnesses or conditions that affect the individual, including foreseeable care decisions that may need to be made at a future time when the individual is likely to be unable to make decisions due to temporary or permanent cognitive incapacity.</text>
 </clause><clause id="idA3D4555A2F074512829A46C79B867AB8" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Assisting the individual in defining and articulating goals of care, values, and preferences.</text>
 </clause><clause id="id346322BE30804F13A845E4F7842F77B8" indent="up1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Providing the individual with and discussing information about the benefits and burdens of relevant ranges of treatment options available to the individual, including disease modifying or potentially curative treatment, palliative care, which may be provided alone or in conjunction with disease modifying treatment, and, when the individual may be currently eligible or may become eligible for hospice care due to disease progression.</text>
 </clause><clause id="id86B4FE46634A44519C63C46255E5A960" indent="up1"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Assisting the individual in evaluating treatment options and approaches to care to identify those that most closely align with the individual’s goals of care, values, and preferences.</text>
 </clause><clause id="id8983DBFCA14B47FF9CE976E22D4DC3C8" indent="up1"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Preparing, and sharing with relevant providers, documentation—</text>
 <subclause id="idA37F0C0D5350458F979B6C8A2E25E01A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>that states the individual’s goals of care, preferences, and values, preferred decisionmaking strategies, and a plan of care that is concrete and actionable; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id161086497FC245CEA1617772F7BF0EB8"><enum>(II)</enum><text>that is in State or locally recognized forms that are used for the purpose of assuring that providers can follow the plan across care settings, such as advance directives or portable treatment orders.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="id06AFAF5EB468402EAE9C1F0055F8FB7C" indent="up1"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>Referrals to providers, including medical and social service providers, who deliver care consistent with the plan.</text>
 </clause><clause id="idDB9DF1757FB44A9FBAABF353984A3FF6" indent="up1"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>Providing culturally and educationally appropriate training for the individual and family caregivers to support their ability to carry out the plan.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id38ECB58B5C2A4F7EB575B7A7927B54BD" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Even when the individual’s decisional capacity is impaired and another person or entity, such as an appointed agent, proxy, or surrogate, is exercising legal authority under State law governing decisionmaking on behalf of incapacitated individuals, the interdisciplinary team shall make a reasonable attempt to include the individual in the planning process.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idF9E22FB88DDC4F33A0685328271A32D7" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <quote>planning services eligible individual</quote> means an individual that meets at least one of the following criteria:</text>
 <subparagraph id="id415C2B2D5F1E4175830F0EC0DD61C9B5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The individual is diagnosed with metastatic or locally advanced cancer.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idDDFB2BF681C642F299B7B0F823482D73"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The individual is diagnosed with Alzheimer’s disease or another progressive dementia.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE1A1E9C979A240F49F02EAC6EC4939B5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The individual is diagnosed with late-stage neuromuscular disease.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7CE04B67A7604CB9956DF7553C34D463"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The individual is diagnosed with late-stage diabetes.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id26C6A6B966FD4763A1A57F0A2FC3588D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The individual is diagnosed with late-stage kidney, liver, heart, gastrointestinal, cerebrovascular, or lung disease.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id1B672A9EAED34341A0BCE1899BD39F7D"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The individual needs assistance with two or more activities of daily living (defined as bathing, dressing, eating, getting out of bed or a chair, mobility, and toileting) not associated with an acute or post-operative conditions that are caused by one or more serious or life threatening illnesses or frailty.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id07CB0D88EFD0418D8EF54BA02C1ABBDA"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The individual meets other criteria determined appropriate by the Secretary, including criteria that are designed to identify individuals with a need for planning services due to a serious or life threatening illness or risk of decline in cognitive function over time.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id777366ED18E744D5829D8F2FFF4A193C" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>applicable provider</term> means a hospice program (as defined in section 1861(dd)(2)) or other provider of services (as defined in section 1861(u)) or supplier (as defined in section 1861(d)) that—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="id02D6D659AFCA49C09472698ECE80198C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>furnishes planning services through an interdisciplinary team; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="idCE2A290C53944C86900B3F919E280E0E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>meets such other requirements the Secretary may determine to be appropriate.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id6E3ECBE4F7D14F77BBECAB1A3CEDB93E" indent="up1"><enum>(5)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id8C17C36BBE714E4BA7BB509DF8E82CEA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <quote>interdisciplinary team</quote> means a group that—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="id14B3F4977CF945389866F30FDD980268" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>includes the personnel described in subsection (dd)(2)(B)(i);</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="idAFC27C6F0441404890FBAC3F1141A0B6" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>may include a chaplain, minister, or personal religious or spiritual advisor;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="id37ABA3BB5CD7446AA54F72D1CE44F482" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>may include other direct care personnel; and</text> </clause><clause id="id7FE064F57F7B472BAB0CA10FEB9E13EB" indent="up1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>meets requirements that may be established by the Secretary.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8241BFEA76B94DAFABDFA5109BCD6955" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An applicable provider furnishing planning services to a planning services eligible individual shall offer to the individual (or the individual’s legally authorized representative when the individual has been found to lack decisional capacity) the opportunity to select either a chaplain affiliated with the provider, a minister, or personal religious or spiritual advisor who can help to represent the individual’s goals, values, and preferences to serve as a core team member at the individual’s (or legally authorized representative’s) request.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA784F0BD77BC4D8E95C6117C42644C2E" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The requirements established by the Secretary under subparagraph (A)(ii) shall include a requirement that interdisciplinary team members (except for the chosen chaplain, minister, or personal religious or spiritual advisor) have training and experience in delivering person-directed planning services and in team-based delivery of services for individuals with dementing illness and individuals with a serious or life threatening illness.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H2A88226F8436405CB26BAB5341632978"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Payment under
 physician fee schedule</header><text>Section 1848(j)(3) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-4">42 U.S.C. 1395w–4(j)(3)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>(2)(GG),</quote> after <quote>(2)(FF) (including administration of the health risk assessment),</quote>.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H489DCC0DB8BC4CCC8DF1E73F6ACE939C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Frequency
 limitation</header><text>Section 1862(a) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395y">42 U.S.C. 1395y(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2CD12533F7A745878C09818B0173E4C2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text>
 <clause id="H2129F5074A0940B0872C7F46AA2CEC5F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (O), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HBAEBA7CBFA984DBCA672B5A3D3F4A3DC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (P) by striking the semicolon at the end and inserting <quote>, and</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HEF9B0DF00DF34740AB93CD5964BDFC0E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text>
							<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCB01EDD27A154AF196ECC6657459E914" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H5E1B75FF10764AB882C1529F5C2793F9"><enum>(Q)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of planning services (as defined in section 1861(iii)(1)), which are furnished more frequently than is covered under subparagraph (B) of such section;</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;
				and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF049770A8E824007997365D09A1C7385"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (7), by striking <quote>or (P)</quote> and inserting <quote>(P), or (Q)</quote>.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id376928E0D72E408F8BB8C9FF5C4F4CCA"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Effective
 date</header><text>The amendments made by this subsection shall apply to services furnished on or after January 1, 2017.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idBF92EF45047F47F6BF4FDDEDA6E962C7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Advanced
 illness care coordination services project</header><text>Section 1115A(b)(2) of title XI of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1315a">42 U.S.C. 1315a(b)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="id74A6D1C1CC2D4C49AB24C85CC8B7B31F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by adding at the end the following new sentence: <quote>The models selected under this subparagraph shall include the model described in subparagraph (D) and such model shall be implemented by not later than December 31, 2017.</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id55CE660BC95044478A0CB1C13DA64724"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7493D3358E5140C2B8615269E16DF9E3" style="OLC">
						<subparagraph id="id452FE18F7CF748D0A714E5EB85CE8730"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Advanced
				illness care coordination services model</header>
							<clause id="idC96CE7EA3D244298B66E41BD919EA3A5"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Model</header>
								<subclause id="id7DE5DBC0F315414B8D0744741DB55F7C"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>The model described in this subparagraph is a model under which payments are made to applicable providers that furnish advanced illness care coordination services to eligible individuals.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id71E25A342A3C4BD5AD892D6DE5E90D29"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>At least one applicable provider selected for participation under the model shall be a hospice program (as defined in section 1861(dd)(2)).</text>
								</subclause></clause><clause id="id364745012C934228B7BB6429E76F8852"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Applicable
 provider</header><text>In this subparagraph, the term <term>applicable provider</term> has the meaning given such term in section 1861(iii)(4).</text>
							</clause><clause id="idD3528B92DF114322829681B053196CB7"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Advanced
 illness care coordination services</header><text>In this subparagraph, the term <quote>advanced illness care coordination services</quote> means the following services:</text>
 <subclause id="id56933b0d98a345e787db82dcba300098"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Planning services (as defined in section 1861(iii)).</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="ide77d2369f5ee4c95b97e17755b15382d"><enum>(II)</enum><text>A multi-dimensional assessment of the individual’s strengths and limitations.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id4c5ad5354283488bb8e287f19293052f"><enum>(III)</enum><text>An assessment of the individual’s formal and informal supports, including family caregivers.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id591b48b266c24165aaf1876017d0e34c"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>Comprehensive medication review and management (including, if appropriate, counseling and self-management support).</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="ida8cbcaf7a08d4017828ac75cb7e47b0a"><enum>(V)</enum><text>In-home supportive services for the eligible individual and family caregivers consistent with the care plan.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id32878ac5c49d4e31974c5b97938d2cb1"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>24-hour access to emergency support in person or via telephone or telemedicine with the individual’s medical record and care plan available to the responder.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id097d70f12a3e44adacaef0346261a9ab"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>Coordination across health care and social service systems, including involvement of the interdisciplinary team to evaluate quality and address concerns over time.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="ida1fc3404e0dc42e79bc72c5796be08b1"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text>Such other services as specified by the Secretary.</text>
								</subclause></clause><clause id="id4E19C57FEC1344B788082D3CD6498F20"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Eligible
 individual</header><text>In this subparagraph, the term <quote>eligible individual</quote> means an individual who—</text>
 <subclause id="idAAE756DA767B4F3B870D2D85D2780428"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is entitled to, or enrolled for, benefits under part A of title XVIII and enrolled under part B of such title, but not enrolled under part C of such title; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id96ABD4982F74411CAD51563E4D0E3846"><enum>(II)</enum><text>has the need for assistance with two or more activities of daily living (defined as bathing, dressing, eating, getting out of bed or a chair, mobility, and toileting) that is not associated with an acute or post-operative condition that is caused by one or more serious or life threatening conditions or frailty.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9843D98CDF884CCAADFE2D8DDB160915"><enum>4.</enum><header>Quality
			 measurement development</header>
			<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id107412047EB74BD595E1A21EA5BF63D3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 931(c)(2) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/299b-31">42 U.S.C. 299b–31(c)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idC75E4225D3A642948FA8A5F8ABFD7C47"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (I) and (J) as subparagraphs (L) and (M), respectively; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8B8A1D7BB6724A038088EE1281DC517C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (H) the following new subparagraphs:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4D0032B0E99C492BA8AACB71953DE469" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="idd1f0f6f1e7814e44bb2c2e6842e387f1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the process of eliciting and documenting patient (and, where relevant and appropriate, family caregiver) goals, preferences, and values from the patient or from a legally authorized representative, including the articulation of goals that accurately reflect how the patient wants to live;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8c46b296716b4b68a59bb7a25dd44f27"><enum>(J)</enum><text>the effectiveness, patient-centeredness (and, where relevant, family caregiver-centeredness), and accuracy of care plans, including documentation of individual goals, preferences, and values;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id89eafe2c337a48a9b237c4c9c0ab096d"><enum>(K)</enum><text>agreement and consistency among—</text>
 <clause id="id1f74afbce9d74812a429559ecda37d29"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the patient’s goals, values, and preferences;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id66e442b07eb64429a61824c3e97dc401"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any documented care plan;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id63ab6a6c4c9341d3a197b37cd2414330"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the treatment delivered; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idcbb4f3e7e89844529ab4723808cc8d0d"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>outcomes of treatment;</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0105B849FF2E4E808A5340A865420521"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorization
 of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of Health and Human Services to carry out the amendments made by this section, $5,000,000 for fiscal year 2016. Amounts appropriated under the preceding sentence shall remain available until expended.</text>
			</subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6CBC4EEF35C5407FBF008941B9D0C6A0"><enum>5.</enum><header>Inclusion of
			 advance care planning materials in the Medicare &amp; You handbook</header>
			<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE8AF512B8F0646468A38891DBD7A91B2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1804(a) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395b-2">42 U.S.C. 1395b–2(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id980B3826A1ED4D66B926DEE2BF0D8421"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9BA88EDACFF94DCCB195F401AF131BF9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF05E83A3877E4C85B8C740420F2BFFE1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (3) the following new paragraphs:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idAE072E58C8A84C9C8A1BEA381E6986FB" style="OLC">
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id29DBD2EA52594A2B9740901F44A92068"><enum>(4)</enum><text>information on—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE25C74ACE5A24EDBBEE68C431E01625E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>care planning;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id96a933f5615b40cc87f94e8ada76a6d8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>how individual goals, values, and preferences should be considered in framing a care plan; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida11dc7b51afc4d0885caf7aeddcb85d0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a range of approaches for treating advanced illness, including disease modifying options, palliative care that supports individuals from the onset of advanced illness and can be provided at the same time as all other care types, and hospice care; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8A7D7D8EA3FD420DB0C0C4F56C25F326"><enum>(5)</enum><text>information on documentation options for care planning or advance care planning, including advance directives and portable treatment orders.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id67A21806B9614E62AE19722DFD772D00"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective
 date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to notices distributed on or after January 1, 2017.</text>
			</subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="IDD773C462BF734C3D8C0D9AAB226658D1"><enum>6.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Improvement of policies related to the use
			 and portability of advance directives</header>
			<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID36490EE859764D9DA28067A60A774AA7"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Medicare</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id60488265BCDA412D8E2DC506250FFFAA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1866(f) of the <act-name parsable-cite="SSA">Social Security Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395cc">42 U.S.C. 1395cc(f)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="IDA042B6E29CB847ACA91E8B06D6145FDA"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (1)—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID01DB59144C9E40D89EF1D082CF2E0CA9"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (A)(i)—</text>
 <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id23222134DE554630A922662DA349F871"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>relevant</quote> after <quote>rights under</quote>; and</text> </subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5A2F07C3EF7F43C5B7C870490639E83F"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>of the State</quote>;</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id01B9188517C948C5AA02F03E5B8A40AD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (B);</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id166FA5CEA6F94B66A52724F29B70348E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (C), (D), and (E) as subparagraphs (G), (H), and (I), respectively;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idBA323BB726E444B8A94EDE24259DFD8F"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (A) the following new subparagraphs:</text>
							<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id524E46031B4E4A97A2A7D942EA6A100E" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="idb0455019369a4fb8937289a4741c33d5" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to request and document in a prominent part of the individual's current medical record the content of (or a copy of) an advance directive or portable treatment order;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id07d785f2b38c4fc4b7bab3f4303fa4ae" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to provide each individual with resources to assist them in understanding the information provided to them pursuant to subparagraph (A);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida176f19c4003451eb16dec055def1997" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in the case of an individual with decisional capacity under State law, to follow the individual’s current treatment instructions, as expressed in writing or through verbal or non-verbal communications;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf15ef05612dd483b86d5933f41219d6c" indent="up1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>in the case of an individual who lacks decisional capacity—</text>
 <clause id="id581ee8f1eceb41c68034e356a66c9a3b"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to follow treatment decisions in accordance with current advance directives and portable treatment orders that are valid under State law where the care is delivered and the instructions provided by legally authorized representatives in accordance with State law; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="ide8e264c7fee543c795e0d0fbc72dff77"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the absence of a current advance directive or portable treatment order that is valid under State law where the care is delivered or instructions provided by a legally authorized representative in accordance with State law, to deliver treatment based on credible evidence of the individual’s treatment preferences, goals, and values, which evidence may include a current advance directive or portable treatment order executed in another State;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB903FE8697DC4A65B0103A37B1D1E5F0" indent="up1"><enum>(F)</enum><text>that specify conditions or circumstances under which an advance directive, portable treatment order, or treatment directions from an individual or legally authorized representative would not be followed;</text>
								</subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;
				</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id752E9BBF649746D18037CC949F168A8F"><enum>(v)</enum><text>in subparagraph (H), as redesignated by subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>State law</quote> and all that follows through <quote>respecting</quote> and inserting <quote>this section and relevant State and Federal law respecting</quote>;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3B0CD5E0089947EC8F7332B923B80CFC"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>in subparagraph (I), as redesignated by subparagraph (C), by inserting <quote>and portable treatment orders</quote> before the period at the end;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1436918B599141BFB528A17C4CD112D7"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>in the flush matter at the end, by striking <quote>(C)</quote> and inserting <quote>(G)</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id68D930F98062484D9162BD8F60ADAE57"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new sentence: <quote>Nothing in subparagraph (D) or (E) shall be construed to apply to a request or directive ordering a sterilization or abortion or ordering withdrawal of treatment from a pregnant woman if continued treatment can reasonably be expected to bring her child to live birth.</quote>;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idBB712A05611747DB8DB236C33CEE94D5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (3) and (4) as paragraphs (4) and (5), respectively;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id90FB691A97B647D6A4E1A301FE4033F1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (2) the following new paragraph:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id721ACEC3BAB54120A5B03759DA3041C9" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="idF745244CBE8048A686CBFBBF0AA6CC63" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to prohibit the application of a State law which allows for an objection on the basis of conscience for any health care provider or any agent of such provider which as a matter of conscience cannot implement an advance directive or portable treatment order.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idEA7861FF57884AFAB1F5F06B21AD06C1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), as redesignated by paragraph (2)—</text>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3F5B96E5D7494D4B84BC0B8CF1C26CA8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>a written</quote> and inserting <quote>an</quote>;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id78D12E3990874BAA996EAC8CC19D098D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>State law</quote> and inserting <quote>State or Federal law</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9814A9463BC6490594300ED54981619A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>of the State</quote>;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6B156DD08A9044399747303FB8F0B181"><enum>(E)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (5), as redesignated by paragraph (2), as paragraph (6);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idBC9DA2D346EE44698C6628B967ECF8ED"><enum>(F)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (4) the following new paragraph:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8B0C3B763E304EA2A9349A532B6144CB" style="OLC">
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id81F295EEA32E44589331666A5D255D9F" indent="up1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>In this subsection, the term <quote>portable treatment order</quote> means a treatment order designed to document a clinical process that includes shared, informed medical decisionmaking, that reflects the individual’s goals of care and values, and that is designed to apply across care settings, including the home.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and
				</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id232344E544BD4565924E1B4570A5BFFC"><enum>(G)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (6), as redesignated by paragraph (6), the following new paragraph:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idBA15F74BC4A843AF82814134EEE883F3" style="OLC">
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5212E0FE250849AA89C14B1BDC7B0224" indent="up1"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Nothing in this subsection shall permit the Secretary to seek civil penalties, including exclusion from participation in the program under this title or the program under title XIX, against a provider or organization if the provider or organization—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idDB63A1AFFA9542D384577CD270840C26"><enum>(A)</enum><text>used reasonable efforts to deliver care that is consistent with an individual's goals, preferences, and values when addressing decisionmaking for an individual who lacks decisional capacity; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id562F46FBC7F44981ABB7F06B8FEE385C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>exercised its right of conscience in accordance with paragraph (3).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idAFBF7D2135A049D1B9C239ED7AC92EE2"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by paragraph (1) shall apply to provider agreements and contracts entered into, renewed, or extended under title XVIII of the <act-name parsable-cite="SSA">Social Security Act</act-name> on or after such date as the Secretary of Health and Human Services specifies, but in no case may such date be later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4DE2F6E2BA4D4BDCA7116E71D5D59EF1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in the provisions of, or the amendments made by, this subsection shall be construed to require a provider of services or an organization to act in a manner contrary to its religious or moral convictions.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id32BBA88D9F12433F84A5F251151405BF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clarification
 with respect to advance directives</header><text>Paragraph (2) of section 7 of the Assisted Suicide Funding Restriction Act of 1997 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/14406">42 U.S.C. 14406</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6A5684D4942E41DDAE38A87EB2D8976A" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="id2873916878f440d59fd83c9d63e5bc2d"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to require any provider or organization, or any employee of such a provider or organization, to follow or be bound by a request from an individual or legally authorized representative, an advance directive, or a portable treatment order that directs the purposeful causing of, or the purposeful assisting in causing, the death of any individuals, such as by assisted suicide, euthanasia, or mercy killing.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section id="id1D6D3BAA05454981959EB715D7A4AAD2"><enum>7.</enum><header>Additional
			 requirements for facilities</header>
			<subsection id="ID97847624A5324A1FACEB61CB8F4E74E8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirements</header>
				<paragraph id="id1A826E8E81D14E3E83CB892DD8868AE0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>Section 1866(a)(1) of the <act-name parsable-cite="SSA">Social Security Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395cc">42 U.S.C. 1395cc(a)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="ID24FC77BFF9114D97BFBC5013D6CA4E70"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (V), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID7A8AF1C53E704A12AE7658B6EC862279"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (W), as added by section 3005(1)(C) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/148">Public Law 111–148</external-xref>), by redesignating such subparagraph as subparagraph (X), moving such subparagraph to follow subparagraph (V), moving such subparagraph 2 ems to the left, and striking the period at the end and inserting a comma;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6A6751DC2B0F460C82DE0CDE662EA714"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subparagraph (W), as added by section 6406(b)(3) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/148">Public Law 111–148</external-xref>), by redesignating such subparagraph as subparagraph (Y), moving such subparagraph to follow subparagraph (X), as added by subparagraph (B), moving such subparagraph 2 ems to the left, and striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>, and</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID8EDC8D0CA96F4B45B429A897AD4A998E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (Y) the following new subparagraph:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id555285DA7DBC4EE6B745B9E60FA83F0C" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="IDF396FBE64BAC4556BE8A0D93C7AE8D6E" indent="up1"><enum>(Z)</enum><text>in the case of hospitals, skilled nursing facilities, home health agencies, and hospice programs, to assure that documented care plans include any advance directives or portable treatment orders made while the individual received care by the provider and that such plan is sent to the individual’s primary care provider upon discharge and any facility to which the individual is transferred.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idD501A35C8110431291DE94568F1136C3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effective
 Date</header><text>The amendments made by this subsection shall apply to agreements entered into or renewed on or after January 1, 2017.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id7018156F540C4057B3D4201A7D26C0EE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>HHS study and
			 report</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id12A8BDA74EF743289D01AF37F86DDB99"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall conduct a study on the extent to which hospitals, skilled nursing facilities, hospice programs, home health agencies, and applicable providers of planning services under section 1861(iii) of the Social Security Act, as added by section 3(a), work with individuals to—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3BA3196CFFF94A1990C2ACC157497D90"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">engage in a care planning process;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id37023AE7C9274782B0059537F08F9C2E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">thoroughly and completely document the care planning process in the medical record;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8F9A7E33740A4179A054336433BF4F48"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">complete documents necessary to support the treatment and care plan, such as portable treatment orders and advance directives;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2ff9be34485849c995a527c08eac5599"><enum>(D)</enum><text>provide services and support that is free from discrimination based on advanced age, disability status, or advanced illness; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id561B740DDD4A4129B5E94AE88CDA07C5"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide documentation necessary to carry out the treatment plan to—</text>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1110B031AC2C46CF9729E77FB8D7240E"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">subsequent providers or facilities; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB616B11FBCB14A24A116934157300FF5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the individual, their legally authorized representatives, and, where appropriate and relevant, their family caregiver.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5DE32069B04B47EAB3F54B5EA0FF2633"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than January 1, 2020, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall submit to Congress a report on the study conducted under paragraph (1) together with recommendations for such legislation and administrative action as the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2A059FAC6F214DBE8D99A0C28C6AE06C"><enum>8.</enum><header>Grants for
			 increasing public awareness of advance care planning and advanced illness
			 care</header>
			<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6A046952BEAE40909D9532CBFEBDABEA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Material and
			 resources development</header>
				<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1E1817BF3A6E4B788570FC2174C292E5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services (in this section referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) is authorized to award grants to entities described in subsection (d) to develop online training modules, decision support tools, and instructional materials for individuals, family caregivers, and health care providers that include—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id6b5e86ca48f5408281ff3b76940b1c1f"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for healthy individuals, the importance of—</text>
 <clause id="idb75b76a21ec9493c912a78679090e0cf"><enum>(i)</enum><text>identifying an individual who will make treatment decisions in the event of future cognitive incapacity;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id1fe98886be184f36b50fbda5f49de298"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>discussing values and goals relevant to catastrophic injury or illness; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id35e34031e3944bce842c8a47d158e8c2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>completing an advance directive that—</text>
 <subclause id="id00b639f6278f4d01b3843380729c8f96"><enum>(I)</enum><text>appoints a surrogate; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id4c2414a82c2b484f9f6866e34ee45ab4"><enum>(II)</enum><text>documents goals and values and other information that should be considered in making treatment decisions;</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idec1de1c62a484614a46bc4fc2bb90f28"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for individuals with advanced illness, the importance of—</text>
 <clause id="id8b8b16fdb8a8473c89853a3bb24edaff"><enum>(i)</enum><text>articulating goals of care;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idcab73ca22a0a4823a3bd3531a5a9ced1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>understanding prognosis and typical disease trajectory;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id3c840f68eb384c27bad165015e04ef06"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>evaluating treatment options in light of goals of care;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id14844f9ac4ea451c843942f78b40e526"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>developing a treatment plan; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id19350a7043c1441aae2d6de16230f792"><enum>(v)</enum><text>documenting the treatment plan on advance directives, portable treatment orders, and other documentation forms used in the locality where the plan is to be executed;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id73cf4327d1ba41aca95731c76298cc56"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the role and effective use of State and other advance directive forms and portable treatment orders; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8e1ccc448b2b4f8fa7482b1a4c3a909c"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the range of services for individuals facing advanced illness, including planning services, palliative care, and hospice care.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id3240FB07026545E8AA712A0568F04265"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Period</header><text>Any grant awarded under paragraph (1) shall be for a period of 3 years.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idb58423c8ab8e46c6a70a8d4dab579594"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment
			 and maintenance of web- and telephone-Based resources</header>
				<paragraph id="idD923BE6C612E44C89FB9F9D0888904EB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>The Secretary is authorized to award grants to entities described in subsection (d) to establish and maintain a website and telephone hotline to disseminate resources developed under subsection (a) and materials designed by the Department of Health and Human Services Center for Faith-Based and Neighborhood Partnerships for faith communities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id79615B36152346A18A395710D6D06659"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Period</header><text>Any grant awarded under paragraph (1) shall be for a period of 5 years.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="id1162E9A41723451A93D2D7FFA32C6D81"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Ability to
 sustain activities</header><text>The Secretary shall take into account the ability of an entity to sustain the activities described in paragraph (1) beyond the 5-year grant period in determining whether to award a grant under paragraph (1) to the entity.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idd8ab90605c1141a5a2ee7b7601a0923b"><enum>(c)</enum><header>National public
			 education campaign</header>
				<paragraph id="idA203E4B436D3405889405646D91B775E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>The Secretary is authorized to award grants to entities described in subsection (d) to conduct a national public education campaign to raise public awareness of advance care planning and advanced illness care, including the availability of the resources created under subsections (a) and (b).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id7077D1CE63264AA7A699A2A97944F34A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Period</header><text>Any grant awarded under paragraph (1) shall be for a period of 5 years.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id28EED32456A7439B821D381B24A76DAE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Eligible
 entities</header><text>Entities described in this subsection are public or private entities (including States or political subdivisions of a State, faith-based organizations, and religious educational institutions), or a consortium of any such entities.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="id8297B340E3E84A50AFAA36061305D1AD"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization
			 of appropriations</header>
				<paragraph id="id4A01FF8E12D74DB0B2E3380F2C52DD72"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idffc56058e5b748e28a511c1bf54a437d"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for purposes of making grants under subsection (a), $5,000,000 for fiscal year 2017, to remain available until expended;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc9482a4b6f054230b1930733a8fe4341"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for purposes of making grants under subsection (b), $5,000,000 for fiscal year 2017, to remain available until expended; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1d43f327fa0d41e096bb787f3ee24b88"><enum>(C)</enum><text>for purposes of making grants under subsection (c), $5,000,000 for fiscal year 2017 to remain available until expended.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id8E30D599DA6C403CBE1B4CFF5A2A1F72"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>None of the funds appropriated under paragraph (1) shall be used to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id48582F2951264DD999AB01AE6E8EE615"><enum>(A)</enum><text>develop a model advance directive;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id84D52B80951C42FF9FDF4E2B9CC96B81"><enum>(B)</enum><text>develop or employ a dollars-per-quality adjusted life year (or similar measure that discounts the value of a life because of an individual's disability); or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idBAD141FB16C445C7AE1BDB1459D2551A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>make a grant to a private entity that advocates, promotes, or facilitates any item or procedure for which funding is unavailable under the Assisted Suicide Funding Restriction Act of 1997 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/105/12">Public Law 105–12</external-xref>).</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idE88EC4FC08C74D0895827A4EC7AA5E27"><enum>9.</enum><header>Rule of
 construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in the provisions of, or the amendments made by, this Act shall be construed to limit the restrictions of, or to authorize the use of Federal funds for any service, material, or activity pertaining to an item or service or procedure for which funds are unavailable under, the Assisted Suicide Funding Restriction Act of 1997 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/105/12">Public Law 105–12</external-xref>).</text></section></legis-body></bill>


