<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1944 IS: Regulations Endanger Democracy Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-08-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 1944</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150805">August 5, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S383">Mr. Sullivan</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To require each agency to repeal or amend 1 or more rules before issuing or amending a rule.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Regulations Endanger Democracy Act of 2015</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>RED Tape Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="id200A76D6C4C54B4B8B9C467BAE6BFA61"><enum>2.</enum><header>Repeal of rules required before issuing or amending rule</header>
 <subsection id="id204D5639A9EC4E37BADA4BCE710EAB1B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text> <paragraph id="id51332BE2EF1E462E87C93E88DBBD89F5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>agency</term> has the meaning given that term in section 551 of title 5, United States Code;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id33E92C3F738E41CABC09126F3FBCB243"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>covered rule</term> means a rule of an agency that causes a new financial or administrative burden on businesses in the United States or on the people of the United States, as determined by the head of the agency;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id58B95D6587D9419090FE23E7F77D437F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>rule</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="id63E6FDDB69C34586A00A6704861DB549"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has the meaning given that term in section 551 of title 5, United States Code; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD52D20F3E84D43E0B5AFB467FFEF816D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes—</text> <clause id="idAFA4968416F44017939F85A528C44F75"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any rule issued by an agency pursuant to an Executive order or Presidential memorandum; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idC510559759EE4153871CF094672CB3F0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any rule issued by an agency due to the issuance of a memorandum, guidance document, bulletin, or press release issued by an agency; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idb389319415094791abe9a5c1545d3a58"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the term <term>Unified Agenda</term> means the Unified Agenda of Federal Regulatory and Deregulatory Actions.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id8C025847770146308DA8EE55070B289C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition on issuance of certain rules</header> <paragraph id="id5ECC0574961645E2916E095A5A9D051D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An agency may not—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idC89890D16CE94747B01B348EC6ED7B9C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>issue a covered rule that does not amend or modify an existing rule of the agency, unless—</text> <clause id="id35F16761EB4E4FB991BEBE9613A8D58C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the agency has repealed 1 or more existing covered rules of the agency; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idB1BD3B22334D4B049FD3095F776C845A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the cost of the covered rule to be issued is less than or equal to the cost of the covered rules repealed under clause (i), as determined and certified by the head of the agency; or</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idED652E982C4F46BB97991CAB52DED442"><enum>(B)</enum><text>issue a covered rule that amends or modifies an existing rule of the agency, unless—</text> <clause id="id74F7615126294375BC7234FCFE7EA76F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the agency has repealed or amended 1 or more existing covered rules of the agency; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id031EE688AE1A4DAFB3D3ABC0B152A1D5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the cost of the covered rule to be issued is less than or equal to the cost of the covered rules repealed or amended under clause (i), as determined and certified by the head of the agency.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idC5B95DE3699D4B9EAC8C7567E6808206"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Penalty for failure to repeal or amend rules</header><text>During the period beginning on the date of failure to comply by an agency with paragraph (1) in issuing a covered rule, and ending on the date on which the agency complies with paragraph (1) with respect to that covered rule, no statutory pay adjustment (as defined in section 147(b) of the Continuing Appropriations Act, 2011 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/5303">5 U.S.C. 5303</external-xref> note)) shall take effect with respect to any employee of the agency.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6F4AF668A3B14C118028E2A641F1F8C8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Application</header><text>Paragraph (1) shall not apply to the issuance of a covered rule by an agency that—</text> <subparagraph id="idAD0B1331494146AAA1F2A1947B6902C6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>relates to the internal policy or practice of the agency or procurement by the agency; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idDC4CA1A0C5D64F47A2C618ED82E8A11E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is being revised to be less burdensome to decrease requirements imposed by the covered rule or the cost of compliance with the covered rule.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7F0BB30F7A7A40C2A98DE37668C03410"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Considerations for repealing rules</header><text>In determining whether to repeal a covered rule under subparagraph (A)(i) or (B)(i) of subsection (b)(1), the head of the agency that issued the covered rule shall consider—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB7F0FCBA32B94C929E403B1792D84F0F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>whether the covered rule achieved, or has been ineffective in achieving, the original purpose of the covered rule;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB27B4EB2BE9E463F9A765B68952407AC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any adverse effects that could materialize if the covered rule is repealed, in particular if those adverse effects are the reason the covered rule was originally issued;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id6148eaa0c54f4bd9b2d705f3bf54437b"><enum>(3)</enum><text>whether the costs of the covered rule outweigh any benefits of the covered rule to the United States;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idA8562A45035E4EACB797FFAFB8CFB9AF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>whether the covered rule has become obsolete due to changes in technology, economic conditions, market practices, or any other factors; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id3F86A8F076E34601A3B999F1FC590FF0"><enum>(5)</enum><text>whether the covered rule overlaps with a covered rule to be issued by the agency.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5AAFAE81E52D42B7A27D72AD04F89665"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Publication of covered rules in Unified Agenda</header> <paragraph id="id957A99CC1CEB4EBBBE35036B6B617E84"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>Each agency shall, on a semiannual basis, submit jointly and without delay to the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs for publication in the Unified Agenda a list containing—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id9575414182FA4B279F01A23E7129681E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>each covered rule that the agency intends to issue during the 6-month period following the date of submission;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9F85139F2CAD42429739F703721B1699"><enum>(B)</enum><text>each covered rule that the agency intends to repeal or amend in accordance with subsection (b) during the 6-month period following the date of submission; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF107CF0459864344816E009F6B4B19BE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the cost of each covered rule described in subparagraphs (A) and (B).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id5658788F72BA44288D2B4A2273F64D64"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>An agency may not issue a covered rule unless the agency complies with the requirements under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


