<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S479 IS: To amend the National Trails System Act to direct the Secretary of the Interior to conduct a study on the feasibility of designating the Chief Standing Bear National Historic Trail, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 479</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150212">February 12, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S357">Mrs. Fischer</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the National Trails System Act to direct the Secretary of the Interior to conduct a study
			 on the feasibility of designating the Chief Standing Bear National
			 Historic Trail, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H4C5448CDE2DC45E0A65BA1CDDF35BB63" style="OLC">
 <section id="H7D468C25773741AB91655C115B570C2B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Chief Standing Bear national historic trail feasibility study</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 5(c) of the National Trails System Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1244">16 U.S.C. 1244(c)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block id="HA542AF45A4CF446FAE08F4C30B6E0318" style="OLC">
				<paragraph id="HE8531746193645D8A4B3466657045D6D"><enum>(46)</enum><header>Chief Standing Bear national historic trail</header>
 <subparagraph id="HBA7D95DF20EA4674860AD3D24B66ADC2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Chief Standing Bear Trail, extending approximately 550 miles from Niobrara, Nebraska, to Ponca City, Oklahoma, which follows the route taken by Chief Standing Bear and the Ponca people during Federal Indian removal, and approximately 550 miles from Ponca City, Oklahoma, through Omaha, Nebraska, to Niobrara, Nebraska, which follows the return route taken by Chief Standing Bear and the Ponca people, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Chief Standing Bear National Historic Trail Feasibility Study</quote>, numbered 903/125,630, and dated November 2014.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC13723CF45434188A8964C975D5D281F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Availability of map</header><text>The map described in subparagraph (A) shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the Department of the Interior.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H08629898A36A4B7398EE1A5BC869E2C2"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Components</header><text>The feasibility study conducted under subparagraph (A) shall include a determination on whether the Chief Standing Bear Trail meets the criteria described in subsection (b) for designation as a national historic trail.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id19154FFE3F344649B9769001DCFB151E"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In conducting the feasibility study under subparagraph (A), the Secretary of the Interior shall consider input from owners of private land within or adjacent to the study area.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill>


