<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S2304 IS: Tribal Early Childhood, Education, and Related Services Integration Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-11-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 2304</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151118">November 18, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S314">Mr. Tester</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S353">Mr. Schatz</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SLIA00">Committee on Indian Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To provide for tribal demonstration projects for the integration of early childhood development,
			 education, including Native language and culture, and related
			 services, for evaluation of those demonstration projects, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Tribal Early Childhood, Education, and Related Services Integration Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="id1d5031aa79bf4f79a31bd956edb7ab88"><enum>2.</enum><header>Tribal early childhood demonstration projects</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Native American Programs Act of 1974 is amended by inserting after section 805 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2991d">42 U.S.C. 2991d</external-xref>) the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id537966fa913249c58e1ed508fbf412d4" style="OLC">
				<section id="id129bf5549fed4632a4d134e92afe539a"><enum>805A.</enum><header>Tribal early childhood demonstration projects</header>
 <subsection id="idf27e822b1fde40179e1d77ab3a571850"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of this section are—</text> <paragraph id="id1a3523f24ce84876ae24d38f1e485d66"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to promote coordination of tribal early childhood education programs to meet the locally determined needs of tribal communities, children, and families, consistent with tribal values and traditions;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idcc4be37bb85c49fdb48982caa7172be6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to support integration of quality early childhood and family support systems, including data systems, across various tribal programs that serve Indian children, pregnant women, parents, primary caregivers, and families, from pregnancy to kindergarten entry;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id723f2434e0814c3a991b8a46f80ef8a0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to strengthen the integration of Native languages and cultures into tribal early childhood education programs, services, and support;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idfba2e7fecb8e4e2f80158425c823cb7f"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to identify and address real and perceived barriers to collaboration and systems improvement across tribal early childhood education programs;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id0f01862ca34c45b4ba9cd2f9da322d1a"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to foster—</text> <subparagraph id="id6D74AE21CCE64CF9AA1DC4831E599CBD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>further development in tribal communities of culturally informed early childhood education programs;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD83742737A8F47D7ABAF696C5E94E62C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ongoing research and continuous improvement in the quality of early childhood educational and professional development; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idFF0586B053F74E5DB6A5A3B912ADFB32"><enum>(C)</enum><text>effective evidence- or research-based practices in tribal communities;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5ea073c1125e415b9048388eab290b05"><enum>(6)</enum><text>to develop, test, and disseminate integrated locally designed and innovative tribal early childhood education program variations that meet the needs of the tribal community in accordance with this section; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id298399897b044bf99074de9c52d7a4e4"><enum>(7)</enum><text>to increase the quality and availability of comprehensive tribal early childhood education services available to Indian children and families, including increasing—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idE99526E6FFF44867A5A00E5B8C3731B9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of Indian children and families receiving high-quality services; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB760775525644C1BB5FF865F322004F6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the availability of full-day, full-year preschool services in tribal communities.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idf218747bd95945d8a04393c33fd9e081"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text>
 <paragraph id="id574BB96C2E3F421C9F2EEA33050A8D0B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Demonstration program</header><text>The term <term>demonstration program</term> means the program established under subsection (c).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id6132D9A8A0E44C52B5E2A298F0894782"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Demonstration project</header><text>The term <term>demonstration project</term> means a project carried out under subsection (d).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id78664dc0e1da4762b01e6c7f2d186b0f"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Early childhood education program</header><text>The term <term>early childhood education program</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="id776117cf8c724965aa296ec7ca18ebd0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a Head Start program or an Early Head Start program carried out under the Head Start Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9831">42 U.S.C. 9831 et seq.</external-xref>), including—</text>
 <clause id="idD41AD0466FED42158234E169B065B9EF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a migrant or seasonal Head Start program;</text> </clause><clause id="id76582457435F46F8972F124FB7E7C524"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an Indian Head Start program; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="id56DE0CB805634FCC90D262347FBCCA63"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a Head Start program or an Early Head Start program that receives State or tribal funding in addition to Federal funding;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4c617038c4aa459fbeb8ea3e60f89292"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a State or tribally licensed or regulated child care program; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd0f6464a413542c8b120eda67ecddcdb"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a program that—</text>
 <clause id="idbe83cc75010f4c39b1ecbcd3929974b6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>serves children from birth through age 6;</text> </clause><clause id="idFC772848ACA14AD08B1130F040F1D93F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>addresses the cognitive (including language, early literacy, and early mathematics), social, emotional, and physical development of children; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="ida5e3e92cb2af4147a009c167ad242573"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is—</text> <subclause id="id1c17bddebc404a1181608b7e2872e6dd"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a State or tribal prekindergarten program;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id843cbcd14afd435fb34d8a59f1217619"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a program authorized under section 619 or part C of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1419">20 U.S.C. 1419</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1431">20 U.S.C. 1431 et seq.</external-xref>);</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id4ed7745261d8467ca57e8c9ca581b412"><enum>(III)</enum><text>a program operated by a local educational agency; or</text> </subclause><subclause id="id6dedcc29f5ce48deb3cfc86c048967ed"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>a program operated by an Indian tribe.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id613436aa98db4ec8ba15b957755332a9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="id944f85f2ac854c9f80a6803d3bc64140"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an Indian tribe;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id106234f064af4f63a865a6e6b7877e34"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a tribal organization, including—</text> <clause id="idEE755EB8C78A4E08A6CFCCF246B1A391"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a tribal education agency (as defined in section 3 of the National Environmental Education Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/5502">20 U.S.C. 5502</external-xref>)) designated by an Indian tribe; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id037E4FCA3CBD4A2EB1CEAB1DCE594321"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a Tribal College or University designated by an Indian tribe; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida039ea64cd524e20bbfb75c23d5b925a"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a consortium that includes as the primary member an entity described in subparagraph (A) or (B).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide76538b40e334f8f9545ccaea3a3d992"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Eligible underlying program</header><text>The term <term>eligible underlying program</term> means any program described in subsection (e).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id1a58a43497694734a591c1fdf26c4f1a"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Grantee</header><text>The term <term>grantee</term> means the eligible entity carrying out a demonstration project using financial assistance provided under subsection (c).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idb55b22d29acf4b9ba3c67d9abcf1feac"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Indian</header><text>The term <term>Indian</term> has the meaning given the term in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/450b">25 U.S.C. 450b</external-xref>).</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="idce28cdfdaa724b67924eb75e81d958d9"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Indian tribe</header>
 <subparagraph id="idf9d45d9eef3241c797d1f121fc81030e"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>Indian tribe</term> has the meaning given the term in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/450b">25 U.S.C. 450b</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd276d4045a654872a5ad933142e9ee4f"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusion</header><text>The term <term>Indian tribe</term> includes a tribal organization that is designated by an Indian tribe.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id4BE5AA007BBD4B01A100F425402E486C"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Tribal College or University</header><text>The term <term>Tribal College or University</term> has the meaning given the term in section 316(b) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1059c">20 U.S.C. 1059c(b)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ida37679a4da154b09af876f78dddfe7df"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Tribal organization</header><text>The term <term>tribal organization</term> has the meaning given the term in section 658P of the Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9858n">42 U.S.C. 9858n</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id8C5B551035474F9F9717C59CE609E927"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Work Group</header><text>The term <term>Work Group</term> means the tribal early childhood demonstration program work group established under subsection (i)(3).</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idcc1db9b08fd84eceb65e8f009d6921ae"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Establishment of demonstration program</header>
 <paragraph id="ida0e996d4f6c14eda87aa687f6d4b6858"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a demonstration program under which the Secretary shall provide to eligible entities financial assistance, using amounts appropriated to the 1 or more underlying eligible programs identified by the eligible entity in the application under subsection (d)(3)(C), for tribal early childhood education demonstration projects.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id5da4d1439a0a416197cf6942b2ea48a3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The Secretary shall select for participation in the demonstration program not more than 10 eligible entities for each fiscal year.</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="id8ad9fbde4956416ab140b920f82d9472"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Duration</header>
 <subparagraph id="id4eb049001f174e2ea0360ed34ef33cac"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B), each grantee shall carry out, during the 5-year period beginning on the date of receipt, a demonstration project described in paragraph (4).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc5c5b37e429c4b8993cae16f682058d1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Extension</header><text>The Secretary may extend the term of a demonstration project under subparagraph (A) for 1 or more additional periods of such time as the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1e19f260f6df43fab13bb638c464e7e1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>To be eligible for participation in the demonstration program under this subsection, an eligible entity shall demonstrate to the satisfaction of the Secretary that the demonstration project proposed to be carried out by the eligible entity is—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id3111e3564ad6449483f2c3ac69814afc"><enum>(A)</enum><text>designed to test or assist in the development of any new approach or method that—</text> <clause id="idbfcc8b0a9df54ddeb10aadcbfed6dcb4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>addresses tribal community needs;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id9c54bbb4b2d14c03b4a5973e7a4472ca"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>aids in overcoming unique tribal community problems impacting the effective delivery of early childhood education and development services;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id50a883f8794b498aa3c82023d3023ccc"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>fosters continuous improvement in the quality of early childhood services and support in tribal communities; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id3dcbb80666484377b1afbf0888e92230"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>enables participating Indian children and families to thrive and succeed in school and otherwise; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf0537442a3b942f0b367a6bd595e1587"><enum>(B)</enum><text>focused on culturally based early childhood education, Native language and cultural revitalization and maintenance, and related services.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idd970d29491614ab1ad4bce992e829fc7"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Waivers</header>
 <subparagraph id="id79a3d465666f4cfd90a39149255d90f6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B), the Secretary shall waive, with respect to a demonstration project, any specific provision of law (including regulations), policy, or procedure described in a waiver requested under subsection (d)(3)(K), if the Secretary determines that—</text>
 <clause id="idb9e3812d34424d4a9d920c6ba8511a01"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the provision, policy, or procedure relates specifically to an eligible underlying program from which the demonstration project receives financial assistance; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idcc0ead1a1f00444495a4cad32639121b"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the waiver—</text> <subclause id="id56a4745f41864a6881001811dcd8770c"><enum>(I)</enum><text>will enhance the ability of the grantee to coordinate and align the eligible underlying program with the demonstration project;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id4f73857f917b40a38ca854f404cf8910"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is consistent with the purposes of this section; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="id8ae8eac25dcf4c5e9ce039e1d20c8b89"><enum>(III)</enum><text>would not jeopardize the health, safety, civil rights, or well-being of the individuals to be served by the demonstration project.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfcd1fa4e4fbe4ef2bcc64bf83ec6835c"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>In carrying out this subsection, the Secretary may not waive—</text> <clause id="id89fb2ab12a82478b8705565c46bc8856"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any specific regulation, policy, or procedure relating to, with respect to center-based or family-based child care operations, a Head Start program or an Early Head Start program carried out under the Head Start Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9831">42 U.S.C. 9831 et seq.</external-xref>); or</text>
 </clause><clause id="idc774d6239265494b833f0b4a66b2853f"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any specific statutory requirement for recipients of Federal funding relating to maintenance of effort or the use of Federal funds to supplement, and not supplant, non-Federal funds.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idff2e6d06cd894a569a9acf2a533a9ab7"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Special rule</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that all demonstration projects carried out under this section respect and incorporate the purposes of each eligible underlying program incorporated by the grantee into the demonstration project.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idced18a3e076b4dcb85f291562106e62e"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Applications</header>
 <paragraph id="idf80623143e464dce9cbb1b8e783a2aaf"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each eligible entity desiring participation in the demonstration program shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id8d95654b9be2485c85a634ed407ff58f"><enum>(2)</enum><header>General application</header><text>An eligible entity may submit 1 general application under this subsection, which shall meet all grant application requirements of each noncompetitively awarded eligible underlying program identified by the eligible entity under paragraph (3)(C).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id78365060191b4b869c59c29673d04716"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Content</header><text>Each application under paragraph (1) shall include a proposal that contains, with respect to the proposed demonstration project—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id07a9cf8eea2b4c468b77df037c2d76f7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an identification of the population to be served by the demonstration project, including—</text> <clause id="id745285a3e6944d31a3ca5f088a2dd431"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an identification of the geographical service area to be covered;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idfe0b571d417f4aedb269a6b9d866bd75"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a comprehensive assessment of early childhood care and development needs within that service area, including a description of the assets of each tribal community benefiting from the demonstration project that will be used to improve project quality and child and family outcomes;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id7885d5e5259347609b85dbb625194fcc"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a description of obstacles to accessing early childhood education opportunities in that service area, such as—</text>
 <subclause id="ide6aa4a5bda5b44d6bccbdd05bb989438"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a shortage of enrollment slots in existing child care or early learning programs;</text> </subclause><subclause id="id63d69ba244f64bde8e4ab12eea874362"><enum>(II)</enum><text>problems in the recruitment and retention of high-quality staff; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idc6969c064ef245429166bd9ac2497c67"><enum>(III)</enum><text>a lack of sufficient transportation or educational facility infrastructure; and</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="id437cbee565e0468b8515e776daa44a92"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a description of the means by which the proposal addresses the items identified in clauses (ii) and (iii);</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id30727bf18af44dd9a3876c3a053ce046"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a plan for improving Indian family and tribal community engagement and consultation services, including a description of—</text>
 <clause id="id20e5dfb574b04ed696c764902b14c565"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the methods the demonstration project—</text> <subclause id="id1f59e89cb29b4d72b12b810534911b5b"><enum>(I)</enum><text>has implemented for effective engagement with Indian families and tribal community members living in the covered geographical service area during development of the demonstration project application through the notice and public comment process; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idb661cd92b88f4435a7aff03380ef0ac1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>will use to continue consultation and engagement with Indian families and tribal community members living in the covered geographical service area during implementation of the demonstration project; and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="id76b8c13606ce4ddfb442ce4d6e6b940a"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>how the demonstration project will engage Indian parents in partnerships to reach proposal goals;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1355eb57ecbb4a3bb616ea1622ecc978"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an identification of the 1 or more eligible underlying programs selected by the eligible entity for inclusion in the proposed demonstration project;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfe7e87cf3f594898940f6b77c8a6e91c"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a description of the framework for center-based and family-based early childhood educational programing to be used by the demonstration project, including a description of how the demonstration project will coordinate with the eligible underlying programs proposed under subparagraph (C) to promote in the applicable tribal community—</text>
 <clause id="id1e637fef36934c0a80b0a31d31ebe982"><enum>(i)</enum><text>school readiness;</text> </clause><clause id="id39029a134a4a4ea6975905978b1a8b69"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>family engagement;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id079ddd048381400d90e9505e3ae1aae2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>parenting skills; and</text> </clause><clause id="idcef541250860466da7f6cf177b5783e8"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>healthy child development;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id80a1e412741d4e36960e0ffca765b666"><enum>(E)</enum><text>an explanation of the role of Native language and culture in the demonstration project;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idaf196af681244914b3eeb9ad6c9ff381"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a description of data that will be collected for monitoring and evaluation purposes, including—</text>
 <clause id="id7c8b20e7432f47e3bddb48740f51f1d7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the methods and systems for data collection and management;</text> </clause><clause id="idcc43e8c3e8a24afa9f830bf500628ee6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>identified metrics that will be used to measure progress toward proposal goals;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id0ae2054724f34fe39248cbe7230e1890"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any duplicative data or administrative systems that will be streamlined through integration with the eligible underlying programs; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id8db9080358cf43dfab5e7fe57ec01b27"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the precautions that will be used to ensure the privacy of participants who have data collected in accordance with the applicable privacy requirements of—</text>
 <subclause id="id09011b4e112a4144a20f268b180e2389"><enum>(I)</enum><text>section 444 of the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1232g">20 U.S.C. 1232g</external-xref>); and</text> </subclause><subclause id="idb5f0ae0868554a9591151a49ba04c53d"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/201">42 U.S.C. 201 et seq.</external-xref>);</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id893e047a93f94f10b281714483fd0127"><enum>(G)</enum><text>a description of technical assistance and training the eligible entity will need to further develop or implement the monitoring and evaluation portion of the proposal;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide979def15e5c4dfe9906f08f4d703a9c"><enum>(H)</enum><text>a description of how programming funded under the demonstration project will address child and family mental health issues, including issues relating to violence and substance abuse;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id286e2e30504b426389f941e840432e73"><enum>(I)</enum><text>an assurance that the total projected expenditures of the demonstration project will be reflected in a single comprehensive budget;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1933fa0c4abc4c11a6b8b446254bd13a"><enum>(J)</enum><text>an identification of the specific tribal entity to administer and implement the delivery of services using the funds received from the underlying eligible programs identified under subparagraph (C); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6ce275ecb093431191baf80bbd8e1a6f"><enum>(K)</enum><text>an identification and explanation of any specific provision of law (including regulations), policy, or procedure of an eligible underlying program identified under subparagraph (C) for which the eligible entity requests a waiver.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ideaa270fb30ac406eb423d35700fdd60c"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Approval or disapproval</header>
 <subparagraph id="iddc274c7c02424ddbae9afa6c3e7091e6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after receipt of an application under this subsection, the Secretary shall notify an applicant in writing of whether the application has been approved or denied.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ided1ee6982a964415948172bbb5d94bae"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Notification requirements</header><text>In each notification under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall include—</text> <clause id="id5147f0063f3c4c6c9358d5f3eb1b33ee"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for each approved application—</text>
 <subclause id="ida1b8ab29e7a94d06b0ef6c96c7fb6bcb"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the terms and conditions of the approval in accordance with paragraph (7); and</text> </subclause><subclause id="idf247cd4f22894557b0f6172b1e59394e"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a notification of whether any waiver request included in the application under paragraph (3)(K) has been approved or denied in accordance with subsection (c)(5); and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="ideebf39ed068f458eb3839d5ab3ef7c4b"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for each disapproved application or waiver request, the reasons for the disapproval.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id6972374f0ba74331869158ec916a9808"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Application amendments</header> <subparagraph id="id01cb2e368bbb4a74a5fc56548b3ccbce"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A grantee may submit to the Secretary a proposed amendment to an application approved under this subsection, including any amendment to a waiver request submitted under paragraph (3)(K), at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may require.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida710428526f94d78ae7b7ba4cb313298"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Approval</header><text>Subject to paragraph (6), not later than 60 days after the date of receipt of a proposed amendment under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall provide to the grantee a written notice describing whether the proposed amendment has been approved or disapproved.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id228ca1f6b6564e569b20746ae02441c1"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Appeal of secretarial  decisions</header>
 <subparagraph id="idd230b63ee32a4f94a7c43366805cf5f5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A grantee may appeal a determination of the Secretary to disapprove a waiver request under subsection (c)(5) or an amendment request under paragraph (5)(B)—</text>
 <clause id="id60f4044a54e84028a2deb3cf64c7fdbb"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by amending and resubmitting to the Secretary the request and explanation in accordance with paragraph (3)(K) or (5), as applicable; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="id6ca364071c1d4a52ab268a79579e9075"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by requesting reconsideration of the request.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8232c820361249e190dee38bcc4e05a3"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Timeframe</header><text>An appeal under subparagraph (A) shall be submitted to the Secretary by not later than the 30 days after the date of receipt of a notification of disapproval of—</text>
 <clause id="idCBC875D02DE140C5A5BFB6CFFCC530ED"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a waiver request under paragraph (4)(B)(i)(II); or</text> </clause><clause id="id19F30B6DAC4742E58607EEBC687797A5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an amendment request under paragraph (5)(B).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5a1354b38b0144e5af96df1fefa6e525"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Final determination</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of receipt of an appeal under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall provide to the grantee a written notice of the final approval or disapproval status of the waiver or amendment request, as applicable.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide1d23a4276cb427c8057ab2323c09a21"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Terms and conditions</header>
 <subparagraph id="idc26580f371f446aebf768fe829ababbd"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall include in each notification of approval of an application under paragraph (4) the terms and conditions of that approval, including—</text>
 <clause id="id3e284a7cb8a541e48df9423e48b202dd"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the date on which the eligible entity may begin implementing the demonstration project;</text> </clause><clause id="idbb99ae2d619f45b68447a75d78f2ac0f"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the services and support to be provided for the demonstration project by the Administration for Children and Families;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id8fee5159d0ad402d9702760925857057"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the responsibilities of the grantee regarding implementation of the demonstration project;</text> </clause><clause id="id49968533a7994ecdbb5d92b560c63956"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the terms of distribution to the demonstration project of funds from the eligible underlying programs identified in the approved application, to be made in accordance with a payment schedule determined by the Secretary; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id374a63acd79348b98e46a80805bc7625"><enum>(v)</enum><text>a requirement that the grantee shall comply with all legal requirements applicable to the eligible underlying programs that have not been waived by the Secretary pursuant to this section.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idc51df429b54d4900b055720d35c9c513"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Selection criteria</header><text>The Secretary may give priority to a demonstration project of sufficient scope and scale to be the basis of a thorough evaluation of any new approach or alternative method that best—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id778c43eff0024fc8a8c6eb2751befd7c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>addresses the unique challenges and barriers to effective and efficient programming; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4d810dc2f738479c9618f3dc76fd1269"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensures access to high-quality early childhood education services in tribal communities.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ide80e47a3d41341abb1f8bc6af8059e53"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Eligible underlying programs</header>
 <paragraph id="id1f91a062e50e460e81b6c44204e71e78"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A program eligible to be an underlying program from which a demonstration project receives financial assistance shall be 1 of the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="id624646d3ddf7411991e7a6ef808fd636"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The social and economic development strategies program carried out under section 803.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id41a45a2ac2b24c9792321dbc19c74d4a"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Native American language preservation and maintenance program carried out under section 803C, including the Esther Martinez initiative.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0f8dbdb5bddc4944b16f5f40c11a99da"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The early childhood infrastructure development grant program carried out under section 805B(c).</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id43c44d80c1c94a4aa17f5bd28f949f7d"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The early childhood professional development grant program carried out under section 805B(d).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3f85f58321c84344a28e88015b42ec3c"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The program of block grants to States and Indian tribes for temporary assistance for needy families for funding for childcare carried out under section 418 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/618">42 U.S.C. 618</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id02d3d3ff2a6141bc985e15109afbcbe7"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The tribal maternal, infant, and early childhood home visiting program carried out under section 511 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/711">42 U.S.C. 711</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcc43a371037242dfb54ada406c5cceb6"><enum>(G)</enum><text>A Head Start program or an Early Head Start program carried out under the Head Start Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9831">42 U.S.C. 9831 et seq.</external-xref>) (except if there has been a determination under section 641(c)(7)(A)(iii) of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9836">42 U.S.C. 9836(c)(7)(A)(iii)</external-xref>) that the Head Start or Early Head Start agency of the Indian tribe submitting an application under subsection (d) has not been delivering a high-quality and comprehensive Head Start or Early Head Start program).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7e41f30619814c339d8795aba2a2ed1c"><enum>(H)</enum><text>The child care and development block grant program carried out under the Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9858">42 U.S.C. 9858 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbd8dabe5b95e4be2b2c0d91d01c5c10b"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Any additional program identified by the Secretary under paragraph (2).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id73c8377f977548f8a05b1adfda02f09b"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional programs</header> <subparagraph id="id60b15d2361434e279dc7d2580855d77c"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>After consultation with the Work Group, the Secretary may include in a report under subsection (f)(2) a proposal to designate any additional program administered by the Secretary of Health and Human Services as an eligible underlying program for purposes of the demonstration program under this section, subject to the condition that the additional program shall be consistent with the purposes of the demonstration program.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfebe97089ffe472190a91ca88907e51a"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Deemed approval</header><text>If Congress fails to act on a proposal of the Secretary under subparagraph (A) by the date that is 180 days after the date of receipt of the applicable report, the proposal shall be deemed to be approved by Congress.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id6dc842e251d544d5b1a8d51fca33dcf6"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header>
						<paragraph id="id4c744276545947b092535804869be849"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible entities</header>
 <subparagraph id="idc5c88be1dae7460f88836109d7fa532d"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each grantee shall submit to the Secretary semiannual reports describing the progress achieved and monitoring conducted by the grantee in carrying out the demonstration project.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc051f36c5e2540429f086d39eab81d7c"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Report contents</header><text>Subject to subsection (g)(4)(B), each report submitted under subparagraph (A) shall include, with respect to the period covered by the report—</text>
 <clause id="id049504547f81469f878080aa09736823"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an identification of—</text> <subclause id="idFD376AEDCB9A44EBA7B811C68756CF69"><enum>(I)</enum><text>all uses of Federal funding, including all major activities and accomplishments; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idD3912FE7B2AE4C699C987A6908311332"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any problems in the implementation of the demonstration project, including any delays and actions taken to address the problems;</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="idf83edbffba834c748f938d2ad7666faf"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a description of—</text> <subclause id="id28ADA9B30220410285D80B9D3C81DF4B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>all services provided to children and families under the demonstration project, including—</text>
 <item id="iddd691f50f31a4b229d27f4d0622abd3d"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the number of children and families directly benefiting from the services; and</text> </item><item id="idb03ecb8265754dd3aa37a54f753fbb20"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the qualifications and credentials of the employees of the demonstration project;</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause id="idaefd8549301240c2be8b2e3e1e432fd9"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the progress of the specific objectives of the demonstration project; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="id37d76783adca47749f80fa58bb79cf3b"><enum>(III)</enum><text>activities planned under the demonstration project for the following reporting period; and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="id504cbfea89994f7a943e346178345f32"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any additional information the Secretary determines to be necessary—</text> <subclause id="id226d856c40a64f60a7c13a76ade88665"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to support the objectives of the demonstration project; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="ida0d37bebda9847679c83d0972ceb8839"><enum>(II)</enum><text>to ensure appropriate use of Federal funding.</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2a60296d8dcf4557b0e1f5e33da46cd4"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Standard form</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the Work Group, shall develop a standard report form—</text>
 <clause id="id6f99f8d65ed44291b8420ac9b97e7c0a"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to be used by all eligible entities to achieve compliance with this paragraph; and</text> </clause><clause id="idda7bbe16b28143f797ba628f64e58584"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that can be used with respect to any eligible underlying program.</text>
								</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1df2dddd4a2d44a99cc57115db4910e1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretarial reports to Congress</header>
 <subparagraph id="id4826159dd6664181bdf6060879c0ed33"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 5 years after the date on which the first demonstration project is implemented under this section, and not less frequently than once every 5 years thereafter for the duration of the demonstration program, the Secretary shall submit to the congressional committees described in subparagraph (B) a report that describes—</text>
 <clause id="id2b9ae2b70bca4208b0b25a6a2c61d17e"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any evidence-based developments achieved as a result of the demonstration program under this section;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idb5da6dd563264e3297b98355cb364506"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the progress and impacts of the demonstration projects carried out under this section; and</text> </clause><clause id="id0c809263b5ae44769a7ec77adbdea782"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>with respect to the initial report required under this subparagraph, a recommendation regarding the ways in which the application process for competitively awarded eligible underlying programs can be reduced and streamlined for grantees under this section.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id56f49ed1c69a403fb11700827d9e8aee"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Congressional committees</header><text>The congressional committees referred to in subparagraph (A) are—</text> <clause id="id0d3074279e984978a04f0c7189fa6e25"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the Senate—</text>
 <subclause id="id1F22E2E904F64C71811497F933BE3689"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the Committee on Indian Affairs; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="id326d3e947f944998a52ad64923f7e56b"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions; and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="id58e023148383467c99b56268b5c5e1a1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the House of Representatives—</text> <subclause id="id5481E7DA47B64960BF2DE05051B0827F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the Subcommittee on Indian, Insular and Alaska Native Affairs; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id69c4ae9abb9d4542827f93193d384210"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id40333a1f86f94202a183ddaa0339aa23"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Monitoring and oversight; termination</header> <paragraph id="idbda5717649524db09613b365d0eb2856"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary, in consultation with the Work Group, shall implement a coordinated monitoring and oversight system that applies to all eligible underlying programs, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id1ea2909056f54e2ea0b431d760729dd9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>review of the reports described in subsection (f); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idde3f0b905cf545f29f5ddf8ef19f7f7b"><enum>(B)</enum><text>onsite visits to demonstration projects, as the Secretary determines to be necessary.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id84af17d2ce134e1884d6d64b718c58e3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Compliance</header><text>For each demonstration project, the Secretary shall use the reports described in subsection (f) and other relevant information as the basis for determining whether a grantee has complied with—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id745026a0825b4a29a23452bdff1d8d18"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the terms and conditions of the demonstration project; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd0d7f03fc7fa48ea916524d252665cb3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any policy, procedure, or guidance issued under paragraph (4).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id19a52d24b373466fa86d0c943ca3fe39"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The Secretary may terminate funding to a demonstration project if—</text> <subparagraph id="id65ae2daee56a4f659672c8d0c3e51555"><enum>(A)</enum><text>pursuant to the monitoring and oversight system under paragraph (1), the Secretary determines that—</text>
 <clause id="id0349ee1c64744524b2ed5ba2776acced"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the implementation of the demonstration project deviates significantly from the approved application without the prior approval of the Secretary;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id22c40d07df9e43c38e8b61c0cf46a1e0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>noncompliance under paragraph (2) has occurred; and</text> </clause><clause id="idcb5c75c1ff014d4da2d617fd6abcfc05"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the grantee has failed to correct the noncompliance described in clause (ii) after sufficient opportunity, as determined by the Secretary, to correct the noncompliance; or</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7fc340aeb98a478482f73f678ceee4e1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the grantee submits to the Secretary a written request to terminate the demonstration project, including an explanation of the reasons for termination, as required by the Secretary.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id7abd8032b9244106ad2e58420ca9cb06"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Policies and procedures</header>
 <subparagraph id="id5d55b1d244744c958634134946b493e2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B), the Secretary may issue policies, procedures, and guidance relating to performance-based standards of accountability and internal controls necessary for a grantee and eligible underlying program to ensure appropriate use of Federal funding.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9ffe7cd83dfb45aa884522ac286df1c2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Restriction</header><text>The Secretary shall not require a grantee to maintain a separate record for each eligible underlying program that traces the use of funds by the demonstration project back to each individual eligible underlying program.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0578e9f49a8e43f796d4b0cebeec28f4"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Evaluation criteria</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with Indian tribes and grantees, shall develop and promulgate regulations prescribing the parameters and evaluation criteria for assessing the quality of a demonstration project.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id3c2323eab3654c1e9cc79e0ab8ff6c46"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Funding</header>
						<paragraph id="id74758fd88d534937a414437afe610ff3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Allocation</header>
 <subparagraph id="id2b8e1459f7cc45569d105cefca283821"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Assistant Secretary for Children and Families (referred to in this subsection as the <term>Secretary</term>), shall distribute to each grantee financial assistance using amounts appropriated to each applicable eligible underlying program identified by the grantee in the application under subsection (d)(3) in proportions to be determined by the Secretary.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6cc2df8a413148e58a49d4c6abc2266c"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Determination</header><text>The Secretary shall determine the amounts allocated to each grantee from each applicable eligible underlying program using the funding schedules or formulas employed by the applicable eligible underlying program.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1050fbeddf8e41be8c7c4677bbe526b8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Unused funds</header>
 <subparagraph id="id2011d580fb794987af55fe04ba3a3d0d"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any grant amounts that are not obligated or expended by the grantee on or before September 30 of the fiscal year for which the amounts were distributed under paragraph (1) shall remain available to the grantee until September 30 of the following fiscal year.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id222fd2d71e0f4bc28d280d89eabc915e"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Reversion of funds</header><text>Any grant amounts that are not obligated or expended by the grantee on or before the deadline described in subparagraph (A) shall revert to the Secretary for reallocation to the eligible underlying programs in the original proportions described in paragraph (1).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idf4f41f4fb4a747c48ffa9fd668b64e71"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, of amounts available to the Secretary and not otherwise obligated, the Secretary shall reserve each fiscal year $3,000,000 for administration of the demonstration program, of which—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id28f62c496b004b9aa2763c816cabee56"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not less than 80 percent shall be used for technical assistance and evaluation capacity building activities under subsection (i); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id889c0b38352845dc9c3d8e94d16aa8de"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not more than 20 percent shall be used for oversight, grant application technical assistance, and demonstration program evaluation.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idf837ded620e84f8db86995e42555375d"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Consolidation of funds</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a grantee may consolidate financial assistance received from each eligible underlying program, subject to the condition that the grantee shall stipulate in the application under subsection (d)(3) that the grantee shall use the funds for the respective statutory and integrated purposes of the eligible underlying programs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idcc6c93c2e68f42f4b5b1645490b4eb42"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Administrative costs</header><text>A grantee may use not more than 15 percent of the total amount of financial assistance received under this section for administrative costs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id2037d1a9bc2745f393c43e2762f6d6a9"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Funding level maintenance</header><text>The Secretary shall not reduce the amount of funding allocated to an eligible underlying program as a result of the eligible underlying program being part of a demonstration project.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id6a7d63e020db4cf398f0d26a3fe39ab3"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Technical assistance and training</header>
 <paragraph id="id489480dee7c541828bcd970286ca26ca"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the Work Group, shall provide to grantees technical assistance and training relating to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idccaf539d61ed408d90718136527ee98e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>demonstration project administration;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id60c2c2236898454fb9da44020657ef91"><enum>(B)</enum><text>monitoring and evaluation capacity development;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide57ee9237bfd495bb024e739d47258b8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>coordination with tribal, Federal, State, and local agencies; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id32a708acbf9c45ea8dcf91bffad5d2fb"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any other activity to achieve the objectives of this section that is—</text>
 <clause id="idd5e5b990e6a54274b41d63ee7c33f8c5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>authorized by the Secretary; or</text> </clause><clause id="id8dae0caa4e80476598d5f3b59373e059"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>recommended by the Work Group.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idc0de90839cb34eca83cd0fcccc284f1c"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Coordination assistance</header><text>The Secretary may provide to an entity approved by the Work Group financial assistance to carry out—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id25d28fa1719e4180aa8e17e24da46023"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an evaluation of the demonstration program to quantify any changes resulting from the demonstration program, based on performance indicators and outcome measurements used by grantees to evaluate progress in achieving the objectives of each demonstration project;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id137624cbe9b94bedb5c16780e3588c3b"><enum>(B)</enum><text>development and implementation of unified data collection and reporting systems;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idab1dbe092a224d62821bcdc775e7d679"><enum>(C)</enum><text>semiannual training and technical assistance meetings and other activities sponsored by the Administration for Children and Families; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5c0cd5698a3442f5b40c1096f27346ee"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any other technical assistance and training activity authorized under paragraph (1).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idad91dc79cae042c8a4623a640f1c564c"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Tribal early childhood work group</header> <subparagraph id="id67becd9b84a440f48eaa248b3b4bb921"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To assist in achieving the purposes of the demonstration program under this section, the Secretary shall establish a tribal early childhood demonstration program work group.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddf58d3624391418aa8f56fd71dff6587"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>The Work Group shall be comprised of representatives of—</text> <clause id="idbd03a954cc4746a4b37541ab420d114a"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the National Indian Child Care Association;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id040e2023bdea4dcb92956af69e7a905a"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Early Head Start Tribal Partnership;</text> </clause><clause id="idC8B2E936169D44DBBCC554DFC0D13361"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the National Indian Head Start Directors Association;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idf2f2693014454eeb9fb3df496a161449"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the Indian Health Service;</text> </clause><clause id="idb2eb556a28674651ae6fd90f63caa762"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Tribal Child Care Development Fund Program Administrators;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id0a548fd29e624f078745064b0d9a328c"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>early childhood research centers with expertise in tribal early childhood programs, including the Tribal Early Childhood Research Center at the University of Colorado;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id7606a4f0e06e4794831cbc1b44c89772"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>to the extent feasible, a diverse sampling of Indian tribes participating in the demonstration program under this section;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id424C1595AE5A417BAAD900B5A8DF4D20"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>the Administration for Native Americans;</text> </clause><clause id="idfd91e8369d244b9f9f6498bec4aa99df"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>the Tribal Home Visiting Program; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id9b1d106df031468d9c2675d2a179bcbb"><enum>(x)</enum><text>such other organizations, agencies, and entities as the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idaea3942d47c047ceb37670eff54720a0"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Work Group shall advise the Secretary regarding the development and implementation of—</text>
 <clause id="id8d19547a6f2242a09ff5facf3e47ed7e"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the demonstration project reporting forms described in subsection (f)(1)(C);</text> </clause><clause id="id59eabea2df904bd5ae86e54c9d1477ba"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the coordinated monitoring and oversight system described in subsection (g)(1); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idab0acf0e183f4c5782423c49f5a4488b"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the technical assistance and training described in this section.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id11ed87c0aa2c44d4a8bc0e5a241ad0ee"><enum>805B.</enum><header>Early childhood infrastructure development grant program; early childhood professional development grant program</header> <subsection id="id8f129594d1f44307861c18ccaa75a123"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of this section are—</text>
 <paragraph id="id62a1d8ebcd7c416b8f6ba4bdcc2b442d"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to increase the number of highly qualified early childhood care and development service providers—</text> <subparagraph id="id890ab882c9674e34a07f757f05b74c66"><enum>(A)</enum><text>who are Indian; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida6fb9b6261474723974b33cca3a32a91"><enum>(B)</enum><text>who work for programs serving tribal communities; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ida97eb3ac1f1c40468eb6fffaddec7357"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to ensure tribal early childhood care and development center infrastructure is safe and conducive to serving the needs of the tribal communities that use that infrastructure.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id504684114e9e47f6b35d93a10605a72e"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="id972b7ca2b0614fbcb4fbac1e9ed4b8c5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means a demonstration project carried out under section 805A that identified in the application under subsection (c)(3)(C)(iii) of that section the program carried out under subsection (c) or (d), as applicable, as 1 of the eligible underlying programs to be used by the demonstration project.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id0f21c7a680b24038bdf3481ab8ce1489"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Indian</header><text>The term <term>Indian</term> has the meaning given the term in section 7151 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7491">20 U.S.C. 7491</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idfd68da7b5ef14a3fb78d3594a41f48ed"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Early childhood infrastructure development grant program</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a program under which the Secretary shall make grants to eligible entities—</text>
 <paragraph id="id39de78451007438e850d5855d968ffce"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to build facilities for early childhood care and development centers; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id2a7eb1cdb9374527b70911b4a158d883"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to upgrade existing childhood learning and development facilities.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id8626464d564c49b0b409d3c6912a41bc"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Early childhood professional development grant program</header>
 <paragraph id="id9be2f097b7e346b4b78e93c20d3a5b22"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a program under which the Secretary shall make grants to eligible entities to reimburse early childhood educators for out-of-pocket costs associated with obtaining early childhood certification or credentials.</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="idb5b29ef87927438a8603bc0500cc21e3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Special rule</header>
 <subparagraph id="id992fafdc26c047809bd168683b55fb6b"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Service for reimbursement</header><text>Eligible entities receiving a grant under paragraph (1) shall require early childhood educators who receive reimbursement under the grant to fulfill a period of obligated service with the demonstration project of the eligible entity in accordance with subparagraph (B).</text>
							</subparagraph><subparagraph id="id64f17577f68642179b726b8d2d8f3126"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Period of obligated service</header>
 <clause id="id456b80371465460287cbf851f32fc30d"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall provide each eligible entity receiving a grant under paragraph (1) with a form contract for obligated service that the eligible entity shall use to carry out subparagraph (A).</text>
 </clause><clause id="idf789612d1962484e951a516d3bb3ad12"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>Before receiving reimbursement, the early childhood educator and the eligible entity shall enter into a contract described in clause (i).</text>
								</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id24ce83d6e0834a0ebd0f4dfc2fb5ee54"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Allocation of grants</header>
 <paragraph id="id1cd5850cedcf45db91a547f14b8a9b47"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Early childhood infrastructure development grants</header><text>In making grants under subsection (c), the Secretary shall—</text> <subparagraph id="id55ec720ebc0541d5bcccb84117fead2b"><enum>(A)</enum><text>allocate to an eligible entity such amounts as are requested in the application of the eligible entity; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida8ccf4bf67ce4ac9a6a39d3d8e070ee7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if funding is insufficient to fulfill the total amount requested by all eligible entities, fully fund a selection of eligible entities based on the following criteria:</text>
 <clause id="idd44adef27b854a84ae755f88f0d7a789"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The likelihood of completing the proposed infrastructure project within the timeframe of the demonstration project.</text>
 </clause><clause id="idf6926122b7d448d3acc54b09c07f8b20"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The ability of the infrastructure project to address outstanding health and safety concerns.</text> </clause><clause id="id3252a3bc165442a5b21005939d3d2a96"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Any other criteria identified by the Secretary, in consultation with the tribal early childhood demonstration program work group established under section 805A(i)(3).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id33f8709074164ec59e507b248cad4cc0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Early childhood professional development grant</header><text>In making grants under subsection (d), the Secretary shall—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idFEBF8928F2F6458CA1489E66C38E676B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">allocate to an eligible entity such amounts as are requested in the application of the eligible entity; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id92c93acf9314450f8f521feecd81d582"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if funding is insufficient to fulfill the total amount requested by all eligible entities, allocate funds to each eligible entity based on the proportion that—</text>
 <clause id="id60620E3FCA3141DF8396FAF28E6DA61F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number of children served by the eligible entity; bears to</text>
 </clause><clause id="idDECB08FAD981499F8DBDBA9BCD14D568"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the total number of children served by all eligible entities approved for funding under subsection (d).</text>
								</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id8333d63e6750439eb4f7db0cad96e58b"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
 <paragraph id="id51f04227bf6a4c6cbef15269ca6d8824"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Early childhood infrastructure development grant program</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out subsection (c)—</text> <subparagraph id="idac962932dbb24f68b7b314828580212d"><enum>(A)</enum><text>$4,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2017 through 2021; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6f1a693b61e2452e802f023beaf5bc4f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such sums as are necessary for each fiscal year thereafter.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id84425b80fc4f4d8085d9a21e752d4494"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Early childhood professional development grant program</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out subsection (d)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id4bb26b128a0443d4a036a7a81aeeba39"><enum>(A)</enum><text>$1,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2017 through 2021; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcc6951712ece4e5c8481ccf5ac87f02f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such sums as are necessary for each fiscal year thereafter.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section><section id="id7edf927a3ec64530972e4883c874cb69"><enum>3.</enum><header>Tribal early childhood educator recruitment and retention</header>
			<subsection id="id753c15b99a2a4010942d32575b3f20f5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Loan forgiveness for early childhood educators</header>
 <paragraph id="idfed131bf23a44a419c3f4927af6e7b9f"><enum>(1)</enum><header>FFEL loans</header><text>Section 428J of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1078-10">20 U.S.C. 1078–10</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="idd13486eaaaee4885bffef5a23b94551c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(1)(A), by striking <quote>section 465(a)(2)(A)</quote> and inserting <quote>subparagraph (A) or (B) of section 465(a)(2)</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7b02393d33ec4bcca756c850f4bfc1c6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (c)(3)—</text> <clause id="id373ff9d9f2fc434482ed4fe092630931"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the paragraph heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">or special education</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">special education, or tribal early childhood development programs</header-in-text></quote>;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id887ee88ac47d47cb8f85caaa1511bd51"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)(ii), by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon;</text> </clause><clause id="ide0bb42936c734725918c051601662f21"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)(iii), by striking the period and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id1c281c24103947cdbf2b6ba03b417d65"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF72B2FAD827D424185724FD881A25A55" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="id450eb34f88324169ba159a51deccb0b9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an early childhood teacher—</text>
 <clause id="idd0847546c7e340858bc22150a6437904"><enum>(i)</enum><text>who meets the requirements of subsection (b); and</text> </clause><clause id="idf7567b2d22c84f588aed65c164bbe180"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>whose qualifying employment for purposes of such subsection is in an early childhood learning and development program—</text>
 <subclause id="id946e6adb732c48488f51798b22ffec70"><enum>(I)</enum><text>that is operated by an Indian tribe (as defined in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/450b">25 U.S.C. 450b</external-xref>)); or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idf57190d0d2bc4e3c887117af38c74d63"><enum>(II)</enum><text>that serves a large percentage of Indian children, as defined by the Secretary.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id7a32b35a61eb45cc90111d20fd3bfbf2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federal direct loans</header><text>Section 460 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087j">20 U.S.C. 1087j</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id21570e546148454880f7c577ea31fc37"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(1)(A), by striking <quote>section 465(a)(2)(A)</quote> and inserting <quote>subparagraph (A) or (B) of section 465(a)(2)</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id92d83a31144e4d47abf8401321a24f40"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (c)(3)—</text>
 <clause id="idca8386caf1c94f0190983eedf1b46a68"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the paragraph heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">or special education</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">special education, or tribal early childhood development programs</header-in-text></quote>;</text> </clause><clause id="id52291749fc654f69a063838a9f114bc7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)(ii), by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon;</text>
 </clause><clause id="ideeb47a81c5a24b6c8793e8d0e6d0271c"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)(iii), by striking the period and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text> </clause><clause id="idccff98298cc44f4aa0e6fedf16165128"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
							<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idEAA1734AB0C94F78B3B0F7C3E3A48BE4" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="id8c6d57e7e47b4cce9d3dc4bae92fff82"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an early childhood teacher—</text> <clause id="id16d09926970b44099508a6d936a41dbc"><enum>(i)</enum><text>who meets the requirements of subsection (b); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id5e933440a16b4694bbc2266937dad246"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>whose qualifying employment for purposes of such subsection is in an early childhood learning and development program—</text>
 <subclause id="id239aab1492a14f50b7490e96e9f15370"><enum>(I)</enum><text>that is operated by an Indian tribe (as defined in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/450b">25 U.S.C. 450b</external-xref>)); or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id98c347441e2e4ac28d8cd1830b4c7990"><enum>(II)</enum><text>that serves a large percentage of Indian children, as defined by the Secretary.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idb404764b48d34503add2f4c8abce3f4f"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Cancellation of loans for tribal early childhood educators</header><text>Subparagraph (B) of section 465(a)(2) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087ee">20 U.S.C. 1087ee(a)(2)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idA99D1F7B92F5406BA03165BC3C3CFC6D" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="ide7c279b850164ca3b328f59204d8bc35"><enum>(B)</enum><text>as a full-time staff member with a baccalaureate degree—</text> <clause id="id04a9c2cb10f94a6b89379aa3a6660c1f"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in a preschool program carried out under the Head Start Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9831">42 U.S.C. 9831 et seq.</external-xref>) that is operated for a period which is comparable to a full school year in the locality, if the salary of such staff member is not more than the salary of a comparable employee of the local educational agency for the locality;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id1b5c20b1e3e74830866bf29cb7154f5d"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in a prekindergarten or child care program that is licensed or regulated by the State or an Indian tribe (as defined in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/450b">25 U.S.C. 450b</external-xref>)) that is operated for a period which is comparable to a full school year in the locality, if the salary is not more than the salary of a comparable employee of the local educational agency for the locality;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idb720f448a0194beb8e059e09353683e6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in a center-based early childhood learning or development program operated through the family and child education program of the Bureau of Indian Education; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="id66fd4694a0544a789681591631a1b6e7"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>in an early childhood learning or development center operated by an Indian tribe (as so defined) utilizing funds from—</text>
 <subclause id="idad91b24bd2c94c2f86427b3412f8d0b9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>early childhood learning and development grants awarded under the Native American Programs Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2991">42 U.S.C. 2991 et seq.</external-xref>), including such grants under section 803C, 805A, or 805B of such Act;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id4998df8e545d479ab979cbde641d205f"><enum>(II)</enum><text>grants awarded under the Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9858">42 U.S.C. 9858 et seq.</external-xref>); or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="ida2a1cec2ac644c43b932ab76a7e4e1d1"><enum>(III)</enum><text>any other early childhood learning and development grants administered by the Administration for Children and Families under the Department of Health and Human Services, as determined by the Assistant Secretary for the Administration for Children and Families.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


