<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1431 IS: Prescription Drug Abuse Prevention and Treatment Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1431</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150521">May 21, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S338">Mr. Manchin</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S363">Mr. King</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S372">Mrs. Capito</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To provide for increased Federal oversight of prescription opioid treatment and assistance to
			 States in reducing opioid abuse, diversion, and deaths.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short
 title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Prescription Drug Abuse Prevention and Treatment Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id859C9075063D4BC7885E04EAD9A238CC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Consumer
 education campaign</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part A of title V of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290aa">42 U.S.C. 290aa et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idDE775F7904274E1FB7FA328F22E01F2F" style="OLC">
				<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9B932E7488614EF0A559EBE97A0A4D20"><enum>506C.</enum><header>Consumer
				education campaign</header>
					<subsection id="idCD1171A5FDF4459D813EF0D832BE3726"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>The Administrator shall award grants to States and nonprofit entities for the purpose of conducting culturally sensitive consumer education about opioid abuse, including methadone abuse. Such education shall include information on the dangers of opioid abuse, how to prevent opioid abuse including through safe disposal of prescription medications and other safety precautions, and detection of early warning signs of addiction.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id69DE285753E7465499B111432278B37D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under subsection (a), an entity shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="idB8DBF9E6914D4B5D9F3B95CB5257C57F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be a State or nonprofit entity; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id0D1E5FE29D3249D7820F09AA21A5F6E3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submit to the Administrator an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Administrator may require.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idE68C7ED2DD3B479FA69B24501D38D7C1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding grants under this section, the Administrator shall give priority to applicants that are States or communities with a high incidence of abuse of methadone and other opioids, and opioid-related deaths.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id983ECE9BF57A4FDEAF55F458E7A03BAF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Evaluations</header><text>The Administrator shall develop a process to evaluate the effectiveness of activities carried out by grantees under this section at reducing abuse of methadone and other opioids.</text>
					</subsection><subsection id="idB618761B3C3442C4A4D4918F6E1E82D5"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization
 of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $15,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2016 through 2020.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section><section id="idB841E52D5F6F4C5EA31A72473250C399"><enum>3.</enum><header>Practitioner
			 education</header>
			<subsection id="id8B7D6D827EBE4EE288341FF5AC75B770"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Education
			 requirements</header>
				<paragraph id="idF40363F4D34E470780344E96B276E6DC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Registration
 consideration</header><text>Section 303(f) of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/823">21 U.S.C. 823(f)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after paragraph (5) the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9A222539540F431D87F17F65952099CE" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="idF8549B0EB29E4311940BE308F7F37B4F"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The applicant's compliance with the training requirements described in subsection (g)(3) during any previous period in which the applicant has been subject to such training requirements.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="id4A0FAEE6CBFB4174A5372A0555091A92"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Training
 requirements</header><text>Section 303(g) of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/823">21 U.S.C. 823(g)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE0EC8BC038034886934D991E8F159BBE" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="id9E8D667540424AEE8FBF71B54FAE6619" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id152D303E91B4453A898ECD539E1ED932"><enum>(A)</enum><text>To be registered to prescribe or otherwise dispense methadone or other opioids, a practitioner described in paragraph (1) shall comply with the 12-hour training requirement of subparagraph (B) at least once during each 3-year period.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id820E7B47850244D8B1A61DF3213D5DFC" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The training requirement of this subparagraph is that the practitioner has completed not less than 12 hours of training (through classroom situations, seminars at professional society meetings, electronic communications, or otherwise) with respect to—</text>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idC7B4700CBEED40EE9991EDA2EBF335F2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the treatment and management of opioid-dependent patients;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idA08A553D66CC4119AD1E80A9AF5FDC12"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>pain management treatment guidelines; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id875E2BC82E6E487AB3C9EBD983EBC53A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>early detection of opioid addiction, including through such methods as Screening, Brief Intervention, and Referral to Treatment (SBIRT),</text>
								</clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph" indent="subsection">that is provided by the American Society of Addiction
				Medicine, the American Academy of Addiction Psychiatry, the
			 American Medical
				Association, the American Osteopathic Association, the American
			 Psychiatric
				Association, the American Academy of Pain Management, the American
			 Pain
				Society, the American Academy of Pain Medicine, the American Board
			 of Pain
				Medicine, the American Society of Interventional Pain Physicians,
			 or any other
				organization that the Secretary determines is appropriate for
			 purposes of this
				subparagraph.</continuation-text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id2564391857604306A72223BDF466ED32"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements
 for participation in opioid treatment programs</header><text>Effective July 1, 2016, a physician practicing in an opioid treatment program shall comply with the requirements of section 303(g)(3) of the Controlled Substances Act (as added by subsection (a)) with respect to required minimum training at least once during each 3-year period.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id238B39EE94E9471C8792F33FC619DDFC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <term>opioid treatment program</term> has the meaning given such term in section 8.2 of title 42, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idDC49608A126E4A26BA9278025930F4CC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>The Drug Enforcement Administration shall fund the enforcement of the requirements specified in section 303(g)(3) of the Controlled Substances Act (as added by subsection (a)) through the use of a portion of the licensing fees paid by controlled substance prescribers under the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/801">21 U.S.C. 801 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="id73F22E1951554761BB7056E0AF6BE6E8"><enum>4.</enum><header>Operation of
 opioid treatment programs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 303 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/823">21 U.S.C. 823</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8579CC95626B4A0399CD805B617B784B" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="idCEE928D8EF0C4345A7D3E1591AEF534B"><enum>(i)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id281A6725667D4C1B93DBB589C5730FCF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An opioid treatment program that is registered under this section, and that closes for business on any weekday or weekend day, including a Federal or State holiday, shall comply with the requirements of this subsection.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idAE88C13C77C54402B2669108CBD78672" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The program shall make acceptable arrangements for each patient who is restricted, by Federal regulation or guideline or by the determination of the program medical director, from having a take home dose of a controlled substance related to the treatment involved, to receive a dose of that substance under appropriate supervision during the closure.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id069B4EA4588A4F0D94CA844982651774" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Administrator of the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration shall issue a notice that references regulations on acceptable arrangements under this subsection, or shall promulgate regulations on such acceptable arrangements.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section><section id="id4EB9E6C26F474EA99E3411161DFFD884"><enum>5.</enum><header>Mortality
 reporting</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part A of title V of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290aa">42 U.S.C. 290aa et seq.</external-xref>), as amended by section 3, is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id39BE3ADBEC0842438776903B13088374" style="OLC">
				<section id="id52EA840E9BB8427E8405097136831280"><enum>506D.</enum><header>Mortality
				reporting</header>
					<subsection id="id015C5B75EBD94C42A6C811C6A7236031"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Model Opioid
				Treatment Program Mortality Report</header>
						<paragraph id="id8632F7DB0C3246DE8D1D20F76B786E19"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>Not later than July 1, 2016, the Secretary, acting through the Administrator, shall require that a Model Opioid Treatment Program Mortality Report be completed and submitted to the Administrator for each individual who dies while receiving treatment in an opioid treatment program.</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="id5EE4D6A5E4A049D8AB7AFA6E9581C2D3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirement of
				States that receive funding for the Controlled Substance Monitoring
 Program</header><text>As a condition for receiving funds under section 399O, each State shall require that any individual who signs a death certificate where an opioid drug is detected in the body of the deceased, or where such drug is otherwise associated with the death, report such death to the Administrator by submitting a Model Opioid Treatment Program Mortality Report described in paragraph (3). Such report shall be submitted to the Administrator on or before the later of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id352FE1BD92494EF8977270922B844C99"><enum>(A)</enum><text>90 days after the date of signing the death certificate; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5DCA868CE5344B519F605E6F600CD2FD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>as soon as practicable after the date on which the necessary postmortem and toxicology reports become available to such individual, as required by the Secretary.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id99B936AB6B9240C9AC3538024A218E51"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Development</header><text>The Administrator, in consultation with State and local medical examiners, prescribing physicians, hospitals, and any other organization that the Administrator determines appropriate, shall develop a Model Opioid Treatment Program Mortality Report to be used under paragraphs (1) and (2).</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id2BCA92D39F0E4576B1266606AD7AF25F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>National Opioid
				Death Registry</header>
						<paragraph id="ID1f2a739080644ced857243b6788bb6cf"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>Not later than July 1, 2016, the Administrator shall establish and implement, through the National Center for Health Statistics, a National Opioid Death Registry (referred to in this subsection as the <term>Registry</term>) to track opioid-related deaths and information related to such deaths.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ID8cd2d312ea3345b498fea4c27c0d01a6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In establishing the uniform reporting criteria for the Registry, the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention shall consult with the Administrator, State and local medical examiners, prescribing physicians, hospitals, and any other organization that the Director determines is appropriate for purposes of this subsection.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idEAA47D33A4A74961806F4AE1BCD07435"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The registry shall be designed as a uniform reporting system for opioid-related deaths and shall require the reporting of information with respect to such deaths, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idA9B5BC551DA84AA4BFA29D5FEA0FCEB4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the particular drug formulation used at the time of death;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id809587A7CEEB487C98551C643052BC81"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the dosage level;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idEBCDD848620B48A6B9625180886614E7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a description of the circumstances surrounding the death in relation to the recommended dosage involved;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id15EED006DBF145738485055B7C05E21B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a disclosure of whether the medication involved can be traced back to a physician’s prescription;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD7BD925A70F240228CB6EBEDF0286CCA"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a disclosure of whether the individual was in an opioid treatment program at the time of death;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2F7926D101E64A14A415BEE6CADB14F3"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the age and sex of the individual; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1CDB36F3692D41908EF01A262813AD34"><enum>(G)</enum><text>other non-personal information such as that included in filed National Association of Medical Examiners Pediatric Toxicology Registry case reports as required under the privacy standard for the de-identification of health information pursuant to the regulations contained in part 164 of title 45, Code of Federal Regulations.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id8214AC608DDA42A0BD12A0711781545E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated $5,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2016 through 2020 to carry out this subsection.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idADFC95B8BA7E4222B117CE2230AA75E1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report on
 Registry information</header><text>Not later than the January 1 of the first fiscal year beginning 2 years after the date of enactment of this section, and each January 1 thereafter, the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention shall submit to the Secretary a report, based on information contained in the Registry described in subsection (b), concerning the number of methadone-related deaths in the United States for the year for which the report is submitted.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idCFB72A171D1D44EBA87CB9827B0DF90D"><enum>6.</enum><header>Development of
			 prescription drug abuse prevention and treatment quality measures across
			 each
 relevant provider setting</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subpart I of part D of title IX of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/299b-31">42 U.S.C. 299b–31 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9624C5A3F29D4E0C9061E7D787CB874C" style="OLC">
				<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id13FB78DA79AC4A7487D55A48B1C75DF4"><enum>932.</enum><header>Development of
				prescription drug abuse prevention and treatment quality measures
			 across each
				relevant provider setting</header>
					<subsection id="id557833bf8bbe4ef5aef44b0e1c77509b"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Director of the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality and in consultation with the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, the Administrator of the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration, and the Director of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services, shall require the development and application of specific prescription drug abuse prevention and treatment quality measures for each relevant health care provider setting, as identified by the Director.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id5DDC1E84F0044E7EB73DA5F9F3354F51"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Dissemination</header><text>Not later than April 1, 2016, the Secretary shall disseminate the quality measure requirements developed under subsection (a) to all affected providers.</text>
					</subsection><subsection id="idF6AD1B2CE10E4196B5DD965708008CA3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Types of
 measures</header><text>Quality measures developed under this section may be structure-oriented (such as the required presence of a hospital-based treatment program), process-oriented (such as requiring patients to be informed of the addictive qualities of the medication being prescribed), or outcome-oriented (such as assessing family satisfaction with care).</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section><section id="H5809060EA60D4BA681F6AFBAD99FBA92" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>7.</enum><header>Programs to prevent prescription drug abuse under Medicare part D</header>
			<subsection id="H1E733B2A13A446FABDB644C59332FE10"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Drug management program for at-Risk beneficiaries</header>
 <paragraph id="H455CBE3CEA4541B6BE9CCB702E0D5BB6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1860D–4(c) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-10">42 U.S.C. 1395w–10(c)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0E054CDF3EEF4D508D7F55987EA215AF" style="OLC">
						<paragraph id="HDA7D6F7521524CBE8D659ABE907E278C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Drug management program for at-risk beneficiaries</header>
 <subparagraph id="H3C2C9255FF894C46BA1669C3BCFCEE79"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Authority to establish</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A PDP sponsor may establish a drug management program for at-risk beneficiaries under which, subject to <internal-xref idref="H34B80A9B3AC5411F8E6DF46A809903B9" legis-path="(4)(B)">subparagraph (B)</internal-xref>, the PDP sponsor may, in the case of an at-risk beneficiary for prescription drug abuse who is an enrollee in a prescription drug plan of such PDP sponsor, limit such beneficiary’s access to coverage for frequently abused drugs under such plan to frequently abused drugs that are prescribed for such beneficiary by a prescriber selected under subparagraph (D), and dispensed for such beneficiary by a pharmacy selected under such subparagraph.</text>
							</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H34B80A9B3AC5411F8E6DF46A809903B9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirement for notices</header>
 <clause id="H59453B6E04F84C2D817D67D47C310AA6"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A PDP sponsor may not limit the access of an at-risk beneficiary for prescription drug abuse to coverage for frequently abused drugs under a prescription drug plan until such sponsor—</text>
 <subclause id="HF94C853BAF974F0B98279BBBEB131E02"><enum>(I)</enum><text>provides to the beneficiary an initial notice described in clause (ii) and a second notice described in clause (iii); and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H3E61965907FB4EC6822FD333C8741D13"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">verifies with the providers of the beneficiary that the beneficiary is an at-risk beneficiary for prescription drug abuse.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause commented="no" id="HE28DD284140041EF8281049BAF7A5A34"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Initial notice</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An initial notice described in this clause is a notice that provides to the beneficiary—</text> <subclause commented="no" id="HA1F24AC2F2F24C1FA52B8C12188D6E83"><enum>(I)</enum><text>notice that the PDP sponsor has identified the beneficiary as potentially being an at-risk beneficiary for prescription drug abuse;</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H4B7DF0258A2D46FABBE94C0386687E13"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information describing all State and Federal public health resources that are designed to address prescription drug abuse to which the beneficiary has access, including mental health services and other counseling services;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H289D80C393DE44A5B05F126ABCFC5C6B"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">notice of, and information about, the right of the beneficiary to appeal such identification under subsection (h) and the option of an automatic escalation to external review;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H23BA486143B94C5793B3F0C045A40F02"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a request for the beneficiary to submit to the PDP sponsor preferences for which prescribers and pharmacies the beneficiary would prefer the PDP sponsor to select under subparagraph (D) in the case that the beneficiary is identified as an at-risk beneficiary for prescription drug abuse as described in clause (iii)(I);</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H414B73F73DE8495985025F3CE77235F0"><enum>(V)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an explanation of the meaning and consequences of the identification of the beneficiary as potentially being an at-risk beneficiary for prescription drug abuse, including an explanation of the drug management program established by the PDP sponsor pursuant to subparagraph (A);</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H3F39BC15A3984AC191A55217284373AA"><enum>(VI)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">clear instructions that explain how the beneficiary can contact the PDP sponsor in order to submit to the PDP sponsor the preferences described in subclause (IV) and any other communications relating to the drug management program for at-risk beneficiaries established by the PDP sponsor; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H14A631B115E741E09A03828B665E4640"><enum>(VII)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">contact information for other organizations that can provide the beneficiary with assistance regarding such drug management program (similar to the information provided by the Secretary in other standardized notices provided to part D eligible individuals enrolled in prescription drug plans under this part).</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H3BD173C76F42443B9F827BCEA03F4C72"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Second notice</header><text>A second notice described in this clause is a notice that provides to the beneficiary notice—</text> <subclause id="HD743108F129B402A96DE517DCDEDDF8B"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that the PDP sponsor has identified the beneficiary as an at-risk beneficiary for prescription drug abuse;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H5D6E4D726EB84C17927F5C75EC28E25D"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that such beneficiary is subject to the requirements of the drug management program for at-risk beneficiaries established by such PDP sponsor for such plan;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HE3D6D6A9B8CC4EF185082094A85BE006"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">of the prescriber and pharmacy selected for such individual under <internal-xref idref="HA762203F956F4E508317C52624430EC5" legis-path="(4)(D)">subparagraph (D)</internal-xref>;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H64834B6BD97A4D8CAD0A371809E1957B"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">of, and information about, the beneficiary’s right to appeal such identification under subsection (h) and the option of an automatic escalation to external review;</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H4EBED387DD914ECBAAC1FB8A787DA0CE"><enum>(V)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that the beneficiary can, in the case that the beneficiary has not previously submitted to the PDP sponsor preferences for which prescribers and pharmacies the beneficiary would prefer the PDP sponsor select under subparagraph (D), submit such preferences to the PDP sponsor; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H727C3D494454457A995F3BA19ED60A17"><enum>(VI)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that includes clear instructions that explain how the beneficiary can contact the PDP sponsor.</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H7321F227A8FE4A37B1A40CF03519C2E6"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Timing of notices</header> <subclause id="H244EF68B2E144CE085D10ABB28FF797F"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subclause (II), a second notice described in clause (iii) shall be provided to the beneficiary on a date that is not less than 60 days after an initial notice described in clause (ii) is provided to the beneficiary.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HE8EFC27566DF4CE38A8A6BD3BCE01022"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case that the PDP sponsor, in conjunction with the Secretary, determines that concerns identified through rulemaking by the Secretary regarding the health or safety of the beneficiary or regarding significant drug diversion activities require the PDP sponsor to provide a second notice described in clause (iii) to the beneficiary on a date that is earlier than the date described in subclause (II), the PDP sponsor may provide such second notice on such earlier date.</text>
									</subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1711069A7C3E446B9F63434279FC7228"><enum>(C)</enum><header>At-risk beneficiary for prescription drug abuse</header>
 <clause id="H30E80D8580404C639EFC8A67F257CDEC"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the term <quote>at-risk beneficiary for prescription drug abuse</quote> means a part D eligible individual who is not an exempted individual described in clause (ii) and—</text> <subclause display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H938E4C8377F04845AB809509FA2C1D93"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">who is identified through the use of guidelines developed by the Secretary in consultation with PDP sponsors and other stakeholders described in section 10(f)(2)(A) of the <short-title>Prescription Drug Abuse Prevention and Treatment Act of 2015</short-title>; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HEB27DC5E7F2840E0A8FF4D39A4A92C76"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to whom the PDP sponsor of a prescription drug plan, upon enrolling such individual in such plan, received notice from the Secretary that such individual was identified under this paragraph to be an at-risk beneficiary for prescription drug abuse under the prescription drug plan in which such individual was most recently previously enrolled and such identification has not been terminated under subparagraph (F).</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H84878971636544FFABE04B6DB69FCE00"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Exempted individual described</header><text>An exempted individual described in this clause is an individual who—</text> <subclause id="HB7FE705949C143FFBDB60EFFB7D6790A"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">receives hospice care under this title; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HF18149485E824CBA972956E657E72D03"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the Secretary elects to treat as an exempted individual for purposes of clause (i).</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA762203F956F4E508317C52624430EC5"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Selection of prescribers</header> <clause id="H5810989E58E74D7EB8B5F696944036EF"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to each at-risk beneficiary for prescription drug abuse enrolled in a prescription drug plan offered by such sponsor, a PDP sponsor shall, based on the preferences submitted to the PDP sponsor by the beneficiary pursuant to clauses (ii)(IV) and (iii)(V) of subparagraph (B), select—</text>
 <subclause id="H3FB15BECD3A540D0A88226A954D979EE"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">one or more individuals who are authorized to prescribe frequently abused drugs (referred to in this paragraph as <quote>prescribers</quote>) who may write prescriptions for such drugs for such beneficiary; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H7F74F124EBEE4DCD894D1DDFCAEAF9A0"><enum>(II)</enum><text>one or more pharmacies that may dispense such drugs to such beneficiary.</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H1A11EBB44BA94FDBA628B2D9E5E15982"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Reasonable access</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In making the selection under this subparagraph, a PDP sponsor shall ensure that the beneficiary continues to have reasonable access to drugs described in subparagraph (G), taking into account geographic location, beneficiary preference, affordability, and reasonable travel time.</text>
								</clause><clause id="H336D0E2F4E824BCBBF95E85296701367"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Beneficiary preferences</header>
 <subclause id="HF441FA501B5447389C73F65C433958AF"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If an at-risk beneficiary for prescription drug abuse submits preferences for which in-network prescribers and pharmacies the beneficiary would prefer the PDP sponsor select in response to a notice under subparagraph (B), the PDP sponsor shall—</text>
 <item id="H746926BB1DDD4490A61E8B894727A5A5"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>review such preferences;</text> </item><item id="HD3C992615B234A15AF4BB5551CF31D73"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>select or change the selection of a prescriber or pharmacy for the beneficiary based on such preferences; and</text>
 </item><item id="H1BBC3203B2384539A4A860050F80D3DE"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>inform the beneficiary of such selection or change of selection.</text> </item></subclause><subclause id="HB1201678A45C4693817AB7FFB6A76879"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case that the PDP sponsor determines that a change to the selection of a prescriber or pharmacy under item (bb) by the PDP sponsor is contributing or would contribute to prescription drug abuse or drug diversion by the beneficiary, the PDP sponsor may change the selection of a prescriber or pharmacy for the beneficiary without regard to the preferences of the beneficiary described in subclause (I).</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H94A44F16DCD14B1BBB221C5C682EF8C8"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Confirmation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Before selecting a prescriber or pharmacy under this subparagraph, a PDP sponsor must request and receive confirmation from the prescriber or pharmacy acknowledging and accepting that the beneficiary involved is in the drug management program for at-risk beneficiaries.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H84CFB4E85722482C8DFF49C9E1C952FA"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Terminations and appeals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The identification of an individual as an at-risk beneficiary for prescription drug abuse under this paragraph, a coverage determination made under a drug management program for at-risk beneficiaries, and the selection of a prescriber or pharmacy under subparagraph (D) with respect to such individual shall be subject to reconsideration and appeal under subsection (h) and the option of an automatic escalation to external review to the extent provided by the Secretary.</text>
							</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD36ACC349E634940890B32676A0282FB"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Termination of identification</header>
 <clause id="HC929037A6F8E4EDFA50137EE6C6179B3"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall develop standards for the termination of identification of an individual as an at-risk beneficiary for prescription drug abuse under this paragraph. Under such standards such identification shall terminate as of the earlier of—</text>
 <subclause id="H4999EF337A594EDB8EBA05E279576D5E"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the date the individual demonstrates that the individual is no longer likely, in the absence of the restrictions under this paragraph, to be an at-risk beneficiary for prescription drug abuse described in subparagraph (C)(i); or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HE69EF5C0A625443A929AF2A65848D854"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the end of such maximum period of identification as the Secretary may specify.</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H04F7AC3CC53244779FD9CBCC4F49C02F"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in clause (i) shall be construed as preventing a plan from identifying an individual as an at-risk beneficiary for prescription drug abuse under subparagraph (C)(i) after such termination on the basis of additional information on drug use occurring after the date of notice of such termination.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD64818DEE5B54EF789AFD45B7E31EBA8"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Frequently abused drug</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>frequently abused drug</term> means a drug that is determined by the Secretary to be frequently abused or diverted and that is—</text> <clause id="H97D40F157DF144F3B0DDE97901ED812C"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a Controlled Drug Substance in Schedule CII–CIV;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4CA64776111544D88163BA223E4CE1AF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>within the same class or category of drugs as a Controlled Drug Substance in Schedule CII–CIV; or</text> </clause><clause id="HF06DEEC176D7445E8563FC7A61E9598A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">within another class or category of drugs that the Secretary determines, in consultation with the Inspector General of the Department of Health and Human Services, is at high risk for diversion or abuse.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H308F15E9F1944E769DF0C2CEF4956E48"><enum>(H)</enum><header>Data disclosure</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an at-risk beneficiary for prescription drug abuse whose access to coverage for frequently abused drugs under a prescription drug plan has been limited by a PDP sponsor under this paragraph, such PDP sponsor shall disclose data, including any necessary individually identifiable health information, in a form and manner specified by the Secretary, about the decision to impose such limitations and the limitations imposed by the sponsor under this part.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE3846FAA60AC4E4B85A85E20ED2C4941"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Education</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall provide education to enrollees in prescription drug plans of PDP sponsors and providers regarding the drug management program for at-risk beneficiaries described in this paragraph, including education—</text>
 <clause id="HB70F0516382F405DBD802A29489FC74B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>provided by Medicare administrative contractors through the improper payment outreach and education program described in section 1874A(h); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HEEE12730DD274EFA924BB5A03B4C3BF8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">through current education efforts (such as State health insurance assistance programs described in subsection (a)(1)(A) of section 119 of the Medicare Improvements for Patients and Providers Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395b-3">42 U.S.C. 1395b–3</external-xref> note)) and materials directed toward such enrollees.</text>
								</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H087C6E4496914CA081792D2862D91BA6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Information for consumers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1860D–4(a)(1)(B) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-104">42 U.S.C. 1395w–104(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1C1AF51ABC88499183F690DF801E783B" style="OLC">
 <clause id="H764C50ABFF13463DA1B2617CA1D9F95E"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The drug management program for at-risk beneficiaries under subsection (c)(4).</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H073EFA9495BD4CE68F6B922F3C249A4E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Utilization management programs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1860D–4(c) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-104">42 U.S.C. 1395w–104(c)</external-xref>), as amended by subsection (a), is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HDA054DDF8D7E435BB337ECD2189964C0"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (1), by inserting after subparagraph (D) the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC9E16993B00743F1866D3BC97726C4AA" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="HA5B112E4BA234543BB9A18B9415FCA93"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A utilization management tool to prevent drug abuse (as described in paragraph (5)(A)).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCB482E480C9E477A8F1A3A331801A9A0"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H23EA0491B6334F9586C59C1DB52173C5" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H1F65A2DCBEF644D292C82D57016D31D9"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Utilization management tool to prevent drug abuse</header> <subparagraph id="HDF002DDFB2784425BC2BA3AE5752DF25"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A tool described in this paragraph is any of the following:</text>
 <clause id="H10D107D4D14D44F5A891B28F0E294C25"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A utilization tool designed to prevent the abuse of frequently abused drugs by individuals and to prevent the diversion of such drugs at pharmacies.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H99ABAD4FA6CC4CFA93A87467E135F96B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Retrospective utilization review to identify—</text> <subclause id="H9879F85C72A24F4DB24FF928D0731D42"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">individuals that receive frequently abused drugs at a frequency or in amounts that are not clinically appropriate; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HB5CBAD66DCC149AABC587776CA0F7066"><enum>(II)</enum><text>providers of services or suppliers that may facilitate the abuse or diversion of frequently abused drugs by beneficiaries.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H7C34C21BCD8C4F4399EE3E90A8C5804B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Consultation with the Contractor described in subparagraph (B) to verify if an individual enrolling in a prescription drug plan offered by a PDP sponsor has been previously identified by another PDP sponsor as an individual described in clause (ii)(I).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCC4A79C4684048DFB596BEB5772CD6F4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text>A PDP sponsor offering a prescription drug plan in a State shall submit to the Secretary and the Medicare drug integrity contractor with which the Secretary has entered into a contract under section 1893 with respect to such State a report, on a monthly basis, containing information on—</text>
 <clause id="H7EFD7B4005BF41CD81C4B69500BAB90B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any provider of services or supplier described in subparagraph (A)(ii)(II) that is identified by such plan sponsor during the 30-day period before such report is submitted; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC06FBADEE1C2413D9F243A122589C43D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the name and prescription records of individuals described in paragraph (4)(C).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCC5EDB58494A4398B9E078BB4482256A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Expanding Activities of Medicare Drug Integrity Contractors (MEDICs)</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1893 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395ddd">42 U.S.C. 1395ddd</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBAB94A5D44224F6FA65070DAB1AAE30E" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="H68D5341C52A24788B93C416935FB44B7"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Expanding Activities of Medicare Drug Integrity Contractors (MEDICs)</header>
 <paragraph id="H90F4E2BEB52841F9A4F6C4229D6274E1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Access to information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Under contracts entered into under this section with Medicare drug integrity contractors, the Secretary shall authorize such contractors to directly accept prescription and necessary medical records from entities such as pharmacies, prescription drug plans, and physicians with respect to an individual in order for such contractors to provide information relevant to the determination of whether such individual is an at-risk beneficiary for prescription drug abuse, as defined in section 1860D–4(c)(4)(C).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H6F2520BDBF9B4D21AA8DAECB081BA14A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirement for acknowledgment of referrals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a PDP sponsor refers information to a contractor described in paragraph (1) in order for such contractor to assist in the determination described in such paragraph, the contractor shall—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H2A4CA5B83F2F40F094AC297711E00CAC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>acknowledge to the PDP sponsor receipt of the referral; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H485E96BC97BF4244BF43B8AD4C61B286"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case that any PDP sponsor contacts the contractor requesting to know the determination by the contractor of whether or not an individual has been determined to be an individual described such paragraph, shall inform such PDP sponsor of such determination on a date that is not later than 15 days after the date on which the PDP sponsor contacts the contractor.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2BEEE6EA48A74049B5EFC701F7483957"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Making data available to other entities</header>
 <subparagraph id="HBA3371A079FA4B20A69E2A559D5E4848"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of carrying out this subsection, subject to subparagraph (B), the Secretary shall authorize MEDICs to respond to requests for information from PDP sponsors, State prescription drug monitoring programs, and other entities delegated by PDP sponsors using available programs and systems in the effort to prevent fraud, waste, and abuse.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H05030102E23A462AA5BC2B2409204799"><enum>(B)</enum><header>HIPAA compliant information only</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Information may only be disclosed by a MEDIC under subparagraph (A) if the disclosure of such information is permitted under the Federal regulations (concerning the privacy of individually identifiable health information) promulgated under section 264(c) of the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1320d-2">42 U.S.C. 1320d–2</external-xref> note).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HB63DBF42CF5A494497ED38063B12F72D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Treatment of certain complaints for purposes of quality or performance assessment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1860D–42 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-152">42 U.S.C. 1395w–152</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD24EC7ECE5FA45349A5E47F68E3E4BE2" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H1F6C2E7435A94F65A6EC43B9B434EF39"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Treatment of certain complaints for purposes of quality or performance assessment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In conducting a quality or performance assessment of a PDP sponsor, the Secretary shall develop or utilize existing screening methods for reviewing and considering complaints that are received from enrollees in a prescription drug plan offered by such PDP sponsor and that are complaints regarding the lack of access by the individual to prescription drugs due to a drug management program for at-risk beneficiaries.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="H94209B24A55C4441852B33223056A76C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>GAO studies and reports</header>
 <paragraph id="HC7EA5188F22446F7A962A62A641B5F4F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Studies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study on each of the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H9607AA268DDC4DE6B5AE738A484593D8"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The implementation of the amendments made by this section.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFA2F1B36643B4E4DA192541CDCF62899"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The effectiveness of the at-risk beneficiaries for prescription drug abuse drug management programs authorized by section 1860D–4(c)(4) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-10">42 U.S.C. 1395w–10(c)(4)</external-xref>), as added by subsection (a)(1), including an analysis of—</text>
 <clause id="HF6F83D35CC004C4A9FBFDA4F3234F590"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the impediments, if any, that impair the ability of individuals described in subparagraph (C) of such section 1860D–4(c)(4) to access clinically appropriate levels of prescription drugs; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H285393516B8F42C8AB224B084217F7B5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the types of—</text> <subclause id="H09B78348E93E4AF3BE5170956CE56025"><enum>(I)</enum><text>individuals who, in the implementation of such section, are determined to be individuals described in such subparagraph; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HD9AEC61CF8C447C4B3DE6F7C5D591369"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prescribers and pharmacies that are selected under subparagraph (D) of such section.</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA2197970AA444D8AA7AE3D9B4835902D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than January 1, 2016, the Comptroller General of the United States shall begin work, with respect to each study described in paragraph (1), on a report that describes the result of such study. Upon the completion of each such report, such Comptroller General shall submit the report to each of the committees described in paragraph (3).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7E0218C495A448699D58E86525877AFC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Committees described</header><text>The committees described in this paragraph are the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H26E20F2818824A00984D9E3752CF0CC2"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H64BA7E2882AC4E1AB1555217707CFC51"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H95906D71C0F14F2C88E212663342812B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Committee on Finance of the Senate.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1013D6E3766E4A8389AD5A05949C3DE4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC1931F60660F4529B297CC77C8DBFAA1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The Special Committee on Aging of the Senate.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7C01F28D92654F3B9908D9ACC28EAD50"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Effective date</header>
 <paragraph id="H8922AAA8B8904581B404CEBE0CE94C82"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to prescription drug plans for plan years beginning on or after January 1, 2017.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HE11746247B164E5E8257C23836C7A10F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Stakeholder meetings prior to effective date</header>
 <subparagraph id="H9A26EC4477AD4CE891D39C5BBCC1B302"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than January 1, 2016, the Secretary shall convene stakeholders, including individuals entitled to benefits under part A of title XVIII of the Social Security Act or enrolled under part B of such title of such Act, advocacy groups representing such individuals, clinicians, plan sponsors, and entities delegated by plan sponsors, for input regarding the topics described in subparagraph (B).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HA45779511FD34AB28D5CF2F247FA46DA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Topics described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The topics described in this subparagraph are the topics of—</text> <clause id="H1965DA6423FD4972899ADDB68D6B6401"><enum>(i)</enum><text>ensuring affordability and accessibility to prescription drugs for enrollees in prescription drug plans of PDP sponsors who are at-risk beneficiaries for prescription drug abuse (as defined in paragraph (4)(C) of section 1860D–4(c) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-10">42 U.S.C. 1395w–10(c)</external-xref>), as added by subsection (a)(1));</text>
 </clause><clause id="H0AFCE811F641427A8DC82A07D691B91B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the use of an expedited appeals process under which such an enrollee may appeal an identification of such enrollee as an at-risk beneficiary for prescription drug abuse under such paragraph (similar to the processes established under the Medicare Advantage program under part C of title XVIII of the Social Security Act that allow an automatic escalation to external review of claims submitted under such part);</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4A7B02F45D244E2CA8A344EE6C6B6CF8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the types of enrollees that should be treated as exempted individuals, as described in clause (ii) of such paragraph;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1C9957667AFB4E0E8AB87DCE5D07CD05"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the manner in which terms and definitions in paragraph (4) of such section 1860D–4(c) should be applied, such as the use of clinical appropriateness in determining whether an enrollee is an at-risk beneficiary for prescription drug abuse as defined in subparagraph (C) of such paragraph (4);</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD85045985EB54142A537D554F816869B"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the information to be included in the notices described in subparagraph (B) of such section and the standardization of such notices; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4684933C2D14476281F83462BBC3EA4F"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to a PDP sponsor that establishes a drug management program for at-risk beneficiaries under such paragraph (4), the responsibilities of such PDP sponsor with respect to the implementation of such program.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7B65F7A483F54AE49C93BFF767DAEEDF"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall promulgate regulations based on the input gathered pursuant to subparagraph (A).</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


