<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S556 RS: Bipartisan Sportsmen's Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><calendar>Calendar No. 328</calendar><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 556</legis-num><associated-doc role="report">[Report No. 114–183]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150225">February 25, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S288">Ms. Murkowski</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSEG00" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><action stage="Reported-in-Senate"><action-date>December 16, 2015</action-date><action-desc>Reported by <sponsor name-id="S288">Ms. Murkowski</sponsor>, with an amendment and an amendment to the title</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To protect and enhance opportunities for recreational hunting, fishing, and shooting, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause">
		<section changed="deleted" committee-id="SSEG00" id="idC156394F33F4425A89EB6A72D99FF7AE" reported-display-style="strikethrough" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header>
 <subsection id="id2EF327F605E74482BAA7E02C33665946"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text>This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Bipartisan Sportsmen's Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="id9C005DD6721844BA8E57B5583BF643B8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents of this Act is as follows:</text><toc changed="deleted" committee-id="SSEG00" reported-display-style="strikethrough"><toc-entry idref="idC156394F33F4425A89EB6A72D99FF7AE" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="id01D61E678D1143F8B545D26E5D98192C" level="title">TITLE I—Regulatory reforms</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="idB3F56405B8894DE28764580C5BE958E2" level="section">Sec. 101. Recreational fishing, hunting, and recreational shooting on Federal public land.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="id3C147CFDDD3144518D1C1971C8A54559" level="section">Sec. 102. Annual permit and fee for film crews of 5 persons or fewer.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="idB8EDE6DC626040DBABFBFA8D877A3DF9" level="section">Sec. 103. Federal action transparency.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="id0b0f6e1ec22f42b494f235d2e0db03d8" level="section">Sec. 104. Bows in the Parks.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="id99ED905A16D64D7CA112442FF262A2C2" level="title">TITLE II—Habitat conservation</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="idA0AAB86A8B5A4985AC7D9F5D27D0FE38" level="section">Sec. 201. Availability of Land and Water Conservation Fund for recreational public access projects.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="idFE4EC41894414BF9B4C57A48935C0681" level="section">Sec. 202. Identifying opportunities for recreation, hunting, and fishing on Federal land.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="id121ABDCAFEB943BF88684E591E930BC6" level="section">Sec. 203. Federal Land Transaction Facilitation Act.</toc-entry></toc>
			</subsection></section><title changed="deleted" committee-id="SSEG00" id="id01D61E678D1143F8B545D26E5D98192C" reported-display-style="strikethrough"><enum>I</enum><header>Regulatory reforms</header>
			<section id="idB3F56405B8894DE28764580C5BE958E2"><enum>101.</enum><header>Recreational
			 fishing, hunting, and recreational shooting on Federal public land</header>
 <subsection id="id10b82dee33074445ad2456735bd6cab1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> <paragraph id="id014a19d7f8744d56b2bd84a2f1d8ce6d"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Federal public land</header> <subparagraph id="id1afb38c953bc4bf5b11e3244bf5ef1bc"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>Federal public land</term> means any land or water that is—</text>
 <clause id="id57bd4dd0631b45b795f0466beb297161"><enum>(i)</enum><text>owned by the United States; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id438d79a98ffc4fa3b7412cd027a63063"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>managed by a Federal agency (including the Department of the Interior and the Forest Service) for purposes that include the conservation of natural resources.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb3e9af555d2348f8baf8c076937f0639"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusions</header><text>The term <term>Federal public land</term> does not include—</text>
 <clause id="idA8A090800C5B46BBBB9498500AADEE41"><enum>(i)</enum><text>land or water held or managed in trust for the benefit of Indian tribes or individual Indians;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id745D162DF6004018BFC4E3B9C4D66DC5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>land or water managed by the Director of the National Park Service or the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id7F8700E0F8234E0E940B13A1B25F3CFF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>fish hatcheries; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="id11B1CE22CF524F7EA48888FC60E943A9"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>conservation easements on private land.</text>
							</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id39160f659d754393ae3f4619845ede93"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Hunting</header>
						<subparagraph id="id571750ab784841ac96c21dac84240aba"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>The term <term>hunting</term> means use of a firearm, bow, or other authorized means in the lawful—</text>
 <clause id="idf105bf7c7e1846fb96d05d21200f3aec"><enum>(i)</enum><text>pursuit, shooting, capture, collection, trapping, or killing of wildlife; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="id18179c5a4ebd43319ce97d5548e0e2fb"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>attempt to pursue, shoot, capture, collect, trap, or kill wildlife.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9db3cc7f8fdc4919a2cdb7f998667a90"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text>The term <term>hunting</term> does not include the use of skilled volunteers to cull excess animals (as defined by Federal law (including regulations)).</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idfba2a2315e324cb7b7e5d658af0a7fb0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Recreational
 fishing</header><text>The term <term>recreational fishing</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="idA079BDA6417E4E1085CC07A5B18C8B6F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an activity for sport or pleasure that involves the lawful—</text>
 <clause id="idb59b51856be64bf4b06d25f137e112f6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>catching, taking, or harvesting of fish; or</text> </clause><clause id="idbb69b6bc6f464c7d8b698e3bb9467f01"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>attempted catching, taking, or harvesting of fish; or</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3c548b0958a740f1947497a9c3ca04c5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other activity for sport or pleasure that can reasonably be expected to result in the lawful catching, taking, or harvesting of fish.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idadcc3e3050674defa6354b036c715324"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Recreational
 shooting</header><text>The term <term>recreational shooting</term> means any form of sport, training, competition, or pastime, whether formal or informal, that involves—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id1D286BD6508D4C759F7821ED06BF562D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the discharge of a rifle, handgun, or shotgun; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4D84143D97CD4E3CB1E1018F7276D79E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the use of a bow and arrow.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id650ff12d18b64119904a05876265d489"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Recreational
			 fishing, hunting, and recreational shooting</header>
					<paragraph id="id59aacb3c5c874dab9ff3bb64ca2a510d"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, and in cooperation with the respective State fish and wildlife agency, a Federal public land management official shall exercise the authority of the official under existing law (including provisions regarding land use planning) to facilitate use of and access to Federal public land for recreational fishing, hunting, and recreational shooting except as limited by—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id3f0b29e6a5c34ba09dc7d218fd9ec461"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any Federal law (including regulations) that authorizes action or withholding action for reasons of national security, public safety, or resource conservation;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide419c420ae7646078498cbde2962490b"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other Federal law (including regulations) that precludes recreational fishing, hunting, or recreational shooting on specific Federal public land units of Federal public land, or water; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2e696af22ca44a1d81943a3136177dd4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>discretionary limitations on recreational fishing, hunting, and recreational shooting determined to be necessary and reasonable, as supported by the best scientific evidence and advanced through a transparent public process.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id39a722874e054de99b3773724c49a33a"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Management</header><text>Consistent with paragraph (1), the head of each Federal public land management agency shall exercise the land management discretion of the head—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id0847c4b59da94dc5ba673ac44db919db"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in a manner that supports and facilitates recreational fishing, hunting, and recreational shooting opportunities;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf410bc11a85245b5b3b2e3809ec5dc63"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to the extent authorized under applicable State law; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id18129f72f7e04ef59955ada4865755e9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in accordance with applicable Federal law.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id2ab5040a7104456d9e86273fed8879f5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Planning</header>
						<subparagraph id="id6d3f739dd3f44e2e8d3f9ab6060132ce"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Effects of
			 plans and activities</header>
							<clause id="ide45bf112ec544834b835b5dd7880c828"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Evaluation of
			 effects on opportunities to engage in recreational fishing, hunting, or
 recreational shooting</header><text>Federal public land planning documents (including land resources management plans, resource management plans, travel management plans, and energy development plans) shall include a specific evaluation of the effects of the plans on opportunities to engage in recreational fishing, hunting, or recreational shooting.</text>
							</clause><clause id="idf6a7f24591ed485f8925e9bae32ecf5d"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Other activity
			 not considered</header>
								<subclause id="id737FCA05651C4C80B5805B5B9D6AFE05"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>Federal public land management officials shall not be required to consider the existence or availability of recreational fishing, hunting, or recreational shooting opportunities on private or public land that is located adjacent to, or in the vicinity of, Federal public land for purposes of—</text>
 <item id="id36B264C2145646F48073AFFD24D2A3D2"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>planning for or determining which units of Federal public land are open for recreational fishing, hunting, or recreational shooting; or</text>
 </item><item id="idD6C6E29CF6BE42B6ACBCDCB7DC1481F9"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>setting the levels of use for recreational fishing, hunting, or recreational shooting on Federal public land.</text>
									</item></subclause><subclause id="id78D20FD2A4DF42F78FE51558F0F5DBD9"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Enhanced
 opportunities</header><text>Federal public land management officials may consider the opportunities described in subclause (I) if the combination of those opportunities would enhance the recreational fishing, hunting, or shooting opportunities available to the public.</text>
								</subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id214f42c7eb6e424fa29ef1d844725b49"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Use of
 volunteers</header><text>If hunting is prohibited by law, all Federal public land planning documents described in subparagraph (A)(i) of an agency shall, after appropriate coordination with State fish and wildlife agencies, allow the participation of skilled volunteers in the culling and other management of wildlife populations on Federal public land unless the head of the agency demonstrates, based on the best scientific data available or applicable Federal law, why skilled volunteers should not be used to control overpopulation of wildlife on the land that is the subject of the planning document.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id4d29362cc0af4c9e98a89b34da5eba1b"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Bureau of land
			 management and forest service land</header>
						<subparagraph id="ide2511c41aea84d4f87426c046d008360"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Land
			 open</header>
							<clause id="id4824DA573B75470AA807593963458380"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>Land under the jurisdiction of the Bureau of Land Management or the Forest Service (including a component of the National Wilderness Preservation System, land designated as a wilderness study area or administratively classified as wilderness eligible or suitable, and primitive or semiprimitive areas, but excluding land on the outer Continental Shelf) shall be open to recreational fishing, hunting, and recreational shooting unless the managing Federal public land agency acts to close the land to the activity.</text>
							</clause><clause id="id8B4BB5EE666A4B2F89E7F2612057C2E0"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Motorized
 access</header><text>Nothing in this subparagraph authorizes or requires motorized access or the use of motorized vehicles for recreational fishing, hunting, or recreational shooting purposes within land designated as a wilderness study area or administratively classified as wilderness eligible or suitable.</text>
							</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idCCBFFF28A65046AB8ADC71092F38AF57"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Closure or
 restriction</header><text>Land described in subparagraph (A)(i) may be subject to closures or restrictions if determined by the head of the agency to be necessary and reasonable and supported by facts and evidence for purposes including resource conservation, public safety, energy or mineral production, energy generation or transmission infrastructure, water supply facilities, protection of other permittees, protection of private property rights or interests, national security, or compliance with other law, as determined appropriate by the Director of the Bureau of Land Management or the Chief of the Forest Service, as applicable.</text>
						</subparagraph><subparagraph id="idAAF1CB52CFD54628B52B35077C377FDE"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Shooting
			 ranges</header>
							<clause id="id9eabd7a2d5eb4f43b772b9f12868342a"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>Except as provided in clause (iii), the head of each Federal public land agency may use the authorities of the head, in a manner consistent with this section and other applicable law—</text>
 <subclause id="ide8c2cd2ce46b430297b3075134c6a88a"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to lease or permit use of land under the jurisdiction of the head for shooting ranges; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idb410ee6a71f1411eab8495b40da1fff9"><enum>(II)</enum><text>to designate specific land under the jurisdiction of the head for recreational shooting activities.</text>
								</subclause></clause><clause id="id5c246fb5c97a446dbc52a1a1182ebd37"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Limitation on
 liability</header><text>Any designation under clause (i)(II) shall not subject the United States to any civil action or claim for monetary damages for injury or loss of property or personal injury or death caused by any recreational shooting activity occurring at or on the designated land.</text>
 </clause><clause id="id6d8339d49e784617b817be62abf66c2e"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The head of each Federal public land agency shall not lease or permit use of Federal public land for shooting ranges or designate land for recreational shooting activities within a component of the National Wilderness Preservation System, land designated as a wilderness study area or administratively classified as wilderness eligible or suitable, and primitive or semiprimitive areas.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1fd5402c66c34e51a56b12c427828edf"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than October 1 of every other year, beginning with the second October 1 after the date of enactment of this Act, the head of each Federal public land agency who has authority to manage Federal public land on which recreational fishing, hunting, or recreational shooting occurs shall submit to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate a report that describes—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id832e049f46cb4bb1aa7e5cd03818e87a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any Federal public land administered by the agency head that was closed to recreational fishing, hunting, or recreational shooting at any time during the preceding year; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0399c23a9eee4cea83800bb937ebb44c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the reason for the closure.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id746d8ae57c01459dbb2793566d001c31"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Closures or
			 significant restrictions of 1,280 or more acres</header>
						<subparagraph id="id4c9b075f6f6e4fc8a045213a2ed83c99"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>Other than closures established or prescribed by land planning actions referred to in paragraph (4)(B) or emergency closures described in subparagraph (C), a permanent or temporary withdrawal, change of classification, or change of management status of Federal public land or water that effectively closes or significantly restricts 1,280 or more contiguous acres of Federal public land or water to access or use for recreational fishing or hunting or activities relating to fishing or hunting shall take effect only if, before the date of withdrawal or change, the head of the Federal public land agency that has jurisdiction over the Federal public land or water—</text>
 <clause id="id91eb56bd736b42788c520e9c6759b192"><enum>(i)</enum><text>publishes appropriate notice of the withdrawal or change, respectively;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id1fab17cfc26548ab90f8239e88f17efb"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>demonstrates that coordination has occurred with a State fish and wildlife agency; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id75f3e3284734477aaf2a7dd9994acc9a"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>submits to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate written notice of the withdrawal or change, respectively.</text>
							</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id717c20b589154cf2946aec6a3c4011ab"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Aggregate or
 cumulative effects</header><text>If the aggregate or cumulative effect of separate withdrawals or changes effectively closes or significantly restricts or affects 1,280 or more acres of land or water, the withdrawals and changes shall be treated as a single withdrawal or change for purposes of subparagraph (A).</text>
						</subparagraph><subparagraph id="id60bd19479ee647529a3b70c251ff1f8c"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Emergency
			 closures</header>
							<clause id="idF93D859420944F6180A23F5D46E4C6AB"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>Nothing in this section prohibits a Federal public land management agency from establishing or implementing emergency closures or restrictions of the smallest practicable area of Federal public land to provide for public safety, resource conservation, national security, or other purposes authorized by law.</text>
 </clause><clause id="id26404F8F71CB4211A2FB75D21FB91C6F"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>An emergency closure under clause (i) shall terminate after a reasonable period of time unless the temporary closure is converted to a permanent closure consistent with this section.</text>
							</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id88ED133DF7544B2299427D96078C92FF"><enum>(7)</enum><header>No
 priority</header><text>Nothing in this section requires a Federal agency to give preference to recreational fishing, hunting, or recreational shooting over other uses of Federal public land or over land or water management priorities established by other Federal law.</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="idc516aaa1cb514308b6c64de547ff794c"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Consultation
 with councils</header><text>In carrying out this section, the heads of Federal public land agencies shall consult with the appropriate advisory councils established under Executive Order 12962 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1801">16 U.S.C. 1801</external-xref> note; relating to recreational fisheries) and Executive Order 13443 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/661">16 U.S.C. 661</external-xref> note; relating to facilitation of hunting heritage and wildlife conservation).</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="id71cff967845546a8aecad5a4ac0ca3c9"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Authority of
			 states</header>
						<subparagraph id="idcabf14afe8754475afebe913372fcd47"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>Nothing in this section interferes with, diminishes, or conflicts with the authority, jurisdiction, or responsibility of any State to manage, control, or regulate fish and wildlife under State law (including regulations) on land or water within the State, including on Federal public land.</text>
						</subparagraph><subparagraph id="id06b5d901cfc14ad9b4acb0baf1361494"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Federal
			 licenses</header>
							<clause id="id612246e4aa434a20aa6eac54aee0b9a3"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>Except as provided in clause (ii), nothing in this subsection authorizes the head of a Federal public land agency head to require a license, fee, or permit to fish, hunt, or trap on land or water in a State, including on Federal public land in the State.</text>
							</clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id38CD676115D64991A6F0D37606FA813B"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Migratory bird
 stamps</header><text>Nothing in this subparagraph affects any migratory bird stamp requirement of the Migratory Bird Hunting and Conservation Stamp Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/718a">16 U.S.C. 718a et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
							</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id3C147CFDDD3144518D1C1971C8A54559"><enum>102.</enum><header>Annual permit
			 and fee for film crews of 5 persons or fewer</header>
 <subsection id="id8EBA3B597DF0494384D4073E6668DA69"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of this section is to provide commercial film crews of 5 persons or fewer access to film in areas designated for public use during public hours on Federal land and waterways.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idE00F538729A24AF9AE5BC7BB390F1F04"><enum>(b)</enum><header>National Park System land</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 100905 of title 54, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="idADE73428C93A446F91B474C8E833C7E3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (a)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id400E6BE24EFD4503ACEDB9AF90605452"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>The Secretary</quote> and inserting <quote>Except as provided in paragraph (3), the Secretary</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF1B056F31D2D49AF8A623213F781460B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by adding at the end the following:</text>
							<quoted-block changed="deleted" committee-id="SSEG00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6A0B94321B4143C48327F35056E9F1D4" reported-display-style="strikethrough" style="OLC">
								<paragraph id="id6D1486043CAD4A419A24A1796F61B4B4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Special rules
				for film crews of 5 persons or fewer</header>
									<subparagraph id="id7C6512700A1C4ECC98FEB1983B026AF2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Definition of
 film crew</header><text>In this paragraph, the term <term>film crew</term> means any persons present on Federal land or waterways under the jurisdiction of the Secretary who are associated with the production of a film.</text>
									</subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE8A4790C0D5840A1A8AC5FAAE60E3F42"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Required permit
 and fee</header><text>For any film crew of 5 persons or fewer, the Secretary shall require a permit and assess an annual fee of $200 for commercial filming activities or similar projects on Federal land and waterways administered by the Secretary.</text>
									</subparagraph><subparagraph id="id25C29B44CE25402BB6162BA28099B53D"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Commercial
 filming activities</header><text>A permit issued under subparagraph (B) shall be valid for commercial filming activities or similar projects that occur in areas designated for public use during public hours on all Federal land and waterways administered by the Secretary for a 1-year period beginning on the date of issuance of the permit.</text>
									</subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA4D0ED78F37A40D08AEDB626DB7DA5A2"><enum>(D)</enum><header>No additional
 fees</header><text>For persons holding a permit issued under this paragraph, during the effective period of the permit, the Secretary shall not assess any fees in addition to the fee assessed under subparagraph (B).</text>
									</subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0B40A11A2CD34DB59DE8E8544E5BA882"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Use of
 cameras</header><text>The Secretary shall not prohibit, as a mechanized apparatus or under any other purposes, use of cameras or related equipment used for the purpose of commercial filming activities or similar projects in accordance with this paragraph on Federal land and waterways administered by the Secretary.</text>
									</subparagraph><subparagraph id="id05BD4CE372E24692BFC4DAB9B8E62AB4"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Notification
 required</header><text>A film crew of 5 persons or fewer subject to a permit issued under this paragraph shall notify the applicable land management agency with jurisdiction over the Federal land at least 48 hours before entering the Federal land.</text>
									</subparagraph><subparagraph id="idFFFB6A22F0C14C76BE55B564B19ABC6A"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Denial of
 access</header><text>The head of the applicable land management agency may deny access to a film crew under this paragraph if—</text>
 <clause id="id8EBD07719BA2480CA5459C6AE266AA42"><enum>(i)</enum><text>there is a likelihood of resource damage that cannot be mitigated;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id96B8142EE8CA46C3B6270EE691116A6E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>there would be an unreasonable disruption of the use and enjoyment of the site by the public;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idF26FF6191C1D4B9A8059FBD9CB67AA27"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the activity poses health or safety risks to the public; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="idDA6C6995AA0D4909857BDACBD89C4338"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the filming includes the use of models or props that are not part of the natural or cultural resources or administrative facilities of the Federal land.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idD03D18C90D164B698AB6C2AA164F4B79"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the first sentence of subsection (b), by striking <quote>collect any costs</quote> and inserting <quote>recover any costs</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id11CC7F32D93049DE9D3578E815B3876C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Other Federal land</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1 of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/106/206">Public Law 106–206</external-xref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/460l-6d">16 U.S.C. 460<italic>l</italic>–6d</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="id14BD0DE97B1E4A04B7CB5AAF7A2721BB"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (a)—</text> <subparagraph id="idB16C19AE3A5148859E947717898C0126"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>The Secretary</quote> and inserting <quote>Except as provided in paragraph (3), the Secretary</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idAB3ADF794BB4491C9FDEF7AA7635C9DB"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block changed="deleted" committee-id="SSEG00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6FBAB288832D45E4A4D5121B0FF467E7" reported-display-style="strikethrough" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="idDF7FB99BFFCA4285B8DD1B1DFB891CFD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Special rules for film crews of 5 persons or fewer</header> <subparagraph id="idCD58D45C66B942CCA11A5E4E704E0C95"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Definition of film crew</header><text>In this paragraph, the term <term>film crew</term> means any persons present on Federal land or waterways under the jurisdiction of the Secretary who are associated with the production of a film.</text>
									</subparagraph><subparagraph id="idCB5C14D8500C4337B63D11B9CA5793B8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Required permit
 and fee</header><text>For any film crew of 5 persons or fewer, the Secretary shall require a permit and assess an annual fee of $200 for commercial filming activities or similar projects on Federal land and waterways administered by the Secretary.</text>
									</subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD517E1EC85B64B6683CEABE0BE2BD22C"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Commercial
 filming activities</header><text>A permit issued under subparagraph (B) shall be valid for commercial filming activities or similar projects that occur in areas designated for public use during public hours on all Federal land and waterways administered by the Secretary for a 1-year period beginning on the date of issuance of the permit.</text>
									</subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC8E0BA47CD5040F3A88BCE5F67309114"><enum>(D)</enum><header>No additional
 fees</header><text>For persons holding a permit issued under this paragraph, during the effective period of the permit, the Secretary shall not assess any fees in addition to the fee assessed under subparagraph (B).</text>
									</subparagraph><subparagraph id="idBDC68495714944F69351BCDE8D87EAA3"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Use of
 cameras</header><text>The Secretary shall not prohibit, as a mechanized apparatus or under any other purposes, use of cameras or related equipment used for the purpose of commercial filming activities or similar projects in accordance with this paragraph on Federal land and waterways administered by the Secretary.</text>
									</subparagraph><subparagraph id="idAF5C1A5179E0474B8DEE7F37EDBFB5DB"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Notification
 required</header><text>A film crew of 5 persons or fewer subject to a permit issued under this paragraph shall notify the applicable land management agency with jurisdiction over the Federal land at least 48 hours before entering the Federal land.</text>
									</subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE2E02A7A909C453CB44002FD4D3D05CB"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Denial of
 access</header><text>The head of the applicable land management agency may deny access to a film crew under this paragraph if—</text>
 <clause id="idD3EFE262DB4A45F9B163FC80AECF808F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>there is a likelihood of resource damage that cannot be mitigated;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id2A987F7C41F349619383C191B3E2A8AA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>there would be an unreasonable disruption of the use and enjoyment of the site by the public;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id2EA0EA740D8C49FC9E189A9AC13D4584"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the activity poses health or safety risks to the public; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="idC358E7A5564441699922355473C7FC3E"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the filming includes the use of models or props that are not part of the natural or cultural resources or administrative facilities of the Federal land.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1106D6F8820B45F0B5B9367685336B71"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the first sentence of subsection (b)—</text> <subparagraph id="id5628658B81A04445AC04A62F4A67EBCD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>collect any costs</quote> and inserting <quote>recover any costs</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id36930E2031A44C9487F44FC5C9F1DBC5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>similar project</quote> and inserting <quote>similar projects</quote>.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idB8EDE6DC626040DBABFBFA8D877A3DF9"><enum>103.</enum><header>Federal action transparency</header>
				<subsection id="H415AE94FCEBB4973B1098DE5C706D7AA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Modification of equal access to justice provisions</header>
 <paragraph id="H92D0ACBF4F52469A82E8402F1DD1EB0F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agency proceedings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 504 of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H2B7EE7BE559B4B7CABC7FF12F0D9549F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (c)(1), by striking <quote>, United States Code</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H11B71FBE97524E8A9B20DF7D7CFDF99E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (f) as subsection (i); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H21981204F060479892C4AE2034111F81"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking subsection (e) and inserting the following:</text>
							<quoted-block changed="deleted" committee-id="SSEG00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDB4368A642B744C0B3396422D9B48A87" reported-display-style="strikethrough" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H82F83B50D73848FC82CF9ED1FF049762"><enum>(e)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H8DDB2616DAC244408C76B1866FFA03CD"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than March 31 of the first fiscal year beginning after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Bipartisan Sportsmen's Act of 2015</short-title>, and every fiscal year thereafter, the Chairman of the Administrative Conference of the United States, after consultation with the Chief Counsel for Advocacy of the Small Business Administration, shall submit to Congress and make publicly available online a report on the amount of fees and other expenses awarded during the preceding fiscal year under this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph changed="deleted" committee-id="SSEG00" id="idE91967907E6C471390B9DD29B337051B" indent="up1" reported-display-style="strikethrough"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each report under paragraph (1) shall describe the number, nature, and amount of the awards, the claims involved in the controversy, and any other relevant information that may aid Congress in evaluating the scope and impact of such awards.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph changed="deleted" committee-id="SSEG00" id="H3E7A3BF4BA594A2DAF4EDFA75811984D" indent="up1" reported-display-style="strikethrough"><enum>(3)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H36602E8DEE7F4F66AEFE8E89AC8F4490"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each report under paragraph (1) shall account for all payments of fees and other expenses awarded under this section that are made pursuant to a settlement agreement, regardless of whether the settlement agreement is sealed or otherwise subject to a nondisclosure provision.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph changed="deleted" committee-id="SSEG00" id="HEEA80BD5BF8B4B61A4648929FAF73A89" indent="up1" reported-display-style="strikethrough"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The disclosure of fees and other expenses required under subparagraph (A) shall not affect any other information that is subject to a nondisclosure provision in a settlement agreement.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8572E82A75D64B1285E3D86924EDB5D6"><enum>(f)</enum><text>As soon as practicable, and in any event not later than the date on which the first report under subsection (e)(1) is required to be submitted, the Chairman of the Administrative Conference of the United States shall create and maintain online a searchable database containing, with respect to each award of fees and other expenses under this section made on or after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Bipartisan Sportsmen's Act of 2015</short-title>, the following information:</text>
 <paragraph id="H0D1745C34BC04C0CB3DFC298C95DD6E1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The case name and number of the adversary adjudication, if available, hyperlinked to the case, if available.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6E40E37A877344A0967C749FFA34D9A3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The name of the agency involved in the adversary adjudication.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HCE6E121D14924410924307B7F00A34FE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A description of the claims in the adversary adjudication.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H356798DDB6CE4C81BA66F67CA3379950"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The name of each party to whom the award was made.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H0060B06E63EB41038FCEEC7F442F8587"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The amount of the award.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9959BF1F0C794DF084012C8715CFFB3E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The basis for the finding that the position of the agency concerned was not substantially justified.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5126570EADC242C58822B8284A36E4B9"><enum>(g)</enum><text>The online searchable database described in subsection (f) may not reveal any information the disclosure of which is prohibited by law or a court order.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H4F15689A8F914B9EA5E30A6D67301380"><enum>(h)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of each agency shall provide to the Chairman of the Administrative Conference of the United States in a timely manner all information requested by the Chairman to comply with the requirements of subsections (e), (f), and (g).</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEB79EBE2AFD1446198948A32E2F480F0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Court cases</header><text>Section 2412(d) of title 28, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block changed="deleted" committee-id="SSEG00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAE8164BB2D4A4E339B0329CA7A5E196E" reported-display-style="strikethrough" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H8B11AA4CDCA44D9EB600B68DA4904A35" indent="up1"><enum>(5)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H7621F789CF1C4F44BC8AA922545537A8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Not later than March 31 of the first fiscal year beginning after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Bipartisan Sportsmen's Act of 2015</short-title>, and every fiscal year thereafter, the Chairman of the Administrative Conference of the United States shall submit to Congress and make publicly available online a report on the amount of fees and other expenses awarded during the preceding fiscal year pursuant to this subsection.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph changed="deleted" committee-id="SSEG00" id="id4E06DBB12C6D43308525700B908B2934" indent="up1" reported-display-style="strikethrough"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Each report under subparagraph (A) shall describe the number, nature, and amount of the awards, the claims involved in the controversy, and any other relevant information that may aid Congress in evaluating the scope and impact of such awards.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph changed="deleted" committee-id="SSEG00" id="H61AB33BEE1D24DB1B27CC4FCC3FDA64A" indent="up1" reported-display-style="strikethrough"><enum>(C)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HE21C44B0F0854C0AB2C3B014AE39E009"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each report under subparagraph (A) shall account for all payments of fees and other expenses awarded under this subsection that are made pursuant to a settlement agreement, regardless of whether the settlement agreement is sealed or otherwise subject to a nondisclosure provision.</text>
 </clause><clause changed="deleted" committee-id="SSEG00" id="HB1B4B2754EF642D2BA2FEA119299F63D" indent="up1" reported-display-style="strikethrough"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The disclosure of fees and other expenses required under clause (i) shall not affect any other information that is subject to a nondisclosure provision in a settlement agreement.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph changed="deleted" committee-id="SSEG00" id="H4D6751A7944B4A2FB7D192141B7A1088" indent="up1" reported-display-style="strikethrough"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Chairman of the Administrative Conference of the United States shall include and clearly identify in each annual report under subparagraph (A), for each case in which an award of fees and other expenses is included in the report—</text>
 <clause id="H9A5976ACDE9344B2AF7D27A9D4FA7FDF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any amounts paid under section 1304 of title 31 for a judgment in the case;</text> </clause><clause id="HCAAFE645CFD34847B534ECF46A272FB8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the amount of the award of fees and other expenses; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HEAD756DBF68C476EBBF51AF59ED150BB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the statute under which the plaintiff filed suit.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H599838F27FDA4E8DA321A1361CAE0F1F" indent="up1"><enum>(6)</enum><text>As soon as practicable, and in any event not later than the date on which the first report under paragraph (5)(A) is required to be submitted, the Chairman of the Administrative Conference of the United States shall create and maintain online a searchable database containing, with respect to each award of fees and other expenses under this subsection made on or after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Bipartisan Sportsmen's Act of 2015</short-title>, the following information:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H7C1D636BD9D642C4BB24F1DA0CE6FB23"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The case name and number, hyperlinked to the case, if available.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD88D496D7B474595A574C1BF3B7A8DAE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The name of the agency involved in the case.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFCEF9A6B460E4473AA1ED2B345C48C2F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The name of each party to whom the award was made.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HED288B0512914A388D254F7E9D999791"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of the claims in the case.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H32B508CE0735491EA14183C5F835E1C5"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The amount of the award.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB698A7D121134610BBC12F49AD961FF0"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The basis for the finding that the position of the agency concerned was not substantially justified.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC4E04641CAB146A689A42B01D2C433F6" indent="up1"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The online searchable database described in paragraph (6) may not reveal any information the disclosure of which is prohibited by law or a court order.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDC46C94ACCC945AEA4ABF21BA79AA5EE" indent="up1"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of each agency (including the Attorney General of the United States) shall provide to the Chairman of the Administrative Conference of the United States in a timely manner all information requested by the Chairman to comply with the requirements of paragraphs (5), (6), and (7).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2AF749F7F2B94FFE8E6D05A817BE349B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendments</header><text>Section 2412 of title 28, United States Code, is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H5C32762DD38E4B7AB81D125F232B49E6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (d)(3), by striking <quote>United States Code,</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4246915F9411400DAEB578DEE3ECB742"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (e)—</text> <clause id="H1A5C2E38D358446F8DB65094E95A1415"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>of section 2412 of title 28, United States Code,</quote> and inserting <quote>of this section</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H39290EB1893B49FDBCDEE3224D2D2272"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>of such title</quote> and inserting <quote>of this title</quote>.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H70C3239986D649938786DE5600CBB967"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Judgment fund transparency</header><text>Section 1304 of title 31, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block changed="deleted" committee-id="SSEG00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H457E4E5CE9ED45289D88E63F19027D79" reported-display-style="strikethrough" style="USC">
 <subsection id="H20CD2BC4BF0B4F688B5F8CBB351B478C"><enum>(d)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning not later than the date that is 60 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Bipartisan Sportsmen's Act of 2015</short-title>, and unless the disclosure of such information is otherwise prohibited by law or a court order, the Secretary of the Treasury shall make available to the public on a website, as soon as practicable, but not later than 30 days after the date on which a payment under this section is tendered, the following information with regard to that payment:</text>
 <paragraph id="H5361375BF6B34397856CA7190FA768CE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The name of the specific agency or entity whose actions gave rise to the claim or judgment.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H054CDA3DCF3F4D7B8F4289460532091A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The name of the plaintiff or claimant.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H91CC9103325540B4A8AC0555B982F4FD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The name of counsel for the plaintiff or claimant.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H4E2DCF58806444E192154A4F76703FAF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The amount paid representing principal liability, and any amounts paid representing any ancillary liability, including attorney fees, costs, and interest.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H730A89BEA78A4C788D2522F2571801C2"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A brief description of the facts that gave rise to the claim.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBEE16401D6014D7197E1DDCADB8CFF56"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The name of the agency that submitted the claim.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</subsection></section><section id="id0b0f6e1ec22f42b494f235d2e0db03d8"><enum>104.</enum><header>Bows in the Parks</header>
 <subsection id="idCAA7439A5A714D08AC59D2D7735FB49D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="id1E87CEC462774B0CB514290C318856E0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The term <quote>Director</quote> means the Director of the National Park Service.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id4217913a74324969a370d55104ac3704"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Not ready for immediate use</header><text>The term <term>not ready for immediate use</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="id4cacc064568344a1bb1cf8ef59bcf947"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a bow or crossbow, the arrows of which are secured or stowed in a quiver or other arrow transport case; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idee8db138ef704f1ba036b8dfe9509b7b"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to a crossbow, uncocked.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idf953223566174555ad809d3467ca5761"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Vehicular transportation authorized</header><text>The Director shall not promulgate or enforce any regulation that prohibits an individual from transporting bows and crossbows that are not ready for immediate use across any unit of the National Park System in the vehicle of the individual if—</text>
 <paragraph id="id46f779651e62402cb85242eb01c335d2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the individual is not otherwise prohibited by law from possessing the bows and crossbows;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id12eba4367bf44970959cab12872e94cc"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the bows or crossbows that are not ready for immediate use remain inside the vehicle of the individual throughout the period during which the bows or crossbows are transported across National Park System land; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idddc287607a024f9a8bbca3eb368047b1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the possession of the bows and crossbows is in compliance with the law of the State in which the unit of the National Park System is located.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section></title><title changed="deleted" committee-id="SSEG00" id="id99ED905A16D64D7CA112442FF262A2C2" reported-display-style="strikethrough" style="OLC"><enum>II</enum><header>Habitat conservation</header>
			<section id="idA0AAB86A8B5A4985AC7D9F5D27D0FE38"><enum>201.</enum><header>Availability of
			 Land and Water Conservation Fund for recreational public access
			 projects</header>
 <subsection id="idAD3D23F6B5184FBA983F4D15F4204C68"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Availability of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 200303 of title 54, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block changed="deleted" committee-id="SSEG00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idD68B48C81F2C475D8963E5C6755BE7B2" reported-display-style="strikethrough" style="USC"> <section id="idD3F77DAAC44D4CADB2611C1BCF55A326"><enum>200303.</enum><header>Availability of funds for certain projects</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of this Act, the Secretary and the Secretary of Agriculture shall ensure that, of the amounts appropriated for the fund for each fiscal year, not less than the greater of 1.5 percent of the amounts or $10,000,000 shall be made available for projects that secure public access to Federal land for hunting, fishing, and other recreational purposes through easements, rights-of-way, or fee title acquisitions from willing sellers.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</subsection><subsection id="idC72F3C2FAFD64030BAF341B65AFFD2A5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming
			 amendments</header>
 <paragraph id="id6AC59037B46F4242AB09116835DB7585"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Availability of deposits</header><text>Section 200302(c)(3) of title 54, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>Notwithstanding section 200303 of this title, money</quote> and inserting <quote>Money</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idE65656F99C704200995E5A33E90A054C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contracts for acquisition of land and water</header><text>Section 200308 of title 54, United States Code, is amended in the first sentence, by striking <quote>by section 200303 of this title</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id2B75F553F0CA4AB9B53328F1194B42E3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Contracts for options to acquire land and water in System</header><text>Section 200309 of title 54, United States Code, is amended in the third sentence by striking <quote>by section 200303 of this title</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idFE4EC41894414BF9B4C57A48935C0681"><enum>202.</enum><header>Identifying opportunities for recreation, hunting, and fishing on Federal land</header> <subsection id="idCD67445F970E4E66979A260701CD117B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text>
					<paragraph id="HC0015C3C04664376BFD0A6F5CB6AA9FF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Federal public
 land management agency</header><text>The term <term>Federal public land management agency</term> means any of the National Park Service, the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, the Forest Service, and the Bureau of Land Management.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id9074728179DB4E719BC1484A72E5069D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>State or regional office</header><text>The term <quote>State or regional office</quote> means—</text> <subparagraph id="id484F7F9547174A1490B362680952B2CF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a State office of the Bureau of Land Management; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idCE44EB95D6124D39B93BE3D574DCE398"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a regional office of the National Park Service, the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, or the Forest Service.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6AA62911C36048AE851B1081D06CF65B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Travel
 management plan</header><text>The term <term>travel management plan</term> means a plan for the management of travel—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H4E9CE711F4194EA2B9587C3E872EC17F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with respect to land under the jurisdiction of the National Park Service, on park roads and designated routes under section 4.10 of title 36, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H68C2757C7D63491D93A91CD63A05859B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to land under the jurisdiction of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, on the land under a comprehensive conservation plan prepared under section 4(e) of the <act-name parsable-cite="CERCL">National Wildlife Refuge System Administration Act of 1966</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/668dd">16 U.S.C. 668dd(e)</external-xref>);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9A871F508050432092E7D55091E62DC9"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to land under the jurisdiction of the Forest Service, on National Forest System land under part 212 of title 36, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2E173E191B8D4703B770DAB144345641"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to land under the jurisdiction of the Bureau of Land Management, under a resource management plan developed under the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1701">43 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H20A07B3812684BF49F54C9F55013236C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Priority lists required</header>
 <paragraph id="idDA6DAD7A79CA45EF9091B753AE156BA9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, annually during the 10-year period beginning on the date on which the first priority list is completed, and every 5 years after the end of the 10-year period, each head of each State or regional office shall prepare a priority list, to be made publicly available on the website of the applicable Federal public land management agency, which shall identify the location and acreage of land under the jurisdiction of the State or regional office on which the public is allowed, under Federal or State law, to hunt, fish, or use the land for other recreational purposes but—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE3FF7360812A48B0A4E1D25D928C39A7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to which there is no public access or egress; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE88CA4FAC7384B30A7424202477488DC"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to which public access or egress to the legal boundaries of the land is significantly restricted (as determined by the head of the State or regional office).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id77B0E8D433C04D8FB94043CA4B92BC67"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Minimum size</header><text>Any land identified under paragraph (1) shall consist of contiguous acreage of at least 640 acres.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HEA7A0BF633FD47FF9CE56DB650527CE7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In preparing the priority list required under paragraph (1), the head of the State or regional office shall consider with respect to the land—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id762e477c5ae944e4806df300b97832c8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>whether access is absent or merely restricted, including the extent of the restriction;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0c3a982d1c704f358d2ca76286c1920b"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the likelihood of resolving the absence of or restriction to public access;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id58880FA358E143188682CED39BAA0300"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the potential for recreational use;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id20B82A1339A54C3094586635A238D03F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any information received from the public or other stakeholders during the nomination process described in paragraph (5); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id46D016EA25D24D809989D7194D2C01BA"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any other factor as determined by the head of the State or regional office.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idBCD05949A27146CFB524EF8E6BADBB19"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Adjacent land status</header><text>For each parcel of land on the priority list, the head of the State or regional office shall state whether resolving the issue of public access or egress to the land would require acquisition of an easement, right-of-way, or fee title from—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idD0533F8E11CE48EE899681263F515716"><enum>(A)</enum><text>another Federal agency;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id373D429DC589467FA7CE74638015EED8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a State, local, or tribal government; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idDB9D8678CB39455A98C845D1CC94AC3F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a private landowner.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id7DC7C2739D8F46AFB99DA339505AB180"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Nomination process</header><text>In preparing a priority list under this section, the head of the State or regional office shall provide an opportunity for members of the public to nominate parcels for inclusion on the priority list.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8ED91DB30C6B466A880E22AE0EE32E5F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Access options</header><text>With respect to land included on a priority list described in subsection (b), the head of the State or regional office shall develop and submit to the Committees on Appropriations and Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committees on Appropriations and Natural Resources of the House of Representatives a report on options for providing access that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H77053B8D520E4070AF264F44097ECE1F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identifies how public access and egress could reasonably be provided to the legal boundaries of the land in a manner that minimizes the impact on wildlife habitat and water quality;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H892B4AC0A9834A97BB222EC88F5BEB95"><enum>(2)</enum><text>specifies the steps recommended to secure the access and egress, including acquiring an easement, right-of-way, or fee title from a willing owner of any land that abuts the land or the need to coordinate with State land management agencies or other Federal, State, or tribal governments to allow for such access and egress; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDD9F099E42CC475AA45909D2AC6F5E27"><enum>(3)</enum><text>is consistent with the travel management plan in effect on the land.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id52BEC95ED6024E2AAA30FD844DFA5D92"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Protection of personally identifying information</header><text>In making the priority list and report prepared under subsections (b) and (c) available, the head of the State or regional office shall ensure that no personally identifying information is included, such as names or addresses of individuals or entities.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idaa13e0258e544eefadf7d856e1fc525b"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Willing owners</header><text>For purposes of providing any permits to, or entering into agreements with, a State, local, or tribal government or private landowner with respect to the use of land under the jurisdiction of the government or landowner, a Federal land management agency shall not take into account whether the State, local, or tribal government or private landowner has granted or denied public access or egress to the land.</text>
				</subsection><subsection id="HD1434364F7624EAF886C5097ED42BE47"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Means of public
 access and egress included</header><text>In considering public access and egress under subsections (b) and (c), the head of the applicable Federal public land management agency shall consider public access and egress to the legal boundaries of the land described in those subsections, including access and egress—</text>
 <paragraph id="HA2481649AA9F4CA8A8C8B570F9174D51"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by motorized or non-motorized vehicles; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0C083BCF776E4F7992BA434D55A636AD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>on foot or horseback.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id3C88F406BDA24BCCAC8A2FCCC542F4AA"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Effect</header>
					<paragraph id="idF48041A9E1C04B33AE3C31F5C7F37A4C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>This section shall have no effect on whether a particular recreational use shall be allowed on the land included in a priority list under this section.</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7D7D5B03BF0948BD924B654F89FE8F6A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effect of
 allowable uses on agency consideration</header><text>In preparing the priority list under subsection (b), the head of the applicable State or regional office shall only consider recreational uses that are allowed on the land at the time that the priority list is prepared.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id121ABDCAFEB943BF88684E591E930BC6"><enum>203.</enum><header>Federal Land
			 Transaction Facilitation Act</header>
 <subsection id="id430D783790B349E182A99C5348934115"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal Land Transaction Facilitation Act is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="idB058ED6B91A44FC584C19DEF48E80927"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 203(2) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/2302">43 U.S.C. 2302(2)</external-xref>), by striking <quote>on the date of enactment of this Act was</quote> and inserting <quote>is</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id23CDF36F2A8A4D06B631762BF07D552B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 205 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/2304">43 U.S.C. 2304</external-xref>)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idB23C98EE57594BF79BA301713F8D837E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>(as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act)</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0799AAE009F34494B03F9F4E9C012D52"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking subsection (d);</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id8DF38E13AE324F2CAD4AA369BEFBF957"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in section 206 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/2305">43 U.S.C. 2305</external-xref>), by striking subsection (f); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idF9C23666FB6544C38EB4210F691FAC19"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in section 207(b) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/2306">43 U.S.C. 2306(b)</external-xref>)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idABC53927B24343C09279AE765E48ED8F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text>
 <clause id="id42D672A42E334ECABC862AAFCBF5FEDD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>96–568</quote> and inserting <quote>96–586</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id49E06E92DAE64CD08D66BABD4F93E18A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>; or</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id43A816A21D23483A8F5BA4675D5540C6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text>
 <clause id="idFA26E6C2CC4041509DF36BA45BF31BF2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>Public Law 105–263;</quote> before <quote>112 Stat.</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id98F987467BAF48518606B2DC2C193156"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id22A5BD2A205948C9B154CCD8F1769FDE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
							<quoted-block changed="deleted" committee-id="SSEG00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id71CC2E8AB5BA4A068CB810017E202633" reported-display-style="strikethrough" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="id48AA7D4F6ACE47CBA498432AFC568272"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the White Pine County Conservation, Recreation, and Development Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/109/432">Public Law 109–432</external-xref>; 120 Stat. 3028);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id861D7303655C458289220C2CEFC1EBF4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the Lincoln County Conservation, Recreation, and Development Act of 2004 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/108/424">Public Law 108–424</external-xref>; 118 Stat. 2403);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id29F162DC4F9D4420A62AD5745DECF6B5"><enum>(5)</enum><text>subtitle F of title I of the Omnibus Public Land Management Act of 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1132">16 U.S.C. 1132</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/11">Public Law 111–11</external-xref>);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id5E4619AE4D214165929B93A80875A02D"><enum>(6)</enum><text>subtitle O of title I of the Omnibus Public Land Management Act of 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/460www">16 U.S.C. 460www</external-xref> note, 1132 note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/11">Public Law 111–11</external-xref>);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id1865647BAF0A4F76B1A19C9656F9D2C0"><enum>(7)</enum><text>section 2601 of the Omnibus Public Land Management Act of 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/11">Public Law 111–11</external-xref>; 123 Stat. 1108); or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0B44512A4D6F466DA7238BFDADBB123F"><enum>(8)</enum><text>section 2606 of the Omnibus Public Land Management Act of 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/11">Public Law 111–11</external-xref>; 123 Stat. 1121).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id52886c55ecb149e89b6052f7a14681ba"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Funds to the Treasury</header><text>Of the amounts deposited in the Federal Land Disposal Account, there shall be transferred to the Treasury $1,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2016 through 2025.</text></subsection></section></title></legis-body>
	<legis-body display-enacting-clause="no-display-enacting-clause">
		<section changed="added" committee-id="SSEG00" id="id2d166e07b8164e538c68cbf12c4d66f7" reported-display-style="italic" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header>
 <subsection id="ida13b279999584adb8826692cdd467b7f"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text>This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Sportsmen's Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="id7994f43d6510485bae25155c605cecb9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents of this Act is as follows:</text><toc changed="added" committee-id="SSEG00" reported-display-style="italic"><toc-entry idref="id2d166e07b8164e538c68cbf12c4d66f7" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="idaa3742e004c14e3ba0f51da6b198a9b9" level="title">TITLE I—National policy</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="id41248c2128764793998b1024b0699a13" level="section">Sec. 101. Congressional declaration of national policy.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="id5fd3842528784f1ba31acf708c431a27" level="title">TITLE II—Sportsmen’s access to federal land</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="id8a2ba12601324a828dd6d19b29d19c96" level="section">Sec. 201. Definitions.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="id57d7190dee6647c1bb982ef632da98a1" level="section">Sec. 202. Federal land open to hunting, fishing, and recreational shooting.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="id52396d4343104872ac74081853cada46" level="section">Sec. 203. Closure of Federal land to hunting, fishing, and recreational shooting.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="id4190d5125de64a7096b9477eb79510d3" level="section">Sec. 204. Shooting ranges.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="id901D6AFB5DC2494BAC67A807AE45F12B" level="section">Sec. 205. Federal action transparency.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="id7cf968acb3b64cfca3c44be8db507ba0" level="title">TITLE III—Filming on federal land management agency land</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="id6a33429ff5564706a462c553ed1e116a" level="section">Sec. 301. Commercial filming.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="id7bf815fb02d6469c91c10083e526b2f6" level="title">TITLE IV—Bows, wildlife management, and access opportunities for recreation, hunting, and fishing</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="id84A073EF202E4DAABB79AB48BFA18BF0" level="section">Sec. 401. Bows in parks.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="id1cb117bf2c82404888de2d1704802f63" level="section">Sec. 402. Wildlife management in parks.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="idde5d3794d5c04908b85422ae123d4be6" level="section">Sec. 403. Identifying opportunities for recreation, hunting, and fishing on Federal land.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="idfe6b7f96c50049c3a9f6fe42dd11a40d" level="title">TITLE V—Federal land transaction facilitation act</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="id60761aa9c2c74381ba8bf74a2168a076" level="section">Sec. 501. Federal Land Transaction Facilitation Act.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="idf183dc6a98e04a11b87cc5142982b510" level="title">TITLE VI—Conservation reauthorization</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="idf2b111fe673e4920bb3ffb57c54ae508" level="section">Sec. 601. National Park Service Maintenance and Revitalization Conservation Fund.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="idb1c8ddeab2c04388984b0d9133a84d3a" level="section">Sec. 602. Land and Water Conservation Fund.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="idf12f2c8d806c413d9f7fbd5d61c107a3" level="section">Sec. 603. Historic Preservation Fund.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="id86a7971defc145499013758b19039e45" level="title">TITLE VII—Miscellaneous</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="id2778207591524402ad5def9a28f67b4b" level="section">Sec. 701. Respect for treaties and rights.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="idf5c964269ff7457ea597360cde52c6b4" level="section">Sec. 702. No priority.</toc-entry></toc>
			</subsection></section><title changed="added" committee-id="SSEG00" id="idaa3742e004c14e3ba0f51da6b198a9b9" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>I</enum><header>National policy</header>
			<section id="id41248c2128764793998b1024b0699a13"><enum>101.</enum><header>Congressional declaration of national policy</header>
 <subsection id="idFDDC0EF63FA34D43A87F157E7779A827"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress declares that it is the policy of the United States that Federal departments and agencies, in accordance with the missions of the departments and agencies, Executive Orders 12962 and 13443 (60 Fed. Reg. 30769 (June 7, 1995); 72 Fed. Reg. 46537 (August 16, 2007)), and applicable law, shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="id07bc3969060145959897bf4bd9511f71"><enum>(1)</enum><text>facilitate the expansion and enhancement of hunting, fishing, and recreational shooting opportunities on Federal land, in consultation with the Wildlife and Hunting Heritage Conservation Council, the Sport Fishing and Boating Partnership Council, State and tribal fish and wildlife agencies, and the public;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idece10c067db2472babe6ee8375d0ee22"><enum>(2)</enum><text>conserve and enhance aquatic systems and the management of game species and the habitat of those species on Federal land, including through hunting and fishing, in a manner that respects—</text>
 <subparagraph id="ida74727054e354091806d64500a033d7a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>State management authority over wildlife resources; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3e5818b76cbf400c8ebbea5cdb63c7e5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>private property rights; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id68445956c3c042df8122822f5732ee97"><enum>(3)</enum><text>consider hunting, fishing, and recreational shooting opportunities as part of all Federal plans for land, resource, and travel management.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="id685EA8F1E5E44EAF8ACFDACAECCCE8F9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text>In this Act, the term <term>fishing</term> does not include commercial fishing in which fish are harvested, either in whole or in part, that are intended to enter commerce through sale.</text>
				</subsection></section></title><title changed="added" committee-id="SSEG00" id="id5fd3842528784f1ba31acf708c431a27" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>II</enum><header>Sportsmen’s access to federal land</header>
 <section id="id8a2ba12601324a828dd6d19b29d19c96"><enum>201.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this title:</text> <paragraph id="idd0bd1eb5465d42ebb02f8cc174ac2242"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Federal land</header><text>The term <term>Federal land</term> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id3fd9042e54a14005b90c69535400abcf"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any land in the National Forest System (as defined in section 11(a) of the Forest and Rangeland Renewable Resources Planning Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1609">16 U.S.C. 1609(a)</external-xref>)) that is administered by the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Chief of the Forest Service; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8701b367b3b7481c8ad2468c02bd351d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>public lands (as defined in section 103 of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1702">43 U.S.C. 1702</external-xref>)), the surface of which is administered by the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the Bureau of Land Management.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0bc0d6b06e064e4f9ffd6f94d19dfcdd"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary concerned</header><text>The term <term>Secretary concerned</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="id577462ea156048e08f8b3765bcfd8dfb"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary of Agriculture, with respect to land described in paragraph (1)(A); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc6ff3b2e88ad42b5a035c2a1ef39d6ee"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary of the Interior, with respect to land described in paragraph (1)(B).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="id57d7190dee6647c1bb982ef632da98a1"><enum>202.</enum><header>Federal land open to hunting, fishing, and recreational shooting</header> <subsection id="iddb266532912c4d488a0efee7a4144c75"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subsection (b), Federal land shall be open to hunting, fishing, and recreational shooting, in accordance with applicable law, unless the Secretary concerned closes an area in accordance with section 203.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id1e4d03efd9f14f2b82ac7b5c83b8d218"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effect of title</header><text>Nothing in this title opens to hunting, fishing, or recreational shooting any land that is not open to those activities as of the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="id52396d4343104872ac74081853cada46"><enum>203.</enum><header>Closure of Federal land to hunting, fishing, and recreational shooting</header>
				<subsection id="idbc97817a362d4f1ab09cf302e40a4e9e"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization</header>
 <paragraph id="idd4a4ec8e226a44b88c220ecb70ca6115"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2) and in accordance with section 302(b) of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1732">43 U.S.C. 1732(b)</external-xref>), the Secretary concerned may designate any area on Federal land in which, and establish any period during which, for reasons of public safety, administration, or compliance with applicable laws, no hunting, fishing, or recreational shooting shall be permitted.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id3ac605da7a2d4005b027d58f6ee4b087"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>In making a designation under paragraph (1), the Secretary concerned shall designate the smallest area for the least amount of time that is required for public safety, administration, or compliance with applicable laws.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id7f40cc5b6ed946a48ab8915e24826f43"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Closure procedures</header>
 <paragraph id="ida64773eff0d049d4b9549c07cf3a8021"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except in an emergency, before permanently or temporarily closing any Federal land to hunting, fishing, or recreational shooting, the Secretary concerned shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id38e5d5c7cead46cfa7db472a10f7a394"><enum>(A)</enum><text>consult with State fish and wildlife agencies; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id600460592b9e4b55add9e2827ba332ac"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide public notice and opportunity for comment under paragraph (2).</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ida91fa2e3ea9f480b87c1cde0934cc235"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Public notice and comment</header>
 <subparagraph id="id977fb0700a3f42e698a110be1e7f5d91"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Public notice and comment shall include—</text> <clause id="id23bc67875d624ab7ae11947bf43313ed"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a notice of intent—</text>
 <subclause id="id90e7200b621a45f4b0af920b11143f7a"><enum>(I)</enum><text>published in advance of the public comment period for the closure—</text> <item id="id63276b9f8e8c41ffbd0872ec2b42f525"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>in the Federal Register;</text>
 </item><item id="id758105ee707045ceb8909347f5a067ba"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>on the website of the applicable Federal agency;</text> </item><item id="id5ca33a29ff3d43f7b8375fc87af32d7b"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>on the website of the Federal land unit, if available; and</text>
 </item><item id="id6baade0334244180a48dca4b0a214310"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>in at least 1 local newspaper;</text> </item></subclause><subclause id="id8b075073d5f242909d4720f2d92f8520"><enum>(II)</enum><text>made available in advance of the public comment period to local offices, chapters, and affiliate organizations in the vicinity of the closure that are signatories to the memorandum of understanding entitled <quote>Federal Lands Hunting, Fishing, and Shooting Sports Roundtable Memorandum of Understanding</quote>; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id87f25c27083e48629753ef869a304ebf"><enum>(III)</enum><text>that describes—</text> <item id="id248102befe9246699a11b6899453d649"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the proposed closure; and</text>
 </item><item id="id421e1cda8b464e989e7d5b87e3607f99"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the justification for the proposed closure, including an explanation of the reasons and necessity for the decision to close the area to hunting, fishing, or recreational shooting; and</text>
 </item></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" id="idac09295196574f4893d55246b9eca444"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an opportunity for public comment for a period of—</text> <subclause commented="no" id="idDAE6BC9B764A496DB0D82C5F22B6A114"><enum>(I)</enum><text>not less than 60 days for a permanent closure; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="id95C7A2A3DC824EC4B71CADFB83BBD5DF"><enum>(II)</enum><text>not less than 30 days for a temporary closure.</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7cad09999f1d4eeaac3c3cf8c01da50d"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Final decision</header><text>In a final decision to permanently or temporarily close an area to hunting, fishing, or recreation shooting, the Secretary concerned shall—</text>
 <clause id="idb42feeb406834f368709ad64bb11316c"><enum>(i)</enum><text>respond in a reasoned manner to the comments received;</text> </clause><clause id="idd5dec76c06b14248b95760255a7fb1af"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>explain how the Secretary concerned resolved any significant issues raised by the comments; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id9a0d0ef59dc849889b0c6199a92fa117"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>show how the resolution led to the closure.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ida7243c1ab1e9461790ac30b656d752c5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Temporary closures</header> <paragraph id="id55ad09a2c11b48eaafe4e46a15c85ef0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A temporary closure under this section may not exceed a period of 180 days.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id0988b942aab645f2be9f805b06cdbfb5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Renewal</header><text>Except in an emergency, a temporary closure for the same area of land closed to the same activities—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id8da493bf02f840938062c8818cc5aa33"><enum>(A)</enum><text>may not be renewed more than 3 times after the first temporary closure; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7a99b86294234cacbebe9786c697c01e"><enum>(B)</enum><text>must be subject to a separate notice and comment procedure in accordance with subsection (b)(2).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9d9904aa14ee4059beba6dc290468425"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Effect of temporary closure</header><text>Any Federal land that is temporarily closed to hunting, fishing, or recreational shooting under this section shall not become permanently closed to that activity without a separate public notice and opportunity to comment in accordance with subsection (b)(2).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idd600dd48468a4f6fba44ff4bacc66800"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text>On an annual basis, the Secretaries concerned shall—</text> <paragraph id="idde87de0aefa9484b8f3da7162fc65002"><enum>(1)</enum><text>publish on a public website a list of all areas of Federal land temporarily or permanently subject to a closure under this section; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idd95542b0377246f7ad32c19c229f064c"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submit to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources and the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives a report that identifies—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idddf8d67149e44197985d5078e893a5fa"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a list of each area of Federal land temporarily or permanently subject to a closure;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id50467e09c4384be8b9dea2deefd5f454"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the acreage of each closure; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd1441baac8da4b1ca0d57a32029ce6c3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a survey of—</text> <clause id="idcfbcbb3bbeab4f95b138da3d10e81ed3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the aggregate areas and acreage closed under this section in each State; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idc98a79fb794640759644604f4e5dc372"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the percentage of Federal land in each State closed under this section with respect to hunting, fishing, and recreational shooting.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idd27899d81d0b4b5cad5469cfb0ca35fa"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Application</header><text>This section shall not apply if the closure is—</text> <paragraph id="id48370dddb0be4b989ef83150f6db46c4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>less than 14 days in duration; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id184bf1429a1b482e9367280bcff3fa1a"><enum>(2)</enum><text>covered by a special use permit.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id4190d5125de64a7096b9477eb79510d3"><enum>204.</enum><header>Shooting ranges</header> <subsection id="idb8b7d5101db14dc29f53ad06def51a5b"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (b), the Secretary concerned may, in accordance with this section and other applicable law, lease or permit the use of Federal land for a shooting range.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idbc437c2c3ca54cc3a60d22de8503c5e5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The Secretary concerned shall not lease or permit the use of Federal land for a shooting range, within—</text>
 <paragraph id="ideaf231d28a86406797d3a5ddb693c603"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a component of the National Landscape Conservation System;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ide13b1e2bbb5d452483788ea640e8a515"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a component of the National Wilderness Preservation System;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idcb3a54040a244736870501e1eec47a94"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any area that is—</text> <subparagraph id="id2048f9d8d6dc4af8a20bbe8059600252"><enum>(A)</enum><text>designated as a wilderness study area;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0eee35a7b97c4466b24f690ef1bf8ef9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>administratively classified as—</text> <clause id="idae669f8c3d01448d8e7918e10a1094b5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>wilderness-eligible; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="id6f7479fd487442baab2e2159bd015430"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>wilderness-suitable; or</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id278f493a82e74afbb5ad17c9501c424b"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a primitive or semiprimitive area;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idbc80ca177cd9458a8a32eedf1f33e313"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a national monument, national volcanic monument, or national scenic area; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idf39992ed07e340c7b9d09b0e042d9d21"><enum>(5)</enum><text>a component of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System (including areas designated for study for potential addition to the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System).</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id901D6AFB5DC2494BAC67A807AE45F12B"><enum>205.</enum><header>Federal action transparency</header>
				<subsection id="id2cfbdd326f6c452ab183d5f18bdcf609"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Modification of equal access to justice provisions</header>
 <paragraph id="id237be81558c54b289608f7d5934b3308"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agency proceedings</header><text>Section 504 of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="idcca796f91fcd43f988715e3071cb0be1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (c)(1), by striking <quote>, United States Code</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id87fdcedcdd3f468abf86af890cd1b81d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (f) as subsection (i); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3e01977e9fde41c291d95a92c185441b"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking subsection (e) and inserting the following:</text>
							<quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="SSEG00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id93C73E028EE64DBD928D4909B5EC5BB2" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="idd0b4755eeeb846beba4b403b9766e832"><enum>(e)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idD0EFAC9425044EA794668A4C900C07A7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Not later than March 31 of the first fiscal year beginning after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Sportsmen's Act of 2015</short-title>, and every fiscal year thereafter, the Chairman of the Administrative Conference of the United States, after consultation with the Chief Counsel for Advocacy of the Small Business Administration, shall submit to Congress and make publicly available online a report on the amount of fees and other expenses awarded during the preceding fiscal year under this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph changed="added" committee-id="SSEG00" id="idC0FA398026C04BEAA0A6375C4E4B1666" indent="up1" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Each report under paragraph (1) shall describe the number, nature, and amount of the awards, the claims involved in the controversy, and any other relevant information that may aid Congress in evaluating the scope and impact of such awards.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph changed="added" committee-id="SSEG00" id="idF630D4B5FCF34C85B0CF7B7DE4901152" indent="up1" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>(3)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id5461185EC62B44A19C8B63BFC7737D47"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Each report under paragraph (1) shall account for all payments of fees and other expenses awarded under this section that are made pursuant to a settlement agreement, regardless of whether the settlement agreement is sealed or otherwise subject to a nondisclosure provision.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph changed="added" committee-id="SSEG00" id="id4C429054C414465EA0388A53D0D19CFA" indent="up1" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The disclosure of fees and other expenses required under subparagraph (A) shall not affect any other information that is subject to a nondisclosure provision in a settlement agreement.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idF20882FA78DC4732BA0FA25989A9CF6E"><enum>(f)</enum><text>As soon as practicable, and in any event not later than the date on which the first report under subsection (e)(1) is required to be submitted, the Chairman of the Administrative Conference of the United States shall create and maintain online a searchable database containing, with respect to each award of fees and other expenses under this section made on or after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Sportsmen's Act of 2015</short-title>, the following information:</text>
 <paragraph id="id53224b9c0e5c4185b19c6bbbf2315cd1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The case name and number of the adversary adjudication, if available, hyperlinked to the case, if available.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id10a2e2de4c8d4b938ea76adbf5fc279a"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The name of the agency involved in the adversary adjudication.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id065281e94d604847a55e6847af894e5c"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A description of the claims in the adversary adjudication.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idceae8ca59a0846fe97bca48bbd45b8bd"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The name of each party to whom the award was made.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idb3b73cd0d5b74cc0a90b15e7f7859161"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The amount of the award.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id5922b5ae357c477d9148a278d3ce1952"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The basis for the finding that the position of the agency concerned was not substantially justified.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idF13DD8F2093347D5BFE164E25491BA56"><enum>(g)</enum><text>The online searchable database described in subsection (f) may not reveal any information the disclosure of which is prohibited by law or a court order.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idF9D6C24C1F4B44E9A2441CE8CE10DF44"><enum>(h)</enum><text>The head of each agency shall provide to the Chairman of the Administrative Conference of the United States in a timely manner all information requested by the Chairman to comply with the requirements of subsections (e), (f), and (g).</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idaecc28f3b1d6465683b2b89701c63698"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Court cases</header><text>Section 2412(d) of title 28, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="SSEG00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id507DC2B2217A4692871A9AF447D90AFB" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="id530250c6fff6410285c9ba2e2da5dbd3" indent="up1"><enum>(5)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id7D2FC93B5FBF4F029551BEC42EE2D280"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Not later than March 31 of the first fiscal year beginning after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Sportsmen's Act of 2015</short-title>, and every fiscal year thereafter, the Chairman of the Administrative Conference of the United States shall submit to Congress and make publicly available online a report on the amount of fees and other expenses awarded during the preceding fiscal year pursuant to this subsection.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph changed="added" committee-id="SSEG00" id="id695FDDA2359743699C860E7A7A488085" indent="up1" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Each report under subparagraph (A) shall describe the number, nature, and amount of the awards, the claims involved in the controversy, and any other relevant information that may aid Congress in evaluating the scope and impact of such awards.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph changed="added" committee-id="SSEG00" id="idD26EE95BA7FB46F7AC7B04B9ED1E7FAE" indent="up1" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>(C)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id2351567901C847BF90D5832CBB12D233"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Each report under subparagraph (A) shall account for all payments of fees and other expenses awarded under this subsection that are made pursuant to a settlement agreement, regardless of whether the settlement agreement is sealed or otherwise subject to a nondisclosure provision.</text>
 </clause><clause changed="added" committee-id="SSEG00" id="idBF345F67E78842D7BD0BCC3E7FAE9913" indent="up1" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The disclosure of fees and other expenses required under clause (i) shall not affect any other information that is subject to a nondisclosure provision in a settlement agreement.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph changed="added" committee-id="SSEG00" id="id07EF12CFC1A942A79F6088885F727A88" indent="up1" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The Chairman of the Administrative Conference of the United States shall include and clearly identify in each annual report under subparagraph (A), for each case in which an award of fees and other expenses is included in the report—</text>
 <clause id="idF3A09A14A38D4E03BF3D1D2E19E112A0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any amounts paid under section 1304 of title 31 for a judgment in the case;</text> </clause><clause id="idD97A048E394A4B8FB5F34D56E6218A60"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the amount of the award of fees and other expenses; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idB4F80869A5254B49BCB3AEC60427782D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the statute under which the plaintiff filed suit.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id450BDD795A894FA190679D8383327EBE" indent="up1"><enum>(6)</enum><text>As soon as practicable, and in any event not later than the date on which the first report under paragraph (5)(A) is required to be submitted, the Chairman of the Administrative Conference of the United States shall create and maintain online a searchable database containing, with respect to each award of fees and other expenses under this subsection made on or after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Sportsmen's Act of 2015</short-title>, the following information:</text>
 <subparagraph id="id159A934CA2ED49E08884EC6155538646"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The case name and number, hyperlinked to the case, if available.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5DCDCA1551874DAFADA41A8E00D825D1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The name of the agency involved in the case.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id93172831678D445A892967252A1C5EB6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The name of each party to whom the award was made.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB7430AA1F2FE4F71B12FA2D8DC51CA41"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A description of the claims in the case.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id36770FE4B4B34FF49951F0E2B325149B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The amount of the award.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idADFD95131BA24DE4B913999B3689E182"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The basis for the finding that the position of the agency concerned was not substantially justified.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5668041BACBD4289A0235683D24ED8B2" indent="up1"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The online searchable database described in paragraph (6) may not reveal any information the disclosure of which is prohibited by law or a court order.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id7A6CF0255EDE4A95B032DD02FE033CD7" indent="up1"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The head of each agency (including the Attorney General of the United States) shall provide to the Chairman of the Administrative Conference of the United States in a timely manner all information requested by the Chairman to comply with the requirements of paragraphs (5), (6), and (7).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id84fbdee95b654bcf88bf8a6abac26d37"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendments</header><text>Section 2412 of title 28, United States Code, is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="id869cbe8ee3254da9a840761a4ac9da4c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (d)(3), by striking <quote>United States Code,</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd68a3b52cb914309a60974ecce87a4a5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (e)—</text> <clause id="id848fc29f5bce40d38f5d1cedca818a85"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>of section 2412 of title 28, United States Code,</quote> and inserting <quote>of this section</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idd8cc10cfabf342f18b575b1914a3e3b6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>of such title</quote> and inserting <quote>of this title</quote>.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idab082802dff647669a7c13e5db929c19"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Judgment Fund transparency</header><text>Section 1304 of title 31, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="SSEG00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4BB0A40540B54F288A821A1EE907A538" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="idc960f0f7c29a4ff2bce0542ed0d908f5"><enum>(d)</enum><text>Beginning not later than the date that is 60 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Sportsmen's Act of 2015</short-title>, and unless the disclosure of such information is otherwise prohibited by law or a court order, the Secretary of the Treasury shall make available to the public on a website, as soon as practicable, but not later than 30 days after the date on which a payment under this section is tendered, the following information with regard to that payment:</text>
 <paragraph id="idc9b20be09f1446479c3005af3d1fde43"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The name of the specific agency or entity whose actions gave rise to the claim or judgment.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idd1f6f96e390e4e678e573ee98c120241"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The name of the plaintiff or claimant.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idf52742e9e62f4012a60e0e5fc2075f43"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The name of counsel for the plaintiff or claimant.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idd63c4f29c7a94ad5a6ffe1c2ff12910c"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The amount paid representing principal liability, and any amounts paid representing any ancillary liability, including attorney fees, costs, and interest.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idd925dd7377cb41e19763e4f5cb950b7f"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A brief description of the facts that gave rise to the claim.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id27d5a2e463d04adca7d3c9dc4dda5577"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The name of the agency that submitted the claim.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</subsection></section></title><title changed="added" committee-id="SSEG00" id="id7cf968acb3b64cfca3c44be8db507ba0" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>III</enum><header>Filming on federal land management agency land</header>
			<section id="id6a33429ff5564706a462c553ed1e116a"><enum>301.</enum><header>Commercial filming</header>
 <subsection id="idc15ce8c1252d4620ad57426e387d208b"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1 of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/106/206">Public Law 106–206</external-xref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/460l-6d">16 U.S.C. 460l–6d</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="id76b8a6d29f854702bedff285dbf27fff"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (a) through (f) as subsections (b) through (g), respectively;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id7dd0b079a54949b1aceafb04ea956447"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting before subsection (b) (as so redesignated) the following:</text> <quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="SSEG00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2eb1ced8c0d74eed8cf0a46e6e9fc38c" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC"> <subsection id="id04da85d955aa4589b06df75d91c5af6b"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition of secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture, as applicable, with respect to land under the respective jurisdiction of the Secretary.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idaba97e505d7d4114a746f14ad6d3e845"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (b) (as so redesignated)—</text> <subparagraph id="idd45bb42220874634886124aa580a654a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text>
 <clause id="idbc89affc363b43e89a4c53955ef06df4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the first sentence, by striking <quote>of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture (hereafter individually referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote> with respect to land (except land in a System unit as defined in section 100102 of title 54, United States Code) under their respective jurisdictions)</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id1cfca811011b401d83f5610563b673df"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by inserting <quote>, except in the case of film crews of 3 or fewer individuals</quote> before the period at the end; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf30dfde001004723a4c57839e18d1a0c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
							<quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="SSEG00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc783b895edb944dc9d6b7420f37d72f0" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="id657e499fd2cd42688cf90078a0124eb4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Fee schedule</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Sportsmen's Act of 2015</short-title>, to enhance consistency in the management of Federal land, the Secretaries shall publish a single joint land use fee schedule for commercial filming and still photography.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id24b656c4098e4a72a699115b8fc28d74"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (c) (as so redesignated), in the second sentence, by striking <quote>subsection (a)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (b)</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="iddc147c229f2a4102916f9fdf1489f322"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in subsection (d) (as so redesignated), in the heading, by inserting <quote>Commercial</quote> before <quote>Still</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id60828cfe5d4e4085a8f2510ca66efab8"><enum>(6)</enum><text>in paragraph (1) of subsection (f) (as so redesignated), by inserting <quote>in accordance with the Federal Lands Recreation Enhancement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/6801">16 U.S.C. 6801 et seq.</external-xref>),</quote> after <quote>without further appropriation,</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="ide05e5ff671914e63869f630558544680"><enum>(7)</enum><text>in subsection (g) (as so redesignated)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idd97d9d86dd46474983dc584993a62587"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>The Secretary shall</quote> and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="SSEG00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id887d0fce4e754373a8a060ceb70ae6da" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="id8e3240d25e1d45dea82cfdb2aeb46e2f"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id726b5c1a1e774af88877b30caea7c5ea"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="SSEG00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida713053ea09f422ca9d965fb5659392f" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="id360575cb59d74dcea8385d925068c3e2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>The Secretary shall not consider subject matter or content as a criterion for issuing or denying a permit under this Act.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idbaa1bd840a454a5696ad0e144104fe1b"><enum>(8)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="SSEG00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3005f489d85a4cf1a0954a0011a0d212" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC"> <subsection id="id6012b5041f124859bdc0a6937aab7de3"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Exemption from commercial filming or still photography permits and fees</header><text>The Secretary shall not require persons holding commercial use authorizations or special recreation permits to obtain an additional permit or pay a fee for commercial filming or still photography under this Act if the filming or photography conducted is—</text>
 <paragraph id="id8658186bc0c74574ae0eee6b79bf41ae"><enum>(1)</enum><text>incidental to the permitted activity that is the subject of the commercial use authorization or special recreation permit; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idd8c3162a28034d84be2ea5de7f47639a"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the holder of the commercial use authorization or special recreation permit is an individual or small business concern (within the meaning of section 3 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/632">15 U.S.C. 632</external-xref>)).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id623e038610c1416e854a5d3e4acc5b5d"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Exception from certain fees</header><text>Commercial filming or commercial still photography shall be exempt from fees under this Act, but not from recovery of costs under subsection (c), if the activity—</text>
 <paragraph id="idefdda9a27d654279affb465bb3d164f1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is conducted by an entity that is a small business concern (within the meaning of section 3 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/632">15 U.S.C. 632</external-xref>));</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id8a062e92935c431abc698b474ad9950f"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is conducted by a crew of not more than 3 individuals; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id962bda9e0df840b8b001fa50a270de3e"><enum>(3)</enum><text>uses only a camera and tripod.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id72962a854fb04799bbba9b6a9176dcea"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Applicability to news gathering activities</header>
 <paragraph id="id7951804448f044de94f1add7736a0dc6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>News gathering shall not be considered a commercial activity.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id578333c1a06849c1b38259f586201a79"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Included activities</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>news gathering</term> includes, at a minimum, the gathering, recording, and filming of news and information related to news in any medium.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id3d89115f46524cc1b8bcc744eeb7517f"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/54/1009">Chapter 1009</external-xref> of title 54, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="id4454bc804ac749c0abd99e6212f5f003"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking section 100905; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id1bae4072e57747a2adf0ab1a2ad40546"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the table of contents, by striking the item relating to section 100905.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section></title><title changed="added" committee-id="SSEG00" id="id7bf815fb02d6469c91c10083e526b2f6" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>IV</enum><header>Bows, wildlife management, and access opportunities for recreation, hunting, and fishing</header> <section id="id84A073EF202E4DAABB79AB48BFA18BF0"><enum>401.</enum><header>Bows in parks</header> <subsection id="idF7FCEEF5C6234FA7AE31C203CC200125"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/54/1049">Chapter 1049</external-xref> of title 54, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="SSEG00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1421F8FB9D8848009C82C527EE3A6570" reported-display-style="italic" style="USC">
						<section id="id3931C42E717E4AB6B3B1333B03556A92"><enum>104908.</enum><header>Bows in parks</header>
 <subsection id="idF459DF8F47CB4500B9DBB1587EF4B5F8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition of not ready for immediate use</header><text>The term <term>not ready for immediate use</term> means—</text> <paragraph id="id8AD684ADC4C14822824E90927942F502"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a bow or crossbow, the arrows of which are secured or stowed in a quiver or other arrow transport case; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idFB29CDEAA3DD4612A35C886F78392428"><enum>(2)</enum><text>with respect to a crossbow, uncocked.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id3F239078E4F14B1B8F025A4846FAEFA9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Vehicular transportation authorized</header><text>The Director shall not promulgate or enforce any regulation that prohibits an individual from transporting bows and crossbows that are not ready for immediate use across any System unit in the vehicle of the individual if—</text>
 <paragraph id="id1A6F291DDF234C70A0E92D9FD8063E79"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the individual is not otherwise prohibited by law from possessing the bows and crossbows;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id1F59FD16C75F4B7DB4759DFE18DAB749"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the bows or crossbows that are not ready for immediate use remain inside the vehicle of the individual throughout the period during which the bows or crossbows are transported across System land; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id6108D2B36C054F90B61C90E9404CD179"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the possession of the bows and crossbows is in compliance with the law of the State in which the System unit is located.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="idDB5BEAB50DB34F32BB41BA9904A2CE58"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/54/1049">chapter 1049</external-xref> of title 54, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/54/104907">section 104907</external-xref> the following:</text>
					<quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="SSEG00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1BFB7A9724114BCBA082510E2C740D98" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC"><toc changed="added" committee-id="SSEG00" reported-display-style="italic"><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">104908. Bows in parks.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</subsection></section><section id="id1cb117bf2c82404888de2d1704802f63"><enum>402.</enum><header>Wildlife management in parks</header>
 <subsection id="id4f96f946881b48e493367c0a3aa0b264"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/54/1049">Chapter 1049</external-xref> of title 54, United States Code (as amended by section 401(a)), is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="SSEG00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9E9F0645557E4C89BE83E9774A5301A8" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC">
						<section id="id2D2E03F95B804732A25754931B5C5DA6"><enum>104909.</enum><header>Wildlife management in parks</header>
 <subsection commented="no" id="id0c3c6bc4eb8448ccbb67ce821b809485"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Use of qualified volunteers</header><text>If the Secretary determines it is necessary to reduce the size of a wildlife population on System land in accordance with applicable law (including regulations), the Secretary may use qualified volunteers to assist in carrying out wildlife management on System land.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="id38b189d3fe934253ad75b13572245fc4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements for qualified volunteers</header><text>Qualified volunteers providing assistance under subsection (a) shall be subject to—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="idFF8698244B2B40919828015DD6AEF7B2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any training requirements or qualifications established by the Secretary; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id2E9AC42113C544F2A904C77F1D3A34E2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any other terms and conditions that the Secretary may require.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="ideeb146c74f9c4c829da48e6c1d5fcfac"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/54/1049">chapter 1049</external-xref> of title 54 (as amended by section 401(b)), United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 104907 the following:</text>
					<quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="SSEG00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id35C2E7A4D30D4498AC5C83434FAA6FD8" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC"><toc changed="added" committee-id="SSEG00" reported-display-style="italic"><multi-column-toc-entry bold="off" level="section"><toc-enum>104909</toc-enum><level-header level="section">. Wildlife management in parks.</level-header></multi-column-toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</subsection></section><section id="idde5d3794d5c04908b85422ae123d4be6"><enum>403.</enum><header>Identifying opportunities for recreation, hunting, and fishing on Federal land</header>
 <subsection id="id25c4bceee51241f5a0308265d3341eab"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="idf700cf7cf6c044e3b2ae72d730f3ef25"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idd4014fa251c74983bf859a8219f2ba11"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary of the Interior, with respect to land administered by—</text> <clause id="iddd0fee05bcd64660b36811c1172586b4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Director of the National Park Service;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idefe4eaa16eb642ad8c7660247ac8504b"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service; and</text> </clause><clause id="id5f8599b08dfb43bd96140cd0f48b0904"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the Director of the Bureau of Land Management; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idde58f65b1529441db85d67dab0f038e1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary of Agriculture, with respect to land administered by the Chief of the Forest Service.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5bdbcd4ec3f14d898dab9cec6b3d71e8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>State or regional office</header><text>The term <term>State or regional office</term> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id42951774edce49099da729e58a0c9f1e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a State office of the Bureau of Land Management; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida847958829244f54bac2dc9b40b4eeba"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a regional office of—</text>
 <clause id="idd894dfb4aaab4becbab61b3472be8691"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the National Park Service;</text> </clause><clause id="id727c7d42792342a386a778d7ff6c02c1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the United States Fish and Wildlife Service; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="idc88b4f162d8c4262b936c772220da463"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the Forest Service.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0fc5e22cf1bc4654b755200e72e57e52"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Travel management plan</header><text>The term <term>travel management plan</term> means a plan for the management of travel—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id4521013392e041f9a3885a1cffd1385e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with respect to land under the jurisdiction of the National Park Service, on park roads and designated routes under section 4.10 of title 36, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id30f5500e2f0b425b94b07367db2c8593"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to land under the jurisdiction of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, on the land under a comprehensive conservation plan prepared under section 4(e) of the National Wildlife Refuge System Administration Act of 1966 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/668dd">16 U.S.C. 668dd(e)</external-xref>);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id10ce209ed46c4511b8a7ba573765735f"><enum>(C)</enum><text>with respect to land under the jurisdiction of the Forest Service, on National Forest System land under part 212 of title 36, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id986324c90e994f6e92105b2d0f0aa077"><enum>(D)</enum><text>with respect to land under the jurisdiction of the Bureau of Land Management, under a resource management plan developed under the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1701">43 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id9f2cca3b60934913a1a20ed13b657ccf"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Priority lists required</header>
 <paragraph id="idf57fadd63bc940669ff3ba39b2c27f37"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, annually during the 10-year period beginning on the date on which the first priority list is completed, and every 5 years after the end of the 10-year period, the Secretary shall prepare a priority list, to be made publicly available on the website of the applicable Federal agency referred to in subsection (a)(1), which shall identify the location and acreage of land within the jurisdiction of each State or regional office on which the public is allowed, under Federal or State law, to hunt, fish, or use the land for other recreational purposes but—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idd48df58126734c7b80232f8fd3fb5fc5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to which there is no public access or egress; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc1aedc2a0bb64b5a9691b43e52951acf"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to which public access or egress to the legal boundaries of the land is significantly restricted (as determined by the Secretary).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id7a721125e8c0499ba33fbcd7e48d5e8c"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Minimum size</header><text>Any land identified under paragraph (1) shall consist of contiguous acreage of at least 640 acres.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id5a46c2851dd64d0d9200bb684f55f9d6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In preparing the priority list required under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall consider with respect to the land—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id3ab1ae6043f243acaffcc2195ab81452"><enum>(A)</enum><text>whether access is absent or merely restricted, including the extent of the restriction;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id53db98168d0c4696b06b8d8aa1021f39"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the likelihood of resolving the absence of or restriction to public access;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0fd64b4c965b4a98a999d894463c6b78"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the potential for recreational use;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4d925dd42a5348bf8857855a2ae1741b"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any information received from the public or other stakeholders during the nomination process described in paragraph (5); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc0675dbdf5794fe7b9f4313a705a4c8c"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any other factor as determined by the Secretary.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id554fc7dff11b404b860049efc58c7c9f"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Adjacent land status</header><text>For each parcel of land on the priority list, the Secretary shall include in the priority list whether resolving the issue of public access or egress to the land would require acquisition of an easement, right-of-way, or fee title from—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idf6ae15b28c484865aaf89eb7ed96a9ad"><enum>(A)</enum><text>another Federal agency;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id689613af137d472ea04184f014824cfc"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a State, local, or tribal government; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide7c7118db08646698a841eaa00bbf772"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a private landowner.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idea8ff33d77cc4729bf0e70c220515085"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Nomination process</header><text>In preparing a priority list under this section, the Secretary shall provide an opportunity for members of the public to nominate parcels for inclusion on the priority list.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id928b6daad254420398c09997aeb9e13e"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Access options</header><text>With respect to land included on a priority list described in subsection (b), the Secretary shall develop and submit to the Committees on Appropriations and Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committees on Appropriations and Natural Resources of the House of Representatives a report on options for providing access that—</text>
 <paragraph id="id6031cedddce7478f898699c7f7c836a1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identifies how public access and egress could reasonably be provided to the legal boundaries of the land in a manner that minimizes the impact on wildlife habitat and water quality;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id73f9a9dc59744347bfbcd19d51b21659"><enum>(2)</enum><text>specifies the steps recommended to secure the access and egress, including acquiring an easement, right-of-way, or fee title from a willing owner of any land that abuts the land or the need to coordinate with State land management agencies or other Federal, State, or tribal governments to allow for such access and egress; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id5b47e4bbbf994cceb58754ed12220395"><enum>(3)</enum><text>is consistent with the travel management plan in effect on the land.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5869fc66c965433eb971cf24edb44d16"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Protection of personally identifying information</header><text>In making the priority list and report prepared under subsections (b) and (c) available, the Secretary shall ensure that no personally identifying information is included, such as names or addresses of individuals or entities.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idb7a45c1cde9941cf8cd6a05fbd3b566c"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Willing owners</header><text>For purposes of providing any permits to, or entering into agreements with, a State, local, or tribal government or private landowner with respect to the use of land under the jurisdiction of the government or landowner, the Secretary shall not take into account whether the State, local, or tribal government or private landowner has granted or denied public access or egress to the land.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idadc433696ac9454fabf91565608ce8a4"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Means of public access and egress included</header><text>In considering public access and egress under subsections (b) and (c), the Secretary shall consider public access and egress to the legal boundaries of the land described in those subsections, including access and egress—</text>
 <paragraph id="id5d72120b98c64348a7cc2a3e349e49db"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by motorized or non-motorized vehicles; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="ide895bf2c2e084d829d310bb8461bb440"><enum>(2)</enum><text>on foot or horseback.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4c92d819d3774aafa5dfe2c882074bdf"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Effect</header>
 <paragraph id="id86e104cb6e184ae48f5c5c9f8e7f4fd7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>This section shall have no effect on whether a particular recreational use shall be allowed on the land included in a priority list under this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id33e0ec175295464495d07d98d1a0502d"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effect of allowable uses on agency consideration</header><text>In preparing the priority list under subsection (b), the Secretary shall only consider recreational uses that are allowed on the land at the time that the priority list is prepared.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section></title><title changed="added" committee-id="SSEG00" id="idfe6b7f96c50049c3a9f6fe42dd11a40d" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>V</enum><header>Federal land transaction facilitation act</header>
			<section id="id60761aa9c2c74381ba8bf74a2168a076"><enum>501.</enum><header>Federal Land Transaction Facilitation Act</header>
 <subsection id="id92853adc340547398565b291dc99799d"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Federal Land Transaction Facilitation Act is amended—</text> <paragraph id="idda1aeb302ffc457fa198537ca9423277"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 203(2) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/2302">43 U.S.C. 2302(2)</external-xref>), by striking <quote>on the date of enactment of this Act was</quote> and inserting <quote>is</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id81538ed4a6e24e2f9cb948e4c5d24260"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 205 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/2304">43 U.S.C. 2304</external-xref>)—</text> <subparagraph id="id4f7383cd91ef4ccea17b9192f9c13194"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>(as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act)</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8049864dd8774816a56d80563c7511ee"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking subsection (d);</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide47e7656c1b340f1ab753970d5cb5d88"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in section 206 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/2305">43 U.S.C. 2305</external-xref>), by striking subsection (f); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id2a75d11666bb43b79ab4e6dc56aa3217"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in section 207(b) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/2306">43 U.S.C. 2306(b)</external-xref>)—</text> <subparagraph id="id69c0a08f9d62459a93f724621c15d747"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text>
 <clause id="id4b8114da84cc4d07997b6b70a239e4fc"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>96–568</quote> and inserting <quote>96–586</quote>; and</text> </clause><clause id="id417ae603477e4547a100ab76464dd9f5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>; or</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id02d5687aaa894114b22e1e89ace92b97"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text> <clause id="id749730789a064d0ea6653c3d02754243"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>Public Law 105–263;</quote> before <quote>112 Stat.</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="ide8fcfe885e89400684cde4d94953c319"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idca3ba8025a5647e4918ff59b97d39f1b"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
							<quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="SSEG00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide9a8d4e5b0e54b36836aca9fe142491d" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="id9fcfbf5436a54caeac5fd6cec5178203"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the White Pine County Conservation, Recreation, and Development Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/109/432">Public Law 109–432</external-xref>; 120 Stat. 3028);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id43e64055365c4ef6a95457092deddd40"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the Lincoln County Conservation, Recreation, and Development Act of 2004 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/108/424">Public Law 108–424</external-xref>; 118 Stat. 2403);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id79ae7a39de574fb5bfdddaf3256d0daf"><enum>(5)</enum><text>subtitle F of title I of the Omnibus Public Land Management Act of 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1132">16 U.S.C. 1132</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/11">Public Law 111–11</external-xref>);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id602f7d424779414a94a9c88d43fbd2d6"><enum>(6)</enum><text>subtitle O of title I of the Omnibus Public Land Management Act of 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/460www">16 U.S.C. 460www</external-xref> note, 1132 note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/11">Public Law 111–11</external-xref>);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idc1e1995a1ee247bbbe1727063dc8a468"><enum>(7)</enum><text>section 2601 of the Omnibus Public Land Management Act of 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/11">Public Law 111–11</external-xref>; 123 Stat. 1108); or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id1b9b740941f74b2c9180c43008a67a76"><enum>(8)</enum><text>section 2606 of the Omnibus Public Land Management Act of 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/11">Public Law 111–11</external-xref>; 123 Stat. 1121).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idd5f8d1db217e4cb3a23a02bd5d9cacff"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Funds to treasury</header><text>Of the amounts deposited in the Federal Land Disposal Account, there shall be transferred to the general fund of the Treasury $1,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2016 through 2025.</text>
				</subsection></section></title><title changed="added" committee-id="SSEG00" id="idf183dc6a98e04a11b87cc5142982b510" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>VI</enum><header>Conservation reauthorization</header>
			<section id="idf2b111fe673e4920bb3ffb57c54ae508"><enum>601.</enum><header>National Park Service Maintenance and Revitalization Conservation Fund</header>
 <subsection id="id4f1e3b121f4c42f487ad791036059dc7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/54/1049">Chapter 1049</external-xref> of title 54, United States Code (as amended by section 402(a)), is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="SSEG00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8E60877A6FCF4063A6FF12594450C044" reported-display-style="italic" style="USC">
						<section id="idca5fd7dc256f41d084bc1d829beb8535"><enum>104910.</enum><header>National Park Service Maintenance and Revitalization Conservation Fund</header>
 <subsection id="idc3a9a89f72d24205a74429ba2fc6499e"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text>There is established in the Treasury a fund, to be known as the <quote>National Park Service Critical Maintenance and Revitalization Conservation Fund</quote> (referred to in this section as the <quote>Fund</quote>).</text> </subsection><subsection id="id2d36d06ec68042f896c63f28777de20a"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Deposits to Fund</header><text>Notwithstanding any provision of law providing that the proceeds shall be credited to miscellaneous receipts of the Treasury, for each fiscal year, there shall be deposited in the Fund, from revenues due and payable to the United States under section 9 of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1338">43 U.S.C. 1338</external-xref>) $150,000,000.</text>
							</subsection><subsection id="idf715fd4ac5154472957079226cc84c38"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use and Availability</header>
 <paragraph id="id8b86902fd3cf4daf9c7f5427f0a93cfc"><enum>(1)</enum><header> In General</header><text>Amounts deposited in the Fund shall—</text> <subparagraph id="id3e4e3f73dad647058f0f0afd1ab37312"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be used only for the purposes described in subsection (d); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida5da0a418f2a49edb7ffe2acafc4c466"><enum>(B)</enum><text>be available for expenditure only after the amounts are appropriated for those purposes.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1d79eb3ae92e4bd687edd66810e5fb70"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>Any amounts in the Fund not appropriated shall remain available in the Fund until appropriated.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ideee4479e5a904c14a8ae64e564cffc22"><enum>(3)</enum><header>No Limitation</header><text>Appropriations from the Fund pursuant to this section may be made without fiscal year limitation.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idc65b1710771a461eb5d0171c71ee0b1d"><enum>(d)</enum><header>National Park System Critical Deferred Maintenance</header><text>The Secretary shall use amounts appropriated from the Fund for high-priority deferred maintenance needs of the Service that support critical infrastructure and visitor services.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="ide7ce8f40fc7d449a91fe9d7991e5d84a"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Land Acquisition Prohibition</header><text>Amounts in the Fund shall not be used for land acquisition.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="id5707dc1c0c6e417d8f59b9701117abee"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/54/1049">chapter 1049</external-xref> of title 54, United States Code (as amended by section 402(b)), is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 104907 the following:</text>
					<quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="SSEG00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id67C3CE0886184A3DBF7C18B1C53AFAC5" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC"><toc changed="added" committee-id="SSEG00" reported-display-style="italic"><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">104910. National Park Service Maintenance and Revitalization Conservation Fund.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</subsection></section><section id="idb1c8ddeab2c04388984b0d9133a84d3a"><enum>602.</enum><header>Land and Water Conservation Fund</header>
 <subsection id="id419e7a632b764eef8476f75d7d4df50c"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reauthorization</header><text>Section 200302 of title 54, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="id902157ff6f6c4809b5d7959e51f46adb"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b), in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by striking <quote>During the period ending September 30, 2015, there</quote> and inserting <quote>There</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id08cd13e458c64ce5bb7eb9f3948dd278"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (c)(1), by striking <quote>through September 30, 2015</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0db8af9108fb4704aa5ecb8e2c044a2c"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Allocation of Funds</header><text>Section 200304 of title 54, United States Code, is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="ida9e6b34e55d240b1a997753274498504"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>There</quote> and inserting <quote>(a) <header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">In general</header-in-text>.—There</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id43f047171fef45908543629d33fc1984"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking the second sentence and inserting the following:</text>
						<quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="SSEG00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2340FE5BC44B4481AE53E9655A0B3BC1" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="id8222e4589b514f1eb4ff146ca5d3446d"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Allocation</header><text>Of the appropriations from the Fund—</text> <paragraph id="id1b6243a0148d452bbc63582f54556b43"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not less than 40 percent shall be used collectively for Federal purposes under section 200306;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id4d1443ce5f924d3cbb22e6a10235bf41"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not less than 40 percent shall be used collectively—</text> <subparagraph id="id22b99ca3460d46588b81eb163578e7f1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to provide financial assistance to States under section 200305;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0056488c10e4494c8d40a6270c9ea5f6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for the Forest Legacy Program established under section 7 of the Cooperative Forestry Assistance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/2103c">16 U.S.C. 2103c</external-xref>);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5e07dadc2947420eb5b0cf7d4e35d739"><enum>(C)</enum><text>for cooperative endangered species grants authorized under section 6 of the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1535">16 U.S.C. 1535</external-xref>); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id89997a329a844435ac38a28811d163b2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>for the American Battlefield Protection Program established under chapter 3081; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id8d6795987b0a407b9a72a6064f05f488"><enum>(3)</enum><text>not less than 1.5 percent or $10,000,000, whichever is greater, shall be used for projects that secure recreational public access to Federal public land for hunting, fishing, or other recreational purposes.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id013700fb6394409e8829516e0e4c0747"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conservation Easements</header><text>Section 200306 of title 54, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="SSEG00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idDC9BDA8A4CFD4D1186EC6FC8C2D1FE78" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC"> <subsection id="id24a6da60841847b5a4420bac3c7fd149"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conservation easements</header><text>The Secretary and the Secretary of Agriculture shall consider the acquisition of conservation easements and other similar interests in land where appropriate and feasible.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="idc237d6114c2c4c7294745877bc1fc3ab"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Acquisition Considerations</header><text>Section 200306 of title 54, United States Code (as amended by subsection (c)), is amended by adding at the end of the following:</text>
					<quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="SSEG00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6C4908CD9FCA4DD0B0CE43E943D1648F" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="id0d7c9264d8714b55b55978e20ac19638"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Acquisition considerations</header><text>The Secretary and the Secretary of Agriculture shall take into account the following in determining the land or interests in land to acquire:</text>
 <paragraph id="idc759ae44d71841338e58a32fff4ad981"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Management efficiencies.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idb3ca5c602047478f98a678a1483d7624"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Management cost savings.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id22285f2457b64b89b779b55d23a4b891"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Geographic distribution.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id48f82e1c3be14191bf67a17b5d13cede"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Significance of the acquisition.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id7547fcf89ca04574bebb15744ff0966a"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Urgency of the acquisition.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idbad2b6e3bf714395817a1ed23fe77a52"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Threats to the integrity of the land to be acquired.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id81386d58ea7a45ef8b3c7e15d217b2be"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The recreational value of the land.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection></section><section id="idf12f2c8d806c413d9f7fbd5d61c107a3"><enum>603.</enum><header>Historic Preservation Fund</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 303102 of title 54, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>of fiscal years 2012 to 2015</quote> and inserting <quote>fiscal year</quote>.</text>
			</section></title><title changed="added" committee-id="SSEG00" id="id86a7971defc145499013758b19039e45" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>VII</enum><header>Miscellaneous</header>
 <section id="id2778207591524402ad5def9a28f67b4b"><enum>701.</enum><header>Respect for treaties and rights</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act or the amendments made by this Act—</text> <paragraph id="id22DEE273AAC24BBA8D31E92B6DEC2065"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">affects or modifies any treaty or other right of any federally recognized Indian tribe; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idA04109989AF34617B71F6EA15127D0EB"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">modifies any provision of Federal law relating to migratory birds or to endangered or threatened species.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="idf5c964269ff7457ea597360cde52c6b4"><enum>702.</enum><header>No priority</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act or the amendments made by this Act provides a preference to hunting, fishing, or recreational shooting over any other use of Federal land or water.</text></section></title></legis-body><official-title-amendment>Amend the title so as to read: <quote>A bill to protect and enhance opportunities for hunting, fishing, and recreational shooting, and
			 for other purposes.</quote>.</official-title-amendment><endorsement><action-date>December 16, 2015</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment and an amendment to the title</action-desc></endorsement></bill>


