<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1203 IS: 21st Century Veterans Benefits Delivery Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1203</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150506">May 6, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S352">Mr. Heller</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S309">Mr. Casey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S347">Mr. Moran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S338">Mr. Manchin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S351">Mr. Toomey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S359">Mr. Heinrich</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S299">Mr. Vitter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S314">Mr. Tester</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S252">Ms. Collins</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSVA00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend title 38, United States Code, to improve the processing by the Department of Veterans
			 Affairs of claims for benefits under laws administered by the Secretary of
			 Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header>
 <subsection id="idA95F3C90097649BB9B1FECED4662543D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>21st Century Veterans Benefits Delivery Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idDE1A0B36B59E4F40AF76B44B2481CA69"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text><toc><toc-entry idref="S1" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id9D6906ACFD6D4B6EB9083F76243118ED" level="title">TITLE I—Benefits claims submission</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id39ABD1E035B24472A19076FA03400D3E" level="section">Sec. 101. Improvements to Transition Assistance Program.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="idEC0D015A7764474FAA92E0DD3E02BF54" level="section">Sec. 102. Requirement that decisions on claims explain advantages of filing appeals within 180 days.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id23C72729B1B84954AB622334A06CD643" level="section">Sec. 103. Determination of manner of appearance for hearings before Board of Veterans' Appeals.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="idFDC759902E08404FBE31DD850A111D51" level="title">TITLE II—Practices of regional offices</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="idd36a86be2c58471d96b82a81e61c6be6" level="section">Sec. 201. Required Comptroller General audit of regional offices of Veterans Benefits Administration.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="idAC4AAEF7B91E4E24B50A055DB64E2904" level="section">Sec. 202. Requirement for management training program for veterans service center managers of Veterans Benefits Administration.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id27CC20F88A5F4A86BDCEA1C955E94EC9" level="section">Sec. 203. Analysis of communication between regional offices of Department of Veterans Affairs and veterans service organizations and Congressional caseworkers.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="idd700b4d663ca4c5889c31b6393c7b280" level="section">Sec. 204. Review of practices of regional offices regarding use of suspense dates.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id3BD35AA7738149FEB77861D21C4D82A2" level="section">Sec. 205. Annual report on capacity of Veterans Benefits Administration to process benefits claims.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id7840B8FF330544CDA5C4426595BA79E8" level="section">Sec. 206. Requirement to complete efforts to revise resource allocation model of Department of Veterans Affairs.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id62A0CA4655144FFAB9AD6EC6DDDA186D" level="section">Sec. 207. Semiannual report on progress in implementing Veterans Benefits Management System.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id49E88379EEFB41FF9A34F33EF02B99F3" level="section">Sec. 208. Report on plans of Secretary of Veterans Affairs to reduce inventory of claims for dependency and indemnity compensation and claims for pension.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="iddd5a1d8f7be24a8582a0c571b07fe580" level="section">Sec. 209. Increased transparency in Monday Morning Workload Report.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id65a3d04b28214932b98e0652e787fd13" level="section">Sec. 210. Reports on appeals of decisions on benefits claims.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="HF34AF2FF67C546DAAE77FF4D61CBC3C3" level="section">Sec. 211. Modification of pilot program for use of contract physicians for disability examinations.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="idBFF6A6B4528646618BF2E11AF9E13CB7" level="title">TITLE III—Government response</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="idb17687d4c7c24efcb3e0373611463c0a" level="section">Sec. 301. Increased cooperation across Government.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="idB8C131ACF78F41D0B71DAD6E45C796A9" level="section">Sec. 302. Report on interoperability between electronic health records systems of Department of Defense and Department of Veterans Affairs.</toc-entry> </toc> </subsection></section><title id="id9D6906ACFD6D4B6EB9083F76243118ED" style="OLC"><enum>I</enum><header>Benefits claims submission</header> <section id="id39ABD1E035B24472A19076FA03400D3E"><enum>101.</enum><header>Improvements to Transition Assistance Program</header> <subsection id="id6E84A00D401E43BA848C969D6BD5A2E9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Modification To enable online access</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1144 of title 10, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5F7018DB03BA407495CAE90844E3920D" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="id290C4059BDD64FC3A75F22D5ADF923AC"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Online access</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id327D490CEBBC4FA5BA3189D7C7789A91"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary of Labor, in conjunction with the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, shall take such actions and make such modifications to the eBenefits Internet website as may be necessary to ensure that members of the armed forces and spouses described in subsection (a)(1) can access materials from the program carried out under this section through an Internet website.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id39FE04B9D1574AFB9E6BD6A4F2871EF9" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An individual subject to a requirement under subsection (c) may not satisfy such requirement by participating in the program carried out under this section solely through an Internet website.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</subsection><subsection id="id577D29A3282D4FA9925F5D28586CCF16"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Participation of veterans service organizations</header>
 <paragraph id="id64A84DCE945643C8ADD1F4DA0FAAA4A8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that the Secretary of Defense, in collaboration with the Secretary of Labor, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, should establish a process by which a representative of a veterans service organization may be present at any portion of the program carried out under section 1144 of title 10, United States Code, relating to the submittal of claims to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs for compensation under chapter 11 or 13 of title 38, United States Code.</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="id4C003C1B19584F55B337F36F4813522B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header>
 <subparagraph id="id1565145ADFE7444BA4CD4E2E77894A96"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to Congress a report on participation of veterans service organizations in the program carried out under section 1144 of title 10, United States Code.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idEE707C56CABB4BADA54BAF2EF8C1944E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report required by subparagraph (A) shall include the following:</text> <clause id="idD80E9BEA98E9444599C923F69B6E2F5B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>An assessment of the compliance of facilities of the Department of Defense with the directives included in the memorandum of the Secretary of Defense entitled <quote>Installation Access and Support Services for Nonprofit Non-Federal Entities</quote> and dated December 23, 2014.</text>
 </clause><clause id="idF3ABD0FD2ACF45999FE90028FBF9BCBF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The number of military bases that have complied with such directives.</text> </clause><clause id="idEEB202B874A34F40B10B204B5A6A40FA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>How many veterans service organizations have been present at a portion of a program as described in paragraph (1).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idE2BB436916044304A76306AA7FE740D4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Veterans service organization defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the term <term>veterans service organization</term> means any organization recognized by the Secretary for the representation of veterans under section 5902 of title 38.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idEC0D015A7764474FAA92E0DD3E02BF54"><enum>102.</enum><header>Requirement that decisions on claims explain advantages of filing appeals within 180 days</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 5104(a) of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="id4786FD5D888A4B86B0613701202C21A7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>(1)</quote> before <quote>In the case</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id20750D6DB18C49798667579856036C5C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking the second sentence and inserting the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id55A308D8FBC6469ABE2792833EBB9DA0" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="idDE882341F7A2468AA181A1259EA7A05C" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The notice shall include the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="id7F14EF0541534A0A8256AD9857336918"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An explanation of the procedure for obtaining review of the decision.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE4C78B5758F9434EABAB783636C79A8E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An explanation of the advantages of filing for review of the decision within 180 days.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></section><section id="id23C72729B1B84954AB622334A06CD643"><enum>103.</enum><header>Determination
			 of manner of appearance for hearings before Board of Veterans' Appeals</header>
				<subsection id="id9531732AF2DF4874BCF450F73957DA07"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>Section 7107 of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="idA84D2124E4F8413AA72325C37D6DA2BD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking subsection (e);</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id4E0A9B7DA28341B18675EDF36F5C1733"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (d) and (f) as subsections (f) and (g), respectively;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idECB124C008984C7D9556CA0F7891D6DA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (c) the following new subsections (d) and (e):</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1B180A20F17D4CC19EC06B8BD5E115B4" style="OLC"> <subsection id="id935D177D666C40CBB0560A45A15366F2"><enum>(d)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idD46C52E838AC4AF6AF549FC26D8C4D7C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Subject to paragraph (2), a hearing before the Board shall be conducted, as the Board considers appropriate—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id903855C314E242849AB2C03B52E104EF" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in person; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id473FA703E789468F98F5A937127FFAE5" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>through picture and voice transmission, by electronic or other means, in such manner that the appellant is not present in the same location as the members of the Board during the hearing.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1BB93F60617C43D9B39BB239B2DEF44C" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Upon request by an appellant, a hearing before the Board shall be conducted, as the appellant considers appropriate—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idAF58A05A7C294693A2803EDBB8635851"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in person; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id34C7D8189CD24657AB8D410C2B1F2F17"><enum>(B)</enum><text>through picture and voice transmission as described in paragraph (1)(B).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id28acdc71747848cb84b6c1275336722c"><enum>(e)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idD9EE3CAF7402485AACE2EB1462B532CC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In a case in which a hearing before the Board is to be conducted through picture and voice transmission as described in subsection (d)(1)(B), the Secretary shall provide suitable facilities and equipment to the Board or other components of the Department to enable an appellant located at an appropriate facility within the area served by a regional office to participate as so described.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id2195d679c1dc4be58145316766e2cc76" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Any hearing conducted through picture and voice transmission as described in subsection (d)(1)(B) shall be conducted in the same manner as, and shall be considered the equivalent of, a personal hearing.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idCA5D59516D1E472C8F2F45F5D3BF7A04"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (f)(1), as redesignated by paragraph (2), by striking <quote>An appellant may request</quote> and all that follows through <quote>office of the Department</quote> and inserting <quote>In a case in which a hearing before the Board is to be conducted in person, the hearing shall be held at the principal location of the Board or at a facility of the Department located within the area served by a regional office of the Department.</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idDACBC5E56B1B49839DC1229DABD41C71"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (a) shall apply with respect to cases received by the Board of Veterans' Appeals pursuant to notices of disagreement submitted on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
				</subsection></section></title><title id="idFDC759902E08404FBE31DD850A111D51" style="OLC"><enum>II</enum><header>Practices of regional offices</header>
			<section id="idd36a86be2c58471d96b82a81e61c6be6"><enum>201.</enum><header>Required Comptroller General audit of regional offices of Veterans Benefits Administration</header>
 <subsection id="idA11E713F40C249938577221156B5B968"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall complete an audit of the regional offices of the Veterans Benefits Administration—</text>
 <paragraph id="id5D41325B5E80475799D9BC02966E4EDE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to assess the consistency of decisions being made with respect to claims for benefits under laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idFB73F0B242F2488980AE96FFC2B28C2B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to identify ways in which the consistency of such decisions can be improved.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5177419D6AFC4303963D5DC32AEF2703"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Identification of factors and best practices</header><text>The audit conducted under subsection (a) shall include the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="idD8AA161CD015430998A4A20512E3F9E0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Identification of the factors, including management practices, that distinguish higher performing regional offices from other regional offices.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id5613A4D47C0E40DDB4AE0F590879910B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Identification of best practices employed by higher performing regional offices that distinguish the performance of such offices from other regional offices.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id09B56946365E41C59D00322E159D2AF2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date on which the Comptroller General completes the audit required by subsection (a), the Comptroller General shall submit to Congress a report on the results of the audit.</text>
				</subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idAC4AAEF7B91E4E24B50A055DB64E2904" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>202.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Requirement for management training program for veterans service center managers of Veterans
 Benefits Administration</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall establish a training program for veterans service center managers, or for employees in successor positions in regional offices of the Veterans Benefits Administration, on matters concerning managerial skills and such other skills as the Secretary considers appropriate for such managers.</text>
			</section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id27CC20F88A5F4A86BDCEA1C955E94EC9"><enum>203.</enum><header>Analysis of communication between regional offices of Department of Veterans Affairs and veterans
			 service organizations and Congressional caseworkers</header>
 <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE677D67820F84EBA8E3BECCC1D02DEC3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall ensure that each systemic analysis of operations that is completed by a veterans service center manager in a regional office of the Department of Veterans Affairs includes an analysis of the communication between the regional office and veterans service organizations and caseworkers employed by Members of Congress.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9A987359BCC9478BBAB8961A9C33B488"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Veterans service organization defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>veterans service organization</term> means any organization recognized by the Secretary for the representation of veterans under section 5902 of title 38, United States Code.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="idd700b4d663ca4c5889c31b6393c7b280"><enum>204.</enum><header>Review of practices of regional offices regarding use of suspense dates</header>
 <subsection id="idB1819FCD7BA7442EA0F66724B3AB0398"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Review required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Inspector General of the Department of Veterans Affairs shall conduct a review of the practices of regional offices of the Department regarding the use of suspense dates during the disability claim assessment process.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6F634147B77946FBABA66A14054914AC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 270 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Inspector General of the Department shall submit to Congress a report on the findings of the Inspector General with respect to the review conducted under subsection (a).</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id700FFA6995F04ADF8F89D112F0E3045D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Suspense date defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>suspense date</term> means a measure used by the Veterans Benefits Administration to set incremental deadlines for disability claims as they progress through the disability claim assessment process.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="id3BD35AA7738149FEB77861D21C4D82A2"><enum>205.</enum><header>Annual report on capacity of Veterans Benefits Administration to process benefits claims</header>
 <subsection id="idCE3E4816C17743628192084663E14854"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Along with the supporting information included in the budget submitted by the President for fiscal year 2017 pursuant to section 1105(a) of title 31, United States Code, and with the supporting information included in each budget submittal under such section thereafter, the President shall include a report that the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall prepare on the capacity of the Veterans Benefits Administration to process claims for benefits under laws administered by the Secretary during the fiscal year covered by the budget with which the report is submitted.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id1AB73937C4294BA4A92F4778EFC4A2F5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each report submitted under subsection (a) shall include, for the period covered by the report, the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="id0bc54483dbe3470d8194fb9aca8306b1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The number of claims for benefits under laws administered by the Secretary that the Secretary expects the Veterans Benefits Administration to process.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id756DD61C6477400EADB8219926609D37"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The number of full-time equivalent employees of the Veterans Benefits Administration who are dedicated to processing such claims.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id30E2DEDF90984A148DE159D72F3BD963"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An estimate of the average number of such claims a single full-time equivalent employee of the Administration can process in a year, based on a time and motion study that the Secretary shall conduct on the processing of such claims.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id610FC5559E8B48A68B682677106CB5E3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An assessment of whether the Administration requires additional or fewer full-time equivalent employees to process such claims during the next one-year, five-year, and ten-year periods.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idF39C55615D874998BFB268E61C80CB93"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A description of the actions the Secretary will take to improve the processing of such claims.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idE1339959408F4BD08B1408E9203A644E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>An assessment of the actions identified by the Secretary in the previous report submitted under subsection (a) and identification of the effects of those actions.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id57923036EF3D40CF8E72C915AFFAA169"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The Secretary shall make each report required by subsection (a) available to the public on an Internet website of the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text>
				</subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7840B8FF330544CDA5C4426595BA79E8"><enum>206.</enum><header>Requirement to complete efforts to revise resource allocation model of Department of Veterans
			 Affairs</header>
 <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idC0B8D3BC97FA44B98514718C1AECDE50"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall complete the efforts of the Department of Veterans Affairs to revise the resource allocation model of the Veterans Benefits Administration.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idCD88052570924AECA684B3D6AFC5AC02"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on the resource allocation model revised pursuant to subsection (a).</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="id62A0CA4655144FFAB9AD6EC6DDDA186D"><enum>207.</enum><header>Semiannual report on progress in implementing Veterans Benefits Management System</header>
 <subsection id="id0F2C109EFECB47D78E37011B630A0B05"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act and not less frequently than once every 180 days thereafter until the date that is three years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to Congress a report on the progress of the Secretary in implementing the Veterans Benefits Management System.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id44C627F342814CA58A576BEDB543FEEE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall include the following:</text> <paragraph id="idD306E81970964B20A828FA24996B2AF8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An assessment of the current functionality of the Veterans Benefits Management System.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id85AD8CAC67954E22BB54BFD74D5EF993"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Recommendations submitted to the Secretary by employees of the Department of Veterans Affairs who are involved in processing claims for benefits under laws administered by the Secretary, including veteran service representatives, rating veteran service representatives, and decision review officers, for such legislative or administrative action as the employees consider appropriate to improve the processing of such claims.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idA757B5577E6E4D24AAE7159550D0DC4B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Recommendations submitted to the Secretary by veterans service organizations who use the Veterans Benefits Management System for such legislative or administrative action as the veterans service organization consider appropriate to improve such system.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id49E88379EEFB41FF9A34F33EF02B99F3"><enum>208.</enum><header>Report on plans of Secretary of Veterans Affairs to reduce inventory of claims for dependency and
 indemnity compensation and claims for pension</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to Congress a report that details the plans of the Secretary to reduce the inventory of—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id27938399FE02489B8C660BADCA716896"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">claims submitted to the Secretary for compensation under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/13">chapter 13</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idA471155A1C8846F2BA2C706B059B1EDF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>claims submitted to the Secretary for pension under chapter 15 of such title.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="iddd5a1d8f7be24a8582a0c571b07fe580"><enum>209.</enum><header>Increased transparency in Monday Morning Workload Report</header> <subsection id="id787ce500ab3447caba4577bbfdd06b1d"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Disaggregation of claims by decisions requiring disability rating</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall include in each Monday Morning Workload Report published by the Secretary the number of claims for benefits under laws administered by the Secretary that have been received by a regional office of the Department of Veterans Affairs and are pending a decision, disaggregated by—</text>
 <paragraph id="idB096A45DEBB04F37B0260C1BC94D3D0C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>claims that have been pending for more than 125 days;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id0EBE7AD0E599466BA720A1D73C793FCC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>claims that have been pending for 125 days or fewer; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id878F0C3DA2214E18BDF64DDE15171146"><enum>(3)</enum><text>claims that do not require a decision concerning a disability rating.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide2d2348b59714ff0ab0e07b59e687a8b"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Inclusion of information on assignment of partial ratings</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall include in each Monday Morning Workload Report published by the Secretary in the portion of the report entitled <quote>Transformation</quote> and in the portion of the report entitled <quote>Aggregate</quote> the number of partial ratings assigned.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id4e52a4ae67b94b79be7356904cae6757"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report on fully developed claims</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall include in each Monday Morning Workload Report published by the Secretary the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="idF4DD741B4DD941159F4F3C62637F099C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The total number of fully developed claims for benefits under laws administered by the Secretary that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id3D1AAB9A53AE4AF497747380E98EC006"><enum>(A)</enum><text>have been received by a regional office of the Department of Veterans Affairs; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idDDA9001CCC9E419AABFFD11E18B5F91F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>are pending a decision.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2EB042CC8EE94C9C8D246A35B9081CC1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The total number of such claims that have been pending for more than 125 days, disaggregated by station.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id536772CD739C4B33A243571930E73139"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Station defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>station</term> means the location of a regional office of the Department where claims for disability compensation are processed.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="id65a3d04b28214932b98e0652e787fd13"><enum>210.</enum><header>Reports on appeals of decisions on benefits claims</header>
 <subsection id="id3B9A1D5694534A0A869E08AC982D9841"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall make the reports of the Department of Veterans Affairs entitled <quote>Appeals Pending</quote> and <quote>Appeals Workload By Station</quote> available to the public on an Internet website of the Department.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1CFF1C6D2732439497F15B6869022104"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Appeals granted by station</header><text>The Secretary shall include in one of the reports described in subsection (a) the percentage of appeals granted by station.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id088E80BA2790456699D2305602B18FD7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Claims previously adjudicated by Appeals Management Center</header><text>The Secretary shall include in one of the reports described in subsection (a) the percentage of claims previously adjudicated by the Appeals Management Center that were either subsequently granted or remanded by the Board of Veterans' Appeals.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id76861865C67A4B81A5C8E035AA7C8EDF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Station defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>station</term> means the location of a regional office of the Department where claims for disability compensation are processed.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HF34AF2FF67C546DAAE77FF4D61CBC3C3"><enum>211.</enum><header>Modification of pilot program for use of contract physicians for disability examinations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 504 of the Veterans’ Benefits Improvement Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/275">Public Law 104–275</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/5101">38 U.S.C. 5101</external-xref> note) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H702E22C2EEEE4244BF6509713B5D2A9C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (c) and (d) as subsections (d) and (e), respectively; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H87F5FF2D74D5486982D04D9590B1DBD1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (b) the following new subsection (c):</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H568C56CFD7DE4DB9AAA407945A26D4CB" style="OLC">
						<subsection id="H4EE5006E0A9C4BDCBF7B8F618437E48E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Licensure of contract physicians</header>
 <paragraph id="H9AE35024B19E47AAA603AB118F837F14"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any law regarding the licensure of physicians, a physician described in paragraph (2) may conduct an examination pursuant to a contract entered into under subsection (a) at any location in any State, the District of Columbia, or a Commonwealth, territory, or possession of the United States, so long as the examination is within the scope of the authorized duties under such contract.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0F86E235530A4A2B8B98B21DE26DF073"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Physician described</header><text>A physician described in this paragraph is a physician who—</text> <subparagraph id="H4D3AD02F290B4BB89C4083A1F0456F1B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has a current license to practice the health care profession of the physician; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBA654B85084F4F48A3BB251F12219633"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is performing authorized duties for the Department of Veterans Affairs pursuant to a contract entered into under subsection (a).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></section></title><title id="idBFF6A6B4528646618BF2E11AF9E13CB7" style="OLC"><enum>III</enum><header>Government response</header>
			<section id="idb17687d4c7c24efcb3e0373611463c0a"><enum>301.</enum><header>Increased cooperation across Government</header>
				<subsection id="idDAF42D09438A48FFA02139DED3F5A2A2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Appointment of liaisons</header>
 <paragraph id="id4FF8290973CD42B98461C012C6A9F2DF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Department of Defense</header><text>The Secretary of Defense shall appoint individuals as follows:</text> <subparagraph id="id51D817296E3B40AAA4748F163EB6409E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>At least one individual to act as a liaison under this section between the Department of Defense and the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4B7FB04EBC8B4BB5BC7B715630B79C50"><enum>(B)</enum><text>At least one individual for each of the reserve components of the Armed Forces to act as a liaison under this section between the respective component of the Armed Forces and the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idE486A2FE2D19443B96ED5045980BB396"><enum>(2)</enum><header>National Archives and Records Administration</header><text>The Archivist of the United States shall appoint at least one individual to act as a liaison under this section between the National Archives and Records Administration and the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0ED3A9C678014C2C94A127B6311C548D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties of liaisons</header><text>Each individual acting as a liaison under this section shall expedite the timely provision to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs of such information as the Secretary requires to process claims submitted to the Secretary for benefits under laws administered by the Secretary.</text>
				</subsection><subsection id="id269BC6019A5C487E8131263D95B0B7F2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Procedures</header>
 <paragraph id="idEB7E45CEE9B145E3B5F09CC2CE466BE6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs, the Secretary of Defense, and the Archivist of the United States shall jointly develop and implement procedures to improve the timely provision to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs of such information as the Secretary requires to process claims submitted to the Secretary for benefits under laws administered by the Secretary.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id3F46F127017A4AE59C03C842280A5CF3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Timely provision</header><text>The procedures developed and implemented under paragraph (1) shall ensure that the information provided to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs is provided to the Secretary not later than 30 days after the date on which the Secretary requests the information.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id8690BB3EFD4944638A65F2DB0DE8FB82"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Annual reports</header><text>Not less frequently than once each year, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to Congress a report on—</text>
 <paragraph id="idBDA75A69B15F4B60ABDA22DAB429938E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the requests for information made by the Secretary during the most recent one-year period for information from the Secretary of Defense and the Archivist of the United States required by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to process claims submitted to the Secretary for benefits under laws administered by the Secretary; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idC17C367B13704F36B0F123D0A02E0670"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the timeliness of responses to such requests.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idB8C131ACF78F41D0B71DAD6E45C796A9"><enum>302.</enum><header>Report on interoperability between electronic health records systems of Department of Defense and Department of Veterans Affairs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall jointly submit to Congress a report that sets forth a timeline with milestones for achieving interoperability between the electronic health records systems of the Department of Defense and the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text></section></title></legis-body></bill>


