<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S2122 IS: Invest in Our Communities Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-10-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 2122</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151001">October 1, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S348">Mr. Paul</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To increase the worldwide level of employment-based immigrants and to reauthorize the EB–5 regional
			 center program.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
 <section id="id0B3197E3022142C29C5C7BBE49A9D0FD" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Invest in Our Communities Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="idc2d349fa668a4fa5b0c2fb5b825c7544" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Exemption of dependents from being counted towards worldwide employment-based immigration level</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 201(b)(1) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1151">8 U.S.C. 1151(b)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2280AAD614454CC9BDDAC58795888015" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3cfd42f678ec415fa192b4498012d69f" indent="up1"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Aliens who are spouses or children of an alien admitted as an employment-based immigrant under section 203(b)(5).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="id29E07E9F0FA54D6ABECBEEA48AF53156" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Worldwide level of employment-based immigrants</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 201(d) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1151">8 U.S.C. 1151(d)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2F8DB5F3822840F3AAE88C300D4E648B" style="OLC">
				<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID17ABC115784C499F95BD134722D470EA"><enum>(d)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Worldwide level of employment-Based immigrants</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9649D4428A9C4E6096263119F87DDB90"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>The worldwide level of employment-based immigrants under this subsection for a fiscal year is equal to the sum of—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0B6BF1838F85445C8A098003F8C2C410"><enum>(A)</enum><text>150,000; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0885CC9537FB465898E5F8AED959E43E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number computed under paragraph (2).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id574C3322D0CD4D93B1304939E12A9A79"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Adjustment</header><text>The number computed under this paragraph for fiscal year 2015 and each subsequent fiscal year is the difference (if any) between—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id37256DDD3EC64524947DFF430085F569"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the maximum number of visas which may be issued under section 203(a) (relating to family-sponsored immigrants) during the previous fiscal year; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF9FA9AEFC65A47DDA4FD05FC15F19CA9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of visas issued under that section during that year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="id6eb73d52ae8b4387bde4366399b8beea"><enum>4.</enum><header>Exclusion of EB–5 visas from country caps</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 202(a)(5) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1152">8 U.S.C. 1152(a)(5)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7E006DE7A8B040CD950C6F9533102678" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="id76A896A485A24750917DEAF20A4A2FD9"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Exclusion of EB–5 visas from per country limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Visas issued under section 203(b)(5) shall not be counted toward the numerical limitation under paragraph (2).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="idB88F2A8B559A454B944A85D7DED8F558" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>5.</enum><header>Permanent reauthorization of employment creation regional centers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 203(b)(5) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(b)(5)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="id461A975534104DA7B4DDDFA1D988CC2C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating subparagraph (D) as subparagraph (H); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id39D39F51438143388CF7724A2830414F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting after subparagraph (C) the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idC8915DFAF1A64871A1CC0F075AA67BBE" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="idae0dedb80feb4f309678ebc537c441d9"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Employment creation regional centers</header> <clause id="id7c333eb3fb284a75a839a5f16e75aa49"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Visas under this paragraph shall be made available to qualified immigrants who participate in a program involving a regional center in the United States, which has been designated by the Secretary of Homeland Security, in consultation with the Secretary of Commerce, on the basis of a general proposal filed with the Secretary of Homeland Security, for the promotion of economic growth, including—</text>
 <subclause id="idD58B8C93724B44E8B4941819D63C2450"><enum>(I)</enum><text>increased exports;</text> </subclause><subclause id="id7936BB5B72E54D919983937A0F51851F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>improved regional productivity;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idEEF72C49BE1047F5A6F626A02B088191"><enum>(III)</enum><text>job creation; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="id46DF56DC319743C38EE735ED776E0E53"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>increased domestic capital investment.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="id9EB9D34C0C1448B7A7A5D8CE4B7C5697"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Jurisdiction</header><text>A regional center shall have jurisdiction over a specific geographic area, which shall be—</text> <subclause id="id16CD42A3CA8E4CF28A707C892B30FC8D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>described in the proposal filed under clause (i); and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idA90D474C37854055A74B9CB5FD0BED87"><enum>(II)</enum><text>consistent with the purpose of concentrating pooled investment in defined economic zones.</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="id4CC4620E98FF4B81B8C3622D03B3C3F5"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>General predictions</header><text>The establishment of a regional center under this subparagraph may be based on general predictions contained in the proposal concerning—</text>
 <subclause id="ided855bf5594c4578a0ed9ea1e6de757c"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the kinds of new commercial enterprises that will receive capital from aliens;</text> </subclause><subclause id="id371653b052564281b9aba6f5a09193e0"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the jobs that will be created directly or indirectly as a result of such investments; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id90504d5637d8497aa539aaeec7ba90f2"><enum>(III)</enum><text>other positive economic effects such investments will have.</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="id741ed9cbba6c415eaff9f343dcb18ab1"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Methodologies for determining job creation</header><text>Notwithstanding requirements applicable to investors not involved in a regional center, in determining compliance with this subparagraph, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall recognize reasonable methodologies for determining the number of jobs created by a designated regional center, including jobs that are estimated to have been created indirectly through revenues generated from—</text>
 <subclause id="idFD743E3BE0AC4AA3AC5CF49B0BF638E5"><enum>(I)</enum><text>increased exports;</text> </subclause><subclause id="id8AD1836FDD83490497768E030A73F715"><enum>(II)</enum><text>improved regional productivity; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id2DE26E0640FD491787FBC35CF3394BC9"><enum>(III)</enum><text>increased domestic capital investment resulting from the regional center.</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="id235f59bb120a409a8a8e8b411e466c7d"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Special procedures</header> <subclause id="idfe48798c048f4781933c8f4781cf88c5"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Preapproval of new commercial enterprises</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall establish a preapproval procedure for new commercial enterprises that—</text>
 <item id="idc298d91ea6584404af1c18243e0d86af"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>allows a regional center or potential regional center to apply to the Secretary for preapproval of a new commercial enterprise before any alien files a petition for classification under this paragraph by reason of investment in the new commercial enterprise;</text>
 </item><item id="id4cb259c556074efb8d87251836a75b1d"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>allows the applicant to address and cure any deficiencies identified by the Secretary in the application before a final determination on the application;</text>
 </item><item id="id03bc993c987c45fc88c595fd45ec3c06"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>requires that the Secretary make final decisions on all issues under this paragraph other than those issues unique to each individual investor in the new commercial enterprise; and</text>
 </item><item id="id3d2563cc14744b7ca1d05bc11ae1f439"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>requires that the Secretary eliminate the need for the repeated submission of documentation that is common to multiple petitions for classification under this paragraph through a regional center.</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause id="id875beb3004e94489a0cb93d7c627aa07"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Deference to prior rulings</header><text>Absent material change, fraud, or legal deficiency, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall give deference to, and not revisit, favorable determinations made pertaining to a commercial enterprise during the adjudication of—</text>
 <item id="ide731a84a6d964f3a9af4a880f905d21d"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>petitions filed by immigrants investing in the commercial enterprise under this subparagraph; and</text> </item><item id="id453ef6dedc174d34bdc1517d3a56701d"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>petitions filed by such immigrants under section 216A for the removal of conditional basis.</text>
								</item></subclause></clause><clause id="ide3d2250ca16b47ceaaf4e2fd7a88fd9c"><enum>(vi)</enum><header>Processing times</header>
 <subclause id="id6FDA3FF2EB9D4102A0AA1C570275D0AA"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall make determinations on a proposal filed under clause (i) or an application filed under clause (v) not later than 180 days after the date on which the proposal or application is filed.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id989DC8E1318849308BEB38909611CE3A"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Additional information</header><text>If the Secretary determines that an initial filing under this section does not meet the standards for approval, the Secretary shall—</text>
 <item id="id7566285DC51349E3A90A8BC16F7FD3EC"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>not later than 30 days after the date of such filing, notify the applicant of the reasons such proposal or application was not approved and the additional information or documentation that is required for approval;</text>
 </item><item id="idA0D1E4B8C4CE4A7C84265DCAB6C70A5E"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>permit the applicant to promptly resubmit a modified filing; and</text> </item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8F7EA5336ACB4E678FA1FE66A6A0B85D"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>adjudicate the modified proposal or application not later than 30 days after it is received.</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></section><section id="id6b02c4f79abb448ea42ad7661e58a9ac"><enum>6.</enum><header>Security reforms</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 203(b)(5) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(b)(5)</external-xref>), as amended by section 5, is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idD246DB4E2AE04BA7BD5EB7B58AA38433" style="OLC">
				<subparagraph id="id1BD0F57E7ADA4AD7BF5DE5D3F8EA8B28"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Appellate rights</header>
 <clause id="id5b0dab86d16649888bbfa25c3d373885"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any person subject to the suspension or termination of rights under this paragraph, if such decision was under the discretion of the Secretary of Homeland Security, may appeal such decision and be entitled to a hearing before an administrative law judge.</text>
 </clause><clause id="id12f36c98102841aca67f0cf14039a08c"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Appellant’s rights</header><text>An appellant under this subparagraph has the right—</text> <subclause id="id3AB1AEA7367E4E58BDEDF1007FB23D41"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to access the facts and documentation underlying the allegations that are the basis of the suspension or termination referred to in clause (i); and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idB7DA4C11905E4A178A6ED456DE84385F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>to cross-examine witnesses during proceedings.</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="ide7a43519e2b64b3083fa6d724fb865ec"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Burden of proof</header><text>In a hearing under this subparagraph, the Secretary has the burden to prove, by a preponderance of the evidence, that the suspension or termination was valid under applicable law.</text>
 </clause><clause id="idb8b49b25985b4ee6b391135aa07385b3"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Finality</header><text>A determination of the administrative law judge in an appeal under this subparagraph shall be final and may not be subject to judicial review.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section><section id="id1762A18CB38E4E8E94C51BF6920613FE"><enum>7.</enum><header>Regional centers</header>
 <subsection id="id2D53BABDEAEF4ACC8B64039EDB9DBA41"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 203(b)(5) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(b)(5)</external-xref>), as amended by sections 5 and 6, is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8D6E4159E43546CFB0794DB43DF179ED" style="OLC">
					<subparagraph id="id63fb7d262a544b2db08e0fb85731ddbf"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Bona fides of
		  persons associated with regional centers or regional center associated commercial
		  enterprises</header>
						<clause id="idC4E8CB0496BD47848DA78C20F1068F98"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>No person shall be permitted by any regional center or regional center associated commercial enterprise to be directly or indirectly involved with the regional center or commercial enterprise as its principal, representative, administrator, owner, officer, board member, manager, executive, general partner, fiduciary, marketer, promoter, or other similar position of substantive authority for the operations, management, or promotion of the regional center or commercial enterprise if—</text>
 <subclause id="id6e4ae69bad4c4087b7f88732567a0655"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the person has been found liable within the previous 5 years for any criminal or civil violation of any law relating to fraud or deceit, or at any time if such violation involved a civil liability in excess of $1,000,000, a criminal conviction with a term of imprisonment of more than 1 year or a criminal or civil violation of any law or agency regulation in connection with the offer, purchase, or sale of a security;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id457848b761bd4f22a090184325b0f381"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the person is subject to a final order of a State securities commission (or an agency or officer of a State who performs similar functions), a State authority that supervises or examines banks, savings associations, or credit unions, a State insurance commission (or an agency of or officer of a State who performs similar functions), an appropriate Federal banking agency, the Commodity Futures Trading Commission, or the National Credit Union Administration, which is based on a violation of any law or regulation that—</text>
 <item id="id22c7563b689f40788704dee116eb0416"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>prohibits fraudulent, manipulative, or deceptive conduct; or</text> </item><item id="id2957ca0e7a284a3a909859e0ce366d32"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>bars the person from—</text>
 <subitem id="id62860c1683954f3eae572ce3d6339710"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>association with an entity regulated by such commission, authority, agency, or officer;</text> </subitem><subitem id="ida979e713527c4de2b7665852321382a3"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>engaging in the business of securities, insurance, or banking; or</text>
 </subitem><subitem id="id71d17bd51a424e20b119ed1d98be22f8"><enum>(CC)</enum><text>engaging in savings association or credit union activities;</text> </subitem></item></subclause><subclause id="idd7b6beeb67064b35b6463c01fb90678d"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the person has been convicted of—</text>
 <item id="id6479da78cf7f41fb8830f67ee72040f2"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>any activity relating to espionage, sabotage, or theft of intellectual property;</text>
 </item><item id="ide2572cfac19b4669a28956550928ffbd"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>any activity related to money laundering (as described in section 1956 or 1957 of title 18, United States Code);</text>
 </item><item id="id74eed1745adf4a7590e603d97521939b"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>any terrorist activity (as defined in clauses (iii) and (iv) of section 212(a)(3)(B)); or</text>
 </item><item id="iddcbd5e91a53e4b9297cc977cb5b5d600"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>any activity related to human trafficking or a human rights offense; or</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause id="id5C875C46295C4D28857D28C0F122CAA5"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the person—</text> <item id="id2F4F3FE5203841519E7E2790F0E0CDEF"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>is, or during the preceding 5 years has been, included on the Department of Justice’s List of Currently Disciplined Practitioners; or</text>
 </item><item id="id2BEE2837F4F447859D44D155116EF605"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>during the preceding 5 years, has received a reprimand or otherwise been publicly disciplined by a bar association of which the person is or was a member.</text>
								</item></subclause></clause><clause id="id01ac23ecf7fd4489bdcf268d5b111d70"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Status of regional center principals</header>
 <subclause id="idDD6164F0544E4466A64471B759E48E7D"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Lawful status required</header><text>No person may be directly or indirectly involved with a regional center as its principal, administrator, owner, officer, board member, manager, executive, general partner, fiduciary, or other similar position of significant authority for the operations or management of the regional center unless the person is a national of the United States or an individual who has been lawfully admitted for permanent residence.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idA28ABCD8D6A244788B62E2E238084E03"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Foreign governments</header><text>No foreign government entity may be directly or indirectly involved with the ownership or administration of a regional center.</text>
							</subclause></clause><clause id="idd5e56e449ead4a5ab61c23c86a93a4cc"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Information
 required</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall require such attestations and information, including the submission of fingerprints or other biometrics to the Federal Bureau of Investigation, and shall perform such criminal record checks and other background checks with respect to a regional center or regional center associated commercial enterprise, and persons involved in a regional center or regional center associated commercial enterprise, to determine whether such regional center or regional center associated commercial enterprise is in compliance with clauses (i) and (ii).</text>
 </clause><clause id="id1dbcf971ba654153bcec4dfdc0d308c7"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The Secretary shall terminate any regional center or regional center associated commercial enterprise from the regional center program if the Secretary determines that—</text>
 <subclause id="idf182b2a91ab849a5b8876a699afe0911"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the regional center or regional center associated commercial enterprise has violated clause (i);</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id3987b53e7be6447e821d9b9fa47f67f0"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the regional center has violated clause (ii); or</text> </subclause><subclause id="id14b20d9308454e7ab3b7800f991f78b1"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the regional center, a regional center associated commercial enterprise, or any person involved with the regional center or regional center associated commercial enterprise—</text>
 <item id="id09D06D7775794FBD91AD58877C50B8A0"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>fails to provide an attestation or information requested by the Secretary;</text>
 </item><item id="id93449D2ED44D4CA190567FBD244404AB"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>provides any false attestation or information under clause (iii);</text>
 </item><item id="id9b8f628578414994955ee5ab3181ae27"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>has engaged in fraud, misrepresentation, or criminal misuse; or</text> </item><item id="id04FAD5B6474E4D559BCD77075973A55F"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>poses a threat to public safety or national security.</text>
								</item></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4326029ad2014261a5e70891383a0cf8"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Compliance with securities laws</header>
 <clause id="id6133a7bed11544fb8e1ee6ea8ff6afbf"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Jurisdiction</header><text>In view of the objective of promoting investment in the United States, in an action filed by the Securities and Exchange Commission, the purchase or sale of securities offered or sold by any regional center or any party associated with a regional center shall be deemed to have occurred within the territory of the United States for purposes of the securities laws, and subject matter jurisdiction shall also lie within the United States.</text>
						</clause><clause id="idccfd2d13757a46cd89dcc87e8cbc1f66"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Regional center certifications required</header>
 <subclause id="id56017213327241b0b88f3ac1088ed4b4"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Initial certification</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security may not approve an application for regional center designation or regional center amendment unless the regional center certifies that the regional center is in compliance with and has policies and procedures reasonably designed to ensure that all parties associated with the regional center remain in compliance with the securities laws of the United States and of any State in which the regional center operates in connection with the offer, purchase, or sale of securities or the provision of investment advice by the regional center or parties associated with the regional center.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="iddcd8c69a941f4cf19335c4b6b2adfe62"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Reissue</header><text>A regional center shall annually reissue a certification described in subclause (I). Annual certifications under this subclause shall certify compliance with clause (iii) by stating that—</text>
 <item id="idB96F5F4A05CF4F9EA28212BD91037D83"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the certifier is in a position to have knowledge of the offers, purchases, and sales of securities or the provision of investment advice by parties associated with the regional center; and</text>
 </item><item id="id4F60D10E5DC74216BEA242C770A439BC"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>to the best of the certifier’s knowledge, after reasonable investigation—</text>
 <subitem id="id3B57BB12CAEB4FAB92968FAD132673D8"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>all such offers, purchases, and sales of securities or the provision of investment advice complied with securities laws of the United States; and</text>
 </subitem><subitem id="idC0096D998E2541DD8B6553F1A5EC2BD6"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>records, data, and information related to such offers, purchases, and sales have been maintained.</text>
 </subitem></item></subclause><subclause id="id0C920A2656B04AA6AD34EA380F175927"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Effect of noncompliance</header><text>If a regional center, through its due diligence, discovered during the previous fiscal year that the regional center or any party associated with the regional center was not in compliance with the securities laws of the United States, the certifier shall—</text>
 <item id="idCAB2D051B5564EC6AF1CDB1008D04140"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>describe the activities that led to noncompliance;</text>
 </item><item id="id899E7D241A0E411F837135AD6C47DE69"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>describe the actions taken to remedy the noncompliance; and</text> </item><item id="id98E83F05C4AF455ABDB28528E5CB7F8E"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>certify that the regional center and all parties associated with the regional center are currently in compliance.</text>
 </item></subclause></clause><clause id="id0a7cbc8b98304ecba23714dcdb3e7b49"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Oversight required</header><text>Each regional center shall—</text> <subclause id="idED1A5A840DFB4AEBA0A2CCA1F8BF4040"><enum>(I)</enum><text>monitor and supervise all offers, purchases, and sales of, and advice relating to, securities made by parties associated with the regional center to ensure compliance with the securities laws of the United States;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id4CB0274B2EF84378B97C1A00BCED2B93"><enum>(II)</enum><text>maintain records, data, and information relating to all such offers, purchases, sales, and advice during the 5-year period beginning on the date of their creation; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idA555E4A0CF5A45888C0DFF3684F2EC46"><enum>(III)</enum><text>make such records, data, and information available to the Securities and Exchange Commission and to the Secretary upon the receipt of a subpoena from the Securities and Exchange Commission.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="ida713043ab102400382321631f88b0464"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Suspension or termination</header><text>The Secretary, in the Secretary’s unreviewable discretion, shall suspend or terminate the designation of any regional center that does not provide the certification described in clause (ii). The Secretary, in the Secretary’s unreviewable discretion, may suspend or terminate the designation of any regional center or impose other sanctions against the regional center if the regional center or any parties associated with the regional center—</text>
 <subclause id="idc23ad7e751bf4f9ab59b3bcb27a71ba4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>are permanently or temporarily enjoined by order, judgment, or decree of any court of competent jurisdiction in connection with the offer, purchase, or sale of a security or the provision of investment advice;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id14aaf7ad9b9b4cdf8ce44174ae125c11"><enum>(II)</enum><text>are subject to any final order of the Securities and Exchange Commission that—</text> <item id="id5d5c0768fd44452b9a92d3b9c012e556"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>bars such person from association with an entity regulated by the Securities and Exchange Commission; or</text>
 </item><item id="id986c4b3e7be24c949b8944d5c083e48b"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>constitutes a final order based on violations in connection with the offer, purchase, or sale of, or advice relating to, a security; or</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause id="idc1b9b80e1a5e4e98a78fcfdcdc5397f3"><enum>(III)</enum><text>knowingly submitted or caused to be submitted a certification described in clause (ii) that contained an untrue statement of a material fact or omitted to state a material fact necessary in order to make the statements made, in light of the circumstances under which they were made, not misleading.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="idd550c315844f4ca79bda735e67dd50ee"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Savings provision</header><text>Nothing in this subparagraph may be construed to impair or limit the authority of the Securities and Exchange Commission under the Federal securities laws.</text>
 </clause><clause id="idd08ced034fbf474ba981d2293380d912"><enum>(vi)</enum><header>Defined term</header><text>In this subparagraph, the term <term>parties associated with a regional center</term> means—</text> <subclause id="id02214FFD822947F5BFCCBF5A47E6415F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the regional center;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idFA0A5B734FA14DDF924CED046BC0557F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any commercial enterprise associated with the regional center;</text> </subclause><subclause id="id36F783BC921848E5914FC823D1DABFBA"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the regional center’s and associated commercial enterprise’s owners, officers, directors, managers, partners, broker-dealers, employees, and attorneys; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idF8374A65D259418694D520FD8EA0BB2F"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>any person in active concert or participation with the regional center or directly or indirectly controlling, controlled by, or under common control with the regional center.</text>
							</subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="id75d9377ff50f46cbb487a1008fa5790a"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Study and report</header>
 <paragraph id="idf3165a745547420ba0867fa47abd4509"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security, in coordination with the Secretary of Commerce and after consultation with relevant Federal agencies, shall submit a report to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate</committee-name> and the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives</committee-name> that describes—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id699a9b2f0bad43339f533706c65c2619"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the percentage of completed and pending capital investment projects, within the scope of business plans both approved and awaiting approval—</text>
 <clause id="id5b86faee161c4236b21432b0fd4f15ad"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in targeted rural employment areas;</text> </clause><clause id="id42ab88ed4d74471885578295ddf20336"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in targeted high unemployment areas;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id1cdda49e62294a8c8e67c99778f24a22"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in high poverty areas;</text> </clause><clause id="id1f5d64ff2da74ae096058ca90e70519c"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>for infrastructure projects; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id048451810d7d4e5b9b551218c4adcde6"><enum>(v)</enum><text>not included in the areas described in clauses (i) through (iii);</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9a519dd0317a484f8d6b4ef08c71f8d8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>whether other Federal financial assistance programs, such as economic development programs administered by the Department of Agriculture, the Department of Housing and Urban Development, or the Community Development Financial Institutions Fund, are also used or intended to support projects described in subparagraph (A); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id881f375078e0443fa4b1f9dae96d4c52"><enum>(C)</enum><text>whether market demands to approve projects described in subparagraph (A) exceed the number of visas allowed under section 203(b)(5)(F) of the Immigration and Nationality Act, as added by subsection (a).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idd2f48254155c40c8b666457e951d7e45"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Public input</header><text>Not later than 60 days before the submission of the report under paragraph (1), the public shall receive notice and an opportunity to comment on such draft study.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id441e34eac9c042499539391506c3fab2"><enum>8.</enum><header>Age determination for children of alien investors</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 203(h) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(h)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id598659E4B2804A158395AA617B0283FA" style="OLC">
				<paragraph id="id2a733b2692214a25af4eb179db74ec2a"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Age determination for children of alien investors</header>
 <subparagraph id="id38B0E2B40D184448BD27773A59C44C1C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B), an alien admitted under subsection (d) as a lawful permanent resident on a conditional basis as the child of an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence under subsection (b)(5), whose lawful permanent resident status on a conditional basis is terminated under section 216A, shall continue to be considered a child of the principal alien for the purpose of a subsequent immigrant petition by such alien under subsection (b)(5) if—</text>
 <clause id="id2715B8F2EF7046C1861F966859CBD2A1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the alien remains unmarried; and</text> </clause><clause id="id09D268A73B6945688383854C89714A89"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the subsequent petition is filed by the principal alien not later than 1 year after the termination of conditional lawful permanent resident status.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE4C4F56551754F23A500340A8C9CD0D0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>An alien shall not be considered a child under this paragraph with respect to more than 1 petition filed after the alien reaches 21 years of age.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


