<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1590 IS: Pregnancy Discrimination Amendment Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-06-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 1590</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150617">June 17, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S288">Ms. Murkowski</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S289">Mr. Alexander</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S357">Mrs. Fischer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S339">Mr. Kirk</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S153">Mr. Grassley</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the Civil Rights Act of 1964 to provide protections against pregnancy discrimination in
			 the workplace, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Pregnancy Discrimination Amendment Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </section><section id="idDFE368B56E7E4602A811B64F73B47FE2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Protections against pregnancy discrimination in the workplace</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 701(k) of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000e">42 U.S.C. 2000e(k)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="id254DE38094384423AABC4A27CE22A36F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the first sentence, by striking <quote>as other persons not so affected but similar in their ability</quote> and inserting <quote>as any other applicants for employment with, or employees employed by, the same employer, in work that is performed under similar working conditions, who are not so affected but similar in their temporary ability</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idAA33D817259D4662A52EADCC67EDA80A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after the first sentence the following: <quote>This subsection shall not permit any labor organization, or agent of such labor organization, representing employees of an employer having employees subject to any provision of this title, directly or through any collective bargaining agreement (agreed to by the labor organization, or agent of such labor organization, and such employer), to cause or attempt to cause such employer to commit an unlawful employment practice against an employee in violation of this subsection.</quote>.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body>
</bill>


