<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1057 IS: Geothermal Energy Opportunities Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1057</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150422">April 22, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To promote geothermal energy, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause">
 <section id="id2CA01DF7925C4C6A9FD42BB32C9F61F3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Geothermal Energy Opportunities Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>GEO Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="id1CBC953E53AE4F84BE07F607021699A5" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>National goals for production and site identification</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that, not later than 10 years after the date of enactment of this Act—</text>
 <paragraph id="idddd225297e9b4299ba019a7cd9d68a8b"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Secretary of the Interior should seek to have approved more than 15,000 megawatts of new geothermal energy capacity on public land across a geographically diverse set of States using the full range of available technologies; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id4c8ab3e104e84fc5bce7f9dd54adee64"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Director of the Geological Survey and the Secretary of Energy should identify sites capable of producing a total of 50,000 megawatts of geothermal power, using the full range of available technologies.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="id2a2280a991594e86a8b701941c3e00f4"><enum>3.</enum><header>Priority areas for development on Federal land</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Director of the Bureau of Land Management, in consultation with other appropriate Federal officials, shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="id710248744B4D4BB9A2F8BCB6DBD5154E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify high priority areas for new geothermal development; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id15D826D9960D4C49B15B85753334732D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">take any actions the Director determines necessary to facilitate that development, consistent with applicable laws.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="id655e46db14064961a885065dd4cbb3c1"><enum>4.</enum><header>Facilitation of coproduction of geothermal energy on oil and gas leases</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 4(b) of the Geothermal Steam Act of 1970 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1003">30 U.S.C. 1003(b)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4D625B6EBF1A45639123C82080402FAC" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="idd1f6e351942e4ef59d59662e3aa09a47"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Land subject to oil and gas lease</header><text>Land under an oil and gas lease issued pursuant to the Mineral Leasing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/181">30 U.S.C. 181 et seq.</external-xref>) or the Mineral Leasing Act for Acquired Lands (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/351">30 U.S.C. 351 et seq.</external-xref>) that is subject to an approved application for permit to drill and from which oil and gas production is occurring may be available for noncompetitive leasing under this section to the holder of the oil and gas lease—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id2d53fd7e5fe541deb7e549d4fe048223"><enum>(A)</enum><text>on a determination that—</text> <clause id="idd0c25da282024e1cb68614491b97361f"><enum>(i)</enum><text>geothermal energy will be produced from a well producing or capable of producing oil and gas; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id01fa8c5d82534d6782e4e7334cf592c2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>national energy security will be improved by the issuance of such a lease; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0382acb4d0b84bc8948d8c06821a4ac3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to provide for the coproduction of geothermal energy with oil and gas.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section><section id="idfdd3c0d7bbae464e8aace118402e3d32"><enum>5.</enum><header>Cost-shared exploration</header>
 <subsection id="idc961d3a6f497467d8b2a0d393d2d621c"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To promote the goals described in section 2, the Secretary of Energy may conduct a federally funded program of cost-shared drilling with industry partners—</text>
 <paragraph id="idF3FCE93FB35B4CB691ADC48DBCF01C3D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to explore and document new geothermal resources in the United States; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id832C4F783DC247A8AB4B58DFF246AB23"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to develop improved tools and methods for geothermal resource identification and extraction, with the goal of achieving material reductions in the cost of exploration with a corresponding increase in the likelihood of drilling success.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idd813c633c0a94f68b977230a356295f1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grants</header>
 <paragraph id="idcf56859d8edc46b985fd98477dc39608"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To carry out the program described in subsection (a), the Secretary of Energy may award cost-share grants on a competitive and merit basis to eligible applicants to support exploration drilling and related activities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idc4cd5849f37643bbb3d83d40829bb5c3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Project criteria</header><text>In selecting applicants to receive grants under paragraph (1), the Secretary of Energy shall—</text> <subparagraph id="id800C86263B93462AB1E3F5B402CA2D75"><enum>(A)</enum><text>give preference to applicants proposing projects located in a variety of geologic and geographic settings with previously unexplored, underexplored, or unproven geothermal resources; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id92F250CD2A2E47F5B43FDCAC00D4D5C9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>consider—</text> <clause id="ide9b79abf945f4c72b33ab3dc58c0f3c4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the potential that the unproven geothermal resources would be explored and developed under the proposed project;</text>
 </clause><clause id="ide8b645dcbf5241999e7683933ff72639"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the expertise and experience of an applicant in developing geothermal resources; and</text> </clause><clause id="id2cd3cbcea29444a9b2f6b4778c479199"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the contribution the proposed project would make toward meeting the goals described in section 2.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id80ed1a2371b94e2983c52d6add0dc3be"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Data sharing</header>
 <paragraph id="idFCBC8AEA279F44C888B5CEF63E17A6E5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Data from all exploratory wells that are carried out under the program described in subsection (a) shall be provided to the Secretary of Energy and the Secretary of the Interior for—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id1462E8495CB742F39EED4255ED09F4EB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>use in mapping national geothermal resources; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id13620EFB79214A53A9F0B5FB0E49545E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>other purposes, including—</text>
 <clause id="id051ea6bc933846aab6c10b5ae2a59432"><enum>(i)</enum><text>subsurface geologic data;</text> </clause><clause id="id884bc1c355d4442a9498b4d38517859a"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>metadata;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idc0c40b8689874d4684c77b3e026d21bc"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>borehole temperature data; and</text> </clause><clause id="idc9d0c7b0f3514ae382a219543671a511"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>inclusion in the National Geothermal Data System of the Department of Energy.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idBFAB66AF31934C6EB281939739133BDD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sharing of confidential data</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, confidential data from all exploratory wells that are carried out under the program described in subsection (a) shall be provided to the Secretary of Energy and the Secretary of the Interior for the purposes described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (1), to be available for a period of time to be determined by the Secretary of Energy and the Secretary of the Interior.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id8849d072dcd84eeaa9b5e94e1ff3333c"><enum>6.</enum><header>Use of geothermal lease revenues</header>
 <subsection id="id469751112ec24735a7f9c4c397c27627"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Amounts deposited</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, beginning in the first full fiscal year after the date of enactment of this Act, any amounts received by the United States as rentals, royalties, and other payments required under leases pursuant to the Geothermal Steam Act of 1970 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1001">30 U.S.C. 1001 et seq.</external-xref>) (excluding funds required to be paid to State and county governments) and from new geothermal leases issued after the date of enactment of this Act shall be deposited into a separate account in the Treasury.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="ide916716f94ec48f59dc081a0c3225890"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of deposits</header><text>Amounts deposited under subsection (a) shall be available to the Secretary of Energy for expenditure, without further appropriation or fiscal year limitation, to carry out section 5.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id83cfd0d1e1bc43e6942d56ef0c0b1fc0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Transfer of funds</header><text>To promote the goals described in section 2, the Secretary of Energy may authorize the expenditure or transfer of any funds that are necessary to other cooperating Federal agencies.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="id96e0ff6ae495413e8013b23d3ab91b3e"><enum>7.</enum><header>Noncompetitive leasing of adjoining areas for development of geothermal resources</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 4(b) of the Geothermal Steam Act of 1970 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1003">30 U.S.C. 1003(b)</external-xref>) (as amended by section 4) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id50FF23A1406C476190B91363097FE0CB" style="OLC">
				<paragraph id="H7BAC16BA7F4B4D219FCB6E771E580873"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Adjoining
				land</header>
 <subparagraph id="H18862B7F8AF14F4999EF8CB1B5B1630E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this paragraph:</text> <clause id="H6B920B1D348B492388DC0380B27BA4B0"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Fair market value per acre</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>fair market value per acre</term> means a dollar amount per acre that—</text>
 <subclause id="H09F9987EDB884C8288DF4FB20880CD4C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>except as provided in this clause, shall be equal to the market value per acre (taking into account the determination under subparagraph (B)(iii) regarding a valid discovery on the adjoining land), as determined by the Secretary under regulations issued under this paragraph;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HF9DEE285BDB442DDBE13620B66F8F853"><enum>(II)</enum><text>shall be determined by the Secretary with respect to a lease under this paragraph, by not later than the end of the 180-day period beginning on the date the Secretary receives an application for the lease; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H07EABD1F2E524D899B040772922DBBAE"><enum>(III)</enum><text>shall be not less than the greater of—</text>
 <item id="H0C7E11E631484F8CA0F2A37F8A544EE8"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>4 times the median amount paid per acre for all land leased under this Act during the preceding year; or</text>
 </item><item id="H191A10BDD74542F789DB6FAEB7E3A480"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>$50.</text> </item></subclause></clause><clause display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H146BE3D619564140AE5BA02B4549EA82"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Industry standards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>industry standards</term> means the standards by which a qualified geothermal professional assesses whether downhole or flowing temperature measurements with indications of permeability are sufficient to produce energy from geothermal resources, as determined through flow or injection testing or measurement of lost circulation while drilling.</text>
						</clause><clause id="HAB71CE283B6B4A1E8F05631AB86734F4"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Qualified
 Federal land</header><text>The term <term>qualified Federal land</term> means land that is otherwise available for leasing under this Act.</text>
						</clause><clause id="H576289DBE7854B5F9FC6E511DF9E6DF3"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Qualified
 geothermal professional</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>qualified geothermal professional</term> means an individual who is an engineer or geoscientist in good professional standing with at least 5 years of experience in geothermal exploration, development, or project assessment.</text>
						</clause><clause id="HB700C1956EA04F928621806666BFFE94"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Qualified
 lessee</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>qualified lessee</term> means a person that is eligible to hold a geothermal lease under this Act (including applicable regulations).</text>
						</clause><clause id="H670E7A7FEFC447859DCB87E73C09B1F6"><enum>(vi)</enum><header>Valid
 discovery</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>valid discovery</term> means a discovery of a geothermal resource by a new or existing slim hole or production well, that exhibits downhole or flowing temperature measurements with indications of permeability that are sufficient to meet industry standards.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H643B8A3E45924065A3F5CD506DB823B2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Authority</header><text>An area of qualified Federal land that adjoins other land for which a qualified lessee holds a legal right to develop geothermal resources may be available for a noncompetitive lease under this section to the qualified lessee at the fair market value per acre, if—</text>
 <clause id="H80DB3170218D4C38812AA56795DFE328"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the area of qualified Federal land—</text>
 <subclause id="HC37A9EB92F7A47C2ADDC57EC65DCB6CA"><enum>(I)</enum><text>consists of not less than 1 acre and not more than 640 acres; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H204A0B46973D49D5962DB0BF3A2D6BEC"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is not already leased under this Act or nominated to be leased under subsection (a);</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H103A154DEDFC4FD3AE0BBAF3AA82DD64"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the qualified lessee has not previously received a noncompetitive lease under this paragraph in connection with the valid discovery for which data has been submitted under clause (iii)(I); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HDF9A5FA2A8E248C69FB900279CCE13FC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>sufficient geological and other technical data prepared by a qualified geothermal professional has been submitted by the qualified lessee to the applicable Federal land management agency that would lead individuals who are experienced in the subject matter to believe that—</text>
 <subclause id="H51BA6137A80646E1ABA50AA28BC8C16C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>there is a valid discovery of geothermal resources on the land for which the qualified lessee holds the legal right to develop geothermal resources; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H6DA607E0D15448E78DD7F0D8E007FDD2"><enum>(II)</enum><text>that thermal feature extends into the adjoining areas.</text>
							</subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H889C420B8E104840B66FDB9EBADC0769"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Determination of
				fair market value</header>
						<clause id="H81DA94F8648C426C882E93C34E5BC2A2"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text> <subclause id="H85A265EF62F943E59439EC5B069A3503"><enum>(I)</enum><text>publish a notice of any request to lease land under this paragraph;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H1A89E674F2E24914BE958D34C2AA2431"><enum>(II)</enum><text>determine fair market value for purposes of this paragraph in accordance with procedures for making those determinations that are established by regulations issued by the Secretary;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="IDd50010c6ead04ec5b7e8cc111a238155"><enum>(III)</enum><text>provide to a qualified lessee and publish, with an opportunity for public comment for a period of 30 days, any proposed determination under this subparagraph of the fair market value of an area that the qualified lessee seeks to lease under this paragraph; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="IDfffa0d7922094e818a09425b0a63b6b6"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>provide to the qualified lessee and any adversely affected party the opportunity to appeal the final determination of fair market value in an administrative proceeding before the applicable Federal land management agency, in accordance with applicable law (including regulations).</text>
							</subclause></clause><clause id="HAD456FA498C4473FBBA0AA13FC1AE5D9"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Limitation on
 nomination</header><text>After publication of a notice of request to lease land under this paragraph, the Secretary may not accept under subsection (a) any nomination of the land for leasing unless the request has been denied or withdrawn.</text>
						</clause><clause id="id8B11DECF91FE4E149C5157D32AEF2DD4"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Annual
 rental</header><text>For purposes of section 5(a)(3), a lease awarded under this paragraph shall be considered a lease awarded in a competitive lease sale.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H905F519DA7CF489BB1BB523A094D2D62"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>Not later than 270 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Geothermal Energy Opportunities Act</short-title>, the Secretary shall issue regulations to carry out this paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="idf65f8d88702a468e924fde433071db24"><enum>8.</enum><header>Large-scale geothermal energy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title VI of the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007 is amended by inserting after section 616 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/17195">42 U.S.C. 17195</external-xref>) the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id59A7D94716974E2A883F410BC9035A02" style="OLC">
				<section id="idBC7F8704D5804B0FB709F06835F8A15F"><enum>616A.</enum><header>Large-Scale
				Geothermal Energy</header>
 <subsection id="ID118774ae479b4dff92ac15be6d8ec52f"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text> <paragraph id="ID646964e1a4014b6ca655d46153095e6e"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Geothermal Technologies Program of the Office of Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy of the Department has included a focus on direct use of geothermal energy in the low-temperature geothermal energy subprogram (including in the development of a research and development plan for the program);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="IDb420712643884c33b7aec4816dd4d70f"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Building Technologies Program of the Office of Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy of the Department—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id000C6C99AE634531895C8B11A2335343"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is focused on the energy demand and energy efficiency of buildings; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD4E6DDDC858C4E829782818B6BC62B3C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes geothermal heat pumps as a component technology in the residential and commercial deployment activities of the program; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="IDfe73654bb5984f5ea97154e62bca557b"><enum>(3)</enum><text>geothermal heat pumps and direct use of geothermal energy, especially in large-scale applications, can make a significant contribution to the use of renewable energy but are underrepresented in research, development, demonstration, and commercialization.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="IDfb7b86ee482940d5a51ca194514f729a"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The purposes of this section are—</text> <paragraph id="ID8ed9ee80266643c4ae6aa4545b0fd4b8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to improve the components, processes, and systems used for geothermal heat pumps and the direct use of geothermal energy; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ID9f199c2b05ca4a3cb97b8928a7f019fb"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to increase the energy efficiency, lower the cost, increase the use, and improve and demonstrate the applicability of geothermal heat pumps to, and the direct use of geothermal energy in, large buildings, commercial districts, residential communities, and large municipal, agricultural, or industrial projects.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID1b7cd599199a47a9b1d0c3d1a9c73a93"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> <paragraph id="ID1a49b5fc68d84937ade21fa7adc0d332"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Direct use of geothermal energy</header><text>The term <term>direct use of geothermal energy</term> means systems that use water that is at a temperature between approximately 38 degrees Celsius and 149 degrees Celsius directly or through a heat exchanger to provide—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idE73BF4D27C2941628CEBCA83FB24DFA6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>heating to buildings; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id009E919D6873421ABC2C65C15C05BA2E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>heat required for industrial processes, agriculture, aquaculture, and other facilities.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID0f60a0a6891849d2b522b4fc7429591c"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Geothermal heat
 pump</header><text>The term <term>geothermal heat pump</term> means a system that provides heating and cooling by exchanging heat from shallow ground or surface water using—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id347313F726A24C41A9A9C3DE6811F9C9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a closed loop system, which transfers heat by way of buried or immersed pipes that contain a mix of water and working fluid; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idAC63E817FE4E4979819C056B6B6B1974"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an open loop system, which circulates ground or surface water directly into the building and returns the water to the same aquifer or surface water source.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID8df48608c7d64f75a5546033920dafd7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Large-scale
 application</header><text>The term <term>large-scale application</term> means an application for space or process heating or cooling for large entities with a name-plate capacity, expected resource, or rating of 10 or more megawatts, such as a large building, commercial district, residential community, or a large municipal, agricultural, or industrial project.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID8f68d5a568af421dbd557435b0bac84e"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Energy, acting through the Assistant Secretary for Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID729fa60d63e24551876380c1007e946d"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Program</header>
						<paragraph id="IDb195088c1649469e954efc076a677c29"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a program of research, development, and demonstration for geothermal heat pumps and the direct use of geothermal energy.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ID78506d1805d54af3818f3f6be3dccc49"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Areas</header><text>The program may include research, development, demonstration, and commercial application of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="ID6c3bfc1eb9d740d1814657e17ab5d436"><enum>(A)</enum><text>geothermal ground loop efficiency improvements through more efficient heat transfer fluids;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="IDc9b9931fe54945ed912bbf7d5b90326a"><enum>(B)</enum><text>geothermal ground loop efficiency improvements through more efficient thermal grouts for wells and trenches;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID2626b4982c7842d9a852b372c9f1250c"><enum>(C)</enum><text>geothermal ground loop installation cost reduction through—</text>
 <clause id="idC18B404366EB4176B7204ABBA4CD82E1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>improved drilling methods;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id1A7EEBC8D29F466E87AA430AEF916787"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>improvements in drilling equipment;</text>
 </clause><clause id="ID5175421b36a64235b6db16612461cf1a"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>improvements in design methodology and energy analysis procedures; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="ID695931466ba44c70a2735804b2ae28bd"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>improved methods for determination of ground thermal properties and ground temperatures;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID1bc0edd05164498b8ab0931f8c02e96e"><enum>(D)</enum><text>installing geothermal ground loops near the foundation walls of new construction to take advantage of existing structures;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idDFB015AE5D664ED6AA23549F97EFA5B6"><enum>(E)</enum><text>using gray or black wastewater as a method of heat exchange;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id3BB9CE0B8824443193473C6790FDE2DD"><enum>(F)</enum><text>improving geothermal heat pump system economics through integration of geothermal systems with other building systems, including providing hot and cold water and rejecting or circulating industrial process heat through refrigeration heat rejection and waste heat recovery;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID81161ecf72984d34a01ed9ae296088a5"><enum>(G)</enum><text>advanced geothermal systems using variable pumping rates to increase efficiency;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID8ad0fe7560d44b6b863bce7844f1860d"><enum>(H)</enum><text>geothermal heat pump efficiency improvements;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID224be3f6d4e94d9fbe57d6a704fac536"><enum>(I)</enum><text>use of hot water found in mines and mine shafts and other surface waters as the heat exchange medium;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID65580ccf09a04752adf50ba528386c6f"><enum>(J)</enum><text>heating of districts, neighborhoods, communities, large commercial or public buildings (including office, retail, educational, government, and institutional buildings and multifamily residential buildings and campuses), and industrial and manufacturing facilities;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID0173aea28789461eae5fc3200d152b27"><enum>(K)</enum><text>geothermal system integration with solar thermal water heating or cool roofs and solar-regenerated desiccants to balance loads and use building hot water to store geothermal energy;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID3437e219d80c4d2f841ec327fea534b7"><enum>(L)</enum><text>use of hot water coproduced from oil and gas recovery;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="IDd9a688e5742d4d2593c08cb7b3c2d9ca"><enum>(M)</enum><text>use of water sources at a temperature of less than 150 degrees Celsius for direct use;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID8877b3a6ed20427aaa793fb93e918625"><enum>(N)</enum><text>system integration of direct use with geothermal electricity production; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE16E072FC0AD495DB3A320E218FCBC25"><enum>(O)</enum><text>coproduction of heat and power, including on-site use.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="IDdf307d8139994f01bcae8ca86fd4f5f5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Environmental
 impacts</header><text>In carrying out the program, the Secretary shall identify and mitigate potential environmental impacts in accordance with section 614(c).</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="IDd580e55f6ecf450ca8e697ab947d4ca9"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Grants</header>
						<paragraph id="ID8d5d6857dff8440196e0d544d2d853cd"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>The Secretary shall make grants available to State and local governments, institutions of higher education, nonprofit entities, utilities, and for-profit companies (including manufacturers of heat-pump and direct-use components and systems) to promote the development of geothermal heat pumps and the direct use of geothermal energy.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ID825ff692d7cc4d24834e84f4d8fc61ce"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In making grants under this subsection, the Secretary shall give priority to proposals that apply to large buildings (including office, retail, educational, government, institutional, and multifamily residential buildings and campuses and industrial and manufacturing facilities), commercial districts, and residential communities.</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="ID52af315d390043799e9971cc42945760"><enum>(3)</enum><header>National
 solicitation</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary shall conduct a national solicitation for applications for grants under this section.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID6f66b2ce59d44395b320a49fb1a3389a"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reports</header>
						<paragraph id="ID6ac46c5450cb43fab2349d8e32a1c399"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this section and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives a report on progress made and results obtained under this section to develop geothermal heat pumps and direct use of geothermal energy.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ID88d4d6f4b42249a0adaea4a7381f18ad"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Areas</header><text>Each of the reports required under this subsection shall include—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idA4E0976C00EE4BEC8852E41FE6D2DAE5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an analysis of progress made in each of the areas described in subsection (d)(2); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idAC4B4F084C5F4CA99FA56B3E7915453A"><enum>(B)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id5F78585BC2724595AFB2B6F231485DEB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a description of any relevant recommendations made during a review of the program; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idBA4B9D34F1A9460492122D965699C0CE" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any plans to address the recommendations under clause (i).</text>
								</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="id97dc863764184824bceb597653a515a4"><enum>9.</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act and not less frequently than once every 5 years thereafter, the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Energy shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report describing the progress made towards achieving the goals described in section 2.</text>
 </section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idD92F9B6946734E30B738EC753431EACA"><enum>10.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act such sums as are necessary.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

