<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Placed-on-Calendar-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S919 PCS: To exclude from gross income certain clean coal power grants to non-corporate taxpayers.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<calendar>Calendar No. 52</calendar>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 919</legis-num>
		<associated-doc>[Report No. 114–29]</associated-doc>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date>April 14, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S118">Mr. Hatch</sponsor>, from the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name>, reported the following original bill; which was read twice and placed on the calendar</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To exclude from gross income certain clean coal power
			 grants to non-corporate taxpayers.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Exclusion from gross income of certain clean coal power grants to non-corporate taxpayers</header>
 <subsection id="idF1EAE84895974A66978C66E2CEC825D4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>General rule</header><text>In the case of an eligible taxpayer other than a corporation, gross income for purposes of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 shall not include any amount which—</text>
 <paragraph id="id25353312C9E5443AB4BFF4E9F065D68F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is received under section 402 of the Energy Policy Act of 2005, and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idAC19410EBDA940939E3C6A1579932045"><enum>(2)</enum><text>if received by a corporation, would be excluded from gross income under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/118">section 118</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idF3E7A7187B454C7894D74785C0136A95"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reduction in basis</header><text>The basis of any property subject to the allowance for depreciation or amortization under the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 which is acquired with any amount to which subsection (a) applies during the 12-month period beginning on the day such amount is received shall be reduced by an amount equal to such amount. The excess (if any) of such amount over the amount of the reduction under the preceding sentence shall be applied to the reduction (as of the last day of the period specified in the preceding sentence) of the basis of any other property held by the taxpayer. The particular properties to which the reductions required by this subsection are allocated shall be determined by the Secretary of the Treasury (or the Secretary's delegate) under regulations similar to the regulations under section 362(c)(2) of such Code.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id90A1079299E04BFB881A56A7ED2803E5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligible taxpayer</header><text>For purposes of this section, with respect to any amount received under section 402 of the Energy Policy Act of 2005, the term <term>eligible taxpayer</term> means a taxpayer that makes a payment to the Secretary of the Treasury (or the Secretary's delegate) equal to 1.18 percent of the amount so received. Such payment shall be made at such time and in such manner as such Secretary (or the Secretary's delegate) shall prescribe. In the case of a partnership, such Secretary (or the Secretary's delegate) shall prescribe regulations to determine the allocation of such payment amount among the partners.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idCF141C13869342E5BA1A52448EC04301"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This section shall apply to amounts received under section 402 of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 in taxable years beginning after December 31, 2011.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
	<endorsement><action-date>April 14, 2015</action-date><action-desc>Read twice and placed on the calendar</action-desc></endorsement></bill>


