<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Placed-on-Calendar-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S2146 PCS: Stop Sanctuary Policies and Protect Americans Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-10-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><calendar>Calendar No. 252</calendar><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2146</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20151006">October 6, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S299">Mr. Vitter</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S351">Mr. Toomey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S153">Mr. Grassley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S355">Mr. Cruz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S345">Mr. Johnson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S287">Mr. Cornyn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S379">Mr. Perdue</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S305">Mr. Isakson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S350">Mr. Rubio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S317">Mr. Barrasso</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S383">Mr. Sullivan</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S236">Mr. Inhofe</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read the first time</action-desc></action><action><action-date>October 7, 2015</action-date><action-desc>Read the second time and placed on the calendar</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To hold sanctuary jurisdictions accountable for defying Federal law, to increase penalties for
			 individuals who illegally reenter the United States after being removed,
			 and to provide liability protection for State and local law enforcement
			 who cooperate with Federal law enforcement and for other purposes. </official-title></form>
	<legis-body>
 <section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop Sanctuary Policies and Protect Americans Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </section><section id="ida638673cd8d64832881409ff74d26b5b"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sanctuary jurisdiction defined</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <term>sanctuary jurisdiction</term> means any State or political subdivision of a State, including any law enforcement entity of a State or of a political subdivision of a State, that—</text>
 <paragraph id="ide0f29b36cce342ffa404e2f4bf6fe267"><enum>(1)</enum><text>has in effect a statute, ordinance, policy, or practice that is in violation of subsection (a) or (b) of section 642 of the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1373">8 U.S.C. 1373</external-xref>); or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idC7E0D0995B1644038134676BA0E33CE5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>has in effect a statute, ordinance, policy, or practice that prohibits any government entity or official from complying with a detainer that has been lawfully issued or a request to notify about the release of an alien that has been made by the Department of Homeland Security in accordance with section 236 and 287 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (8 U.S.C. 1226 and 1357) and section 287.7 of title 8, Code of Federal Regulations.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="idbffea6a098e34b8eb1d13744626da19d"><enum>3.</enum><header>Limitation on grants to sanctuary jurisdictions</header>
			<subsection id="id3dce332e89a04c2496a4660f8bca54ec"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Ineligibility for grants</header>
				<paragraph id="idBB51D0681D924AEE9B95FD2B62FADA8A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Law enforcement grants</header>
 <subparagraph id="id53385D56575E4FD3893A5286DAA7EC31"><enum>(A)</enum><header>SCAAP grants</header><text>A sanctuary jurisdiction shall not be eligible to receive funds pursuant to the State Criminal Alien Assistance Program under section 241(i) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1231">8 U.S.C. 1231(i)</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide833f38b9fa44d7a9c12081de8e5fd56"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Cops grants</header><text>No law enforcement entity of a State or of a political subdivision of a State that has a departmental policy or practice that renders it a sanctuary jurisdiction, and such a policy or practice is not required by statute, ordinance, or other codified law, or by order of a chief executive officer of the jurisdiction, or the executive or legislative board of the jurisdiction, shall be eligible to receive funds directly or indirectly under the ‘Cops on the Beat’ program under part Q of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3796dd">42 U.S.C. 3796dd et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id27B548A30D9743659D5C640EBB1E9EDD"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text>The Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary of Homeland Security, shall terminate the funding described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) to a State or political subdivision of a State on the date that is 30 days after the date on which a notification described in subsection (d)(2) is made to the State or subdivision, unless the Secretary of Homeland Security, in consultation with the Attorney General, determines the State or subdivision is no longer a sanctuary jurisdiction.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id53B96DAEEAD54C449CE211B0DDB57AF5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Community development block grants</header>
 <subparagraph id="id0D598658862346458C887ECFE2D4263A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Title I of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5301">42 U.S.C. 5301 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <clause id="id3A9119CDC175417BA32FF104D9C582DB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in section 102 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5302">42 U.S.C. 5302</external-xref>), by adding at the end the following:</text>
							<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9778D9985D744D7EBB18F0931EECEC2E" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="id131939F89C2C4AE7B37ECC15298A91D9"><enum>(25)</enum><text>The term <term>sanctuary jurisdiction</term> means any State or unit of general local government that—</text> <subparagraph id="id2C0E47C5DF9F450C954FB3A31A0CA50A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has in effect a statute, ordinance, policy, or practice that is in violation of subsection (a) or (b) of section 642 of the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1373">8 U.S.C. 1373</external-xref>); or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2EFBD6A5DC5F4A4F94A8994A13C58AE1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has in effect a statute, ordinance, policy, or practice that prohibits any government entity or official from complying with a detainer that has been lawfully issued or a request to notify about the release of an alien that has been made by the Department of Homeland Security in accordance with section 236 and 287 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (8 U.S.C. 1226 and 1357) and section 287.7 of title 8, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </clause><clause id="id6E0C018AFEF3497D8D978C0432FC6ACA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in section 104 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5304">42 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>)—</text> <subclause id="idF70983622D3E47D58E626123DDF4205D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text>
 <item id="id026C7B003BEB4BEC9DC1A51192B9D4C1"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>in paragraph (5), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text> </item><item id="idC0D7B0DDD7DE4461B4E6571143C0E6D5"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (6) as paragraph (7); and</text>
 </item><item id="id282325A6E0CE41FBAE726F6DE6247A11"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (5) the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id431E8EE841DC4EE19758EDB622B94038" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="id699EF42F084D41E1A5872832D4CB4560"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the grantee is not a sanctuary jurisdiction and will not become a sanctuary jurisdiction during the period for which the grantee receives a grant under this title; and</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </item></subclause><subclause id="id5B5745042A57428C986830A022E217A7"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id80FD3B9D19C14EC5B258923C923650E8" style="OLC"> <subsection id="id2E8166A8EFEB4B148DBBC4A9659C906E"><enum>(n)</enum><header>Protection of individuals against criminal aliens</header> <paragraph id="id8EEBCC09CFF4407592AC1E353A2DB068"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>No funds authorized to be appropriated to carry out this title may be obligated or expended to any State or unit of general local government that is a sanctuary jurisdiction.</text>
										</paragraph><paragraph id="id107C6C87E8C74ADFAE8E6E43698E85CC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Returned amounts</header>
 <subparagraph id="id65DF2F6BA24247BF964FE6F8F3A1717D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>State</header><text>If a State is a sanctuary jurisdiction during the period for which the State receives amounts under this title, the Secretary—</text>
 <clause id="id40CF798CFF0C49FFA32739F6B6072990"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall direct the State to immediately return to the Secretary any such amounts that have not been obligated by the State as of the date on which the State became a sanctuary jurisdiction; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idA09F51636CF7494B812EFF7E22CF030A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>may use any returned amounts under clause (i) to make grants to other States that are not sanctuary jurisdictions in accordance with this title.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id782EAFE86B0548B5A69C7946111C5486"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Unit of general local government</header><text>If a unit of general local government is a sanctuary jurisdiction during the period for which the unit of general local government receives amounts under this title, any such amounts that have not been obligated by the unit of general local government as of the date on which the unit of general local government became a sanctuary jurisdiction—</text>
 <clause id="idBB6393DA91044A21A7C0106D4EE514DA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the case of a unit of general local government that is not in a nonentitlement area, shall be returned to the Secretary to make grants to States and other units of general local government that are not sanctuary jurisdictions in accordance with this title; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id2A524DE5BB254678A4E1C2B3A449F4CB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case of a unit of general local government that is in a nonentitlement area, shall be returned to the Governor of the State to make grants to other units of general local government that are not sanctuary jurisdictions in accordance with this title.</text>
												</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4D153B2085AE407ABDC52D0175BB99E3"><enum>(o)</enum><header>Enforcement against funding for sanctuary jurisdictions</header>
 <paragraph id="idCBEF170AB0B54A0FA927CE1B26116CE7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall verify, on a quarterly basis, the determination of the Secretary of Homeland Security and the Attorney General as to whether a State or unit of general local government is a sanctuary jurisdiction and therefore ineligible to receive a grant under this title for purposes of subsections (b)(6) and (n).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idE5540FB64B514ABFA624CECA8875ADB3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notification</header><text>If the Secretary verifies that a State or unit of general local government is determined to be a sanctuary jurisdiction under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall notify the State or unit of general local government that it is ineligible to receive a grant under this title.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id97140FCE1CA745299B139227C8BEE1A3"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by subparagraph (A) shall only apply with respect to community development block grants made under title I of the Housing and Community Development Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5301">42 U.S.C. 5301 et seq.</external-xref>) after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idC9D74D37132849C785A76B893A404A44"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Allocation</header><text>Any funds that are not allocated to a State or political subdivision of a State pursuant to subsection (a) and the amendments made by subsection (a) shall be allocated to States and political subdivisions of States that are not sanctuary jurisdictions.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id5e940232d1ad49149d04afae36177769"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Notification of Congress</header><text>Not later than 5 days after a determination is made pursuant to subsection (a) to terminate a grant or to refuse to award a grant, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on Appropriations and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate</committee-name> and the Committee on Appropriations and the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives</committee-name> a report that fully describes the circumstances and basis for the termination or refusal.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idb968897d11124ada9a3cba861c66d3d7"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Transparency and accountability</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and quarterly thereafter, the Secretary of Homeland Security and the Attorney General shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="id96AF135C4C5E4C9EA53BE91C6016FD24"><enum>(1)</enum><text>determine the States and political subdivisions of States that are sanctuary jurisdictions;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9D877CEB34A047CB98BC4B991E5CAAE3"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">notify each such State or subdivision that it is determined to be a sanctuary jurisdiction; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id1C7C5E17E78F4C31B936F59D6AFA2D1C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>publish on the website of the Department of Homeland Security and of the Department of Justice—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idb60e63d71e4f4aafaad26bd27dd52b13"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a list of each sanctuary jurisdiction;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide431e359953a447f83d8e0c8f5b8490a"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the total number of detainers and requests for notification of the release of any alien that has been issued or made to each State or political subdivision of a State; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id47992666bb5146ab9a006f6dd30f66af"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the number of such detainers and requests for notification that have been ignored or otherwise not honored, including the name of the jurisdiction in which each such detainer or request for notification was issued or made.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id39ef0c9a3bea469bbd6159d8b84ea310"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Construction</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to require law enforcement officials of a State or a political subdivision of a State to provide the Secretary of Homeland Security with information related to a victim or a witness to a criminal offense.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="idc882050f6e284a3d88ca78cc78bedb49"><enum>4.</enum><header>State and  local government and individual compliance with detainers</header>
 <subsection id="idfe77ea1ab8ad4e798737de83cf33e3c0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority to carry out detainers</header><text>A State, a political subdivision of a State, or an officer, employee, or agent of such State or political subdivision that complies with a detainer issued by the Department of Homeland Security under section 236 or 287 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (8 U.S.C. 1226 and 1357)—</text>
 <paragraph id="ide441e5d2d4ed46fd912ea16ced9c972e"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall be deemed to be acting as an agent of the Department of Homeland Security; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id663768083f8d4654b8db8ca561ea1d00"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall have the authority available to employees of the Department of Homeland Security with regard to actions taken to comply with the detainer.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1b984bab90e6409ba2ed8cc86f32bf5d"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Liability</header><text>In any legal proceeding brought against a State, a political subdivision of State, or an officer, employee, or agent of such State or political subdivision, which challenges the legality of the seizure or detention of an individual pursuant to a detainer issued by the Department of Homeland Security under section 236 or 287 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (8 U.S.C. 1226 and 1357)—</text>
 <paragraph id="idf74bec1436da4418991386db40538717"><enum>(1)</enum><text>no liability shall lie against the State or political subdivision for actions taken in compliance with the detainer;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id7f1d7a3471d14fcf8a8787b20f9a322c"><enum>(2)</enum><text>if the actions of the officer, employee, or agent of the State or political subdivision were taken in compliance with the detainer—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idcf2c5437dee54fc08ac4eac321ba9ebe"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the officer, employee, or agent shall be deemed to be an employee of the Federal Government and an investigative or law enforcement officer and to have been acting within the scope of his or her employment under section 1346(b) and <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/171">chapter 171</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id34ba70d760a64f7caf552a7123a7d47e"><enum>(B)</enum><text>section 1346(b) of title 28, United States Code, shall provide the exclusive remedy for the plaintiff; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1e1c5e362b3849be9a00e4c5c1792530"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the United States shall be substituted as defendant in the proceeding.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4ed173c817954b00b76c5635bf655b2b"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Construction</header><text>Nothing in this Act may be construed—</text>
 <paragraph id="id42301AAAADD640C4A2687E3D02913526"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to provide immunity to any person who knowingly violates the civil or constitutional rights of an individual; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id8B6AFF27025D40A6A70B4B9DF22C08D8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to limit the application of the doctrine of official immunity or of qualified immunity in a civil action brought against a law enforcement officer acting pursuant to a detainer issued by the Department of Homeland Security under section 236 or 287 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (8 U.S.C. 1226 and 1357).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idC70B1D751EF64F77AEF224F048486EB4"><enum>5.</enum><header>Increased penalties for reentry of removed alien</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 276 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1326">8 U.S.C. 1326</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="idF40D993A28E44DAFA6ACE00A119FF4C4"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating subsections (c) and (d) as subsections (d) and (e), respectively;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idA708790BDF824AA2BDEF6B8B6649D1F8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking subsections (a) and (b) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id73D8694C79BD4863AD15E8A967B6DD46" style="OLC"> <subsection id="id7FF23A60D88344EFA9840418D759E623"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to subsections (b) and (c), any alien who—</text>
 <paragraph id="idE9CE80F8CC46436D82A43932AE3A4596"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has been denied admission, excluded, deported, or removed or has departed the United States while an order of exclusion, deportation, or removal is outstanding; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idFBDB497920344C488EFF4EC6304CB3DE"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">thereafter enters, attempts to enter, or is at any time found in, the United States, unless—</text> <subparagraph id="idA81213031D054BE89B87A9FAACB814FC"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prior to the alien’s reembarkation at a place outside the United States or the alien’s application for admission from foreign contiguous territory, the Secretary of Homeland Security has expressly consented to such alien’s reapplying for admission; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9BDCCC288F054320B8FC40800F06C0B4"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to an alien previously denied admission and removed, such alien shall establish that the alien was not required to obtain such advance consent under this Act or any prior Act;</text>
							</subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">shall be fined under title 18, United States Code, or imprisoned not more than five years, or both.</continuation-text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0211DB930CB444E4BE22D74B6A62A846"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Criminal penalties for reentry of certain removed aliens</header>
 <paragraph id="idAB0DB76704134A84B4BA63E7B0D41B1F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding the penalty provided in subsection (a), and except as provided in subsection (c), an alien described in subsection (a)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id73146A190E5C4C3E816D6F746B586475"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">who was convicted before such removal or departure of three or more misdemeanors involving drugs, crimes against the person, or both, or a felony (other than an aggravated felony), shall be fined under title 18, United States Code, imprisoned not more than 10 years, or both;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1BA9BD18CFE2482698A62A280589FB7E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">who has been excluded from the United States pursuant to section 235(c) because the alien was excludable under section 212(a)(3)(B) or who has been removed from the United States pursuant to the provisions of title V, and who thereafter, without the permission of the Secretary of Homeland Security, enters the United States, or attempts to do so, shall be fined under title 18, United States Code, and imprisoned for a period of 10 years, which sentence shall not run concurrently with any other sentence;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id773DA8E7120C4F8393F269B9FF064227"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">who was removed from the United States pursuant to section 241(a)(4)(B) who thereafter, without the permission of the Secretary of Homeland Security, enters, attempts to enter, or is at any time found in, the United States (unless the Secretary of Homeland Security has expressly consented to such alien’s reentry) shall be fined under title 18, United States Code, imprisoned for not more than 10 years, or both; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0657D119694D4782B09788300C21D6B5"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">who has been denied admission, excluded, deported, or removed 3 or more times and thereafter enters, attempts to enter, crosses the border to, attempts to cross the border to, or is at any time found in the United States, shall be fined under title 18, United States Code, imprisoned not more than 10 years, or both.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idC199BC693C5949F7885825FF6619BA94"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Removal defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection and subsection (c), the term <quote>removal</quote> includes any agreement in which an alien stipulates to removal during (or not during) a criminal trial under either Federal or State law.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id481FED8FF96E47DB81925AC98746F9BB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Mandatory minimum criminal penalty for reentry of certain removed aliens</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding the penalties provided in subsections (a) and (b), an alien described in subsection (a)—</text>
 <paragraph id="idCA19A90D0508442ABDFA26F8CFF21BAF"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">who was convicted before such removal or departure of an aggravated felony; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id91DC77AC400D4DA0999867B30E32B603"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">who was convicted at least two times before such removal or departure of illegal reentry under this section;</text>
						</paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">shall be imprisoned not less than five years and not more than 20 years, and may, in addition, be
			 fined under title 18, United States Code.</continuation-text></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idBAAEDB0CC7C248D0ACA480D7943B29A5"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (d), as redesignated by paragraph (1)—</text> <subparagraph id="id682279465D444A71BE79529BBEEF6FB5"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>section 242(h)(2)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 241(a)(4)</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA94FF0E4864148E6B3F77DC7A74C019D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Attorney General</quote> and inserting <quote>Secretary of Homeland Security</quote>.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></section><section commented="no" id="id9FB2C024EBD345D48C23EC065FF9B09D"><enum>6.</enum><header>Severability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any provision of this Act or the application of such provision to any person or circumstance is held invalid for any reason, the remainder of this Act, and the application of such provision to other persons not similarly situated or to other circumstances, shall not be affected by such invalidation.</text></section></legis-body><endorsement><action-date>October 7, 2015</action-date><action-desc>Read the second time and placed on the calendar</action-desc></endorsement></bill>


