<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S528 IS: Empowering Parents and Students Through Information Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 528</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150212">February 12, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S309">Mr. Casey</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S229">Mrs. Murray</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 in order to improve the requirements
			 regarding alternate standards and assessments for students with the most
			 significant cognitive disabilities, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Empowering Parents and Students Through Information Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </section><section id="idc1c414b5f0f540bc8fb48dcfcec9aa40"><enum>2.</enum><header>Alternate standards and assessments for students with the most significant cognitive disabilities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1111 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6311">20 U.S.C. 6311</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="idaa90fe5ef7eb41fdb1ec32ee550a304a"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id2FE5FC6912A44B478112307600D67CB1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8b6a51ff8c374b3cb90ede6addc4567d" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="idb2265a5e647a4659850726b624034b03"><enum>(G)</enum><header>State requirements for alternate achievement standards</header><text>Notwithstanding subparagraph (B), in the case of any State that elects to use alternate academic achievement standards in any subject included in the State’s accountability system under paragraph (2) for students with the most significant cognitive disabilities, in accordance with section 612(a)(16) of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act and sections 200.1(d) and 200.6(a)(2) of title 34, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor regulation, the State shall—</text>
 <clause id="ida71571c984ac4be9bca1631a2f41a11b"><enum>(i)</enum><text>establish and monitor implementation of clear and appropriate guidelines for individualized education program teams (as defined in section 614(d)(1)(B) of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act) to apply in determining, on an annual and subject-by-subject basis, when a child’s significant cognitive disability justifies assessment based on alternate academic achievement standards;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idc705158a6b7549aaa93c5b66fdec68e9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ensure that parents of the students whom the State plans to assess using alternate assessments—</text> <subclause id="id651B372D05B9453C90E208FF08165BE0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>are involved in the decision that their child’s academic achievement will be measured against alternate academic achievement standards, consistent with section 614(d)(1)(A)(i)(VI)(bb) of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id9F7E33FCAD794F6FAC1F0CEC47533A57"><enum>(II)</enum><text>provide informed consent that their child’s achievement will be measured against alternate academic achievement standards using such assessment; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id9C0BA40CBF774377ADE908B89F09469C"><enum>(III)</enum><text>are informed of any effect that participation in such assessment may have on their child’s academic preparation and eligibility for a regular secondary school diploma, as determined by the State;</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="id283ac1188441445fa790188330897605"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>provide evidence that students with the most significant cognitive disabilities are included in and making progress in the general curriculum for the grade in which the students are enrolled and in assessments aligned with that curriculum, as described in section 601(c)(5)(A) of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id2ec6a8499d514b72b89a6e41346eb3e5"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>develop, disseminate information about, make available, and promote the use of reasonable accommodations to increase the number of students with the most significant cognitive disabilities participating in grade-level academic instruction and assessments aligned with grade-level academic standards, and promote the use of reasonable accommodations to increase the number of students with the most significant cognitive disabilities who are tested against grade-level academic achievement standards;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idb9300ca65cfb474d861af8cfdfe07442"><enum>(v)</enum><text>take steps to ensure general and special education teachers and other appropriate staff know how to administer assessments, including how to make appropriate use of accommodations, for students with disabilities;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idc22e9d45247041ababee33ef637c5f5c"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>require separate annual determinations about whether a student should be assessed using an alternate assessment based on alternate academic achievement standards for each subject assessed; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id10096d8815ee4fe6a067178afe4bad74"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>ensure that students who take an alternate assessment based on alternate academic achievement standards are not precluded from attempting to complete the requirements for a regular secondary school diploma, as determined by the State.</text>
							</clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id99C9225437E7470388736624F514312F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id37D4092BDE0E47E4B243AD45A5DED9C3" style="OLC"> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc4a71a8a1a764126a7a75b0a8a1bec69"><enum>(L)</enum><header>No inclusion of IEPs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State shall not use any student individualized education program, as defined in section 602(14) of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act, in the State accountability system.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id984f07d4113e4224857c4a160540264a"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (h)(1)(C)—</text> <subparagraph id="id20d3cffa51e043e9828796fc6ac045e6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in clause (i), by striking <quote>disability status</quote> and inserting <quote>disability category described in section 602(3) of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2d20cf9c02a34b70adad91c52d9ab4fc"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in clause (vii), by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide5be1e06cc574d29b81e972411ae5e85"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in clause (viii), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd1b78eb444cd46ba9f28ba0c76f3fb07"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9cfc4ca9066a4009ae0ef328447fa048" style="OLC"> <clause id="id0652507ea43f43478c1c573ec9906fd5"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>the number and percentage of students with disabilities who take an alternate assessment based on alternate achievement standards, by grade and subject, and, for each grade and subject, by disability category described in section 602(3) of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act, except that disaggregation shall not be required in a case in which the number of students in a category is insufficient to yield statistically reliable information or the results would reveal personally identifiable information about an individual student.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</subparagraph></paragraph></section></legis-body>
</bill>


