<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1579 IS: Native American Tourism and Improving Visitor Experience Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-06-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1579</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150616">June 16, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S353">Mr. Schatz</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S303">Mr. Thune</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S326">Mr. Udall</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S352">Mr. Heller</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S314">Mr. Tester</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S332">Mr. Franken</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S288">Ms. Murkowski</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S381">Mr. Rounds</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SLIA00">Committee on Indian Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To enhance and integrate Native American tourism, empower Native American communities, increase
			 coordination and collaboration between Federal tourism assets, and expand
			 heritage and cultural tourism opportunities in the United States.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body>
 <section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Native American Tourism and Improving Visitor Experience Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>NATIVE Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="id6FCBD50475A9477DBF79B6D99D0D3157"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purposes of this Act are—</text>
 <paragraph id="idD8789232707041ECAC2D9C4CAE285973"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to enhance and integrate Native American tourism—</text> <subparagraph id="id7336A08F8C494DF89E797B63A56683CC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to empower Native American communities; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id276B1A6BCB3F4B3CB2B42FAB9BEC6C3B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to advance the National Travel and Tourism Strategy;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id7E73F5875CC14D53B2F205F5DD013969"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to increase coordination and collaboration between Federal tourism assets to support Native American tourism and bolster recreational travel and tourism;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id6E94777F20874943BBA2694ADA6A7818"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to expand heritage and cultural tourism opportunities in the United States to spur economic development, create jobs, and increase tourism revenues;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id39ab1248eea34ababd9d50330c87d9a1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to enhance and improve self-determination and self-governance capabilities in the Native American community and to promote greater self-sufficiency;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id3f0f7991a1af41d3abb7d38aa6ef0791"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to encourage Indian tribes and tribal organizations to engage more fully in Native American tourism activities to increase visitation to rural and remote areas in the United States that are too difficult to access or are unknown to domestic travelers and international tourists;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idED2FB81F5EDF4898A856AA1266357FFC"><enum>(6)</enum><text>to provide grants, loans, and technical assistance to Indian tribes and tribal organizations that will—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id4D1CAA0BC8554DDF812C4F5993647720"><enum>(A)</enum><text>spur important infrastructure development;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE38606B6A90A4374903DE8C0C3528880"><enum>(B)</enum><text>increase tourism capacity; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idCECA09F21F9243BF9470978F6D715B51"><enum>(C)</enum><text>elevate living standards in Native American communities; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id976FC1AE33D04C5794A468C1B0ACEF30"><enum>(7)</enum><text>to support the development of technologically innovative projects that will incorporate recreational travel and tourism information and data from Federal assets to improve the visitor experience.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="id6B845C30ABF24C41ACF659A889B0E4DA"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="idC72B609A1E524CD79B03EC561BE06B54"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agency</header><text>The term <term>agency</term> has the meaning given the term in section 551 of title 5, United States Code.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idD2AF7FE0E91241FE88DB537494C5A866"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Indian tribe</header><text>The term <term>Indian tribe</term> has the meaning given the term in section 4 of the <act-name parsable-cite="ISDA">Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/450b">25 U.S.C. 450b</external-xref>).</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="id28C579FD2C464D8BA5D1E5F99E0EB25E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Tribal organization</header>
 <subparagraph id="id5C23013DD9934EA3BFDB49520F874B3C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>tribal organization</term> has the meaning given the term in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/450b">25 U.S.C. 450b</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1115DFF665E544D4A5B197B9B8D93D5B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusion</header><text>The term <term>tribal organization</term> includes a Native Hawaiian organization (as defined in section 7207 of the Native Hawaiian Education Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7517">20 U.S.C. 7517</external-xref>)).</text>
				</subparagraph></paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id46402FA2144F4F7A842A1988653B2419"><enum>4.</enum><header>Integrating Federal tourism assets to strengthen Native tourism opportunities</header>
 <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id173D75773A3C481C99E925C88C3702F3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Secretary of Commerce and Secretary of the Interior</header><text>The Secretary of Commerce and the Secretary of the Interior shall update the respective management plans and tourism initiatives of the Department of Commerce and the Department of the Interior to include Indian tribes and tribal organizations.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id283DD247BF6247999B17C3B629EAEA32"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Other agencies</header><text>The head of each agency that has recreational travel or tourism functions or complementary programs shall update the respective management plans and tourism strategies of the agency to include Indian tribes and tribal organizations.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="id83751B91101A4725999BCA2F7F16478D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Native American tourism plans</header>
 <paragraph id="idCF23E42A2C37490581EFFE0DD507438F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The plans shall outline policy proposals—</text> <subparagraph id="id5CEBB2D26D7A4D439B7D8D8609EE89E3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to improve travel and tourism data collection and analysis;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id96E96891714E443D96A98C89F123482D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to increase the integration, alignment, and utility of public records, publications, and Web sites maintained by Federal agencies;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id96EA781933E64705957F652643316352"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to create a better user experience for domestic travelers and international visitors;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id18CA9B231C1A4AC1B7341593468B4DF5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to align Federal agency Web sites and publications;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id754C38128B514922B9C7F86937E03C8C"><enum>(E)</enum><text>to support national tourism goals;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id130E4192B58B4B038079952ACEE89F6A"><enum>(F)</enum><text>to identify agency programs that could be used to support tourism capacity building and help sustain tourism infrastructure in Native American communities;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3F19AAD3FFD84EA3A915FD4ED2229AAE"><enum>(G)</enum><text>to develop innovative visitor portals for parks, landmarks, heritage and cultural sites, and assets that showcase and respect the diversity of the indigenous peoples of the United States;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF948C681745E44C681206608CD2DE999"><enum>(H)</enum><text>to share local Native American heritage through the development of bilingual interpretive and directional signage that could include or incorporate English and the local Native American language or languages; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id57E0069BFA07428C885740E19CE34EE1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to improve access to transportation programs related to Native American community capacity building for tourism and trade, including transportation planning for programs related to visitor enhancement and safety.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idAC913F73DEE34A0F99A4CB5A3CA81D61"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consultation with Indian tribes and Native Americans</header><text>In developing the plan under paragraph (1), the head of each agency shall consult with Indian tribes and the Native American community to identify appropriate levels of inclusion of the Indian tribes and Native Americans in Federal tourism activities, public records and publications, including Native American tourism information available on Web sites.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id111A959ECC074129A12EB6C1F53AF715"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idCE63977AD3D449B2A9B75CB43FDA2183"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of the Interior, in consultation with the Secretary of Commerce, shall enter into a memorandum of understanding or cooperative agreement with an entity or organization with a demonstrated record in tribal communities of defining, introducing, developing, and sustaining American Indian, Alaska Native, and Native Hawaiian tourism and related activities in a manner that respects and honors native traditions and values.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5B03501014C4496A9F05E23BF5EB2EC3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>The memorandum of understanding or cooperative agreement described in paragraph (1) shall formalize a role for the organization or entity to serve as a facilitator between the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Commerce and the Indian tribes and tribal organizations—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1E6953AA0E8B4768862E2FD7013D2D64"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to identify areas where technical assistance is needed through consultations with Indian tribes and tribal organizations to empower the Indian tribes and tribal organizations to participate fully in the tourism industry; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id87FC2C52E12D468B99E5A9F118773ACA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to provide a means for the delivery of technical assistance and coordinate the delivery of the assistance to Indian tribes and tribal organizations in collaboration with the Secretary of the Interior, the Secretary of Commerce, and other entities with distinctive experience, as appropriate.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idC402FD81C61D488B911E7BF8BF780945"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>Subject to the availability of appropriations, the head of each Federal agency, including the Secretary of the Interior, the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of Transportation, the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, and the Secretary of Labor shall obligate any funds made available to the head of the agency to cover any administrative expenses incurred by the organization or entity described in paragraph (1) in carrying out programs or activities of the agency.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE9A3026E23AF40B08FE1ED05944A8519"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Metrics</header><text>The Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Commerce shall coordinate with the organization or entity described in paragraph (1) to develop metrics to measure the effectiveness of the entity or organization in strengthening tourism opportunities for Indian tribes and tribal organizations.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idFBFA95B14D4F48B1B2F8F0268599CB6C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reports</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and occasionally thereafter, the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Commerce shall each submit to the Committee on Indian Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives a report that describes—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE6EAEBBC15AE476CA64A6898D158C1A6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the manner in which the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Commerce, as applicable, is including Indian tribes and tribal organizations in management plans;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id99E11ECB5F174E9DA97079ABF013A86E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the efforts of the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Commerce, as applicable, to develop departmental and agency tourism plans to support tourism programs of Indian tribes and tribal organizations;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2A1B93A8A9AD4405B2562BC872486991"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the manner in which the entity or organization described in subsection (d)(1) is working to promote tourism to empower Indian tribes and tribal organizations to participate fully in the tourism industry; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9E9C86AFCDB6466B809C81427A681609"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the effectiveness of the entity or organization described in subsection (d)(1) based on the metrics developed under subsection (d)(4).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idF1CF40C33E654022A1D66D4E8BBC7ECE"><enum>5.</enum><header>Native American tourism and branding enhancement</header>
 <subsection id="idB1FB0CFF5C2C423C96653FEA1198B3A1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of each agency shall—</text> <paragraph id="idA0E879DBDA6A47C59A032104F6C47481"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">take actions that help empower Indian tribes and tribal organizations to showcase the heritage, foods, traditions, history, and continuing vitality of the Indian tribes and tribal organizations;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id87C739DFC5974279AB2D865A461449F7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>support the efforts of Indian tribes and tribal organizations—</text> <subparagraph id="idEEA4D59C924E4FCC90575CAA29E41E27"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to identify and enhance or maintain traditions and cultural features that are important to sustain the distinctiveness of the local Native American community; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8FB9B4D6FEDD4200926BDD1FCA87DFDD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to provide visitor experiences that are authentic and respectful;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idDBE8895A8897427AB591A02A50A34C55"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provide assistance to interpret the connections between the indigenous peoples of the United States and the national identity of the United States;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id0A69E57EAB1D46D3AD86F5B407CC9D29"><enum>(4)</enum><text>enhance efforts to promote understanding and respect for diverse cultures and subcultures in the United States and the relevance of those cultures to the national brand of the United States; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id7E2E78FBF5074322B34DCE6FF29D6268"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">enter into appropriate memoranda of understanding and establish public-private partnerships to ensure that arriving domestic travelers at airports and arriving international visitors at ports of entry are welcomed in a manner that both showcases and respects the diversity of Indian tribes and tribal organizations.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1FCC668DEEA54879BC1E896DE846ED55"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To the extent practicable, grants administered by the Commissioner of the Administration for Native Americans, Chairman of the National Endowment for the Arts, Chairman of the National Endowment for the Humanities, and any other grant program administered by the head of an agency for which Indian tribes or tribal organizations are eligible may be used—</text>
 <paragraph id="idB579DECA7BF74A528B269BB071B0EB7B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to support the efforts of Indian tribes and tribal organizations to tell the story of those Indian tribes and tribal organizations as the First Peoples of the United States;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id0A3960C0144F48E1ABB3D7B95A92ACDB"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to use the arts and humanities to help revitalize Native communities, promote economic development, increase livability, and present the uniqueness of the United States to visitors in a way that celebrates the diversity of the United States; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id13CDFE2466AF4830848DD0C9480431F1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to carry out this section.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id38386A1656184A55804E4300DC3984D4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Smithsonian</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Advisory Council and the Board of Regents of the Smithsonian Institution shall work with Indian tribes, tribal organizations, and nonprofit organizations to establish long-term partnerships with non-Smithsonian museums and educational and cultural organizations—</text>
 <paragraph id="id32D042685B904359915E920681410C50"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to share collections, exhibitions, interpretive materials, and educational strategies; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id3385571E014C4CEAB8D40576401FBF5F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to conduct joint research and collaborative projects that would support tourism efforts for Indian tribes and tribal organizations and carry out the intent of this section.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


