<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S2166 IS: Timely Mental Health for Foster Youth Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-10-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 2166</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151008">October 8, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S342">Mr. Blunt</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S284">Ms. Stabenow</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend part B of title IV of the Social Security Act to ensure that mental health screenings and
			 assessments are provided to children and youth upon entry into foster
			 care.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Timely Mental Health for Foster Youth Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="id955B255F94944E7491A429499734B2AE"><enum>2.</enum><header>Timely mental health screenings and assessments for children and  youth upon
			 entry into foster care</header>
 <subsection id="idAEFF951740AA4D54B306525E75B41C0B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>State plan requirement</header><text>Section 422(b)(15)(A) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/622">42 U.S.C. 622(b)(15)(A)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="idC4F00B2F0DB842C18681D8AC375BBA5D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in clause (i), by inserting <quote>and that require that an initial mental health screening of any child in foster care be completed not later than 30 days after the date the child enters into foster care and, in the case of any child in foster care for whom a mental health issue is identified in such initial screening, that a comprehensive assessment of the mental health of the child be completed not later than 60 days after the date the child enters into foster care</quote> before the semicolon; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id5397A41FAB854B3EB445846DBB885BE8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by striking <quote>screenings</quote> and inserting <quote>such screenings and assessments</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id9B2F531900C444A195EF5F111817C967"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical amendment</header><text>Section 422(b)(15)(A) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/622">42 U.S.C. 622(b)(15)(A)</external-xref>) is further amended in the matter before clause (i), by striking <quote>provides</quote> and inserting <quote>provide</quote>.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="id49E43FDAC5D54939A8F32B4755ADF228"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header>
 <paragraph id="id0DA9E5EFB25E409FAF790B035577257D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the amendments made by this section shall take effect on January 1, 2016.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id0ED673B4E0624E1CA5E03C74F7EA2E07"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Delay permitted if state legislation required</header><text>In the case of a State plan approved under part B of title IV of the Social Security Act which the Secretary of Health and Human Services determines requires State legislation (other than legislation appropriating funds) in order for the plan to meet the additional requirements imposed by this section, the State plan shall not be regarded as failing to comply with the requirements of such part solely on the basis of the failure of the plan to meet such additional requirements before the first day of the first calendar quarter beginning after the close of the first regular session of the State legislature that begins after the date of enactment of this section. For purposes of the previous sentence, in the case of a State that has a 2-year legislative session, each year of such session shall be deemed to be a separate regular session of the State legislature.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


