<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S348 IS: Protecting Lands Against Narcotics Trafficking Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 348</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150203">February 3, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S118">Mr. Hatch</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S221">Mrs. Feinstein</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To impose enhanced penalties for conduct relating to unlawful production of a controlled substance
			 on Federal property or while intentionally trespassing on the property of
 another that causes environmental damage.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting Lands Against Narcotics Trafficking Act of 2015</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PLANT Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idD973647AC7E94B3CA568FD82627DE7E4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Controlled Substances Act penalty amendments</header><subsection id="idE0B7711A9FB74CD893632F5C37B533BE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Cultivating or manufacturing controlled substances on Federal property</header><text>Section 401(b)(5) of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/841">21 U.S.C. 841(b)(5)</external-xref>) is amended, in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>as provided in this subsection</quote> and inserting <quote>for not more than 10 years, in addition to any other term of imprisonment imposed under this subsection</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="idE337E9B5B9B547EC9401BF4ECBA4D533"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Environmental harms and other hazards</header><text>Pursuant to its authority under section 994 of title 28, United States Code, the United States Sentencing Commission shall amend and review the Federal Sentencing Guidelines and policy statements to ensure that the guidelines provide for a penalty enhancement of not less than 1 offense level for a violation of section 401(a) of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/841">21 U.S.C. 841(a)</external-xref>) while on Federal property or while intentionally trespassing on the property of another if the offense—</text><paragraph id="id75A34A7127CF456191A72A10B0CC7EE5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>creates a hazard to humans, wildlife, or domestic animals;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idAB684C390E1948BCBE7C4AE666315EDD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>degrades or harms the environment or natural resources; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idE570C828B35C43BC8983333C68C58B3C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>pollutes an aquifer, spring, stream, river, or body of water.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id9F1F187088DC4C0299DD007D0585BECD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Stream diversion or clear cutting on Federal property or while intentionally trespassing on the property of another</header><paragraph id="id108FD3096084465AAE5CD217BB9C84C6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Prohibition on stream diversion or clear cutting on Federal property or while intentionally trespassing on the property of another</header><text>Section 401(b) of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/841">21 U.S.C. 841(b)</external-xref>), as amended by subsection (a), is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB7EFCD77A1674134A401EBB68D6CF6D6" style="OLC"><paragraph id="idD2C23242BEFD46C9AFD197173591467C"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Destruction of bodies of water or timber</header><subparagraph id="id11BCC319D06949BBB2AA5496CC188A7A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any person who violates subsection (a) in a manner that diverts, redirects, obstructs, or drains an aquifer, spring, stream, river, or body of water or clear cuts timber while cultivating or manufacturing a controlled substance on Federal property or while cultivating or manufacturing a controlled substance while intentionally trespassing on the property of another shall be fined an amount not to exceed—</text><clause id="id2C650CAA144D4420AC52769C6C888F07"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the amount authorized in accordance with this section;</text></clause><clause id="idB7255AA7467B4EA988F536293734C7C5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the amount authorized in accordance with the provisions of title 18, United States Code;</text></clause><clause id="id7647A995D0E64C8BAE815AD276D2F35C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>$500,000 if the defendant is an individual; or</text></clause><clause id="id15B138817FD9469BA44C21C1E30E2E93"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>$1,000,000 if the defendant is other than an individual.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idDFCB5ED339DC487FAE169B99B52175F8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Use of amounts from fines</header><clause id="idB057A27FC1AD44C8AA976246159A1685"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall transfer to the Secretary of the Interior, for use in accordance with clause (ii), the amounts received as fines for a violation described in subparagraph (A).</text></clause><clause id="idCE423D8AEA76402B99AEC31C8000473F"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Funds</header><text>The Secretary of the Interior shall use the amounts transferred under clause (i) to address the environmental damage caused by any offense described in subparagraph (A).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="id19007B1C4ACF426BA38436E3D4394EE0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federal sentencing guidelines enhancement</header><text>Pursuant to its authority under section 994 of title 28, United States Code, the United States Sentencing Commission shall review and amend the Federal Sentencing Guidelines and policy statements to ensure that the guidelines provide for a penalty enhancement of not less than 1 offense level for a violation of section 401(a) of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/841">21 U.S.C. 841(a)</external-xref>) if the offense involves the diversion, redirection, obstruction, or draining of an aquifer, spring, stream, river, or body of water or the clear cut of timber while cultivating or manufacturing a controlled substance on Federal property or while cultivating or manufacturing a controlled substance while intentionally trespassing on the property of another.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3D93A86327DF47219AD7C968CB041F03"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendment</header><text>Section 1402(b)(1)(A) of the Victims of Crime Act of 1984 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/10601">42 U.S.C. 10601(b)(1)(A)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="id09DCA7CC2C43447B8D71FBA01BEA9516"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in clause (i), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id25DC47B017E14CFFA548A3D00A47101E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after clause (ii) the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id70D5DE3037E0460DAC399C0D02922481" style="OLC"><clause id="idB3B000B3C8554CEBB459666A3656CE78"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>section 401(b)(8) of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/841">21 U.S.C. 841(b)(8)</external-xref>); and</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id44528ed36b16441a9349ae0db9a1befd"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Booby traps on Federal property</header><text>Section 401(d)(1) of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/841">21 U.S.C. 841(d)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>cultivated,</quote> after <quote>is being</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="id9ca2fb0145ac4a22b0dbf70d647219b4"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Use or Possession of Firearms in Connection With Drug Offenses on Federal property or while intentionally trespassing on the property of another</header><text>Pursuant to its authority under section 994 of title 28, United States Code, the United States Sentencing Commission shall review and amend the Federal Sentencing Guidelines and policy statements to ensure that the guidelines provide for a penalty enhancement of not less than 1 offense level for a violation of section 401(a) of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/841">21 U.S.C. 841(a)</external-xref>) if the offense involves the possession of a firearm while cultivating or manufacturing a controlled substance on Federal property or while cultivating or manufacturing a controlled substance while intentionally trespassing on the property of another.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


