<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1065 IS: School Asthma Management Plan Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1065</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150423">April 23, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S331">Mrs. Gillibrand</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend title IV of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to provide grants for the
			 development of asthma management plans and the purchase of
			 asthma inhalers and spacers for emergency use, as necessary. </official-title></form>
	<legis-body>
 <section id="id020B43B3062A41D69806CAB268EEEF4A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>School Asthma Management Plan Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="id857A55F2A6BC48F4B5589C862EEA6348" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>School asthma management plans</header> <subsection id="id46E1453B4553491F82BEE2E321E8A107"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title IV of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7101">20 U.S.C. 7101 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4EBC35F5792841CB84850EEFB49066B0" style="OLC">
					<part id="id6D8EE4E6FD7E4C998A4F9EDB40640EBF" style="OLC"><enum>D</enum><header>School Asthma Management Plans</header>
						<section id="id35B75D4CFAC249BAB8DBA5392A530A94"><enum>4401.</enum><header>School asthma
				management plans</header>
							<subsection id="id91D90AECA5FE4B37B4DA5119A1D25F02"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grants
				Authorized</header>
								<paragraph id="id82954619250B4E1BA5C2EA64FCF5136C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>The Secretary is authorized to award grants to local educational agencies to enable public elementary schools and secondary schools served by the local educational agencies to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id902FA73E4D4A429A956CD6F8FCD5ECC9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>develop and implement a school asthma management plan; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idCD173778581346B7A934850DF7EC4B03"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if the school chooses, purchase drugs and devices for emergency use that are approved or cleared by the Food and Drug Administration, including bronchodilators, spacers, and inhalers, and other supplies determined necessary by the Secretary, for students served by the school, as needed, as well as devices that measure pulmonary function or asthma education tools, or both.</text>
									</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idA4D21D991B994874A031D39B1CA7E8CF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Alternative
 grantees</header><text>The Secretary may award a grant under this section to a local health or education department to carry out the activities described in this section if the Secretary determines that in such local area such department is the entity that would routinely carry out such activities.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id9DC657E2256C481EBAF8F2C4A0D9A68F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text>A local educational agency or department that desires to receive a grant under this section shall submit an application at such time, in such manner, and accompanied by such information as the Secretary may require.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idDDAAC0E451A74D538E2BF30FD313E7AB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall give a priority to—</text> <paragraph id="id0374E9E7BEAD4979A97C6BB8598E936A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any local educational agency that will use grant funds to assist a public elementary school or secondary school that has a high burden of asthma, as determined by the Secretary; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id1E7DC268C792452F897C04568306DDBC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>if the Secretary elects to award grants described in subsection (a)(2), any department that proposes to carry out the grant activities at a school described in paragraph (1).</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1D5D6B16EAC1468DA7795B019C503599"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Use of grant
 funds</header><text>A local educational agency or department that receives a grant under this section shall develop and implement a comprehensive school asthma management plan based on national guidelines at each school to be served under the grant, and may purchase drugs and devices for emergency use that are approved or cleared by the Food and Drug Administration, including bronchodilators, spacers, and inhalers, and other supplies determined necessary by the Secretary, for students served by the school or department, as needed, as well as devices that measure pulmonary function or asthma education tools, or both. Such management plan shall include the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="ID5b6344b21b85439491aefbf6bcfac9ef"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A method to identify all students with a diagnosis of asthma.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="ID9d5ae262346c42b3add7b27514f85872"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An asthma action plan for each student with a diagnosis of asthma.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ID6b1e2a7be58e458681324152ab9098fe"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Asthma education for all school staff, such as education regarding asthma basics, asthma management, trigger management, and comprehensive emergency responses to asthma attacks.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="IDe6e1d2ea938e4c219b146db555015272"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Access to medication and to methods to administer medication, for all students served by the school or department who have asthma, based on the student's prescription and individual needs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="IDeddcf16f959e4937a9bdc3d3ca364713"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Asthma medication and emergency policies that are specific to the school.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="IDb74450822b2140ab8a7cd8a619a69788"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Protocols and training to support clinical management of acute symptoms of asthma and ongoing management of asthma.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="IDa307d89308334de488888a0556843c30"><enum>(7)</enum><text>A system to support ongoing coordination of asthma care with the family, the primary care provider, and others as necessary.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ID5fe18a16a9914dadab083d411cca3496"><enum>(8)</enum><text>A method to monitor the quality and outcomes of the care provided to each student served by the school or department who has asthma, including how often treatment is needed and what treatment students get.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idd45b55d9be3246df8321dd5e1430a837"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Successful completion of the Environmental Protection Agency's Indoor Air Quality Tools for Schools Indoor Air Quality Profile.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id63BD93717C7D4F26BE6F86916B919A9C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Grant recipient
 actions</header><text>A school or department that receives a grant under this section shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="ID70e327b222a24bcfba9d65846e7fd5da"><enum>(1)</enum><text>utilize existing systems, when possible, including the use of forms developed in accordance with section 504 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/794">20 U.S.C. 794</external-xref>);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ID6bc4999455184b2bb9e45c063514e429"><enum>(2)</enum><text>find innovative ways—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id4DF26C1D1FEF48DE9DB04D0BF26F6CA4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to encourage bidirectional communication between schools and students' physicians in a rapid manner; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID017d8f236fb24dbd93ef7e040986b940"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to encourage adherence to asthma treatment by students;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id2CA6E3D1606C4804ABD052BC26B69B55"><enum>(3)</enum><text>ensure that a nurse or another individual who is trained to administer emergency asthma care is on staff;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ida4602129e8584f0d936d7023e93492c0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>ensure that all student asthma action plans include asthma triggers, both allergens and irritants, for the student; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id1b983ed1b3044c66909d22eaf82f870c"><enum>(5)</enum><text>ensure that each school served under the grant report asthma emergency events involving students to the State health department by school identifier.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id9D53E59BEAC948DB9FFFCFE14F7B3AEC"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization
 of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section such sums as may be necessary for fiscal year 2016 and each of the 4 succeeding fiscal years.</text></subsection></section></part><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="idB923E06169AE4E24A63BB69AC285498D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of
 contents</header><text>The table of contents in section 2 of such Act is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 4304 the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="idc76b94da-632f-4b2e-a1c9-6eff82363887" style="OLC"><toc><toc-entry idref="id6D8EE4E6FD7E4C998A4F9EDB40640EBF" level="part">PART D—School Asthma Management Plans</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry idref="id35B75D4CFAC249BAB8DBA5392A530A94" level="section">Sec. 4401. School asthma management plans.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


