<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1215 IS: Methane Hydrate Research and Development Amendments Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 1215</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150506">May 6, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S288">Ms. Murkowski</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the Methane Hydrate Research and Development Act of 2000 to provide for the development of
			 methane hydrate as a commercially viable source of energy.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Methane Hydrate Research and Development Amendments Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="idBDDA6FFE3E464640BA21A999707D18D4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Amendments to
			 the Methane Hydrate Research and Development Act of 2000</header>
 <subsection id="id42FCCD8BE1424591A9455AFE5011C204"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2 of the Methane Hydrate Research and Development Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/2001">30 U.S.C. 2001</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="ID8dfbb4295ad649388e2be96050074f1a"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id7D1E9F88A92F42F898B44D64ACDBED0C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (5), by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id3B4C2788294F4DBF83DD5C9FCA2DB16D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB029F75BC3624504AA01F9FFAF7A69BE" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="ID23b4bc7d451e470784a53fded1c45923"><enum>(6)</enum><text>methane is a powerful greenhouse gas that may be exchanged between terrestrial methane hydrate reservoirs and the atmosphere by natural or anthropogenic processes; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ID78c10b45d2d54d1db349c64bdb504f8e"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the short- and long-term release of methane from arctic or marine reservoirs may have significant environmental effects, including global climate change.</text>
						</paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID3deec382f4924849a221ba1d40408024"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Methane hydrate
			 research and development program</header>
				<paragraph id="idEBAFC553EFF4486D86B93555BB02BBFD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>Section 4 of the Methane Hydrate Research and Development Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/2003">30 U.S.C. 2003</external-xref>) is amended by striking subsection (b) and inserting the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id245E2E52CA1742DC9C3214DFD637FAE9" style="OLC">
						<subsection id="ID78c32bcd81354408b6e7362b0520e20c"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grants,
				contracts, cooperative agreements, interagency funds transfer
			 agreements, and
				field work proposals</header>
							<paragraph id="ID32ced2f215cd434ca28f104acb17d20a"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Assistance and
 coordination</header><text>In carrying out the program of methane hydrate research and development authorized by this section, the Secretary may award grants to, or enter into contracts or cooperative agreements with, institutions that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="ID840a5ad6f3204d34a507967fdbf79277"><enum>(A)</enum><text>conduct basic and applied research to identify, explore, assess, and develop methane hydrate as a commercially viable source of energy;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID4a95115e593e4126a8a7c276bedd222b"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identify and characterize methane hydrate resources using remote sensing and seismic data, including the characterization of hydrate concentrations in marine reservoirs in the Gulf of Mexico or the Atlantic Ocean Basin by the date that is 4 years after the date of enactment of the Methane Hydrate Research and Development Amendments Act of 2015;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="IDda2a25c224f94b6c98df434076456ebd"><enum>(C)</enum><text>develop technologies required for efficient and environmentally sound development of methane hydrate resources;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID407541b224ae46c5a02adb2e6e4b4c11"><enum>(D)</enum><text>conduct basic and applied research to assess and mitigate the environmental impact of hydrate degassing (including natural degassing and degassing associated with commercial development);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="IDebcb8b6fd2074a9f8418d01bd362346a"><enum>(E)</enum><text>develop technologies to reduce the risks of drilling through methane hydrates;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="IDa1196233dd27426283584f7cd10878a9"><enum>(F)</enum><text>conduct exploratory drilling, well testing, and production testing operations on permafrost and nonpermafrost gas hydrates in support of the activities authorized by this paragraph, including—</text>
 <clause id="idED3EE46D994D42D08813BD9E8F3899E3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>drilling of a test well and performing a long-term hydrate production test on land in the United States Arctic region by the date that is 4 years after the date of enactment of the Methane Hydrate Research and Development Amendments Act of 2015;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idFD6716299AEA405DBFEBC45AC1DC3FAB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>drilling of a test well and performing a long-term hydrate production test in a marine environment by the date that is 10 years after the date of enactment of the Methane Hydrate Research and Development Amendments Act of 2015; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idF0B657B7AEE240109E64B8AA4721E289"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>drilling a full-scale production test well at a location to be determined by the Secretary; or</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID53cf88d1c2494cb6bcd6eda6cc099827"><enum>(G)</enum><text>expand education and training programs in methane hydrate resource research and resource development through fellowships or other means for graduate education and training.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID9422f63e1bf6426ca7d19717ace67b0c"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Environmental
 monitoring</header><text>The Secretary shall conduct a long-term environmental monitoring program to study the effects of production from methane hydrate reservoirs.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="id1B7E0648465B4D78B8B11F6AA33FCF91"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Competitive
 peer review</header><text>Funds made available under paragraphs (1) and (2) shall be made available based on a competitive process using external scientific peer review of proposed research.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="id0CBC1BDB96D54731A5485E34C0503358"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming
 amendment</header><text>Section 4(e) of the Methane Hydrate Research and Development Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/2003">30 U.S.C. 2003(e)</external-xref>) is amended in the matter preceding paragraph (1) by striking <quote>subsection (b)(1)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (b)</quote>.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID247972ececb744f4971fd8c3cc7584bd"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization
 of appropriations</header><text>The Methane Hydrate Research and Development Act of 2000 is amended by striking section 7 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/2006">30 U.S.C. 2006</external-xref>) and inserting the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8BE8A540CF904ED095A2674E7BE6425B" style="OLC">
					<section id="IDd63c509bd08145db8dfc4ac689c471e8"><enum>7.</enum><header>Authorization of
 appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary such sums as are necessary to carry out this Act.</text>
					</section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


