<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S526 IS: Sunset of the 2001 Authorization for Use of Military Force Act </dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 526</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150212">February 12, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S308">Mr. Cardin</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S364">Mr. Murphy</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To sunset the 2001 Authorization for Use of Military Force after three years.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Sunset of the 2001 Authorization for Use of Military Force Act </short-title></quote>.</text>
 </section><section id="id176b2be960474190ad622008247b2d77"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text> <paragraph id="idd0014c63169f49cd868a302d97a64f49"><enum>(1)</enum><text>On September 11, 2001, the United States and its citizens were victims of the worst terrorist attacks in world history.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idad31b255b2ac4e80b1f347063c4dc734"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The September 11, 2001, terrorist attacks were planned, financed, and executed by al Qaeda, a terrorist organization led by Osama bin Laden.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id18da8515b5b3483abd118d947752338c"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Al Qaeda was based in Afghanistan throughout the period leading up to the attacks, and the three previous attacks against United States targets, the 1993 World Trade Center bombing, the 1998 East Africa bombings, and the 2000 attack on the USS Cole, were planned by al Qaeda central.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id2cdcb2d6a06b4cd98771ee60f4876bd0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>From 1996 to 2001, the Taliban government of Afghanistan knowingly harbored al Qaeda, and was complicit in its plots against the United States, and al Qaeda, in turn, supported the Taliban, including sponsoring and training the elite Arab 55th Brigade of the Taliban Army.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id9baf3d4c0b3142f783c74e7ab03fa8f0"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Following the September 11, 2001, attacks, Congress passed the Authorization for Use of Military Force (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/107/40">Public Law 107–40</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1541">50 U.S.C. 1541</external-xref> note) to provide the President with requisite authorization to use <quote>force against those nations, organizations, or persons he determines planned, authorized, committed, or aided the terrorist attacks that occurred on September 11, 2001, or harbored such organizations or persons, in order to prevent any future acts of international terrorism against the United States by such nations, organizations or persons</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ida574fbe042eb41aaa0ddc4d53eca03da"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Congress never intended and did not authorize a perpetual war.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="iddadb6979ed6f49c691858f4ce2096cbd"><enum>(7)</enum><text>With the withdrawal of United States combat troops from Afghanistan and the transition to Afghan national security forces at the end of 2014, the Authorization for Use of Military Force, which was focused on the September 11th attacks and those directly responsible, will have largely served its purpose.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idbbf0a748d24243c487da016be5c8ee3a"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The homeland and the American people face new threats from individuals, entities, and organizations that may affiliate with al Qaeda, or share its ideology and its determination to attack Americans, but which may not be connected to the September 11, 2001, attacks or those who carried them out to a degree sufficient to be covered by the Authorization for Use of Military Force.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ide8675860269049b2bceb3fb77f23e752"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Even after the expiration of the Authorization for Use of Military Force, there is likely to remain the need to defend against specific networks of violent extremists, including al Qaeda and its affiliates, that threaten the United States, and the President must work with the legislative branch to secure whatever new authorities may be required to meet the threat and comply with the Constitution and the War Powers Resolution (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1541">50 U.S.C. 1541 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="id8312bf959da94f13be1b488f1d614544"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sunset of 2001 Authorization for Use of Military Force</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Authorization for Use of Military Force (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/107/40">Public Law 107–40</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1541">50 U.S.C. 1541</external-xref> note) shall terminate on the date that is three years after the date of the enactment of this Act, unless reauthorized.</text>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


