<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S2369 IS: Community Partnership Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-12-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2369</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20151208">December 8, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S277">Mr. Carper</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to establish an Office for Community Partnerships.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body>
 <section id="HA4382E3705444A5885A4BCDBF456A140" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Community Partnership Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="id053B338F3D374D1F9B529EEAEB1241B2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Authorization of the Office for Community Partnerships of the Department of Homeland Security</header> <subsection id="H008138F64E464572B9008D842AE12849"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title I of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/101">6 U.S.C. 101 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0CAE57CEC3024BCFB4A0D6724D5DE9CA" style="OLC">
					<section id="H96EA0C6C60B344DA844493B791C3FA53"><enum>104.</enum><header>Office for Community Partnerships</header>
 <subsection id="HD8CEAABDF232429EBCB1CE0B22463B65"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text> <paragraph id="idB6CF47F94583466CBFBC8834189EF6EF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>countering violent extremism</term> means proactive and relevant actions to counter efforts by extremists to radicalize, recruit, and mobilize followers to violence and to address the conditions that allow for violent extremist recruitment and radicalization; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id451A8EC78DD04BE695EA28E422A1C34C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>violent extremism</term> means ideologically motivated violence as a method of advancing a cause.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id705184CB7A974082B925A669DA09E15A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is in the Department an Office for Community Partnerships.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id3913289792384E9F90B47B45E44E8110"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Head of Office</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Office for Community Partnerships shall be headed by an Assistant Secretary for Community Partnerships, who shall be designated by the Secretary.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA61AA652A03C402C872401BA2AAB8C8F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Deputy Assistant Secretary; assignment of personnel</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text> <paragraph id="id98EFC564EF664E2193BBEAE0748C9703"><enum>(1)</enum><text>designate a career Deputy Assistant Secretary for Community Partnerships; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id6CA040377248452284DA4B4057D49775"><enum>(2)</enum><text>assign or hire, as appropriate, permanent staff to the Office for Community Partnerships.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD8AF4FC4D5254F25B1741F3F6E8193C4"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Assistant Secretary for Community Partnerships shall be responsible for the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="idbaaa6a5f7bf545f1822665308374a3a4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Leading the efforts of the Department to counter violent extremism across all the components and offices of the Department that conduct strategic and supportive efforts to counter violent extremism. Such efforts shall include the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="id078630fc612f432c8006e56d69af6d2f"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Partnering with communities to address vulnerabilities that can be exploited by violent extremists in the United States and explore potential remedies for government and nongovernment institutions.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5f0e319c0d064f47bf0746d8f9f54b66"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Working with civil society groups and communities to counter violent extremist propaganda, messaging, or recruitment.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id19489e1982ae4505ab3f9c19e42888f7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>In coordination with the Office for Civil Rights and Civil Liberties of the Department, managing the outreach and engagement efforts of the Department directed toward communities at risk for radicalization and recruitment for violent extremist activities.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id22708c398ac94d50ba1edaeeaab379b2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Ensuring relevant information, research, and products inform efforts to counter violent extremism.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2a4947d6ba474a6fbc3c622540e27ea7"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Developing and maintaining Departmentwide plans, strategy guiding policies, and programs to counter violent extremism. Such plans shall, at a minimum, address each of the following:</text>
 <clause id="id39edddca50bc4aaea6358eac0020889b"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The Department’s plan to leverage new and existing Internet and other technologies and social media platforms to improve nongovernment efforts to counter violent extremism, as well as the best practices and lessons learned of other Federal, State, local, tribal, territorial, and foreign partners engaged in similar counter-messaging efforts.</text>
 </clause><clause id="idf34ffd3a30ae45bca385726a8bb8a443"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The Department’s countering violent extremism-related engagement efforts.</text> </clause><clause id="idd6b771fa65e74337a11b659694fe8bf1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The use of cooperative agreements with State, local, tribal, territorial, and other Federal departments and agencies responsible for efforts relating to countering violent extremism.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id710d20d6bb6f4b47b2a7be9ba7b3821c"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Coordinating with the Office for Civil Rights and Civil Liberties of the Department to ensure all of the activities of the Department related to countering violent extremism fully respect the privacy, civil rights, and civil liberties of all persons.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9646b8b5e2cb4237a6cb78680f4e54fd"><enum>(G)</enum><text>In coordination with the Under Secretary for Science and Technology and in consultation with the Under Secretary for Intelligence and Analysis, identifying and recommending new research and analysis requirements to ensure the dissemination of information and methods for Federal, State, local, tribal, and territorial countering violent extremism practitioners, officials, law enforcement, and nongovernmental partners to utilize such research and analysis.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfa5907046af947299b97228a8a78b8b6"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Assessing the methods used by violent extremists to disseminate propaganda and messaging to communities at risk for recruitment by violent extremists.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="iddf0a38b2dee54b189bbd89c74823372b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Developing a digital engagement strategy that expands the outreach efforts of the Department to counter violent extremist messaging by—</text>
 <subparagraph id="ida2a85fa20141445f97004f7de3fe0fbf"><enum>(A)</enum><text>exploring ways to utilize relevant Internet and other technologies and social media platforms; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id99c8468b5e2f4957943fc033dc7513c5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>maximizing other resources available to the Department.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ida1833d28b4b54139a49b56792fb358ea"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Serving as the primary representative of the Department in coordinating countering violent extremism efforts with other Federal departments and agencies and nongovernmental organizations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ide1b880cf0bd240ab9bb7237a1bf98973"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Serving as the primary Department-level representative in coordinating with the Department of State on international countering violent extremism issues.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idaa4e2d94c7a247e081e7bac46df5283d"><enum>(5)</enum><text>In coordination with the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, providing guidance regarding the use of grants made to State, local, and tribal governments under sections 2003 and 2004 under the allowable uses guidelines related to countering violent extremism.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id44c7bf029e2b4a3eaff8c265b9e60b51"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Developing a plan to expand philanthropic support for domestic efforts related to countering violent extremism, including by identifying viable community projects and needs for possible philanthropic support.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id3634F2634BFC4A848BCB929086D620CE"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Administering the assistance described in subsection (f).</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id9a7845bfc53b4a3ab6c47ac684b1a4a1"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Grants To counter violent extremism</header> <paragraph id="id084F70BAC9CF47D4AA8A85ED198A7207"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In accordance with this subsection, the Secretary may award grants or cooperative agreements directly to eligible recipients identified in paragraph (2) to support the efforts of local communities in the United States to counter violent extremism.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id607658d798904c0d96d09385342290a2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible recipients</header><text>The Secretary may award competitive grants or cooperative agreements based on need directly to—</text> <subparagraph id="id32eee536990b44128a5f706a1cbbae59"><enum>(A)</enum><text>States;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1ce19229652247e6a03047b949b3146f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>local governments;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9ae892019eb846d28cda27eb5a343981"><enum>(C)</enum><text>tribal governments;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7aebe8e0279d468f998c0afd877e5a7d"><enum>(D)</enum><text>nonprofit organizations; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2ae68e4406204727bdd890cbc401d61a"><enum>(E)</enum><text>institutions of higher education.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id4946a8efc012447e83b5a0e076eb71cf"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Use of Funds</header><text>Each entity receiving a grant or cooperative agreement under this subsection shall use the grant or cooperative agreement for one or more of the following purposes:</text>
 <subparagraph id="ide095b07e8cc54d1da5eaee17f4c7b1b9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>To train or exercise for countering violent extremism, including building training or exercise programs designed to improve cultural competency and to ensure that communities, government, and law enforcement receive accurate, intelligence-based information about the dynamics of radicalization to violence.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9576380530e145c5893f7713090c8cda"><enum>(B)</enum><text>To develop, implement, or expand programs or projects with communities to discuss violent extremism or to engage communities that may be targeted by violent extremist radicalization.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id97943cb42dcb451f9a78e66f4ea6c1c1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>To develop and implement projects that partner with local communities to prevent radicalization to violence.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6de0e0c7d1e74d5c9472a243dd0b934c"><enum>(D)</enum><text>To develop and implement a comprehensive model for preventing violent extremism in local communities, including existing initiatives of State or local law enforcement agencies and existing mechanisms for engaging the resources and expertise available from a range of social service providers, such as education administrators, mental health professionals, and religious leaders.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc995f197a78d45dab60d317f1dee74f2"><enum>(E)</enum><text>To educate the community about countering violent extremism, including the promotion of community-based activities to increase the measures taken by the community to counter violent extremism.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb3271b7ea5864d4aa7e8f0698a2667d5"><enum>(F)</enum><text>To develop or assist social service programs that address root causes of violent extremism and develop, build, or enhance alternatives for members of local communities that may be targeted by violent extremism.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2050665ca8614cceb89c064ee940fed0"><enum>(G)</enum><text>To develop or enhance State or local government initiatives that facilitate and build overall capacity to address the threats post by violent extremism.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfd12977d7ba842b5b931448b18eab50d"><enum>(H)</enum><text>To support such other activities, consistent with the purposes of this subsection, as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id69b90bce6dc54dda8b91fb13acb84435"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Grant guidelines</header>
 <subparagraph id="idC45B5F8EAEFE45479D7C3410BCEBD187"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For each fiscal year, before awarding a grant or cooperative agreement under this subsection, the Secretary shall develop guidelines published in a notice of funding opportunity that describe—</text>
 <clause id="idbdd797b919224d7394a0df8e0277d595"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the process for applying for grants and cooperative agreements under this subsection;</text> </clause><clause id="id7b58afe96de2491da7f913255daef320"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the criteria that the Secretary will use for selecting recipients based on the need demonstrated by the applicant; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idfc7902f086c04a3581ac29c46bf3c933"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the requirements that recipients must follow when utilizing funds under this subsection to conduct training and exercises and otherwise engage local communities regarding countering violent extremism.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2a849b6967fc450cb9682c435e09d1d9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In developing the requirements under subparagraph (A)(iii), the Secretary shall consider the following:</text>
 <clause id="id60F94BF2361945B08B4D2F4B16C84920"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Training objectives should be clearly defined to meet specific countering violent extremism goals, such as community engagement, cultural awareness, or community-based policing.</text>
 </clause><clause id="id59c5b3c74345467391a1c9d7a9d0b992"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Engaging diverse communities in the United States to counter violent extremism may require working with local grassroots community organizations to develop engagement and outreach initiatives.</text>
 </clause><clause id="id5a80d1308f344308a7eb85ee3e870df7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Training programs should—</text> <subclause id="id596b5160a87a4f1ea9b367cec1763a97"><enum>(I)</enum><text>be sensitive to constitutional values, such as protecting fundamental civil rights and civil liberties, and eschew notions of racial and ethnic profiling; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="ida7bae95bcea846e5867080262b4ea1fb"><enum>(II)</enum><text>adhere to the standards and ethics of the Department, ensuring that the clearly defined objectives are in line with the strategies of the Department to counter violent extremism.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="id939cd038114b4ab988b94368fda5d580"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Establishing vetting procedures for self-selected countering violent extremism training experts who offer programs that may claim to counter violent extremism, but serve to demonize certain individuals or whole cross sections of a community.</text>
 </clause><clause id="idf09928df8c044edc8cae01386bd666a0"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Providing a review process to determine if countering violent extremism training focuses on community engagement and outreach.</text>
 </clause><clause id="id4cd8b3d7c95d4c2faf35d85511fd19cc"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Providing support to law enforcement to enhance knowledge, skills, and abilities to increase engagement techniques with diverse communities in the United States.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id587b23a0b99346a5a624e125b349501b"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>Beginning in the first fiscal year beginning after the date of enactment of this section, and in each of the next 5 fiscal years, the Assistant Secretary of the Office for Community Partnerships shall submit to Congress an annual report on the Office for Community Partnerships, which shall include—</text>
 <paragraph id="idc8dd3750474341868d5371a3b821e38f"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a description of the status of the programs and policies of the Department for countering violent extremism in the United States;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id93fdeeba17584761a3c0214296416bff"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of the efforts of the Office for Community Partnerships to cooperate with and provide assistance to other Federal departments and agencies;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id4a2ccde6ee7e4cb697dfc0ce5485dba1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>qualitative and quantitative metrics for evaluating the success of such programs and policies and the steps taken to evaluate the success of such programs and policies; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id6058b4b2c0c9495f9c6ae6aa277ec5a2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>an accounting of—</text> <subparagraph id="idC1D3EF2FE7794543981F696A8B968052"><enum>(A)</enum><text>grants awarded by the Department to counter violent extremism; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idBB4C3D92C14A4B479B3ADEBA71B530F4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>all training specifically aimed at countering violent extremism sponsored by the Department.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="HB42496614ECF47BFA6C8D8484D6CC3BF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents in section 1(b) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/107/296">Public Law 107–296</external-xref>; 116 Stat. 2135) is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 103 the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB9333C48A60B4C95896084ACB030EDA9" style="OLC"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 104. Office for Community Partnerships.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


