<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S2273 IS: Strengthening Technical Assistance, Resources, and Training to Unleash the Potential of Veterans Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-11-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 2273</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151110">November 10, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSSB00">Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To require the Administrator of the Small Business Administration to establish an incubator and
			 accelerator grant program for veterans and members of the Armed Forces.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause">
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Strengthening Technical Assistance, Resources, and Training to Unleash the Potential of Veterans Act of 2015</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>STARTUP Vets Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </section><section id="id7E993EAC8A754A00B6EAE15AD62C1439"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text> <paragraph id="id81245cbe5ac94fdaa31c7a5fc845368f"><enum>(1)</enum><text>startups face common challenges as they seek to transform their ideas into successful, high-growth businesses;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id117fbb583fdf407d85badaacafb05f75"><enum>(2)</enum><text>incubators and accelerators are new models of growth that drive innovation by connecting entrepreneurial individuals and teams to create viable business ventures and social initiatives;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id798d3143655b49508f27addf509f4fff"><enum>(3)</enum><text>incubators and accelerators support promising start-ups through partnerships, mentoring, and resources connecting them with seasoned entrepreneurs;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id50cf1a1997fe4ff19b7c4cefa7cd44e3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the goal of an incubator or an accelerator is to help create and grow young businesses by providing them with necessary financial, technical, and industry support and financial and technical services; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id5a18cc14c99149b2aa3aa60ae5b6ca9f"><enum>(5)</enum><text>veterans and members of the Armed Forces can amplify the skills they have acquired through their service in the military through entrepreneurship.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="id2FD3FB7B17FE469F84E1AAB1209EEA14"><enum>3.</enum><header>Incubator and accelerator grant program</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 32 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/657b">15 U.S.C. 657b</external-xref>) is amended by striking subsection (f) and inserting the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id089F88E4C19F4123AA062097587D20E4" style="OLC">
				<subsection id="idD3746B53275341C0B479A969B8262E02"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Incubator and accelerator grant program</header>
 <paragraph id="id445BE38B6CDB47309C26DB21AB2091EA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection—</text> <subparagraph id="idE8655CEC641843A1A9375535998E4D35"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the term <term>accelerator</term> means an organization that—</text>
 <clause id="idEC204B173A804161AFE1BFF8BB43AF69"><enum>(i)</enum><text>frequently provides, but is not exclusively designed to provide, seed investment in exchange for a small amount of equity;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id43905CBC95D6470AA4F95EBA68887631"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>works with a startup for predetermined amount of time; or</text> </clause><clause id="idCCA263AD96444F44BC29779EF45C0A13"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>offers startups capital and mentorship to scale businesses;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5297D67C68D54C7C946F0EFF90776DCC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the term <term>covered individual</term> means—</text> <clause id="id4aa51e36-5997-4929-8505-47652a71f6da"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a member of the Armed Forces, without regard to whether the member is participating in the Transition Assistance Program of the Department of Defense;</text>
 </clause><clause id="ida2c9e88b-e742-43e0-a4dc-6bcb138ecf92"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an individual who is participating in the Transition Assistance Program of the Department of Defense;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id24227300-cb55-49ca-8f23-501e467f2986"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an individual who—</text> <subclause id="id25d32115-3458-414e-be39-dd00429794c0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>served on active duty in any branch of the Armed Forces, including the National Guard and Reserves; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idad23d4bf-ba24-4535-9618-2a71c595fb54"><enum>(II)</enum><text>was discharged or released from such service under conditions other than dishonorable; and</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="id7af63698-38f0-4abd-a1e4-6f86c0131414"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a spouse or dependent of an individual described in clause (i), (ii), or (iii);</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF35B1D53AB964602BCE787B02B2BB8E0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the term <term>eligible grantee</term> means an incubator or accelerator that—</text> <clause id="idB2D36A9649114B2D94C42D6AEB29FB13"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has a physical space, and not necessarily exclusive use of physical space, in which veterans may come together to work on business ideas; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idDCDDAE2CD0364D778ECB7EDE9DC656D7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has been operational for not less than 1 year before receiving a grant under the program;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7ED29BDEC40D4195BF3524D49F44E7C7"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the term <term>incubator</term> means an organization that is designed to accelerate the growth and success of businesses through a variety of business support resources and services, including physical space, capital, coaching, common services, and networking connections; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id35F647C8226840ABA66C4AECF7D8D0E3"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the term <term>program</term> means the grant program established under paragraph (2)(A).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id904CB14A0F0E41E3A7035705BAE718E6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Establishment</header> <subparagraph id="idF2D9E398D23C4C2FA3AD38B2A9637EC8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this subsection, the Administrator shall establish a grant program under which the Administrator shall make grants to eligible grantees to create and operate incubators and accelerators that provide technical assistance and training to covered individuals on how to become successful entrepreneurs and form small business concerns.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id37D95DD1FBA0426AB70FB69698FF5B4B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Goals</header><text>The goals of the program are—</text> <clause id="idC025950419C64224AB86183E56519058"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to enable covered individuals to effectively transfer relevant skills to launch and accelerate small business concerns owned and controlled by covered individuals; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id18FD9BD0BD134B13A4F6BFFEC0768200"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to create an avenue for high-performing covered individuals to meet and collaborate on business ideas.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id75E81B41140346CC8043069827FE6011"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Designation as a technical assistance program</header><text>The program shall be considered a management and technical assistance training program of the Administration.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id571DDDEB144B466AA7933AEFC7EF53F9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Application</header>
 <subparagraph id="id4C2348CC09DF46D4B4A1916524DFB9AF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An eligible grantee desiring to receive a grant under the program shall submit an application to the Administrator at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Administrator may require.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD173BADFA2794E97A59C69196421BC40"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text>Before making an award to an eligible grantee under the program, the Administrator or a designee of the Administrator shall conduct a site visit or evaluate a video submission of the eligible grantee.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5104916CDDCD4005AE6ADE5900F4D67E"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Preference</header><text>In awarding grants under the program, the Administrator shall give a preference to an eligible grantee that operates a veterans-focused incubator or accelerator within the eligible grantee as of the date on which the eligible grantee submits an application under subparagraph (A).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idBD7CD7F184E24B5990C9EB4FF0335A5C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>Each eligible grantee that is awarded a grant under the program shall operate and, if necessary, create, within the eligible grantee—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idAF94BD82CE5242039E3A2ED4C63A35F4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an incubator or accelerator focused on assisting covered individuals; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC4E43941CB0B487F8798C4A8D1AA9B9F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an incubator or accelerator that assists all types of entrepreneurs, which shall provide targeted activities, curriculum, events, and mentorship tailored to covered individuals.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id29B553D821C54248B480EF59DFB30C91"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>Each eligible grantee awarded a grant under the program shall—</text> <subparagraph id="id9F99926D59B144BDA469246E5BEDABC0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>establish and use a competitive process, if such a process has not been established, for selecting covered individuals to participate in the incubator or accelerator, as applicable;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id224B85CF143B49AD96A3D3D0092BD48D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>create a forum for high-performing covered individuals to meet and collaborate;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0FE6B667D83746F09B2DBE5394D4C309"><enum>(C)</enum><text>designate a full-time executive director or program manager, if such a director or manager has not been designated, to manage the incubator or accelerator, as applicable;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idEDB5117A42414977B847FB97158230DD"><enum>(D)</enum><text>provide training and education, including curriculum on entrepreneurship, to meet the needs of covered individuals to enable them to translate skills from their military service to entrepreneurship;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idAB35211A61454E1AB992775A86AF45DB"><enum>(E)</enum><text>provide mentoring to covered individuals who are entrepreneurs, which shall consist of experienced and successful entrepreneurs providing advice and guidance to covered individuals who have had similar experiences; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF2357602420B479FA8842BB347B6D144"><enum>(F)</enum><text>connect covered individuals with investors who are looking to support covered individuals as entrepreneurs.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idf7ecdb21cb3f4e7799290cc8f75f641d"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Availability to Veterans Affairs</header><text>In consultation with the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, the Associate Administrator shall make available outreach materials regarding the program for distribution and display at local facilities of the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="id22995A7C394D4ADC8497856C6EFA8F2C"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Duration of grant</header>
 <text>A grant awarded under the program—</text> <subparagraph id="idC86E0BB10A8248D8900D41A252A2DA79"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall be for a period of not more than 2 years; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id505ACF6FDF0B42C8AA623532355777BD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may be renewed for additional 2-year periods in accordance with paragraph (8).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id46776A71633E4F4CAC88D80E74029D76"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Renewal of grant</header><text>In renewing a grant under the program, the Administrator—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id5B41FE81C3B54126BBFDE6EE7BF6C5CC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall consider the results of the most recent annual evaluation of the eligible grantee under paragraph (9); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idCD14F3A210014523A05B6B6C74044189"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may withhold a grant if the Administrator determines that the eligible grantee failed to provide the Administrator with information necessary to complete an annual evaluation of the eligible grantee under paragraph (9).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5B063C3D9A304DC299A50952B47F967D"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Annual evaluations</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the Administrator awards a grant to an eligible grantee under the program, and every year thereafter in which the eligible grantee is awarded a grant under the program, the Administrator shall conduct an evaluation of and issue a report on the eligible grantee, which shall include—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id7784FD980A7D4B29A5593F99A025C4CF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the total number of covered individuals served by the eligible grantee; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idCCA6F604F1D24E11A4FE802FF1D0F3C7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the total number of startups assisted by the eligible grantee.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id23c4647b553a40359a25fba48ea70fa7"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Annual report</header>
 <subparagraph id="idD98AC6CD8E354CA794364A8953EBA959"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date on which the Administrator establishes the program, and every year thereafter, the Associate Administrator shall submit to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship of the Senate and the Committee on Small Business of the House of Representatives a report on the performance and effectiveness of the program, which shall include—</text>
 <clause id="id215A3C205680441DBE3C5FF2982285E8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the total number of covered individuals served by each eligible grantee awarded a grant under the program;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id099BD4920D4F4F21839AE6E1A5E382DC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to the extent possible—</text> <subclause id="idFF80F1191F2D4BF794E3C7741CD532E3"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the demographics of covered individuals assisted under the program, to include gender, age, race, relationship to military, Military Occupational Code, and years of service of covered individuals;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id62108A088FCC414D944800738C4167FE"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the number of startups launched or expanded with assistance provided under the program; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="idF4C08594A6F44C548CC2FEE09F45EC6F"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the number of jobs created with assistance provided under the program;</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="idAFFD1D88C33B48BA851E15E02808779C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>results of participant satisfaction surveys, including a summary of any comments from covered individuals assisted under the program; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idD1472E19D8F442DAB6F50126F6E0ADB3"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>an evaluation of the effectiveness of the program in each region of the Administration during the most recent fiscal year.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idEBE734C072DB4CB997B38C510C48C313"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>For each of fiscal years 2016 through 2020, the Administration shall use not more than $1,000,000 from amounts made available to the Office of Veterans Business Development to carry out the program.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


