<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1353 IS: Ensuring Access to Justice for Claims Against the United States Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1353</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150514">May 14, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S318">Mr. Wicker</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S057">Mr. Leahy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S287">Mr. Cornyn</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S314">Mr. Tester</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To ensure appropriate judicial review of Federal Government actions by amending the prohibition on
			 the exercise of jurisdiction by the United States Court of Federal Claims
			 of certain claims pending in other courts.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HE645EBD8E62F41628AF8508D35CF7CD0" style="OLC">
 <section id="H5CA83C7B8C264FF29DC5223D5B33EB10" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Ensuring Access to Justice for Claims Against the United States Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HA4F67EC7DF3947068778E596B8FB4525" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Jurisdiction of United States Court of Federal Claims</header> <subsection id="H786DCD7765D04B20A2F227CCA9E9D50E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Amendments to title 28, United States Code</header> <paragraph id="H5C450EF29EE249E2BBD7D08496770F2C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1500 of title 28, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H22FF2DE0AF0441EEBC6B1447FA92DB15" style="USC">
						<section id="H0DAD4850B3C245D2B0B154B311A626FD"><enum>1500.</enum><header>Presumption of stay</header>
 <subsection id="H46A9F17437314C10A08952E6D20D96B0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text> <paragraph id="H96D5FA8D00AE4853A7C15C0E34F0F74F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>court</term> means any of the courts described in section 610; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFC7F7854A2494B639A0B4EA7A82D9A7A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>Court of Federal Claims</term> means the United States Court of Federal Claims.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC1D01C57E1FB402B85537629C8452A4A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Presumption of stay</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (d), if a civil action is pending in, or on appeal from, the Court of Federal Claims, and the plaintiff or assignee of the plaintiff also has pending in any other court a civil action that includes a claim against the United States or an agency or officer of the United States arising from substantially the same set of operative facts, the court presiding over the action that was filed later shall stay the action, in whole or in part, until the action that was filed first is no longer pending.</text>
							</subsection><subsection id="HA8CFDD8CAD9E440C8F61510D666BFD01"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Determining first-Filed action</header>
 <paragraph id="HF696F3C1290946D6B9AB1F5625EC1D87"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appeals</header><text>For purposes of subsection (b), the date of filing for a civil action that is pending on appeal from the Court of Federal Claims is the date on which the action was filed in the Court of Federal Claims.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB21F430853324DC88FF03245F082C25A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Actions or appeals filed on same day</header><text>For purposes of subsection (b), if the actions described in subsection (b) were filed on the same day, without regard to the time of day, the action that is pending in, or on appeal from, the Court of Federal Claims shall be treated as having been filed first.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2ED6B2EF27AC4E84A4430D483556AB9C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>The requirement to stay an action under subsection (b) shall not apply if—</text> <paragraph id="HACE752EA61B542BE9847D859F7344EFD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the parties in each of the actions that include a claim based on substantially the same set of operative facts otherwise agree; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBD3269C3E9F14719AC23071613A904FF"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in exceptional circumstances the court finds, upon the motion of any party, that termination or modification of the stay is necessary to preserve material evidence or to prevent irreparable prejudice to that party.</text>
								</paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">The United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit shall have jurisdiction of an appeal
			 from an interlocutory order terminating or modifying a stay pursuant to
			 paragraph (2).</continuation-text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4954DE306357429BAE2A0805F5B406BE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/91">chapter 91</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code, is amended by striking the item relating to section 1500 and inserting the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAB9F3785E44B4D43ACB2F9A3154D9C98" style="OLC"><toc><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">1500. Presumption of stay.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBEDC038E1F1B4818AE554CA8A252648F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicability</header>
 <paragraph id="H5E2E8043B22F49A4AB4693228D798BB1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1500 of title 28, United States Code, as amended by subsection (a), shall apply to any action pending on, or filed on or after, the date of the enactment of this Act, but does not apply in a case in which the action filed later (as determined in accordance with such section, as so amended) is pending (on such date of enactment) in a court of appeals of the United States or the Supreme Court of the United States, or in a case in which a judgment has been entered as of such date of enactment but for which the time to file an appeal has not expired.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFFD104DAA5884C4390FDF3314850C953"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Previous jurisdictional bar</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any claim in an action pending on the date of the enactment of this Act either in a court of appeals of the United States or the Supreme Court of the United States, or for which the time to file an appeal has not expired, shall not be subject to the jurisdictional bar under section 1500 of title 28, United States Code, as in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


