<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1186 IS: Move America Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1186</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150504">May 4, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S344">Mr. Hoeven</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for Move America bonds and to allow such
			 bonds to be converted into tax credits to support public-private
			 partnerships.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body>
 <section id="idD6BE7FE846A84124892AA9B0840A6F43" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Move America Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="id470AC2F6A97A4A1D9D6D9F4537C88D02"><enum>2.</enum><header>Move America Bond</header> <subsection id="id23C244AD6F054FA292D2C48E6F13BF12"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header> <paragraph id="idB3AAEBFFBCBD4BA28665F9B4FA50B454"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Move America bonds</header><text>Subpart A of part IV of subchapter B of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting after section 142 the following new section:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6D3519FDBC30486385A183D98FE45E43" style="OLC">
						<section id="idAB50C29D2C5C4109A84B01CCB12660F3"><enum>142A.</enum><header>Move America bonds</header>
							<subsection id="id04F5560E117148F5AB5A9E631588609A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header>
 <paragraph id="idE46983CD2F2A4A2FAA30C349250D7A31"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Treatment as exempt facility bond</header><text>Except as otherwise provided in this section, a Move America bond shall be treated for purposes of this part as an exempt facility bond.</text>
								</paragraph><paragraph id="idD1A8E5DB4845493BBA04F7336C20E592"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exceptions</header>
 <subparagraph id="idCB43D236FF4E449CA4009355A380DB77"><enum>(A)</enum><header>No government ownership requirement</header><text>Paragraph (1) of section 142(b) shall not apply to any Move America bond.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA48E632D1C9049B2938AB5C7C02F9F31"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Special rules for high-speed rail bonds</header><text>Paragraphs (2) and (3) of section 142(i) shall not apply to any Move America bond described in subsection (b)(4).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idEB773AE37539449FBC3B90C0DD4B418C"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Special rules for highway and surface transportation facilities</header><text>Paragraphs (2), (3), and (4) of section 142(m) shall not apply to any Move America bond described in subsection (b)(5).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id49C53CF51720496DBE42B25AAAC795E8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Move America bond</header><text>For purposes of this part, the term <term>Move America bond</term> means any bond issued as part of an issue 95 percent or more of the net proceeds of which are used to provide—</text>
 <paragraph id="id574DEB340E8648B6A666CF7FF8496F2C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>airports,</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id296CD13D0BF948B496FE46F3F0B29CC8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>docks and wharves, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idE3BCC2EABCDA46BABD1915CBFFDA1C35"><enum>(A)</enum><text>waterborne mooring infrastructure,</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF377562B46A3422EB22C010172BAE4FE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>dredging in connection with a dock or wharf, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB07AC86CFC2F4176AA3AE4974857A2EE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any associated rail and road infrastructure for the purpose of integrating modes of transportation,</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idB89FAF07DA594ACD9FA91FB1C70644C2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>mass commuting facilities,</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id1CFA43666D984568B78BE16EE43702EC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>railroads (as defined in section 20102 of title 49, United States Code) and any associated rail and road infrastructure for the purpose of integrating modes of transportation,</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id9B967E2835204CA19F418D36C82694B8"><enum>(5)</enum><text>any—</text> <subparagraph id="ide6ab259559004f5aaf7541b3fea56d7b"><enum>(A)</enum><text>surface transportation project which is eligible for Federal assistance under title 23, United States Code (as in effect on the date of the enactment of this section),</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb3533238805a469880b98ea055a7cb0c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>project for an international bridge or tunnel for which an international entity authorized under Federal or State law is responsible and which is eligible Federal assistance under title 23, United States Code (as so in effect), or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida49676f20faf412e9db73cbca97e5f72"><enum>(C)</enum><text>facility for the transfer of freight from truck to rail or rail to truck (including any temporary storage facilities directly related to such transfers) which is eligible for Federal assistance under either title 23 or title 49, United States Code (as so in effect),</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idb1ff42788cba4aa8b4ac5189f4e87f4e"><enum>(6)</enum><text>flood diversions, or</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id51BD88546C8049A09405B5CDDED6202D"><enum>(7)</enum><text>inland waterways, including construction and rehabilitation expenditures for navigation on any inland or intracoastal waterways of the United States (within the meaning of section 4042(d)(2)).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="idE18FEAB1656B4DA9940D59AD53306B84"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Flood diversions</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>flood diversion</term> means any flood damage risk reduction project authorized under any Act for authorizing water resources development projects.</text>
							</subsection><subsection id="id1AD99E2825764623A120547F2979B09A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Move America volume cap</header>
 <paragraph id="id837C50017CC745B4ABB6980239E49B73"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The aggregate face amount of Move America bonds issued pursuant to an issue, when added to the aggregate face amount of Move America bonds previously issued by the issuing authority during the calendar year, shall not exceed such issuing authority's Move America volume cap for such year.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id6D82264082EC4F6D8778725639CBFD08"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Move America volume cap</header><text>For purposes of this subsection—</text> <subparagraph id="id7AE02EC5D77D4B68BF3E5AE072CD2F22"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Move America volume cap shall be 50 percent of the State ceiling under section 146(d) for such State for such year.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idBECAB75270394DA5BDB34B58E9A73C81"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Allocation of volume cap</header><text>Each State may allocate the Move America volume cap of such State among governmental units (or other authorities) in such State having authority to issue private activity bonds.</text>
									</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idE1F9914B3548438D96718FE4AE71D9E1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Carryforwards</header>
 <subparagraph id="id83AA3E6F536A4693853488C583C6C3AE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If—</text> <clause id="idC42E0660F3AD483A88CC94A02256DA21"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an issuing authority's Move America volume cap, exceeds</text>
 </clause><clause id="id42ACB6242F6A49E497D5237107F2B7F6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the aggregate amount of Move America bonds issued during such calendar year by such authority,</text> </clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">any Move America bond issued by such authority during the 3-calendar-year period following such calendar year shall not be taken into account under paragraph (1) to the extent the amount of such bonds does not exceed the amount of such excess. Any excesses arising under this paragraph shall be used under this paragraph in the order of calendar years in which the excesses arose.</continuation-text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id59D6F3FBB408468D99689BEB64674532"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Reallocation of unused carryforwards</header> <clause id="id00359DF20AE94C089120632D7B68B1C6"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Move America volume cap under paragraph (2)(A) for any State for any calendar year shall be increased by any amount allocated to such State by the Secretary under clause (ii).</text>
 </clause><clause id="id6C2F50BA573F4B2387BD450D10BD2BA5"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Reallocation</header><text>The Secretary shall allocate to each qualified State for any calendar year an amount which bears the same ratio to the aggregate unused carryforward amounts of all issuing authorities in all States for such calendar year as the qualified State's population for the calendar year bears to the population of all qualified States for the calendar year. For purposes of the preceding sentence, population shall be determined in accordance with section 146(j).</text>
 </clause><clause id="id421d4ca726df4a8e82b68ae8e8eb2d7e"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Qualified State</header><text>For purposes of this subparagraph, the term <term>qualified State</term> means, with respect to a calendar year, any State—</text> <subclause id="id7b21546146b64c309a060dc10d20930a"><enum>(I)</enum><text>which allocated its entire Move America volume cap for the preceding calendar year, and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id0ab67a98b0e244c8904af7e3f155c2ae"><enum>(II)</enum><text>for which a request is made (not later than May 1 of the calendar year) to receive an allocation under clause (ii).</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="idECE10253D41E489C9917C6714F834CAB"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Unused carryforward amount</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>unused carryforward amount</term> means, with respect to any issuing authority for any calendar year, the excess of—</text> <subclause id="id8E7F1B33FEB4457C9D36DEC934BF3496"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the amount of the excess described in subparagraph (A) for the fourth preceding calendar year, over</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idD99E7E3CB5544FCD84A6F43E38BF61B1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the amount of bonds issued by such issuing authority to which subparagraph (A) applied during the 3 preceding calendar years.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idF2CEFCCD46924FC992F72204090A1B82"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Applicability of certain federal laws</header><text>An issue shall not be treated as an issue under subsection (b) unless the facility for which the proceeds of such issue are used would be subject to the requirements of any Federal law (including titles 23, 40, and 49 of the United States Code) which would otherwise apply to similar projects.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id467D016019234B0B94509FE560397142"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Special rule for environmental remediation costs for docks and wharves</header><text>For purposes of this section, amounts used for working capital expenditures relating to environmental remediation required under State or Federal law at or near a facility described in subsection (b)(2) (including environmental remediation in the riverbed and land within or adjacent to the Federal navigation channel used to access such facility) shall be treated as an amount used to provide for such a facility.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id2D06891F100E402791011DEA25E510D8"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this section, including regulations requiring States to report the amount of Move America volume cap of the State carried forward for any calendar year under subsection (d)(3).</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id3B9DD90F6B2E4BF6BDAD782B4AFE239E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>The table of sections for subpart A of part IV of subchapter B of chapter 1 of such Code is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 142 the following new item:</text>
					<quoted-block id="id67725734-086a-419a-b8d2-e48df5f88eb1" style="OLC"><toc><toc-entry idref="idAB50C29D2C5C4109A84B01CCB12660F3" level="section">Sec. 142A. Move America bonds.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idB9D53289701D4C59A0897B5069988D45"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application of other private activity bond rules</header>
 <paragraph id="id82445267445241F6B1A2EE1959EEF875"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Treatment under private activity bond volume cap</header><text>Subsection (g) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/146">section 146</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of paragraph (3), by striking the period at the end of paragraph (4) and inserting <quote>, and</quote>, and by inserting after paragraph (4) the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id353A5A4E88894DBC93AD36A7B9DC7638" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="idAD67B4B7E14C44D294602F5C4B8A3284"><enum>(5)</enum><text>any Move America bond.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idCB5CE43513324F42AA7D15435334D3B5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rule for facilities located outside the State</header><text>Paragraph (2) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/146">section 146(k)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting <quote>or to any Move America bond</quote> after <quote>section 142(a)</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id7EA34659EBA041A6ABF2F7AC394F034C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Special rule on use for land acquisition</header><text>Subparagraph (A) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/147">section 147(c)(1)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting <quote>(50 percent in the case of any issue of Move America bonds)</quote> after <quote>25 percent</quote>.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="idF4C4470AA8554BED84E665584D18FBAB"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Special rules for rehabilitation expenditures</header>
 <subparagraph id="id1ADDA25D9C1B42088D579319F7FE9142"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Inclusion of certain expenditures</header><text>Subparagraph (B) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/147">section 147(d)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting <quote>, except that, in the case of any Move America bond, such term shall include any expenditure described in clause (iii) or (v) thereof</quote> before the period at the end.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD92403DDE9CB4F20A0739DE47E79741B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Period for expenditures</header><text>Subparagraph (C) of section 147(d)(3) of such Code is amended by inserting <quote>(5 years, in the case of any Move America bond)</quote> after <quote>2 years</quote>.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idBAFE3ADD688547EDB4CA9D50D64E281E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Treatment under the alternative minimum tax</header><text>Subparagraph (C) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/57">section 57(a)(5)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new clause:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id11DFC328CEAF4A3BA920C9DC90B4CE21" style="OLC">
 <clause id="idD3A6744DF7E744D09B08951EEC9B918B"><enum>(vii)</enum><header>Exception for Move America bonds</header><text>For purposes of clause (i), the term <term>private activity bond</term> shall not include any Move America bond (as defined in section 142A).</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="idB4B15B45CD1740E9A5B9754A6966B405"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to obligations issued in calendar years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="idC222A11C84584389A247930C29867D37"><enum>3.</enum><header>Move America tax credits</header>
 <subsection id="idD2C3DC495F064DD092C2FB311ED00B4A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subpart B of part IV of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idCDA5B1CF66B3439EBAB1A66E70B2F6E4" style="OLC">
					<section id="idB81E62D6485B46B7A6CFAA0D52FBA873"><enum>30E.</enum><header>Move America credit</header>
 <subsection id="idFEC01255F75D4E05ACE6592BE63B304B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Allowance of credit</header><text>In the case of a Move America credit certificate purchased by the taxpayer, there shall be allowed as a credit against the tax imposed by this chapter for any taxable year in the credit period an amount equal to 10 percent of the value of such certificate.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idC6AF5EE63E1B4E2CBF32B08CE4D72682"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Credit period</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>credit period</term> means, with respect to any Move America credit certificate, the period of 10 taxable years beginning with the first taxable year that begins in the calendar year in which the qualified project to which such certificate relates is placed in service.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idB10349CE37FD4332903FE2A0F38407CB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Move America credit certificate</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text> <paragraph id="id1DDE0860E9CD4612BAC219787DB620B0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Move America credit certificate</header><text>The term <term>Move America credit certificate</term> means any certificate that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idCB5D795DE0034D7E8E08B9726DFB3FCC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is sold to the taxpayer under a qualified Move America credit program by a State or by a project sponsor to whom the State has allocated such certificate for sale under paragraph (2)(B)(ii)(I),</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idEBA209C8D19A4062BF07EED4A84E7D5B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is designated by the State as relating to a qualified project,</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id366E2278058F434D9DAFBEFAD4CE6D9E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the proceeds of the sale of which are used to finance the qualified project designated under subparagraph (B),</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id96BC7856FFA5408893072F5CF60985D2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>specifies—</text> <clause id="idEC6EC360F94C479198364EF67F2BCD3E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the value of the certificate and the purchase price, and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idCC5D0BD9400B4726A9DF8B66170BB96F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the qualified project to which it relates,</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id25ce6e7f46bb4be79f22ff755367ff93"><enum>(E)</enum><text>is sold no later than the end of the calendar year in which the project is placed in service, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id804FEE39C64D48578633709412AB594D"><enum>(F)</enum><text>is in such form as the Secretary may prescribe.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idCCB2C7DD7C494008943FD35E1E34A641"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualified Move America credit program</header> <subparagraph id="idFF8469FD4F3C42A4B6700D4079A31493"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>qualified Move America credit program</term> means any program—</text>
 <clause id="idA2189F572B174656877932AFBDB77E40"><enum>(i)</enum><text>which is established by a State for any calendar year for which it is authorized to issue Move America bonds (as defined in section 145A),</text>
 </clause><clause id="idEE48D98001C44962A440B248DF45BB36"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>under which the State exchanges (in such manner as the Secretary may prescribe) an amount of the Move America bonds (as so defined) which it may otherwise issue during such calendar year for the ability to sell Move America credit certificates, and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id7E8421B643BB488CAA38840EFDA90A7F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>under which the State is obligated to repay to the Secretary an amount equal to the recapture amount, if applicable, with respect to any Move America credit certificate.</text>
									</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9B7D629521EA4115BE5606D77F81C66F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Allocation of certificates to project sponsors</header>
 <clause id="id2B62ECD18CEE4734B768D4E929CAA14D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A State that has established a qualified Move America credit program under subparagraph (A) may allocate any Move America credit certificate that is eligible to be sold by such State to the project sponsor of the qualified project to which such certificate relates.</text>
 </clause><clause id="id82576DDE51A24AF883FEEC7EAF3B5DE1"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Sale or use</header><text>A project sponsor to whom any Move America certificate is allocated under clause (i) may—</text> <subclause id="id814003E8A235428E877DB4B8306B77F7"><enum>(I)</enum><text>sell such certificate, or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id0B9CE92A8A1549E38843626FCAEBA487"><enum>(II)</enum><text>claim the credit under this section with respect to such certificate as if the project sponsor had purchased the certificate from the State.</text>
										</subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id81CC627F95AA41C4A9B536C85B3B2732"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Value</header>
 <subparagraph id="id16D325086B914D959888D877598AA810"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The aggregate value of the Move America credit certificates sold or allocated by a State in a calendar year shall equal 25 percent of the value of Move America bonds exchanged by the State under paragraph (2)(A)(ii).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id852A37F1052045779E9D4C2CEF24D939"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitation relating to qualified project cost</header><text>The aggregate value of the Move America credit certificates sold or allocated by a State and designated by the State as relating to any qualified project shall not exceed the lesser of—</text>
 <clause id="id64AE5E9771FF4B17B8FE33C5AA54B784"><enum>(i)</enum><text>20 percent of the estimated cost of the project, or</text> </clause><clause id="idA5ADF5F771AB4480B1A62DEB32B784E2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>50 percent of the total amount of private equity invested in the project.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id923F15A49DC34C4ABFAADC0B4C0841C3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Certificate nontransferable</header><text>A Move America credit certificate, once purchased from a State or a project sponsor to whom the State has allocated such certificate for sale under paragraph (2)(B)(ii)(I), may not be sold or transferred to any other person.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idDC307D88DBF540FF8EF73D671E4DCF37"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions and special rules</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text> <paragraph id="idE0D336FC213347E1B49F3867F47855D8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Qualified project</header><text>The term <term>qualified project</term> means a project which—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id20D0F03A4BBA4512ACE26A49BF536AD1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>would be subject to the same requirements of any Federal law (including titles 23, 40, and 49 of the United States Code) which would otherwise apply to similar projects, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idABA2C61DA3C14323AA803A2DFBF7DB70"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is for the construction of a facility described in section 142A(b), but only if such project, upon completion, will be generally available for public use.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idCF77211E9C9445549501AD32CBCAEC2B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Recapture amount</header>
 <subparagraph id="id263382C2F74B418DBA6D5D6384DFE0CD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of any Move America credit certificate, if the project to which the certificate is designated under subsection (c)(1)(B) as relating—</text>
 <clause id="id7F5D7893587646F280F609BFCA3F0982"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is never placed in service, or</text> </clause><clause id="id9D1009B8572543F98E1C25D93C784A92"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ceases to be a qualified project at any time during the credit period,</text>
 </clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">the recapture amount is the amount determined under subparagraph (B).</continuation-text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id26599734CD224886A48626212C2975B7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Amount determined</header><text>The amount determined under this subparagraph is—</text> <clause id="id88AFB53E290545578C8D9EAFB677534C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the case of a project to which subparagraph (A)(i) applies, the value of the Move America credit certificate, and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id48A99D51538F44AE856C8F8784239B88"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case of a project to which subparagraph (A)(ii) applies, the product of—</text> <subclause id="id5F946641E7284CA9AB34988DDACEA799"><enum>(I)</enum><text>an amount equal to 10 percent of the value of the Move America credit certificate, and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id1624869718624F30A713D13AB4E8BD46"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the number of calendar years in the credit period beginning with the calendar year in which the project ceases to be a qualified project.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idF75E9A240E004B0CB1B7384CA2A3A4D9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Special rule for projects not placed in service</header><text>For purposes of subsection (a), if the project to which a Move America credit certificate is designated under subsection (c)(1)(B) as relating is never placed in service, the first taxable year that begins in the calendar year in which the State certifies (at such time and in such manner as may be prescribed by the Secretary) that the project will not be placed in service shall be treated as the year in which the project was placed in service.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idB7000E94999D4712899F2DF065E927B9"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Application with other credits</header>
 <paragraph id="idABFE5D0AFE6E4D6DA7887E83035C99A0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Business credit treated as part of general business credit</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the credit which would be allowed under subsection (a) for any taxable year (determined without regard to this subsection) shall be treated as a credit listed in section 38(b) for such taxable year (and not allowed under subsection (a)).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id5E1E5CC2D45C456DA2B660F2730754EC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Personal credit</header><text>For purposes of this title, in the case of an individual, the credit allowed under subsection (a) for any taxable year shall be treated as a credit allowable under subpart A for such taxable year.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="id89B037FBB5BA489E976D5C0A2EBC7D88"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Credit made part of general business credit</header><text>Subsection (b) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/38">section 38</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended—</text> <paragraph id="id4E2D12076FA34211851CFBB92DF5DA10"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>plus</quote> at the end of paragraph (35),</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id96DC2D357FC843ECA21F4116174BCE2A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end of paragraph (36) and inserting <quote>, plus</quote>, and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idD48B19BA5E9D409F988BE17E3E316852"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
					<quoted-block act-name="" id="id2457CB7C72554FE6B2A61AC6E53D5424" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="idCABA3A7F4FC94341B3DACADB303362BD"><enum>(37)</enum><text>the portion of the Move America credit to which section 30E(e)(1) applies.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0E6EA89B4AE642059478783144BF3AED"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for subpart B of part IV of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block id="id9051a38d-0fc3-4efb-8c21-1599dc94e7ab" style="OLC"><toc><toc-entry idref="idB81E62D6485B46B7A6CFAA0D52FBA873" level="section">Sec. 30E. Move America credit.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="id6BD0856DB9C84539A4B3F91A4FB1D0FE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id221B236F06414EEA8F0B48F20970D4C4"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text>A State that sells any Move America credit certificate shall report, at such time and in such manner as the Secretary of the Treasury shall require—</text>
 <paragraph id="idBACFAB9EBE104FA1BAC94345F08F355F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to the Secretary of the Treasury—</text> <subparagraph id="id8A496CF49E3C4759A7458F89A0814748"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the value of the Move America bonds otherwise allowed to be issued by the State which are exchanged under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/30E">section 30E(c)(2)(A)(ii)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 for the ability to sell such Move America credit certificates, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id071A7674EA0E4B5B80C61E61C5F3BD8F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of Move America credit certificates sold by the State or allocated to project sponsors, the value of each such certificate, and to whom it was sold (including the name of the purchaser and any other identifying information as the Secretary of the Treasury shall require), and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0F4979CB5FD24141B91A50B958DC013B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to the Secretary of the Treasury and the purchaser of any Move America credit certificate—</text> <subparagraph id="id64586CBDE1484796BFEE287794910167"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the placed in service date of the qualified project to which the certificate is designated under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/30E">section 30E(c)(1)(B)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 as relating, or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3D3F1968CB8840489A2A0DDE9E115F7A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that the State has made a certification under section 30E(d)(3) of such Code that such project will not be placed in service.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><continuation-text commented="no" continuation-text-level="subsection">For purposes of this subsection, any term used in this subsection that is also used in section 30E
			 or 142A of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 has the same meaning as when
			 used in such section.</continuation-text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


