<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1310 IS: Deficit Reduction Through Fair Oil Royalties Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1310</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150512">May 12, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To prohibit the Secretary of the Interior from issuing new oil or natural gas production leases in
			 the Gulf of Mexico under the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act to a person
			 that does not renegotiate its existing leases in order to require royalty
			 payments if oil and natural gas prices are greater than or equal to
			 specified price thresholds, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H2CDDD75831CD49129A67437B61F55AD6" style="OLC">
		<section id="H9C3535DBBBCB4AF7B650D6260D3B5031" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short
 title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Deficit Reduction Through Fair Oil Royalties Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="H9A598A9F425E4586A1284366899A6749"><enum>2.</enum><header>Eligibility for
			 new leases and the transfer of leases</header>
 <subsection id="H67AEE34AC52840BCABAEC6F5A89A64AE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HC1D62EECD2E04AE39442A4B4E4E79815"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered lease</header><text>The term <term>covered lease</term> means a lease for oil or gas production in the Gulf of Mexico that is—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HFDDBA0A70E6B446CA2CCCF01D5986AB0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in existence on the date of enactment of this Act;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1040D0527BB746C08C6AF2C8A143D00E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>issued by the Secretary under section 304 of the Outer Continental Shelf Deep Water Royalty Relief Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1337">43 U.S.C. 1337</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/58">Public Law 104–58</external-xref>); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBD0232F3C2054138B888F267B0CC1FEB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>not subject to limitations on royalty relief based on market price that are equal to or less than the price thresholds described in clauses (v) through (vii) of section 8(a)(3)(C) of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1337">43 U.S.C. 1337(a)(3)(C)</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H507D1CD0E22F4FACACD0FC337CC2511A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Lessee</header><text>The term <term>lessee</term> includes any person or other entity that controls, is controlled by, or is in or under common control with, a lessee.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9BE19C235A3248E5A31DC2A338DE5063"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idFDD6509DEA084EE28C71822D57E94923"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Issuance of New
			 Leases</header>
				<paragraph id="H2A20381115274DE89773C17DBBB67F5D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall not issue any new lease that authorizes the production of oil or natural gas under the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1331">43 U.S.C. 1331 et seq.</external-xref>) to a person described in paragraph (2) unless the person has renegotiated each covered lease with respect to which the person is a lessee, to modify the payment responsibilities of the person to require the payment of royalties if the price of oil and natural gas is greater than or equal to the price thresholds described in clauses (v) through (vii) of section 8(a)(3)(C) of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1337">43 U.S.C. 1337(a)(3)(C)</external-xref>).</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H36E97BA6FB9149D085DD570E54215B5C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Persons
 described</header><text>A person referred to in paragraph (1) is—</text> <subparagraph id="H2D43327EB78E4A7FB43B1AF1FC218EBD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a lessee that—</text>
 <clause id="HB28ADA55DCDE4C668E8BA79AB0ED0577"><enum>(i)</enum><text>holds a covered lease on the date on which the Secretary considers the issuance of the new lease; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HBA09BC9A639342E1AB4566CA2A414C43"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>was issued a covered lease before the date of enactment of this Act, but transferred the covered lease to another person or entity (including a subsidiary or affiliate of the lessee) after the date of enactment of this Act; or</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H13662D186FD14627871EE737ADC050E0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other person that has any direct or indirect interest in, or that derives any benefit from, a covered lease.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE679C8B21ACB433186FF55A057E930FF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Multiple
			 lessees</header>
					<subparagraph id="H5410040DE0CE4E07B742D1E1D5BD17D5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1), if there are multiple lessees that own a share of a covered lease, the Secretary may implement separate agreements with any lessee with a share of the covered lease that modifies the payment responsibilities with respect to the share of the lessee to include price thresholds that are equal to or less than the price thresholds described in clauses (v) through (vii) of section 8(a)(3)(C) of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1337">43 U.S.C. 1337(a)(3)(C)</external-xref>).</text>
					</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H011F85275B9342AB9661221A0F6B2CC1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Treatment of
 share as covered lease</header><text>Beginning on the effective date of an agreement under subparagraph (A), any share subject to the agreement shall not constitute a covered lease with respect to any lessees that entered into the agreement.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF9D0889D2DD14128B50C46A7F020D458"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Transfers</header><text>A lessee or any other person who has any direct or indirect interest in, or who derives a benefit from, a lease shall not be eligible to obtain by sale or other transfer (including through a swap, spinoff, servicing, or other agreement) any covered lease, the economic benefit of any covered lease, or any other lease for the production of oil or natural gas in the Gulf of Mexico under the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1331">43 U.S.C. 1331 et seq.</external-xref>), unless the lessee or other person—</text>
 <paragraph id="H4835EBEAA664420A8365A12AA5694C48"><enum>(1)</enum><text>has renegotiated each covered lease with respect to which the lessee or person is a lessee, to modify the payment responsibilities of the lessee or person to include price thresholds that are equal to or less than the price thresholds described in clauses (v) through (vii) of section 8(a)(3)(C) of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1337">43 U.S.C. 1337(a)(3)(C)</external-xref>); or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9047A62E1C7A49D2916C2549078C3F63"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has entered into an agreement with the Secretary to modify the terms of all covered leases of the lessee or other person to include limitations on royalty relief based on market prices that are equal to or less than the price thresholds described in clauses (v) through (vii) of section 8(a)(3)(C) of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1337">43 U.S.C. 1337(a)(3)(C)</external-xref>).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD866283537D946738B82B74F9C41348E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Use of amounts
 for deficit reduction</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any amounts received by the United States as rentals or royalties under covered leases shall be deposited in the Treasury and used for—</text>
 <paragraph id="idAE49D985606B47EBBEDEFF5F86402F83"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Federal budget deficit reduction; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id836E0B7E55DB46D79A3746B9533046A3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>if there is no Federal budget deficit, reducing the Federal debt in such manner as the Secretary of the Treasury considers appropriate.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H7915086CCDB9472A9B30F5F6F8DA6AB2"><enum>3.</enum><header>Price
			 thresholds for royalty suspension provisions</header>
 <subsection id="id82CF8692900544B0B1F54A8EF92AA7E5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of the Interior shall agree to a request by any lessee to amend any lease issued for any Central and Western Gulf of Mexico tract during the period of January 1, 1996, through November 28, 2000, to incorporate price thresholds applicable to royalty suspension provisions, that are equal to or less than the price thresholds described in clauses (v) through (vii) of section 8(a)(3)(C) of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1337">43 U.S.C. 1337(a)(3)(C)</external-xref>).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idDAB2347403264816B13FD45D00D8C310"><enum>(b)</enum><header>New or revised price thresholds</header><text>An amended lease under subsection (a) shall impose the new or revised price thresholds effective on October 1, 2015.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idAEC188C258C840029DB7AC210D58478D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Existing lease provisions</header><text>Lease provisions in effect on the date of enactment of this Act shall prevail through September 30, 2015.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


