<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S2046 IS: To authorize the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission to issue an order continuing a stay of a hydroelectric license for the Mahoney Lake hydroelectric project in the State of Alaska, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-09-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2046</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150917">September 17, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S288">Ms. Murkowski</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To authorize the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission to issue an order continuing a stay of a
			 hydroelectric license for the Mahoney Lake hydroelectric project in the
			 State of Alaska, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="id7ABD949A4B4543BE9FF356AC2C68BACB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Stay and Reinstatement of FERC License No. 11393 for the Mahoney Lake Hydroelectric Project</header>
 <subsection id="idDE54DF23D6B04CE4AA95195497ADC077"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="id79FC416DE4FF4504B4CD181529C001D8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <quote>Commission</quote> means the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idCE59295C643746D2AF06453771A0A727"><enum>(2)</enum><header>License</header><text>The term <quote>license</quote> means the license for Commission project number 11393.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id3E9C2D8EDF2A41EEA728E7AB23FB75E5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Licensee</header><text>The term <quote>licensee</quote> means the holder of the license.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id556B272643D147B29DFDF241F51003FB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Stay of license</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On the request of the licensee, the Commission shall issue an order continuing the stay of the license.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id26a1b8be35b84343918495f74d63f168"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Lifting of stay</header><text>On the request of the licensee, but not later than 10 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commission shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="id9931CF4186C840D4BC4C88B2E62F1483"><enum>(1)</enum><text>issue an order lifting the stay of the license under subsection (b); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id9FAA9E0B44C648BF958574D40F91F1AF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>make the effective date of the license the date on which the stay is lifted under paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idf24de28f60e84982a4df8acee3aa57f1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Extension of license</header><text>On the request of the licensee and notwithstanding the time period specified in section 13 of the Federal Power Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/806">16 U.S.C. 806</external-xref>) for commencement of construction of the project subject to the license, the Commission shall, after reasonable notice and in accordance with the good faith, due diligence, and public interest requirements of that section, extend the time period during which the licensee is required to commence the construction of the project for not more than 3 consecutive 2-year periods, notwithstanding any other provision of law.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idd6a6f7a24cae461cbc6715253618615b"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effect</header><text>Nothing in this Act prioritizes, or creates any advantage or disadvantage to, Commission project number 11393 under Federal law, including the Federal Power Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/791a">16 U.S.C. 791a et seq.</external-xref>) or the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/2601">16 U.S.C. 2601 et seq.</external-xref>), as compared to—</text>
 <paragraph id="id2619368640874E3E9CF97E4CE8A86A9A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any electric generating facility in existence on the date of enactment of this Act; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idB8E893EDD0A34306B73BAF11C06FB2B4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any electric generating facility that may be examined, proposed, or developed during the period of any stay or extension of the license under this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


