<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1260 IS: Sunshine in Sponsorship Identification Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 1260</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150507">May 7, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S282">Mr. Nelson</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S312">Mrs. McCaskill</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S380">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To direct the Federal Communications Commission to revise and update its sponsorship identification
			 rules applicable to commercial and political advertising.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Sunshine in Sponsorship Identification Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </section><section id="idF683BD6568FC43509C1D70646D40EA70"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text> <paragraph id="idCE2D51AE278E4C0D98CF7F7FFB0A56BD"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Federal law has required broadcasters to identify the sponsors of broadcast content since the Radio Act of 1927 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/81">47 U.S.C. 81 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id444ADAA0AB7B40B5B195B61CF2A56EF2"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal Communications Commission has had the authority to adopt and enforce rules requiring the disclosure of the sponsors of commercial and political broadcasts since the passage of section 317 of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/317">47 U.S.C. 317</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id9CDF5D581DF84DBC8B2ACF19D4E642D8"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 317 of the Communications Act of 1934 requires the full and fair disclosure of the true identity of the sponsors of all on-air commercial and political broadcasts.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id945B747DE81F49AFA85C0DA516103A93"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In 1944, the Federal Communications Commission adopted rules implementing section 317 of the Communications Act of 1934. Those rules remain largely in place today.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id0CBE6D04B65B4338A2D6720CBC244531"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">While the Federal Communications Commission has periodically issued updated rules and guidance regarding its application of section 317 and its rules promulgated under that section, the Commission has not engaged in a thorough review of those rules in many decades.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id992638D775D14A509BF3064773643AE9"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In a 2013 report, the Government Accountability Office recommended that the Federal Communications Commission engage in a comprehensive review of its sponsorship identification rules to ensure that such rules are reflective of the current practices of commercial and political advertisers.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idCA8BCD8A458C4BCB96B84D54AC1C9E10"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Given the dramatic changes in technology in the many years since the Federal Communications Commission put forth formal guidance on these issues, the Commission should review its sponsorship identification policies to make sure that American citizens are fully apprised of the identity of entities seeking to influence them.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="id941CA65232BA4A75932F71215A6CA5D5"><enum>3.</enum><header>Modernization of sponsorship identification rules</header>
 <subsection id="idDB32A89C3CFA49A89A6ED37815288EDA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Rulemaking required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Federal Communications Commission shall commence a rulemaking to update its rules and guidance promulgated under section 317 of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/317">47 U.S.C. 317</external-xref>).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id86385CF7B9BB47A98EB639DC51C19D2E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As part of the rulemaking required under subsection (a), the Federal Communications Commission shall, at a minimum—</text>
 <paragraph id="idF29B10A234064E10B99F16C8F918CE9B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">update and modernize its sponsorship identification rules and guidance to reflect current technologies and commercial and political advertising practices;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id861E466483234FCD85B376904CB34540"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure that political broadcasts include disclosures containing more detailed information about the identity of the true sponsors of such broadcasts; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id0BEC4A7BA9B14819929CFE4650EB935F"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consider how best to require the disclosure of sponsorship identification information, including by requiring that more detailed sponsorship identification information be placed online or in another form more readily accessible to the public.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idBFA3D3F1755449D98BA86CA9177FF542"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Timeframe</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal Communications Commission shall complete the rulemaking required by subsection (a) not later than 270 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


