<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1058 IS: Marine and Hydrokinetic Renewable Energy Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1058</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150422">April 22, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S353">Mr. Schatz</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S363">Mr. King</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To promote research, development, and demonstration of marine and hydrokinetic renewable energy
			 technologies, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="id53535020-c63d-4b4b-8e61-9afb3125ad7e" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short
 title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Marine and Hydrokinetic Renewable Energy Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="id59c037b6-3c77-4093-94e5-74d1fd11af09"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definition of
 marine and hydrokinetic renewable energy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 632 of the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/17211">42 U.S.C. 17211</external-xref>) is amended in the matter preceding paragraph (1) by striking <quote>electrical</quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="idd0480542-8063-4de4-a96c-5f0491de8470"><enum>3.</enum><header>Marine and
 hydrokinetic renewable energy research and development</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 633 of the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/17212">42 U.S.C. 17212</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id13db52c7-709f-4b62-8f60-0e4babbcf6a7" style="OLC">
				<section id="id40b76ee3-5641-4f0f-8743-1a6f2a71d6dd"><enum>633.</enum><header>Marine and
 hydrokinetic renewable energy research and development</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of the Interior, the Secretary of Commerce, and the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, shall carry out a program of research, development, demonstration, and commercial application to accelerate the introduction of marine and hydrokinetic renewable energy production into the United States energy supply, giving priority to fostering accelerated research, development, and commercialization of technology, including programs—</text>
 <paragraph id="idcb9bed70-5728-46ef-a61c-2b7bb9256e90"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to assist technology development to improve the components, processes, and systems used for power generation from marine and hydrokinetic renewable energy resources;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id7ee4a556-589a-4e17-82ab-abdb5cfe3607"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to establish critical testing infrastructure necessary—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id85abd1e3-3ef5-4737-af0a-d33493ed7dec"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to cost effectively and efficiently test and prove marine and hydrokinetic renewable energy devices; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id660a0e97-3438-42c0-917e-1451738abbee"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to accelerate the technological readiness and commercialization of those devices;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id95b6c759-dac8-4ac4-871b-378bb1013bc5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to support efforts to increase the efficiency of energy conversion, lower the cost, increase the use, improve the reliability, and demonstrate the applicability of marine and hydrokinetic renewable energy technologies by participating in demonstration projects;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id2db238bf-90ae-400f-8bb1-4a65b8eac8d9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to investigate variability issues and the efficient and reliable integration of marine and hydrokinetic renewable energy with the utility grid;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idaea53d4f-6688-4c4e-a94b-eec4aed7a47f"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to identify and study critical short- and long-term needs to create a sustainable marine and hydrokinetic renewable energy supply chain based in the United States;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idfc847baf-78cc-4375-bba5-bb91a3f477e9"><enum>(6)</enum><text>to increase the reliability and survivability of marine and hydrokinetic renewable energy technologies;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ida2ccca11-bf9c-4c5c-bd64-da8d2bbcdc8d"><enum>(7)</enum><text>to verify the performance, reliability, maintainability, and cost of new marine and hydrokinetic renewable energy device designs and system components in an operating environment;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id58b2cf1f-ba3e-41b1-9d76-115377329993"><enum>(8)</enum><text>to coordinate and avoid duplication of activities across programs of the Department and other applicable Federal agencies, including National Laboratories and to coordinate public-private collaboration in all programs under this section;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id46a46d58-5eab-4a7a-a12d-adbc75985baf"><enum>(9)</enum><text>to identify opportunities for joint research and development programs and development of economies of scale between—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idb987f8db-46c3-4b57-a9ea-62a0bed2ef63"><enum>(A)</enum><text>marine and hydrokinetic renewable energy technologies; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6fcb66fa-25f1-464c-875b-aeff7c1e4324"><enum>(B)</enum><text>other renewable energy and fossil energy programs, offshore oil and gas production activities, and activities of the Department of Defense; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idf06c03b6-1633-427b-85a6-a30c50824efa"><enum>(10)</enum><text>to support in-water technology development with international partners using existing cooperative procedures (including memoranda of understanding)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id313b4d57-82bd-4dcb-a5a4-35c8244914d8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to allow cooperative funding and other support of value to be exchanged and leveraged; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id50c24964-09f2-43ee-9571-ed937a7f9144"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to encourage the participation of international research centers and companies within the United States and the participation of United States research centers and companies in international projects.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section><section id="ide1e82b6d-57bb-4948-9c42-3fea8ab654f7"><enum>4.</enum><header>National
			 Marine Renewable Energy Research, Development, and Demonstration
 Centers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 634 of the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/17213">42 U.S.C. 17213</external-xref>) is amended by striking subsection (b) and inserting the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1b9e0135-476e-4bfd-b490-af02c6170389" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="idacc94040-71d6-4b29-a66b-e7a8318fd129"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>A Center (in coordination with the Department and National Laboratories) shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="id0d22ef09-76a3-410f-9a5a-047ba57d0c1e"><enum>(1)</enum><text>advance research, development, demonstration, and commercial application of marine and hydrokinetic renewable energy technologies;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id58ce3962-9c08-4a17-8537-a72695a786ba"><enum>(2)</enum><text>support in-water testing and demonstration of marine and hydrokinetic renewable energy technologies, including facilities capable of testing—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id9ac2923f-1413-4114-8581-84cc851eecee"><enum>(A)</enum><text>marine and hydrokinetic renewable energy systems of various technology readiness levels and scales;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4671277f-2ecc-4624-a213-2be409a5df08"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a variety of technologies in multiple test berths at a single location; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idadb30582-4929-48d4-b1dc-0d700b25fa5d"><enum>(C)</enum><text>arrays of technology devices; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id8336d745-2056-4376-90b7-5105377cbd6a"><enum>(3)</enum><text>serve as information clearinghouses for the marine and hydrokinetic renewable energy industry by collecting and disseminating information on best practices in all areas relating to developing and managing marine and hydrokinetic renewable energy resources and energy systems.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section><section id="ide6f9f544-9ed8-4312-81cf-48f9b9095585"><enum>5.</enum><header>Authorization
 of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 636 of the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/17215">42 U.S.C. 17215</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>2008 through 2012</quote> and inserting <quote>2016 through 2019</quote>.</text></section></legis-body></bill>


