<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1869 IS: Federal Cybersecurity Enhancement Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 1869</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150727">July 27, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S277">Mr. Carper</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S345">Mr. Johnson</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To improve Federal network security and authorize and enhance an existing intrusion detection and
			 prevention system for civilian Federal networks. </official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Federal Cybersecurity Enhancement Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </section><section id="id86C13F8EF018432185CD9A8C12328A80"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act—</text> <paragraph id="id2673D6CDA0BC4084AFBFFA2486F3871E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>agency</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3502 of title 44, United States Code;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id9F9DD5AE73D94EE09207BB15D4F82670"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>agency information system</term> has the meaning given the term in section 228 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002, as added by section 3(a);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id9E03D5331EE4469591BEBC0CE5910E5B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="id00602E393E304EC8960823E1A6858D86"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id28E3BD91D81745CD95E7372E5408C4F5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idDF5176842D934DF4A135B5343B242BD7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the terms <term>cybersecurity risk</term> and <term>information system</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 227 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002, as so redesignated by section 3(a);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idCC46FA8C43EB4132ABD07408C8888479"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the term <term>Director</term> means the Director of the Office of Management and Budget;</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idFC9279FF10C94C229C9B6AC21D5DADFC"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the term <term>intelligence community</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3(4) of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3003">50 U.S.C. 3003(4)</external-xref>); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id934C89CB175F45FCB5555A2371C0852E"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Homeland Security.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="id4ADD3A699B3E448185C5D96C4748D2F1"><enum>3.</enum><header>Improved Federal network security</header> <subsection id="id08E79F8214A742BAA23F98CC70FB184C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subtitle C of title II of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/141">6 U.S.C. 141 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id68A4329B0FD24C499FA69460860601C6"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating section 228 as section 229;</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id52A651A4E1FF4B8A8D89D9FA5CA3E5C8"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating section 227 as subsection (c) of section 228, as added by paragraph (4), and adjusting the margins accordingly;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id1DACEBD396FE412B9621898A1BEA79ED"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by redesignating the second section designated as section 226 (relating to the national cybersecurity and communications integration center) as section 227;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id9999ABD7164A48B8A007E0CDA54A30B0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by inserting after section 227, as so redesignated, the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id983FCBC63EA44338B264D262AF9D03C1" style="OLC"> <section id="idD4D3C10897674E0F83AA63DED7CDF0AD"><enum>228.</enum><header>Cybersecurity plans</header> <subsection id="id7ceb5f120a734fcdb2a071e4c5d23397"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text>
 <paragraph id="idB7CE8347FDB8445D841D6E12FD313C1A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>agency information system</term> means an information system used or operated by an agency, by a contractor of an agency, or by another entity on behalf of an agency;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idBD3520C2B43A45EFA7C3158FAE693B39"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the terms <term>cybersecurity risk</term> and <term>information system</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 227;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idF531D151C67244938B909BD52A8FAFC8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>information sharing and analysis organization</term> has the meaning given the term in section 212(5); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id85F3FDBC126E4E59B44FF616CE985EB4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the term <term>intelligence community</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3(4) of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3003">50 U.S.C. 3003(4)</external-xref>).</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id406401782B954E4EB3F495609C732D66"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Intrusion assessment plan</header>
 <paragraph id="id6cec1332df5243cb9962f9881a4f1223"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>The Secretary, in coordination with the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, shall develop and implement an intrusion assessment plan to identify and remove intruders in agency information systems.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id6bfc71a984994034a9faa0f20ef6e6ea"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The intrusion assessment plan required under paragraph (1) shall not apply to the Department of Defense or an element of the intelligence community.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id8F150FA09EFE40DC94AE33A3EF1860A6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in section 228(c), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>section 226</quote> and inserting <quote>section 227</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idFEFD6E614B624DC0A0AF09DB2D8A76B7"><enum>(6)</enum><text>by inserting after section 229, as so redesignated, the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idDBBD15DFFEAD4A6EBAE82AB821D7E176" style="OLC">
						<section id="idC234A0EE9A6A47A6ACE76C4294D8F23A"><enum>230.</enum><header>Federal intrusion detection and prevention system</header>
 <subsection id="idBF5E65F4A6014074AFEE3DE53A420AA8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text> <paragraph id="id6076F1F9D3AB4A9A95EFBC892B3E202D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>agency</term> has the meaning given that term in section 3502 of title 44, United States Code;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id709FD18BC0EE4D20ABFBC11320FA4F7D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>agency information</term> means information collected or maintained by or on behalf of an agency;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idF35A9471D0244DF1A467FF269C39E00B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>agency information system</term> has the meaning given the term in section 228; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id80DE6432B03F498FA359FE8B98883B98"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the terms <term>cybersecurity risk</term> and <term>information system</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 227.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2AE9BBE3B6594D93A8304CB70B14E2CF"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Requirement</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id58B7B3EFF40E49F889372A335096ABD0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary shall deploy, operate, and maintain, to make available for use by any agency, with or without reimbursement—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id9095cdb8620a4ed89192bb9b78e9d24d"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a capability to detect cybersecurity risks in network traffic transiting or traveling to or from an agency information system; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id585bd50465e742e4a1f22ee8d26d51a3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a capability to prevent network traffic associated with such cybersecurity risks from transiting or traveling to or from an agency information system or modify such network traffic to remove the cybersecurity risk.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id25F34699A25148AA99C90A92E5597C1E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Regular improvement</header><text>The Secretary shall regularly deploy new technologies and modify existing technologies to the intrusion detection and prevention capabilities described in paragraph (1) as appropriate to improve the intrusion detection and prevention capabilities.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id48ac7881edd7411aa42c5330292feb4b"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Activities</header><text>In carrying out subsection (b), the Secretary—</text> <paragraph id="id7c27eb0a61974c6f86df85a7b0d30565"><enum>(1)</enum><text>may access, and the head of an agency may disclose to the Secretary or a private entity providing assistance to the Secretary under paragraph (2), information transiting or traveling to or from an agency information system, regardless of the location from which the Secretary or a private entity providing assistance to the Secretary under paragraph (2) accesses such information, notwithstanding any other provision of law that would otherwise restrict or prevent the head of an agency from disclosing such information to the Secretary or a private entity providing assistance to the Secretary under paragraph (2);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ida0edb5a3d7504231934b833ae5837e0b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may enter into contracts or other agreements with, or otherwise request and obtain the assistance of, private entities to deploy and operate technologies in accordance with subsection (b);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idee92f108c7e64062a1eaea9d6faf268d"><enum>(3)</enum><text>may retain, use, and disclose information obtained through the conduct of activities authorized under this section only to protect information and information systems from cybersecurity risks;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idcad97d0ea79e40ea999f11b1ad8498c3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>shall regularly assess through operational test and evaluation in real world or simulated environments available advanced protective technologies to improve detection and prevention capabilities, including commercial and non-commercial technologies and detection technologies beyond signature-based detection, and utilize such technologies when appropriate;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idCE51E30ECF7441B58DE8B322D32E21D3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>shall establish a pilot to acquire, test, and deploy, as rapidly as possible, technologies described in paragraph (4); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idfd1d27e2cde540a79d9684cc8e822856"><enum>(6)</enum><text>shall periodically update the privacy impact assessment required under section 208(b) of the E-Government Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/44/3501">44 U.S.C. 3501</external-xref> note).</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idc30086ab58b64861bb1e69d599045868"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Private entities</header>
 <paragraph id="idf43e407097d24b33956d6c3d92c7571b"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Conditions</header><text>A private entity described in subsection (c)(2) may not—</text> <subparagraph id="idaccc35542ff54507a2f796d1aa42617c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>disclose any network traffic transiting or traveling to or from an agency information system to any entity other than the Department or the agency that disclosed the information under subsection (c)(1); or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9b65c6ab78314666861b68075eca668d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>use any network traffic transiting or traveling to or from an agency information system to which the private entity gains access in accordance with this section for any purpose other than to protect agency information and agency information systems against cybersecurity risks or to administer a contract or other agreement entered into pursuant to subsection (c)(2) or as part of another contract with the Secretary.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id713548701c444d868df242c2d337f30d"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation on liability</header><text>No cause of action shall lie in any court against a private entity for assistance provided to the Secretary in accordance with this section and any contract or agreement entered into pursuant to subsection (c)(2).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id890c6f0c90c44c64ab8fd9de4459c08d"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prioritizing advanced security tools</header>
 <text>The Director and the Secretary, in consultation with appropriate agencies, shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="idB87E6B1793F54AF29EFA768CFC1D2807"><enum>(1)</enum><text>review and update Governmentwide policies and programs to ensure appropriate prioritization and use of network security monitoring tools within agency networks; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id4B90469052274F018B32A389CBA882FD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>brief appropriate congressional committees on such prioritization and use.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4867C86C3B164AF8BE57264C44D598C0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Agency responsibilities</header> <paragraph id="id10315EA04D9F4A64A4B5317A076E983B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idC496352CC9A24AF09E60BA4650CD75E8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act or 2 months after the date on which the Secretary makes available the intrusion detection and prevention capabilities under section 230(b)(1) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002, as added by subsection (a), whichever is later, the head of each agency shall apply and continue to utilize the capabilities to all information traveling between an agency information system and any information system other than an agency information system; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0F2A9FAA844848A48756ACE6F5EF79F4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not later than 6 months after the date on which the Secretary makes available improvements to the intrusion detection and prevention capabilities pursuant to section 230(b)(2) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002, as added by subsection (a), the head of each agency shall apply and continue to utilize the improved intrusion detection and prevention capabilities.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idCF92F1F4881B4B4DBEFDF93312A7F779"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The requirements under paragraph (1) shall not apply to the Department of Defense or an element of the intelligence community.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idE14612F7F85046B88C989027C52269EC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Table of contents amendment</header><text>The table of contents in section 1(b) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/101">6 U.S.C. 101</external-xref> note) is amended by striking the items relating to the first section designated as section 226, the second section designated as section 226 (relating to the national cybersecurity and communications integration center), section 227, and section 228 and inserting the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF353BCD1BEBC4A8DB4EF24D5B6EC75DD" style="OLC"><toc><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Sec. 226. Cybersecurity recruitment and retention.</toc-entry><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Sec. 227. National cybersecurity and communications integration center.</toc-entry><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Sec. 228. Cybersecurity  plans.</toc-entry><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Sec. 229. Clearances.</toc-entry><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Sec. 230. Federal intrusion detection and prevention system.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section id="id9f0207dc38764a0994bbddbc04481781"><enum>4.</enum><header>Advanced internal defenses</header>
			<subsection id="id349cd0473fb54154876663862bad5837"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Advanced network security tools</header>
 <paragraph id="idD89B63CBFA7F4054B10F88142CC4A4BA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall include in the Continuous Diagnostics and Mitigation Program advanced network security tools to improve visibility of network activity, including through the use of commercial and free or open source tools, to detect and mitigate intrusions and anomalous activity.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ide6653e1e7f104bfc90129499101bc7e3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Development of plan</header><text>The Director shall develop and implement a plan to ensure that each agency utilizes advanced network security tools, including those described in paragraph (1), to detect and mitigate intrusions and anomalous activity.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ided6595bfe8b14c5da02c76922dee84e6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Improved metrics</header><text>The Secretary, in collaboration with the Director, shall review and update the metrics used to measure security under section 3554 of title 44, United States Code, to include measures of intrusion and incident detection and response times.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id867b11e2b8dd493599f8ea0f9b0d696a"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Transparency and accountability</header><text>The Director, in consultation with the Secretary, shall increase transparency to the public on agency cybersecurity posture, including by increasing the number of metrics available on Federal Government performance websites and, to the greatest extent practicable, displaying metrics for department components, small agencies, and micro agencies.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id0A731E28507046258C3166D6BB40DC94"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Maintenance of technologies</header><text>Section 3553(b)(6)(B) of title 44, United States Code, is amended by inserting <quote>, operating, and maintaining</quote> after <quote>deploying</quote>.</text> </subsection></section><section id="id2a7f04934513472d80dafbd591f7c304"><enum>5.</enum><header>Federal cybersecurity best practices</header> <subsection id="idc3eaded4fb9345a88292bb653293e45b"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Assessment of best practices for Federal cybersecurity</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the Director, shall regularly assess and require implementation of best practices for securing agency information systems against intrusion and preventing data exfiltration in the event of an intrusion.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="id36271ffad7c742289065af0d9bc2f941"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Cybersecurity requirements at agencies</header>
 <paragraph id="id2ad6ba9d64244644972b8778a0a2f068"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the head of each agency shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id1e90a12e31f843ef95159871f2cd1700"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identify sensitive and mission critical data stored by the agency consistent with the inventory required under the first subsection (c) (relating to the inventory of major information systems) and the second subsection (c) (relating to the inventory of information systems) of section 3505 of title 44, United States Code;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id41dac44c19534c9288e0e48df57cbe33"><enum>(B)</enum><text>assess access controls to the data described in subparagraph (A), the need for readily accessible storage of the data, and individuals' need to access the data;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6bc0e4e85cb84669bceff96c9fa53cf3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>encrypt the data described in subparagraph (A) that is stored on or transiting agency information systems consistent with standards and guidelines promulgated under section 11331 of title 40, United States Code;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6fc9a99ac42b45e0bf69381bd150b6a8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>implement a single sign-on trusted identity platform for individuals accessing each public website of the agency that requires user authentication, as developed by the Administrator of General Services in collaboration with the Secretary; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9c56d889c7584e6eadbdc087b77bb607"><enum>(E)</enum><text>implement multi-factor authentication consistent with standards and guidelines promulgated under section 11331 of title 40, United States Code, for—</text>
 <clause id="id21f9d71ef5114f9abdcc83c43dc9d807"><enum>(i)</enum><text>remote access to an agency information system; and</text> </clause><clause id="id292541e0e5964679a36675fc5507022d"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>each user account with elevated privileges on an agency information system.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id405b787ed9764a64a05609bc219662f7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The requirements under paragraph (1) shall not apply to the Department of Defense or an element of the intelligence community.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idE98CA081137049CC87BF3C6B18F625E1"><enum>6.</enum><header>Assessment; reports</header>
 <subsection id="idacabf89fa6aa4f53aa72b76c272b70a8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text> <paragraph id="id4ddfdd3d7b01447597315ef2c9bcf021"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>intrusion assessments</term> means actions taken under the intrusion assessment plan to identify and remove intruders in agency information systems;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id8895ef7ae65d486fb7326cbb7c162761"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>intrusion assessment plan</term> means the plan required under section 228(b)(1) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002, as added by section 3(a) of this Act; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idb440e54e2a0643319a48c7e47368169d"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>intrusion detection and prevention capabilities</term> means the capabilities required under section 230(b) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002, as added by section 3(a) of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idec063aaf35bb4c9eaf13ff3ee1319a47"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Third-Party assessment</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Government Accountability Office shall conduct a study and publish a report on the effectiveness of the approach and strategy of the Federal Government to securing agency information systems, including the intrusion detection and prevention capabilities and the intrusion assessment plan.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="idb10c596d49d74da48474162bcc6ab9c9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header>
				<paragraph id="idcea5a269c7ee459fafca7e13562d2ef1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Intrusion detection and prevention capabilities</header>
 <subparagraph id="id38cbb55632434032af2a30d43b8a7a63"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Secretary of Homeland Security report</header><text>Not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the status of implementation of the intrusion detection and prevention capabilities, including—</text>
 <clause id="id15d8681a761a42ef98b033ac7cf9d9c8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a description of privacy controls;</text> </clause><clause id="id36b16132f5bd41399650043ed7f6e9f7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a description of the technologies and capabilities utilized to detect cybersecurity risks in network traffic, including the extent to which those technologies and capabilities include existing commercial and non-commercial technologies;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idc2759225983f4f4291387e04dd1ce81d"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a description of the technologies and capabilities utilized to prevent network traffic associated with cybersecurity risks from transiting or traveling to or from agency information systems, including the extent to which those technologies and capabilities include existing commercial and non-commercial technologies;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id751a9e3715ad420b8cc703dccecd9dfd"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a list of the types of indicators or other identifiers or techniques used to detect cybersecurity risks in network traffic transiting or traveling to or from agency information systems on each iteration of the intrusion detection and prevention capabilities and the number of each such type of indicator, identifier, and technique;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idd512ec7e063a4f49bf7b98588b33395b"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the number of instances in which the intrusion detection and prevention capabilities detected a cybersecurity risk in network traffic transiting or traveling to or from agency information systems and the number of times the intrusion detection and prevention capabilities blocked network traffic associated with cybersecurity risk; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id3D6D19E724264687A03797E17AF13E12"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>a description of the pilot established under section 230(c)(5) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002, as added by section 3(a) of this Act, including the number of new technologies tested and the number of participating agencies.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idca5fb27f079d43f1b4eeadbd6ab5bb6b"><enum>(B)</enum><header>OMB report</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Director shall submit to Congress, as part of the report required under section 3553(c) of title 44, United States Code, an analysis of agency application of the intrusion detection and prevention capabilities, including—</text>
 <clause id="id7f8edd660fc44725ad1dfc5ee2ce28ed"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a list of each agency and the degree to which each agency has applied the intrusion detection and prevention capabilities to an agency information system; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idf7a48c8f730c4dee8fbe90308b9b24a2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a list by agency of—</text> <subclause id="id8C7DA083698B4C9F85734565BD3419E6"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the number of instances in which the intrusion detection and prevention capabilities detected a cybersecurity risk in network traffic transiting or traveling to or from an agency information system and the types of indicators, identifiers, and techniques used to detect such cybersecurity risks; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id3F0EAAA499AD4C738C48220496F0CDF3"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the number of instances in which the intrusion detection and prevention capabilities prevented network traffic associated with a cybersecurity risk from transiting or traveling to or from an agency information system and the types of indicators, identifiers, and techniques used to detect such agency information systems.</text>
							</subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id2694312433544ba4b8b5441cf31e05cf"><enum>(2)</enum><header>OMB report on development and implementation of intrusion assessment plan, advanced internal
 defenses, and Federal cybersecurity best practices</header><text>The Director shall—</text> <subparagraph id="id7aafd20e5684443f83d13be44fff7ac5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of this Act, and 30 days after any update thereto, submit the intrusion assessment plan to the appropriate congressional committees;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0ece71f199e04142a20c41db9ad7f405"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, submit to Congress, as part of the report required under section 3553(c) of title 44, United States Code—</text>
 <clause id="idCC6ECD6EB2C745D28DF8E8020F46F1EF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a description of the implementation of the intrusion assessment plan;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id3C224127FCEC48BD8523D0E102817DA8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the findings of the intrusion assessments conducted pursuant to the intrusion assessment plan;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id7dc453f6e05c4bd89031a4de77320f41"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>advanced network security tools included in the Continuous Diagnostics and Mitigation Program pursuant to section 4(a)(1);</text>
 </clause><clause id="id92916342261a4c7981faa31a23b48f76"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the results of the assessment of the Secretary of best practices for Federal cybersecurity pursuant to section 5(a); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idfcf7bee5940d4ad3846dae45a3e7a758"><enum>(v)</enum><text>a list by agency of compliance with the requirements of section 5(b); and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf12e180f1bde4bb9a3468bc135bdf172"><enum>(C)</enum><text>not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, submit to the appropriate congressional committees—</text>
 <clause id="id9453d3d143a947a097980f0b0b28cebd"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a copy of the plan developed pursuant to section 4(a)(2); and</text> </clause><clause id="idbffcc3a8557343619c54563dff472645"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the improved metrics developed pursuant to section 4(b).</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idcfd62630c37549d797ec8d610edcae77"><enum>7.</enum><header>Termination</header>
 <subsection id="idB314B56F204A47D299CCA5DB066D0244"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The authority provided under section 230 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002, as added by section 3(a) of this Act, and the reporting requirements under section 6(c) shall terminate on the date that is 7 years after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id8BAB76D5FDF2448ABF2FBBB27D812E0C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in subsection (a) shall be construed to affect the limitation of liability of a private entity for assistance provided to the Secretary under section 230(d)(2) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002, as added by section 3(a) of this Act, if such assistance was rendered before the termination date under subsection (a) or otherwise during a period in which the assistance was authorized.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


