<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S2306 IS: To require the Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, to undertake remediation oversight of the West Lake Landfill located in Bridgeton, Missouri.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-11-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2306</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20151119">November 19, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S342">Mr. Blunt</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S312">Mrs. McCaskill</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEV00">Committee on Environment and Public Works</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, to undertake
			 remediation oversight of the West Lake Landfill located in Bridgeton,
			 Missouri.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Transfer of oversight authority from EPA to Corps of Engineers</header>
 <subsection id="id316A190C7DD34572AF31BC8C168FA2D3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="id7ED70FFB45534107A01ED9C0403719DC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idE720F6F3A19F41708683274ADCE98C11"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Site</header><text>The term <term>site</term> means the West Lake Landfill located in Bridgeton, Missouri.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id113DC93B44714C59BCAF0E6D764B7673"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Transfer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, as soon as practicable after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="idE166E8355D2144CB94E50CAFD1A21267"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">under the Formerly Utilized Sites Remedial Action Program, undertake the functions and activities described in section 611 of the Energy and Water Development Appropriations Act, 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/2701">10 U.S.C. 2701</external-xref> note; 113 Stat. 502) as the lead agency responding to radioactive contamination at the site; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idA2192CE031BC40B48F47C1B250429702"><enum>(2)</enum><text>carry out remediation activities at the site in accordance with that section.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id3AD9AC19492348AFA525FFD96BC3FF27"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Cost recovery</header><text>The Secretary, in coordination with the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency and the Attorney General, shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="id233400053DC4401E9A26AFB028079E8C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>seek to recover any response costs incurred by the Secretary in carrying out this section in accordance with the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9601">42 U.S.C. 9601 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id5F6D2C57717C48E6BE87CD7A2FC151BA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>return any funds that are recovered under paragraph (1) to be used to carry out the Formerly Utilized Sites Remedial Action Program of the Corps of Engineers.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id94A030767A4E4C53A4050582F5B76ECB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>The Secretary shall use amounts made available to the Secretary to carry out the Formerly Utilized Sites Remedial Action Program to carry out this section.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="id9A603E6CD1AA42568B785949237C15C8"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Savings provisions</header>
 <paragraph id="id394DA4EAE223465AB4AF5B0EF70D9708"><enum>(1)</enum><header>No liability</header><text>Nothing in subsection (b) creates liability for—</text> <subparagraph id="id7A9A36A0017243D5809CC821EAD48260"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary for—</text>
 <clause id="idC5FB1AA67067435FA84192A86CE111A8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>contamination at the site; or</text> </clause><clause id="id9B01F46FB45E42E5BA84B4408246F60F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any actions or failures to act by any past, current, or future licensees, owners, operators, or users of the site; or</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id78856A13485E470885DAA5724BD37DD0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other party involved with the site.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idED2EED5A00E4419F950E85B7FAF089CE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No effect on liability under other law</header><text>Nothing in subsection (b) alters the liability of any party relating to the site under any other provision of law.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idD553CF9A5CB64F418472A93158B4A5FF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>No effect on Superfund status; national priorities list designation</header><text>Nothing in this Act affects the designation of the site as a Superfund site under the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9601">42 U.S.C. 9601 et seq.</external-xref>) or the listing of the site on the national priorities list under section 105 of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9605">42 U.S.C. 9605</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


