<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1866 IS: Veterans Small Business Ownership Improvements Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1866</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150727">July 27, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S299">Mr. Vitter</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSSB00">Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To establish the veterans’ business outreach center program, to improve the programs for veterans
			 of the Small Business Administration, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short
 title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Veterans Small Business Ownership Improvements Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="id91041948-fbc7-4aca-9d10-025058c92a34" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Veterans' business
			 outreach center program; Office of Veterans Business Development</header>
			<subsection id="idfae4212c-fc15-4ed0-a3fc-f78002e64759"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 32 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/657b">15 U.S.C. 657b</external-xref>) is amended by striking subsections (d), (e), and (f) and inserting the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id53782EBD5CDA40C29795B839A71A9D5E" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="idcf7efd13173b4445a0ee30abf5ed11d0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Boots to
				Business Program</header>
 <paragraph id="idec010491f45c425fa348420e4aa1b33a"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idEE52025950684C41B65121A7047B73BB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the term <term>covered individual</term> means—</text> <clause id="id1BAD61A965C04AC98F48F427AB4AF849"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a member of the Armed Forces, without regard to whether the member is participating in the Transition Assistance Program of the Department of Defense;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id42280BE1908F46ABA8F3C18E0AE258C7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an individual who is participating in the Transition Assistance Program of the Department of Defense;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id26C55922AA2147D586F44AFFAE76B3D2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an individual who—</text> <subclause id="idd95e873389644fb0b5bdeb8ce0a451ee"><enum>(I)</enum><text>served on active duty in any branch of the Armed Forces, including the National Guard and Reserves; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id94c52328972b424a808eace3a4c72f91"><enum>(II)</enum><text>was discharged or released from such service under conditions other than dishonorable; and</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="idB841E5C041BD470DB8B24F5F5B2C5973"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a spouse or dependent of an individual described in clause (i), (ii), or (iii); and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE8E3D20C5AE040CBA454065209F27062"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the term <term>Vet Center</term> means a center for readjustment counseling and related mental health services for veterans under section 1712A of title 38, United States Code.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idA875D4C9FEE74E0E9750049EF18DB526"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established a program to be known as the <quote>Boots to Business Program</quote> to provide entrepreneurship training to covered individuals, which shall be carried out by the Administrator.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idbc704e6db0ff413098d251fac44cd57f"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Goals</header><text>The goals of the Boots to Business Program are to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idC5DE049222574F61A7B9C6ABF6BDC213"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide exposure, introduction, and in-depth training for covered individuals interested in business ownership; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF0D4B68EAC5841DFA3B0E5D460793F8F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide covered individuals with the tools and knowledge necessary to identify a business opportunity, draft a business plan, identify sources of capital, connect with local small business resources, and launch a small business concern.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id81e1e240f24e4afe96600a3ab041064f"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Program
				components</header>
							<subparagraph id="idEE0A5EC3D016411097A53D473247A7EF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>The Boots to Business Program may include—</text> <clause id="idf8b79da550804b1c9fbd6492bd44573d"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a brief presentation providing exposure to the considerations involved in self-employment and small business ownership;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4D2DD1CC8635462CAA275C443EE63819"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an online, self-study course focused on the basic skills of entrepreneurship, the language of business, and the considerations involved in self-employment and small business ownership;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id7905afd76c2c4b7a918b0c723b13aa2c"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an in-person classroom instruction component providing an introduction to the foundations of self-employment and small business ownership; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id6138537a70ce4cefa7db34d525c52c22"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>in-depth training delivered through online instruction, including an online course that leads to the creation of a business plan.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id05a3580189aa4519b70a9fd854352b34"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Collaboration</header><text>The Administrator may—</text>
 <clause id="id677D857955FA4CEC9C2F5A60CABF47BE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>collaborate with public and private entities to develop a course curriculum for the Boots to Business Program; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id5B6C2FEDC68643D38F17C64E91D039B6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>modify program components in coordination with entities participating in the Warriors in Transition programs, as defined in section 738(f) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2013 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/1071">10 U.S.C. 1071</external-xref> note).</text>
								</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1eda99e3a9b44b118b1fcb9f72319531"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Utilization of resource partners</header>
 <clause id="id272b7722775c4e60bfbf7877bde2befe"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Associate Administrator shall—</text> <subclause id="id4C54E0D35F8B4584B11F7945566CF766"><enum>(I)</enum><text>ensure that veterans' business outreach centers regularly participate, on a nationwide basis, in the Boots to Business Program; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id8f1b2a589fec49d0b80e7afc078fd1b9"><enum>(II)</enum><text>to the maximum extent practicable, use a variety of other resource partners and entities in administering the Boots to Business Program.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="iddcbc294bf9794f67ae737148ce322810"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Grant authority</header><text>In carrying out clause (i), the Associate Administrator may make grants to veterans' business outreach centers, other resource partners, and other entities to carry out components of the Boots to Business Program.</text>
								</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide42a9997af3b41f182e05a90b5d73be4"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Availability to
 DOD</header><text>The Administrator shall—</text> <clause id="idF331DBE7B3C54F4E93651503D772AB03"><enum>(i)</enum><text>make available electronically information regarding the Boots to Business Program and all course materials created for the Boots to Business Program to the Secretary of Defense for inclusion on the website of the Department of Defense relating to the Transition Assistance Program and in the Transition Assistance Program manual and other publications and materials available for distribution from the Secretary of Defense; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id146CF9843D3C42FCAC650B65A019235C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>fully participate in the interagency governance of the Transition Assistance Program.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idae00c280f1ed4b34a405e65b37f9a5f7"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Availability to Veterans Affairs</header><text>In consultation with the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, the Associate Administrator shall make available outreach materials regarding the Boots to Business Program for distribution and display at local facilities of the Department of Veterans Affairs (including medical centers, community-based outpatient clinics, Vet Centers, and other facilities determined appropriate by the Associate Administrator and the Secretary), which shall, at a minimum—</text>
 <clause id="id94A71282BA424104B1F3AEF1CC80D204"><enum>(i)</enum><text>describe the Boots to Business Program, including a description of services provided; and</text> </clause><clause id="idFBE58447546449D886A87D48DA803D94"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>include eligibility requirements for participating in the Boots to Business Program.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0F367BF605AF4B69AF144A1278076455"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Review</header><text>The Inspector General of the Administration shall submit to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship of the Senate and the Committee on Small Business of the House of Representatives an annual report regarding the awarding of grants under the Boots to Business Program.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id2a56f546d29d41a39ead0d266824b601"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Women Veterans Business Training Program</header>
 <paragraph id="idca9f1013460640fe87876ae3d6f8395a"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>covered individual</term> means an individual who—</text> <subparagraph id="idF71EC22450F849A982D6B95C0A0FBCC0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is female; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id745A754616D742FDB7CBEA94DFDA8B88"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is—</text> <clause id="id3839985EAB7440F1AB9E0A331FE4B222"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a member of the Armed Forces;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idB7394322F5D14BB4B4DB17D959DE2E72"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a veteran; or</text> </clause><clause id="id7BEB71345F204343A74F8883E9E521BC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the spouse or dependent of a member of the Armed Forces or a veteran.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id41B0E824F85943BD983AFCED63267889"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Administrator shall establish a program, to be known as the Women Veterans Business Training Program, to provide specific training for covered individuals interested in exploring careers as owners of small business concerns.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id8260c79fb97b4570b31076e8cf99f9db"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Goals</header><text>The goals of the Women Veterans Business Training Program are to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idDDFE4A04213F49D9A31C800BD00A3D3E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>help covered individuals by providing the tools to become successful entrepreneurs; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0315D96DFC4A4980B30405016804C880"><enum>(B)</enum><text>integrate the leadership, integrity, focus, and drive of covered individuals into a premier education training program taught by accomplished entrepreneurs and entrepreneurship educators from across the United States.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idc0b87a06d78c40908301957c53d2379a"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Program
				components</header>
							<subparagraph id="id7d7e9bfd152147629cd5b9f907d9d6c2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>The Women Veterans Business Training Program may include—</text> <clause id="ideec6253dde3941419b9131f2cc074e00"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an online, self-study course focused on the basic skills of entrepreneurship and the language of business;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id8ff6cea4ceef4b4b80dfa9a707bfa1db"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a conference where participants are exposed to accomplished entrepreneurs and entrepreneurship educators from across the United States; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id6dd3dcec0af5459d8d3a36b4dff49b4e"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a plan to provide ongoing support and mentorship.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1981E0F95B3B48FFAC2AABB40ACC869E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Collaboration</header><text>The Administrator may collaborate with public and private entities to develop a course curriculum for the Women Veterans Business Training Program.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id08ef06115f6340d492831d2a695322cb"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Women veterans business training</header><text>The Associate Administrator shall—</text> <subparagraph id="idcf566366009e44d185e78f9a631ad0ca"><enum>(A)</enum><text>compile information on resources available to women veterans for business training, including resources for—</text>
 <clause id="id334819a14cff4ec9b6d3698327efb3e3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>vocational and technical education;</text> </clause><clause id="id9c81995195224039a240067ad6d93011"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>general business skills, such as marketing and accounting; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id886c62a79b2e497aa0c7ca476bd3a97d"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>business assistance programs targeted to women veterans;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4a084a7ae2cd4d398a4950465b4f0c9d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>disseminate the information compiled under subparagraph (A) through veterans' business outreach centers and women's business centers; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd0415fa821494f71b1d69cb08bf8a8f0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in consultation with the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, make available outreach materials regarding the Women Veterans Business Training Program for distribution and display at local facilities of the Department of Veterans Affairs (including medical centers, community-based outpatient clinics, Vet Centers (as defined in subsection (d)(1)), and other facilities determined appropriate by the Associate Administrator and the Secretary), which shall, at a minimum—</text>
 <clause id="id4963C4011EC24ED580AE4B7DE914C22D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>describe the Women Veterans Business Training Program, including a description of services provided; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id8798DDADFBFB41FBB7D7D6F958AE6BC6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>include eligibility requirements for participating in the Women Veterans Business Training Program.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5a52d74c8ff741b8b6cc075082783ddf"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Grant authority</header><text>The Associate Administrator may make grants to veterans' business outreach centers, women’s business centers, and other entities, including other resource partners, to carry out components of the Women Veterans Business Training Program.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id82df61361e0e43b190c1a0e78a378d45"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Business Training Program for Service Disabled Veterans</header>
 <paragraph id="ida653bbe5a40c45e4b61fef9978805a56"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator shall establish a Business Training Program for Service Disabled Veterans to provide specific training for service-disabled veterans interested in exploring careers as owners of small business concerns.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id489ffb5355774ecebdc4a5d0c7888017"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Goals</header><text>The goals of the Business Training Program for Service Disabled Veterans are to—</text> <subparagraph id="idc71e6e99a3c245b28af5ad4b4d0e774a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>help service-disabled veterans by providing the tools to become successful entrepreneurs; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1d541aa3f61a4bc39667d20b23c2c0e4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>integrate the leadership, integrity, focus, and drive of service-disabled veterans into a premier education training program taught by accomplished entrepreneurs and entrepreneurship educators from across the United States.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id3ea936b56fd4440cbeee477c4fa7ef1c"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Program components</header>
 <subparagraph id="id4484fc901f754abbaf9a3a0e7bfe1725"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Business Training Program for Service Disabled Veterans may include—</text> <clause id="id3007f259ae8b4456a9e2ec242a6113ef"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an online, self-study course focused on the basic skills of entrepreneurship and the language of business;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id645c681fe2f14dde94203fa6fcad0812"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a conference where participants are exposed to accomplished entrepreneurs and entrepreneurship educators from across the United States; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="ide5dcd62a11c74ef9ab24b950c09966d6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a plan to provide ongoing support and mentorship.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5ddda5b0c2e547ae8a34086c6a738d30"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Collaboration</header><text>The Administrator may collaborate with public and private entities to develop a course curriculum for the Business Training Program for Service Disabled Veterans.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id08a3dc73178c44faaca5ce59df9a46ad"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Availability to Veterans Affairs</header><text>In consultation with the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, the Associate Administrator shall make available outreach materials regarding the Business Training Program for Service Disabled Veterans for distribution and display at local facilities of the Department of Veterans Affairs (including medical centers, community-based outpatient clinics, Vet Centers (as defined in subsection (d)(1)), and other facilities determined appropriate by the Associate Administrator and the Secretary), which shall, at a minimum—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id11CB0CB5852C47BDBC6FE5162B89A0CE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>describe the Business Training Program for Service Disabled Veterans, including a description of services provided; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8645970C2DB748DA97F85F5E91E5E92C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>include eligibility requirements for participating in the Business Training Program for Service Disabled Veterans.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id775525b23b554bcc95343ca07bedb473"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Grant authority</header><text>The Associate Administrator may make grants to veterans' business outreach centers and other entities, including other resource partners, to carry out components of the Business Training Program for Service Disabled Veterans.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id79babdce-0662-4505-a508-45d271f4534b"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Veterans'
				Business Outreach Center Program</header>
 <paragraph id="id25571cfe-3cfd-4b95-ba81-1bdd841b791c"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="id6d0400bc-e4d1-42ed-a964-93b4c106de2c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the term <term>active duty</term> has the meaning given that term in section 101 of title 10, United States Code;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb98be969-a983-4b71-a0b2-0a19eee4f415"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the term <term>Reservist</term> means a member of a reserve component of the Armed Forces, as described in section 10101 of title 10, United States Code;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id23e0f29e-7777-45e8-b142-d610fa675e70"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the term <term>small business concern owned and controlled by veterans</term>—</text>
 <clause id="idc8153efd-afdb-43fa-8fa7-419dbf4e41f9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has the meaning given that term in section 3(q); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idee0f4bb9-e074-4498-83c3-26e16d1b46f8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>includes a small business concern—</text>
 <subclause id="id8f278d4b-7f3d-4e50-a0d5-490df418a500"><enum>(I)</enum><text>not less than 51 percent of which is owned by 1 or more spouses of veterans or, in the case of any publicly owned business, not less than 51 percent of the stock of which is owned by 1 or more spouses of veterans; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idacf9c0e3-563e-4615-a29d-68229e0c1fa9"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the management and daily business operations of which are controlled by 1 or more spouses of veterans;</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id99dd5058-db87-43d2-a42d-ea38162725ca"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the term <term>spouse</term>, relating to a member of the Armed Forces on active duty, veteran, service-disabled veteran, or Reservist, includes an individual who, on the date on which the member of the Armed Forces on active duty, veteran, service-disabled veteran, or Reservist died, is the spouse of the member of the Armed Forces on active duty, veteran, service-disabled veteran, or Reservist; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb3f59d82-316d-4f09-83da-c251c9d03a19"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the term <term>veterans' business outreach center program</term> means the program established under paragraph (2)(A).</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idce0cc809-99b7-40c2-930c-7225df3d67ad"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Program
				Established</header>
 <subparagraph id="ide19992a6a89641f48002f99838efb0dc"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator, acting through the Associate Administrator, shall establish a veterans’ business outreach center program, under which the Associate Administrator may provide financial assistance to educational institutions, veterans’ nonprofit community-based organizations, and Federal, State, and local departments and agencies to conduct a 5-year project for the benefit of small business concerns owned and controlled by veterans, which, upon application by the entity receiving financial assistance, may be renewed for 1 or more additional 5-year periods.</text>
							</subparagraph><subparagraph id="id55ef4f3e-0550-4f49-a0f1-bbcaa436a4a4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Form of
 Financial Assistance</header><text>Financial assistance under this subsection may be in the form of a grant, a contract, or a cooperative agreement.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1d531e3b-133e-4769-ba0f-49e9496b5932"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Veterans'
 business outreach centers</header><text>Each entity that receives financial assistance under this subsection shall establish or operate a veterans' business outreach center (which may include establishing or operating satellite offices in the region described in paragraph (5) served by that entity) that provides to veterans (including service-disabled veterans), Reservists, and the spouses of members of the Armed Forces on active duty, veterans (including service-disabled veterans), and Reservists—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id03e2c848-43bc-4be0-8eec-6e2d78ff599a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>financial advice, including training and counseling on applying for and securing business credit and investment capital, preparing and presenting financial statements, and managing cash flow and other financial operations of a small business concern;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id22fa36f6-2bff-4945-abdc-a124fd6d23a9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>management advice, including training and counseling on the planning, organization, staffing, direction, and control of each major activity and function of a small business concern;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide6cf4828bca4494c9802eccbadd5204b"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">technical assistance, training, and counseling to assist in identifying and obtaining Federal procurement opportunities;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id389bb05d-8367-45f9-a6ec-8af949c97e0d"><enum>(D)</enum><text>marketing advice, including training and counseling on identifying and segmenting domestic and international market opportunities, preparing and executing marketing plans, developing pricing strategies, locating contract opportunities, negotiating contracts, and using public relations and advertising techniques; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="idb34b94cc-8ef3-464e-b649-7831a04e6ddf"><enum>(E)</enum><text>other advice, including training and counseling.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id62250086-3840-4acf-b4fc-83fa56568d15"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Application</header>
							<subparagraph id="idf98d3486-e7c7-46a7-9d18-7592426bba80"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>An entity desiring to receive financial assistance under this subsection shall submit an application to the Associate Administrator at such time and in such manner as the Associate Administrator may require.</text>
							</subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4ce5f966-d9b4-4a3f-8f37-8cc3d51bb48e"><enum>(B)</enum><header>5-year
 plan</header><text>Each application described in subparagraph (A) shall include a 5-year plan on proposed fundraising and training activities relating to the veterans' business outreach center.</text>
							</subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfc72af44-a158-4690-9cf4-463839efe75d"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Determination
 and Notification</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date on which applications for a fiscal year are required to be submitted under subparagraph (A), the Associate Administrator shall approve or deny any application submitted and notify the applicant of the determination.</text>
							</subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc6716075-b774-4f65-a9af-83d44edef70e"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Availability
 of application</header><text>The Associate Administrator shall make every effort to make the application under subparagraph (A) available online.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1ccfc775-07a8-4606-b082-87e58436af6b"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>The Associate Administrator may select to receive financial assistance under this subsection—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idc621124d-72f0-4460-b99d-d8fe1c8452c7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a Veterans' Business Outreach Center established by the Administrator under section 8(b)(17) on or before the day before the date of enactment of this subsection; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8dff72adf4bb4df2af0dd328eca2bdf7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>educational institutions, veterans’ nonprofit community-based organizations, and Federal, State, and local departments and agencies located in various regions of the United States, as the Associate Administrator determines is appropriate.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1d74c05b-be57-4497-ba4d-f188ed7c459d"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Selection
				criteria</header>
							<subparagraph id="ide30b41c5-9325-4619-9f45-2f546a303295"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>The Associate Administrator shall establish selection criteria, stated in terms of relative importance, to evaluate and rank applicants under paragraph (5)(B) for financial assistance under this subsection.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd6b869b0-ae88-4b22-b424-9590e6fa6ef2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Criteria</header><text>The selection criteria established under this paragraph shall include—</text>
 <clause id="ida8fe1db4-6f87-4283-adbe-39dd2af5d889"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the experience of the applicant in conducting programs or ongoing efforts designed to impart or upgrade the business skills of veterans (including service-disabled veterans), Reservists, and the spouses of members of the Armed Forces on active duty, veterans (including service-disabled veterans), and Reservists who own or may own small business concerns;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id1588e767-94ab-414e-ba72-0a9890108127"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for an applicant for initial financial assistance under this subsection—</text>
 <subclause id="id8784e636-73eb-44ed-bf89-d2e0b2e34e03"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the ability of the applicant to begin operating a veterans' business outreach center within a minimum amount of time; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id4a2818b4-9d74-48a1-b5a8-69c49dbe2dfb"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the geographic region to be served by the veterans' business outreach center;</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="idf50b063d-de84-4006-b447-f6014d139537"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the demonstrated ability of the applicant to—</text>
 <subclause id="ide5016a82-7f8f-427c-857d-9497c70cf96b"><enum>(I)</enum><text>provide managerial counseling and technical assistance to entrepreneurs; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id16faeec5-9377-4931-84e0-4f051a63e9a8"><enum>(II)</enum><text>coordinate services provided by veterans service organizations and other public or private entities;</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="idb3fa660c-e444-4242-afd2-1d36330166a3"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the demonstrated ability to leverage and coordinate with existing resources and infrastructure of the Administration; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id4B16B9CA7BA542B48E27F74EBF244C44"><enum>(v)</enum><text>for any applicant for a renewal of financial assistance under this subsection, the results of the most recent examination under paragraph (11) of the veterans' business outreach center operated by the applicant.</text>
								</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id29d7d82a-db29-4d28-b9b2-e333ae945ead"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Criteria
 publicly available</header><text>The Associate Administrator shall—</text> <clause id="ida5b719c4-e7b9-4b2a-b208-40e1819f4e25"><enum>(i)</enum><text>make publicly available the selection criteria established under this paragraph;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idf5db31e0-380d-4843-9031-c9d13d8d6ad8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>include the criteria in each solicitation for applications for financial assistance under this subsection;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idac787483a6f84e0192a6066129615909"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>make every effort to ensure regional accessibility and geographic representation in awarding financial assistance under this subsection; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id272685b3c94d48c3afb11f42bbdc8cc9"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>to the extent practicable, make publicly available the approximate anticipated date for the determination of award recipients by the Administration and the anticipated timing of disbursement.</text>
								</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idaa680aa8-3a08-49b8-8fbf-7b82a08b084b"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Amount of
 assistance</header><text>The amount of financial assistance provided under this subsection to an entity for each fiscal year shall be not less than $100,000.</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="id218effbe-354e-4ba7-90df-2b94f056a5ff"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Federal
				share</header>
							<subparagraph id="id4064eea2-fbf8-4b1c-a3c6-860c141e8e13"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In
				general</header>
								<clause id="idd93798d0-3904-4ec6-86d1-dfd6470ff2e1"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Initial
 financial assistance</header><text>Except as provided in clause (ii) and subparagraph (E), an entity that receives financial assistance under this subsection shall provide non-Federal contributions for the operation of the veterans' business outreach center established by the entity in an amount equal to—</text>
 <subclause id="id59523185-852e-49df-a9b7-00b5211cb2f7"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in each of the first and second years of the project, not less than 33 percent of the amount of the financial assistance received under this subsection; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id9a3e2422-9b83-4fe1-ae6c-f235f032aa6c"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in each of the third through fifth years of the project, not less than 50 percent of the amount of the financial assistance received under this subsection.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="id2d50e6e1-30d7-46d7-b538-3a7abb581226"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Renewals</header><text>An entity that receives a renewal of financial assistance under this subsection shall provide non-Federal contributions for the operation of the veterans' business outreach center established by the entity in an amount equal to not less than 50 percent of the amount of the financial assistance received under this subsection.</text>
								</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb8289b90-8ded-4593-85db-c86e48c0b699"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Form of
 non-federal share</header><text>Not more than 50 percent of the non-Federal share for a project carried out using financial assistance under this subsection may be in the form of in-kind contributions.</text>
							</subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddda060b7-7596-4df2-85da-f56b99f4d201"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Timing of
 disbursement</header><text>The Associate Administrator may disburse not more than 25 percent of the financial assistance awarded to an entity before the entity obtains the non-Federal share required under this paragraph with respect to that award.</text>
							</subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id956a54da-0fbd-415f-a930-aba208f4466d"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Failure to
				obtain non-federal funding</header>
								<clause commented="no" id="id5e2b9a87-66ab-44e2-8a97-47cac1086cd2"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>If an entity that receives financial assistance under this subsection fails to obtain the non-Federal share required under this paragraph during 2 consecutive fiscal years, the entity may not receive a disbursement under this subsection in a subsequent fiscal year or a disbursement for any other project funded by the Administration, unless the Administrator makes a written determination that the entity will be able to obtain a non-Federal contribution.</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="ide6c919f8-e172-47a0-9708-6d8306be21d4"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Restoration</header><text>An entity prohibited from receiving a disbursement under clause (i) in a fiscal year may receive financial assistance in a subsequent fiscal year if the entity obtains the non-Federal share required under this paragraph for the subsequent fiscal year.</text>
								</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB87D620898DF40D7B5F9AF725A469CAB"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Waiver of
				non-Federal share</header>
								<clause id="idE74170DCC5824CEBA7587C7B957636CD"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>Upon request by an entity, and in accordance with this subparagraph, the Administrator may waive, in whole or in part, the requirement to obtain non-Federal funds under subparagraph (A) for a fiscal year. The Administrator may not waive the requirement for an entity to obtain non-Federal funds under this subparagraph for more than a total of 2 fiscal years.</text>
 </clause><clause id="id31CA94961E334656A1D1AF3AF9FA2385"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In determining whether to waive the requirement to obtain non-Federal funds under this subparagraph, the Administrator shall consider—</text>
 <subclause id="id986E88DD4FD64D55A06AB86A050A9E2A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the economic conditions affecting the entity;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id50BC515AABBF4E9189400BFBFA708608"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the impact a waiver under this subparagraph would have on the credibility of the veterans' business outreach center program;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idF9C7B5743BF94750A3C9F12AC3AE615B"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the demonstrated ability of the entity to raise non-Federal funds; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id898D400F11CF4457B98201D97EA570AC"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the performance of the entity.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="id36F0D9A8611D4A4AA8EE6F4CB6E521EE"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The Administrator may not waive the requirement to obtain non-Federal funds under this subparagraph if granting the waiver would undermine the credibility of the veterans' business outreach center program.</text>
								</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id7BDFE7BEAA9940BEBDF015393C3B27B6"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Affiliation with small business development centers</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="id839A290321B747908DE44F5B26B67D17"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An entity receiving financial assistance under this subsection shall enter into an agreement to affiliate with a small business development center for purposes of carrying out the activities of the entity using the financial assistance.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id35A5D9C87851482EADD5B523A7DD8A00"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Consistency with agreement</header><text>The terms of an agreement to affiliate under subparagraph (A) shall be in accordance with the terms of any agreement between the applicable small business development center and the Administration.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ida765bf0bba074e349fc8ec3c381fe1cd"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Contract authority</header><text>A veterans’ business outreach center may enter into a contract with a Federal department or agency to provide specific assistance to veterans, service-disabled veterans, Reservists, or the spouses of members of the Armed Forces on active duty, veterans, service-disabled veterans, or Reservists with prior written approval of the Associate Administrator. Performance of such contract shall not hinder the veterans’ business outreach center in carrying out the terms of the grant received by the veterans’ business outreach center from the Administrator.</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="ideeecf13141854a1984456f4f02f3d678"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Examination and determination of performance</header>
							<subparagraph id="id0731cd4b5bb74e1b84bd8a49ce681614"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Examination</header>
 <clause id="id0ad2fa1a19844e4994bd4c368b04d310"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this subsection and every year thereafter, the Associate Administrator shall conduct an annual examination of the programs and finances of each veterans’ business outreach center established or operated using financial assistance under this subsection.</text>
 </clause><clause id="id7300057a-d6e6-4f9f-9a29-ffe6f2124daf"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Factors</header><text>In conducting the examination under clause (i), the Associate Administrator shall consider whether the veterans' business outreach center has failed—</text>
 <subclause id="id837f31ce-56af-4bd3-a52a-46946b42ff06"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to provide the information required to be provided under subparagraph (B), or the information provided by the center is inadequate;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idd4c49564-a71a-4429-86a2-b0f36de66a5c"><enum>(II)</enum><text>to comply with a requirement for participation in the veterans' business outreach center program, as determined by the Associate Administrator, including—</text>
 <item id="id82aa4ef3-56e6-4334-9a21-ebf76155bb9d"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>failure to acquire or properly document a non-Federal share;</text>
 </item><item id="id319f5cf5-238a-4aa5-81ce-fc5227ff8890"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>failure to establish an appropriate partnership or program for marketing and outreach to small business concerns;</text>
 </item><item id="idcc13cbca-97be-4f65-ae02-2014fcadab3b"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>failure to achieve results described in a financial assistance agreement; and</text>
 </item><item id="id68377214-f153-4680-b5c0-3b0230eef07d"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>failure to provide to the Administrator a description of the amount and sources of any non-Federal funding received by the center;</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause id="ide12dbd94-ec82-4d79-834c-20d17eefe35a"><enum>(III)</enum><text>to carry out the 5-year plan under in paragraph (4)(B);</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idb2fbf260-754e-40ea-87a3-e4c5864f15d2"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>to meet the eligibility requirements under paragraph (5); or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idcddc4f873e1a420a989f42a50d7498dd"><enum>(V)</enum><text>to serve small business concerns in the geographic region served by the veterans' business outreach center.</text>
									</subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id96d9cf51-8fac-4147-b6c2-eccf9718ad3b"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Information
 provided</header><text>In the course of an examination under subparagraph (A), the veterans' business outreach center shall provide to the Associate Administrator—</text>
 <clause id="id0cab7c22-5776-4370-92ef-01f12e2b806b"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an itemized cost breakdown of actual expenditures for costs incurred during the most recent full fiscal year, including the amount spent on administrative expenses;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id3b821cc4-0b13-4945-8979-09f3c8b2f456"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>documentation of the amount of non-Federal contributions obtained and expended by the veterans' business outreach center during the most recent full fiscal year;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idcfd5dff9-63e7-43a9-bd4f-c351a124ffb8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>with respect to any in-kind contribution under paragraph (8)(B), verification of the existence and valuation of such contribution; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id81213AEFC7494E4BB282FC9793C87AEC"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>any additional information the Associate Administrator determines necessary.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id025c5986-1441-4d11-ba2c-85b97784d328"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Determination of performance</header> <clause id="id37AB220DC9C044A18B708362EF3625BB"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Associate Administrator shall analyze the results of each examination under subparagraph (A) and, based on that analysis, make a determination regarding the performance of the programs and finances of each veterans' business outreach center.</text>
 </clause><clause id="idC080F376942D45C0BAA9CA511A300E34"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Nondelegation of determination</header><text>The duty under clause (i) to make a determination regarding the performance of the programs and finances of a veterans' business outreach center may not be delegated.</text>
								</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0d7c879f-0df5-4523-a734-b7b658ecb36d"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Discontinuation
				of funding</header>
								<clause id="id82095363-382a-41b2-a355-5a04188c2e2e"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>The Associate Administrator may discontinue an award of financial assistance to an entity at any time for poor performance as determined under subparagraph (C).</text>
 </clause><clause id="idaf77e7b8-c20a-44d5-8cde-1e071897dea8"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Restoration</header><text>The Associate Administrator may continue to provide financial assistance to an entity in a subsequent fiscal year if the Associate Administrator determines under subparagraph (C) that the veterans' business outreach center has taken appropriate measures to improve its performance and it is viable.</text>
								</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0fba5254-feb5-4a53-b4b8-8268bc74c55a"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Coordination
				of efforts and consultation</header>
							<subparagraph id="id1465e84d-dfc5-438d-a8bb-439e08575af8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Coordination
 and consultation</header><text>To the extent practicable, the Associate Administrator and each entity that receives financial assistance under this subsection shall—</text>
 <clause id="id3d6a180a-e023-4b48-a209-4052716fa474"><enum>(i)</enum><text>coordinate outreach and other activities with other programs of the Administration and the programs of other Federal agencies, including programs at local facilities of the Department of Veterans Affairs;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id6eed48ea-fa6a-444e-9d6b-d9e0322bf0ea"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>consult with technical representatives of the district offices of the Administration in carrying out activities using financial assistance under this subsection; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id1e8cebaa-a4a9-4d05-b67c-a9542f960675"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>provide information to the veterans business development officers designated under subparagraph (B) and coordinate with the veterans business development officers to increase the ability of the veterans business development officers to provide services throughout the area served by the veterans business development officers.</text>
								</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2ec48124-62f3-4099-a378-445c28717324"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Veterans
				business development officers</header>
 <clause id="id2cf30cf0-c0f9-440c-9215-cb496da68e0c"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Designation</header><text>The Administrator shall designate not fewer than 1 individual in each district office of the Administration as a veterans business development officer, who shall communicate and coordinate activities of the district office with entities that receive financial assistance under this subsection.</text>
								</clause><clause id="id264adf7f-4806-4b6c-9e6f-540acfbb113c"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Initial
 designation</header><text>The first individual in each district office of the Administration designated by the Administrator as a veterans business development officer under clause (i) shall be an individual that is employed by the Administration on the date of enactment of this subsection.</text>
								</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id3a892bc0-1a71-42ce-9471-d30a5c423c81"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Existing
 contracts</header><text>An award of financial assistance under this subsection shall not void any contract or cooperative agreement between any entity and the Administration or grant to any entity from the Administration that is in effect on the date of such award.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id78B7F58099DE46D39E0671D74E25D6C6"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Online Coordination</header>
 <paragraph id="id8acfe3d1-94af-443c-bcb9-95b3ed2c6efb"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>veterans' assistance provider</term> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id669350a5-54e5-4cf1-bfda-ba097cd82eb6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a veterans' business outreach center established under subsection (g);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf78759bc-e279-445b-a64c-3803c7fa8b4f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an employee of the Administration assigned to the Office of Veterans Business Development; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id660e0805-6904-445d-ba55-4929a0c80287"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a veterans business development officer designated under subsection (g)(12)(B).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idbb5a3712-5db3-418d-8184-ce9fb74ef99e"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Associate Administrator shall establish an online mechanism to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id8c4fc24a-cecb-41a5-b168-f43dcbe81f68"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide information that assists veterans' assistance providers in carrying out the activities of the veterans' assistance providers; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6bc3ebb4-d8e5-41c9-818d-b5ddc8ff6387"><enum>(B)</enum><text>coordinate and leverage the work of the veterans' assistance providers, including by allowing a veterans' assistance provider to—</text>
 <clause id="id32603791-6b2b-4a5b-9808-797e7fd8cb83"><enum>(i)</enum><text>distribute best practices and other materials;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id079bc919-f12e-4fc1-9d61-4f1031b02524"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>communicate with other veterans' assistance providers regarding the activities of the veterans' assistance provider on behalf of veterans; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="ide2adaead-66f7-4469-a7a1-0848a6a0bfb4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>pose questions to and request input from other veterans' assistance providers.</text>
								</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id13d454bb-7e33-4d6e-86d1-1f8473821453"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Authorization
 of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated for each of fiscal years 2016 through 2020—</text>
 <paragraph id="id0AA4C96081FD4E43832012E2FB0ABABD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$2,500,000 to carry out subsection (g); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idF562E4BC67CE42CBBD7CCF2EF8FCA74C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$8,000,000 to carry out subsections (d), (e), and (f).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id051e0f0168b04c52b132ca4d9b406daf"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Prohibition on overseas travel</header><text>Financial assistance made available under this section may not be used to subsidize travel outside of the United States (as defined in section 202(a)(7) of the State Department Basic Authorities Act of 1956 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/4302">22 U.S.C. 4302(a)(7)</external-xref>)).</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idCF03ADB445C841648D28993CD03129AA"><enum>(k)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this subsection and every year thereafter, the Associate Administrator shall submit to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship of the Senate and the Committee on Small Business of the House of Representatives a report on the performance and effectiveness for the programs authorized under this section, which may be included as part of another report submitted to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship of the Senate and the Committee on Small Business of the House of Representatives by the Associate Administrator, and which shall include the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="id0c2080ea6dcd46ca84107ef5a011e592"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Boots to business</header><text>For the Boots to Business Program under subsection (d)—</text> <subparagraph id="id8e0e36b2eba449738ca824ca525d769c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of program participants using each component of the Boots to Business Program;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbac80cf70f0041629da1f5aa902b276a"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the completion rates for each component of the Boots to Business Program;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb2f9d43230654105ac4ecd4475474de7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to the extent possible—</text>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8e39bf1e829a47fc810c20623a72beb3"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the demographics of program participants, to include gender, age, race, relationship to military, Military Occupational Code, and years of service of program participants;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id368baee7f7dd45ac821548261b26534d"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the number of small business concerns formed or expanded with assistance under the Boots to Business Program;</text>
 </clause><clause id="ide3c73aef41b542d28e8b209c8ff304f6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the gross receipts of small business concerns receiving assistance under the Boots to Business Program;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id1a7aced0a9e44743b68dd3559ef522a6"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the number of jobs created with assistance under the Boots to Business Program;</text> </clause><clause id="id75105453dffc4c2abcc3d0a1377a08d2"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the number of referrals to other resources and programs of the Administration;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idf6460cc20562475fb84af06705701438"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the number of program participants receiving financial assistance under loan programs of the Administration;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idfa04c9a5b429480593faf86af8c44f97"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>the type and dollar amount of financial assistance received by program participants under loan programs of the Administration; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="ide0833a90f7f64a3e9e2245ca9eb1427e"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>results of participant satisfaction surveys, including a summary of any comments received from program participants;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7f095631113d451a983b36a01ea167ce"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an evaluation of the effectiveness of the program in each region of the Administration during the most recent fiscal year;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3e4c21605c084ff391358ea0f808ef66"><enum>(E)</enum><text>an assessment of additional performance outcome measures for the Boots to Business Program, as identified by the Associate Administrator;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id287ac344dd514f54a683046552ebbf24"><enum>(F)</enum><text>any recommendations of the Administrator for improvement of the Boots to Business Program, which may include expansion of the types of individuals who are covered individuals;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2fd17c0d1f5c4db2b2e9c0d168881fb2"><enum>(G)</enum><text>an explanation of how the Boots to Business Program has been integrated with other transition programs and related resources of the Administration and other Federal agencies; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida7db8a486cde46479a361a695dc197e1"><enum>(H)</enum><text>any additional information the Administrator determines necessary.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id8bb84fcb373f4d2780fe948eb3167d5c"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Women Veterans Business Training Program</header><text>For the Women Veterans Business Training Program under subsection (e)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id187d745cc05b451a8b2ff9ecdbda2e7f"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of program participants using each component of the Women Veterans Business Training Program;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc2bd3b50622e4bcfb5a286a2f2318ead"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the completion rates for each component of the Women Veterans Business Training Program;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id71B338AD4A404720B5FEDABCEBF7B336"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to the extent possible—</text>
 <clause id="id06ac2ed254b64e9b87da5b0f102f4c05"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the demographics of program participants, to include gender, age, race, relationship to military, and years of service;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id3d83b34885484d0688e1f88212360699"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the number of small business concerns formed or expanded with assistance under the Women Veterans Business Training Program;</text>
 </clause><clause id="ide76b63f590e847f293a1a6435198f728"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the gross receipts of small business concerns receiving assistance under the Women Veterans Business Training Program;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id9c9b16d6c7ce44cab6674572372282e1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the number of jobs created with assistance under the Women Veterans Business Training Program;</text> </clause><clause id="id2742c2c8aa3d4345befb994f5957800f"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the number of referrals to other resources and programs of the Administration;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id2f176a61a5d142a68428096f97b57717"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the number of referrals from other resources and programs of the Administration and other Federal agencies;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id21c563913dbd4859bd2eb9ad79a7e2ef"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>the number of program participants receiving financial assistance under loan programs of the Administration;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id771489aadb5b41f98607acd6164d1aef"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>the type and dollar amount of financial assistance received by program participants under loan programs of the Administration; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id64489d49ddb040aa92aed3bf6dc2bc63"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>the results of participant satisfaction surveys, including a summary of any comments received from program participants;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id378ddb416b7c49c19a7d46fcf6da191a"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an assessment of additional performance outcome measures for the Women Veterans Business Training Program, as identified by the Associate Administrator;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id85099eddda294512aa29619e8223a79f"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any recommendations of the Administrator for improvement of the Women Veterans Business Training Program;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id52032ef47ec142599b6fb6b539274d75"><enum>(F)</enum><text>an explanation of how the Women Veterans Business Training Program has been integrated with other transition programs and related resources of the Administration and other Federal agencies; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc5e3b349a44d429b8e0d60b422038fda"><enum>(G)</enum><text>any additional information the Administrator determines necessary.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0f89968f2b8c4e3081313cfefa3cf4a7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Business Training Program for Service Disabled Veterans</header><text>For the Business Training Program for Service Disabled Veterans under subsection (f)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id4f3117822cc1412a8162fc31bd556c2a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of program participants using each component of the Business Training Program for Service Disabled Veterans;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2dcf9a3ccb7142e397ddc0a11e287328"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the completion rates for each component of the Business Training Program for Service Disabled Veterans;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbf6b741824ec43028f8ba30d80ee1559"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to the extent possible—</text> <clause id="id4a6897331ff64317b8a0fc4ff02517c9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the demographics of program participants, to include gender, age, race, relationship to military, and years of service;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id3cc9bc00dfe245938506f561c4e86297"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the number of small business concerns formed or expanded with assistance under the Business Training Program for Service Disabled Veterans;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id8ad9ba79e2e84a339bee1c7e0612b076"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the gross receipts of small business concerns receiving assistance under the Business Training Program for Service Disabled Veterans;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id19efd4114ede434d853f9fe0d6c61dcd"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the number of jobs created with assistance under the Business Training Program for Service Disabled Veterans;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id48e4999c118a4610b5ab0b41155e2ea2"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the number of referrals to other resources and programs of the Administration;</text> </clause><clause id="idbbbe4f8629aa4518b576e634325c02f8"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the number of referrals from other resources and programs of the Administration and other Federal agencies;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id689a0d908fd84eaba9f88394676a7bc0"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>the number of program participants receiving financial assistance under loan programs of the Administration;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id23cbd141b70d46469b7a0d0350b6140b"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>the type and dollar amount of financial assistance received by program participants under loan programs of the Administration; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id5c939b2cc7e94bf29776197a7bec8c6d"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>the results of participant satisfaction surveys, including a summary of any comments received from program participants;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbaa47f6ea33347fb96131d4e2ccd91cf"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an assessment of additional performance outcome measures for the Business Training Program for Service Disabled Veterans, as identified by the Associate Administrator;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id85b94f8680c54254b34797f9892c877b"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any recommendations of the Administrator for improvement of the Business Training Program for Service Disabled Veterans;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6dfae01311884575b706a8914bc6e3fd"><enum>(F)</enum><text>an explanation of how the Business Training Program for Service Disabled Veterans has been integrated with other transition programs and related resources of the Administration and other Federal agencies; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide1a2f12ece884ebaad3cdc5b830aa8a3"><enum>(G)</enum><text>any additional information the Administrator determines necessary.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9ef8125ae8c44ff6a4e1cfc0ca445ce2"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Veteran's business outreach center program</header><text>For the veterans’ business outreach center program under subsection (g)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id838e1394f117412681b024a0e259e8b1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an evaluation of the effectiveness of the veterans’ business outreach center program in each region of the Administration during the most recent full fiscal year;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id750b29490d234474875db7a21b1977d1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for each veterans’ business outreach center established or operated using financial assistance provided under subsection (g)—</text>
 <clause id="idc49947c7de43460fbc24fdbf8b318b9f"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number of individuals receiving assistance from the veterans’ business outreach center, including the number of such individuals who are—</text>
 <subclause id="idc2726156469e45139449c2a985fd8578"><enum>(I)</enum><text>veterans or spouses of veterans;</text> </subclause><subclause id="idd3aa62e73d38470abdff20f8511041a4"><enum>(II)</enum><text>service-disabled veterans or spouses of service-disabled veterans;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idadf3616594cc458bb1a47d4ff4920a2e"><enum>(III)</enum><text>Reservists or spouses of Reservists; or</text> </subclause><subclause id="idc8817eb05ca64473b6c7fe8a97c4c062"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>spouses of members of the Armed Forces on active duty;</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="id98a58fe0e1dc4744a22bf786da58b682"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the average distance traveled by veterans to access services at the veterans' business outreach center;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id8c6f749ce1644434b52dad7ace88e05f"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the number of small business concerns formed by individuals receiving assistance from the veterans’ business outreach center, including—</text>
 <subclause id="id5b2c3aded85a4f63ab62512dc6f62317"><enum>(I)</enum><text>veterans or spouses of veterans;</text> </subclause><subclause id="ide52ad8d19d4848c390f47ff159eb7b91"><enum>(II)</enum><text>service-disabled veterans or spouses of service-disabled veterans;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idaaabbc0910934568956d95cedc2e71a5"><enum>(III)</enum><text>Reservists or spouses of Reservists; or</text> </subclause><subclause id="id07b4231c57bc417d9b034120e73661de"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>spouses of members of the Armed Forces on active duty; and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="idfd27f5bae14941a58866636e5137d42e"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>to the extent possible—</text> <subclause id="id26571a801fe844b78a5898ae1b582ac0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the gross receipts of small business concerns receiving assistance from the veterans’ business outreach center;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idfe4590f4194e4bdba70764af93ca48e7"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the employment increases or decreases of small business concerns receiving assistance from the veterans’ business outreach center;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id0471ffc0b45a4fdc8401d8c4de0ff0cc"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the increases or decreases in profits of small business concerns receiving assistance from the veterans’ business outreach center;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idd97e0ee7be004a5397bcc6a7b82ec677"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the number of referrals by the veterans’ business outreach center to other resources and programs of the Administration;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idf51510af99ce4d5bb86f60ac5212bfc9"><enum>(V)</enum><text>the results of satisfaction surveys, including a summary of any comments received from small business concerns receiving assistance from the veterans’ business outreach center;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id8c33060a8ee441ddbe96410a4f06773e"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>the number of small business concerns receiving assistance from the veterans’ business outreach center that received financial assistance under loan programs of the Administration;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id813a2d443d2243b0a7971c11f90647fb"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>the type and dollar amount of financial assistance received under loan programs of the Administration by small business concerns receiving assistance from the veterans’ business outreach center;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idba002130e5994e9cb406644a553ed361"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text>the number of small business concerns receiving assistance from the veterans’ business outreach center that obtained a Federal contract through a small business contracting program;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id41f08530e98844dfa9e3384a2990df3d"><enum>(IX)</enum><text>the type and dollar amount of the Federal contracts awarded to small business concerns receiving assistance from the veterans' business outreach center;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id1cbff3781d2e48d593538e6cfe255ea5"><enum>(X)</enum><text>an assessment of additional performance outcome measures for the veterans’ business outreach center, as identified by the Associate Administrator; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id434d5d5ddcef4aa7a9c4a24fd0522002"><enum>(XI)</enum><text>the results of the examination of the veterans’ business outreach center under subsection (g)(10);</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3bddbc36153245d9b291ab1b5d1cd0b1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any recommendations of the Administrator for improvement of the veterans’ business outreach center program;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id04103dbcbad84b209ae0bdc04b17c08f"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an explanation of how the veterans’ business outreach center program has been integrated with other transition programs and related resources of the Administration and other Federal agencies; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id501bb36eb8af42878a98098ad5ce2a4d"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any additional information the Administrator determines necessary.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id93a5e2a727f24fe9b13983c7cdffbd91"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Other activities and programs administered by the office of veterans business development</header><text>An evaluation of the effectiveness of any other activities and programs administered by the Office of Veterans Business Development, including using the metrics identified in paragraphs (1) through (4).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="id4E5FF4056D464973A8DAC07DD1F19955"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Federal share for existing program</header>
 <paragraph id="idC433A6C58E9A4AFFA06334D30CCB526A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>existing award</term> means an award made under the Veterans’ Business Outreach Center Program of the Small Business Administration before the date of enactment of this Act that is in effect on the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="id567C4EFB3BB646038FCAC93FC7C23D5E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception from provision on failure to
 obtain non-Federal funding</header><text>During the 2-year period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act, subsection (g)(8)(D) of section 32 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/657b">15 U.S.C. 657b</external-xref>), as added by subsection (a), shall not apply to an existing award.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id895956bb-4b74-4967-9551-0b90c67ca3be"><enum>(c)</enum><header>GAO
			 Reports</header>
 <paragraph id="id6a7471e0-020b-4bb0-93d5-cfe7fc6d081a"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id05f4a0a0-fbc0-4e46-b96a-f80292e08041"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the term <term>covered individual</term> means—</text> <clause id="idD5288AEB4CA54206A36F6C83A9D6E55A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a veteran;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id65A5964355A047129AEAFC5E9F362E9F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a service-disabled veteran;</text> </clause><clause id="idDFEFD6DF467C474D83AF90C1729A7D07"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a Reservist;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idBBBADF933D1A4FAAB569C439F2A82AE9"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the spouse of an individual described in clause (i), (ii), or (iii); or</text> </clause><clause id="idD2AF57077F3046DEAF8A3DA039DCB25B"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the spouse of a member of the Armed Forces;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idFC5B84DA14D64C00A83E86185BFAA6EA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the terms <term>Reservist</term>, <term>small business concern owned and controlled by veterans</term>, and <term>veterans’ business outreach center program</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 32(g) of the Small Business Act, as added by subsection (a); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id17AAED6287404838B1A2928B51716711"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the terms <term>service-disabled veteran</term>, <term>small business concern</term>, and <term>veteran</term> have the meanings given those terms under section 3 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/632">15 U.S.C. 632</external-xref>).</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idB1ED0E6495E34045883CD2D369AA04C2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report on
			 access to credit</header>
					<subparagraph id="id5703F43BD5FB41BE83AC54BE4FCECDDB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit a report regarding the ability of small business concerns owned and controlled by covered individuals to access credit to—</text>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE0FF84A4E2AD4DB087045B420C0A9A3A"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Veterans' Affairs and the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship of the Senate; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3274D3C4B2D74F0889974EB8EDFA9453"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Veterans' Affairs and the Committee on Small Business of the House of Representatives.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idDF54250F0FBB42BB975E805F299ADE77"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report submitted under subparagraph (A) shall include an analysis of—</text>
 <clause id="IDd8319f6410554bba93cf2f32f7588daf"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the sources of credit used by small business concerns owned and controlled by covered individuals and the percentage of the credit obtained by small business concerns owned and controlled by covered individuals that is obtained from each source;</text>
 </clause><clause id="ID035ca3975af24701a345cf5c4a36f532"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the default rate for small business concerns owned and controlled by covered individuals separately for each source of credit described in clause (i), as compared to the default rate for the source of credit for small business concerns generally;</text>
 </clause><clause id="ID7b91b164f85f4c05ae38a774a26c729b"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the Federal lending programs available to provide credit to small business concerns owned and controlled by covered individuals;</text>
 </clause><clause id="IDbf83d22646ba4b37a3cf4025cea29958"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>gaps, if any, in the availability of credit for small business concerns owned and controlled by covered individuals that are not being filled by the Federal Government or private sources;</text>
 </clause><clause id="IDb4df05b0f6fa47a4939a157ae34d5d78"><enum>(v)</enum><text>obstacles faced by covered individuals in trying to access credit;</text>
 </clause><clause id="ID946e25f203e14452b6a3f7cdf1014b69"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the extent to which deployment and other military responsibilities affect the credit history of veterans and Reservists; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="ID632aeaa1530f419f8573d35826982e79"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>the extent to which covered individuals are aware of Federal programs targeted towards helping covered individuals access credit.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id3e3344b0-2347-4e5a-aea2-f0059beff116"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report on
			 veterans’ business outreach center program</header>
					<subparagraph id="id6ce32c20-311a-439c-a9bc-73cc552421a5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the end of the second fiscal year beginning after the date on which the veterans’ business outreach center program is established, the Comptroller General of the United States shall evaluate the effectiveness of the veterans’ business outreach center program, and submit to Congress a report on the results of that evaluation.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id18e7b7c7-2dbc-46ce-8469-b116558eca56"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report submitted under subparagraph (A) shall include—</text>
 <clause id="idf2efc901-3807-49be-8c9f-787a459d8e00"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an assessment of—</text>
 <subclause id="id9eda3a3a-762b-45f3-a9e7-81e63c66ace7"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the use of amounts made available to carry out the veterans’ business outreach center program;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id1f28b4b2-2adb-4be2-9b84-b23e69516f07"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the effectiveness of the services provided by each entity receiving financial assistance under the veterans’ business outreach center program;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id69727f78-44a4-4aef-87c6-77f75c6f0f0d"><enum>(III)</enum><text>whether the services described in subclause (II) are duplicative of services provided by other veterans service organizations, programs of the Small Business Administration, or programs of another Federal department or agency and, if so, recommendations regarding how to alleviate the duplication of the services;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id6c0e1c96-3bb0-4330-b3d3-e75dbc1ef3a1"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>whether there are areas of the United States in which there are not adequate entrepreneurial services for small business concerns owned and controlled by veterans and, if so, whether there is a veterans' business outreach center established under the veterans’ business outreach center program providing services to that area; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id3de3c31b09274a56958d2641dc51d54f"><enum>(V)</enum><text>whether there is a correlation between the proximity of a veterans’ business outreach center to small business concerns owned and controlled by veterans and the rate of the use of the services of the veterans’ business outreach center; and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id529ba3e6-016c-4997-a416-8bbb058ec238"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>recommendations, if any, for improving the veterans’ business outreach center program.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id52FB0B4A902D44E0922E059CB0115164"><enum>3.</enum><header>Improvements to business development and entrepreneurial programs</header>
 <subsection id="id8995CA1D4B2142F6BD1FC81068B1955D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text> <paragraph id="id3C66EDB03DEC4AD99086E585F62BDAA6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the terms <term>Administration</term> and <term>Administrator</term> mean the Small Business Administration and the Administrator thereof, respectively;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idF757F6DE205B45F0A88AFCA3FB783189"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>individual eligible for a veteran entrepreneurial development program</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="idd6483221c1a6406a9f907cb931ff3351"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a covered individual, as defined in section 32(d)(1) of the Small Business Act, as amended by section 2;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id372417ce3296409b9991e6733242018e"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a covered individual, as defined in section 32(e)(1) of the Small Business Act, as amended by section 2;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id86789500465a46d59047626097f521b3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a service-disabled veteran, as defined in section 3(q)(1) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/632">15 U.S.C. 632(q)(1)</external-xref>); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id43e3ea6ddafc4d7aab7d7d5d5e28ebfe"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an individual who qualifies to be the owner of a small business concern owned and controlled by veterans, as defined in section 32(g)(1)(C) of the Small Business Act, as amended by section 2;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id4B12F6720247415387D8FBFF396A97E1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>one-stop resource</term> means the one-stop online resource established under subsection (c)(1); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id47F86690B9F24CAD8914B6284BFA0BF0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the term <term>small business concern</term> has the meaning given that term under section 3 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/632">15 U.S.C. 632</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id7947E48C92F44B43B24ED975F9C357FD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Veteran peer-to-Peer networks</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall establish guidelines to improve the network of peer-to-peer counseling and mentoring for individuals eligible for a veteran entrepreneurial development program relating to the business development and entrepreneurial programs of the Administration.</text>
			</subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2dde3bd5f60045dcb6320c91fbbca24e"><enum>(c)</enum><header>One-Stop online resource</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7958DA2D142546F9AA58E9CCA7DB324F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall establish an online mechanism that serves as a one-stop online resource for veterans regarding all of the entrepreneurial development programs of the Administration.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idD613428EA9944C43B8D19E57843DB472"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The one-stop resource shall include descriptions of each entrepreneurial program of the Administration (which shall include the programs described in paragraph (3)), including—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id08174399B54D497E9F8F516A49D156CE"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">target client descriptions for each program;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0F5E277769E04F1EA48C01B3450120E9"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">contact information for information on or assistance regarding each program from locally, State-wide, and nationally available sources;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB7FCA03C13BC4AD18DEE2555B88C8803"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a detailed description of the services available under each program;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id983BCAA01C8140FA9DB9185F720317C5"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of any costs associated with the services under each program;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id41278903459A4BD69C2A9BE008FDEF40"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an outline of program curriculums if training seminars or courses are offered; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idCC7E580EFDF443DE9BADE48830D292AB"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">other resource information that the Administrator determines appropriate and necessary for veteran entrepreneurs and veterans who own small business concerns, in order to ensure the one-stop online resource provides information and resources necessary for a veteran beginning to develop a small business concern.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1212559C53144449A39103FC3256A793"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Programs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The programs identified and described under the one-stop resource shall include—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idA66F840021A44050A768944ECDCC0E77"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the small business development center program under section 21 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/648">15 U.S.C. 648</external-xref>);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4600F06F45A341BCA4C17D30D8A0C953"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the women's business center program under section 29 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/656">15 U.S.C. 656</external-xref>);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idFD48F6BC151049D7B60A692A520D38F5"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the programs of the Office of Entrepreneurship Education of the Administration;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id156B3BA77EBE455199F56B1FDBF56C88"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Boots to Business Program under section 32(d) of the Small Business Act, as amended by section 2(a) of this Act;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id75AC8D00E39247F48A2D356BCC058656"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the veterans’ business outreach center program under section 32(e) of the Small Business Act, as amended by section 2(a) of this Act;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idDFF8A84AF3664D16AF16329FE2435AC0"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the Service Corps of Retired Executives program authorized by section 8(b)(1) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/637">15 U.S.C. 637(b)(1)</external-xref>); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB7425C76169B49CAADBB89CF3CF1214E"><enum>(G)</enum><text>any other program of the Administration determined appropriate by the Administrator.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id0d4226cd-5e74-4287-be6e-3aa442a27724"><enum>4.</enum><header>Reporting requirement for interagency task force</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 32(c) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/657b">15 U.S.C. 657b(c)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2f6991db-2135-4698-9968-65b5a3c50187" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="idf1f2f8e9-a412-4dbd-a185-a9edba3d254a"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not less frequently than once each year, the Administrator shall submit to Congress a report—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idE0996872A1034A459BF7AAD4BF2E1476"><enum>(A)</enum><text>discussing the appointments made to and activities of the task force; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idC999718EC4774159855ADBC3502E8826"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identifying and outlining a plan for outreach and promotion of all the programs authorized under the <short-title>Veterans Small Business Development Act of 2015</short-title>, or an amendment made by that Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="idAA4A52C05C454745BBD9155736D13D9E"><enum>5.</enum><header>Educational training</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 8(b) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/637">15 U.S.C. 637(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="id3A6DE8466D044B19ADDC547B937E011F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (16), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id0A303B316C984576BF3DC87158257496"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (17), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id302A649DE07F4C5FAC7B9F62E91A02A9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF475DD4688C8470393AD655B385F07B2" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="id58928c4bbadf40e9ad5ed00d2bc976a6"><enum>(18)</enum><text>to make a grant to, or enter into a cooperative agreement with, a nonprofit entity to operate an educational training program to provide assistance to small business concerns owned and controlled by veterans regarding how to increase the likelihood of being awarded contracts with the Federal Government—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id882F09281FD24A719C5AC939D906A606"><enum>(A)</enum><text>which shall be made to or entered into with a nonprofit entity that has a track record of successfully providing educational and job training services to targeted veterans populations in diverse locations;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5924A9FE606B4B3FA6FB30A2615D7C1E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>under which the nonprofit entity shall be required to match any Federal funds received for the program with State, local, or private sector funds; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id012622E50251454FB22F4049C38E3ED7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>under which the nonprofit entity shall use a diverse group of professional service experts, such as Federal, State, and local contracting experts and private sector industry experts with first-hand experience in Federal Government contracting, to provide instruction to small business concerns owned and controlled by veterans.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


