<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1612 IS: Safe Skies Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-06-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1612</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150618">June 18, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S223">Mrs. Boxer</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S275">Ms. Cantwell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S332">Mr. Franken</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Secretary of Transportation to modify the final rule relating to flightcrew member
			 duty and rest requirements for passenger operations of air carriers to
			 apply to all-cargo operations of air carriers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HEF5EAC376D4E412D8CCB905B92AB4895" style="OLC">
 <section id="HF097D77FD8A848C8A88BDBED124EE10F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Safe Skies Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="H0D6C7319ADC24359BA16D39F4106CBDB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Modification of
			 final rule relating to flightcrew member duty and rest requirements for
			 passenger operations to apply to all-cargo operations</header>
			<subsection id="H25B96DAAACB2481784C9A79680BA9251"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation shall modify the final rule specified in subsection (b) so that the flightcrew member duty and rest requirements under that rule apply to flightcrew members in all-cargo operations conducted by air carriers in the same manner as those requirements apply to flightcrew members in passenger operations conducted by air carriers.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H51C6B472F16E4A6DB1B532B0F29F25CE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Final rule
 specified</header><text>The final rule specified in this subsection is the final rule of the Federal Aviation Administration—</text>
 <paragraph id="H11CA0D00E84E4EA4B45B0860BD493BDE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>published in the Federal Register on January 4, 2012 (77 Fed. Reg. 330); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAC7DB886387E4101938307870E05088B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>relating to flightcrew member duty and rest requirements.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id44B24B9F420D480E9435A3E616A70D33"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applicability
 of rulemaking requirements</header><text>The requirements of section 553 of title 5, United States Code, shall not apply to the modification required by subsection (a).</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


