<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S129 IS: Repeal Executive Amnesty Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 129</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150115">January 8, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S345">Mr. Johnson</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To repeal executive immigration overreach, to clarify that the proper constitutional authority for
			 immigration policy belongs to the legislative branch, and for other
 purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H48576A4498CF43A08A039172603F7456" style="OLC"><section id="HEDAA04665D4D431AAEF88F5F3668AE96" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header><subsection id="HB267CA8B31134C20BFC046E8A9E9C4D9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Repeal Executive Amnesty Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HFB3D7C65487749C29FD2B96E814655A3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents is as follows:</text><toc><toc-entry idref="HEDAA04665D4D431AAEF88F5F3668AE96" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H600A1937CC1B483498A84FC1AB3673F4" level="section">Sec. 2. Severability.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H9ECC7C2B99F9445295F301E8655E1C91" level="title">TITLE I—Parole authority</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="HD5AC592264FD40E1907115E306E0D140" level="section">Sec. 101. Parole reform.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="HA1F2235D75EA45CCA4F7D88DB3E8118D" level="section">Sec. 102. Adjustment of status limited to aliens admitted to the United States.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H1E41B0D48D4C4086994D50259D2303A7" level="section">Sec. 103. Presence in the United States pursuant to parole added to priority date.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="HB0211D9839234D288453AE37F4B20FAF" level="section">Sec. 104. Admission and lawful presence required for employment authorization.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="HBF1FA5BB7C7C483584EEA6AE01D5CDD6" level="title">TITLE II—Limitation on Executive overreach</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H7C337C3BF1E9417DBF2DBC3338B24096" level="section">Sec. 201. Denial of funds for implementation of unauthorized actions.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="idC1065077578B430390F5C91FE16B0A1A" level="section">Sec. 202. Prohibition on hiring by U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H50EE646F9A144D3B88CAD86E724A6176" level="title">TITLE III—Unaccompanied alien children</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H56F5DE975F6A48B7B7AE938A73BC2370" level="section">Sec. 301. Repatriation of unaccompanied alien children.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H684A3BE6B91E45548CBD87FB3C52B261" level="section">Sec. 302. Special immigrant juvenile status for immigrants unable to reunite with either parent.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H833E703356EB441AA54B0C1F1F392066" level="section">Sec. 303. Modifications to preferential availability for asylum for unaccompanied alien minors.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H5B51E0D3E70D4EFDA54250FFD01A902B" level="section">Sec. 304. Unaccompanied alien child defined.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H84A6B0E898E645D4A18D3A6DBA5A7165" level="title">TITLE IV—Eligibility criteria for aliens to receive certain benefits</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="HC8B8694A6CB94AA2ADAFA49D6BA328BC" level="section">Sec. 401. Aliens without lawful status ineligible to receive social security and medicare benefits.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H4A2590DF234D444B8F8BA7C5001C9ECC" level="section">Sec. 402. Applying citizenship and immigration status eligibility criteria for Federal programs to Affordable Care Act benefits.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H964D0AF6D11C4CBBA3B8B4A076DB4390" level="section">Sec. 403. Aliens paroled into the United States ineligible for Federal public benefits.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="HDE36039EA2454DB2A889C15A1805AB03" level="title">TITLE V—State and local enforcement of the immigration laws</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H942DDC7713F2420FAA84565052F22E85" level="section">Sec. 501. Definitions.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H7744F86267894538ACAC67D73B4797F1" level="section">Sec. 502. Immigration law enforcement by States and localities.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H86D0B138A4D0441A80D5ADB97BD5A7A0" level="section">Sec. 503. Immunity.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H3FB03AC5D7B643DDBA22B3CB41650C64" level="section">Sec. 504. Federal custody of inadmissible and deportable aliens in the United States apprehended by State or local law enforcement.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H300D5FDC3A0F418CB8E811BD86F72E94" level="section">Sec. 505. State Criminal Alien Assistance Program (SCAAP).</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H4F76D24815D140D18A6E0B5B3BE6EB1D" level="section">Sec. 506. Limitation on State receipt of Federal funding.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H3D03B239E50146B49D1A32996AC99BB5" level="section">Sec. 507. ICE detainers.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H8A4012E2D9644D1FB7B8817830B3A741" level="section">Sec. 508. Preservation of the Secure Communities program and removal of deportable aliens identified under the interoperable law enforcement and intelligence electronic data system.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H5F94F5AA61E34DA8B832616DD451D066" level="title">TITLE VI—Asylum Reform and Border Protection</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H7C663A556DFE4F4BA78B6D141E4CC83D" level="section">Sec. 601. Clarification of intent regarding taxpayer-provided counsel.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H8AF7441D42D640FD8CC3253B4C575EE6" level="section">Sec. 602. Credible fear interviews.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H404877D7126B4ACEB41BDAA3F498C0A0" level="section">Sec. 603. Recording expedited removal and credible fear interviews.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H5A6C167DE7654AABBFE8B55C3410FB4A" level="section">Sec. 604. Safe third country.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="HDCF9440B05404B0C8BD605636B7D41FE" level="title">TITLE VII—Miscellaneous</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H7AF2CCAE57834F27BD6E008549D39E9F" level="section">Sec. 701. Suspension of effectiveness of certain laws.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H198462755EF5433D8916AD702D9A0233" level="section">Sec. 702. Temporary protected status reform.</toc-entry> </toc></subsection></section><section id="H600A1937CC1B483498A84FC1AB3673F4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Severability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any provision of this Act, or the application of such provision to any person or circumstance, is held invalid, the remainder of this Act, and the application of such provision to other persons not similarly situated or to other circumstances, shall not be affected by such invalidation.</text></section><title id="H9ECC7C2B99F9445295F301E8655E1C91"><enum>I</enum><header>Parole authority</header><section id="HD5AC592264FD40E1907115E306E0D140"><enum>101.</enum><header>Parole reform</header><subsection id="HE03CB7C673F942759CFC6FBA8E10ECA6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Paragraph (5) of section 212(d) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(d)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="H1F486AEAE883461E81D9B605093EC86C" style="OLC"><paragraph id="HF176EF4874A94E1391B5E281A279AE63" indent="up1"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Humanitarian and public interest parole</header><subparagraph id="H10F60021D5EB4599A7FA7CD16E458054"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to the provisions of this paragraph and section 214(f)(2), the Secretary of Homeland Security, in the sole discretion of the Secretary of Homeland Security, may on a case-by-case basis parole an alien into the United States temporarily, under such conditions as the Secretary of Homeland Security may prescribe, only—</text><clause id="H796785FF2A3F4C15ACC7A9EF51C3FF2A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for an urgent humanitarian reason (as described under subparagraph (B)); or</text></clause><clause id="H219A9175397B4F7A97BC07760BE3CF85"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for a reason deemed strictly in the public interest (as described under subparagraph (C)).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC5F536AA32B846E5A58977EB85109D8E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Humanitarian parole</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security may parole an alien based on an urgent humanitarian reason described in this subparagraph only if—</text><clause id="H8A21BAC329D2492C8943565ACCF6C2BF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the alien has a medical emergency and the alien cannot obtain necessary treatment in the foreign state in which the alien is residing or the medical emergency is life-threatening and there is insufficient time for the alien to be admitted through the normal visa process;</text></clause><clause id="HCB9468E1515C41C68D32449AF22E2AD2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the alien is needed in the United States in order to donate an organ or other tissue for transplant into a close family member; or</text></clause><clause id="H748062B6758245FEA75669E08AA7D595"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the alien has a close family member in the United States whose death is imminent and the alien could not arrive in the United States in time to see such family member alive if the alien were to be admitted through the normal visa process.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5E606A6AF1734E37838312BFF55DA7CA"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Public interest parole</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security may parole an alien based on a reason deemed strictly in the public interest described in this subparagraph only if the alien has assisted the United States Government in a matter, such as a criminal investigation, espionage, or other similar law enforcement activity, and either the alien’s presence in the United States is required by the Government or the alien’s life would be threatened if the alien were not permitted to come to the United States.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7773423D07CE4A1180D48EFAFE63F1E8"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Limitations on the use of parole authority</header><clause id="H1FDE16CC5E6F4D67BFAD6203F3F9A7A1"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Aliens ineligible for refugee status</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security may not use the parole authority under this paragraph to permit to come to the United States aliens who have applied for and have been found to be ineligible for refugee status or any alien to whom the provisions of this paragraph do not apply.</text></clause><clause id="HB1B0537382934EF2985CF2FCC3F3148B"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Aliens present in the United States ineligible for parole</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security may not parole into the United States an alien who—</text><subclause id="HAFB9D11221FC45C3A368D03C5F670EEE"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is physically present in the United States; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H43F3BEEFA0EA4E5389EABC3239D14C26"><enum>(II)</enum><item commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HC4FEE8078575458A9F26A92D216E918E"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>has not been admitted to the United States; or</text></item><item id="H83274B27E8AB4DA0BA45244DC53A84B0" indent="up1"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>was lawfully admitted to the United States as a nonimmigrant and remained in the United States unlawfully after the period of authorized stay ended.</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="H8461E09D2BC14C769C129296AC95BFF7"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Limitation on work authorization and adjustment of status</header><text>In the case of an alien who is present in the United States pursuant to a grant of parole under this paragraph, the Secretary of Homeland Security may not—</text><subclause id="H47E4CFF263CC4A48890F3BF7968C0341"><enum>(I)</enum><text>grant employment authorization to the alien; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H94E2A18B88224F809174567860FB620C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>admit the alien to the United States as a nonimmigrant or as an alien admitted for lawful permanent residence.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H90D9DF773D3F405A829248C865FC3284"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Parole not an admission</header><text>Parole of an alien under this paragraph shall not be considered an admission of the alien into the United States. When the purposes of the parole of an alien have been served, as determined by the Secretary of Homeland Security, the alien shall immediately return or be returned to the custody from which the alien was paroled and the alien shall be considered for admission to the United States on the same basis as other similarly situated applicants for admission.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFAB8965F4B6448F49A6E5AE1E1EF2C16"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the end of each fiscal year, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate and the Committee on Homeland Security and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives a report describing the number and categories of aliens paroled into the United States under this paragraph. Each such report shall contain information and data concerning the number and categories of aliens paroled, the duration of parole, and the current status of aliens paroled during the preceding fiscal year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HDACA185E021F4376982A75F990836A39"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (a) shall take effect on the first day of the first month beginning more than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section commented="no" id="HA1F2235D75EA45CCA4F7D88DB3E8118D"><enum>102.</enum><header>Adjustment of status limited to aliens admitted to the United States</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subsection (a) of section 245 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1255">8 U.S.C. 1255</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>or paroled</quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" id="H1E41B0D48D4C4086994D50259D2303A7"><enum>103.</enum><header>Presence in the United States pursuant to parole added to priority date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 203(e) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(e)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" id="H73AB57B2543E4E6EB5ECC43CA15E263D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>, in accordance with the requirement under paragraph (4).</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H510A88BA8E074E37933A0F901C0F8CB7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0E62B85EDA8C47378D9CCF70FE2ED041" style="OLC"><paragraph commented="no" id="H0E3ADBAD72834573851E4C68B35B62A2"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an applicant for a visa under this section who is present in the United States pursuant to a grant of parole under section 212(d)(5) for a period of time after making such application, the time period during which the applicant is present in the United States pursuant to such a grant of parole shall be added to the applicant’s priority date.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="HB0211D9839234D288453AE37F4B20FAF"><enum>104.</enum><header>Admission and lawful presence required for employment authorization</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Paragraph (3) of section 274A(h) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1324a">8 U.S.C. 1324a(h)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H455592D64832455CA42669C1ED9603F7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>an alien otherwise admitted to the United States and present in the United States with a lawful immigration status, who is</quote> before <quote>authorized to be so employed by this Act</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE96CB2AAF8934825A63C9E31BC96D801"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or by the Attorney General</quote>.</text></paragraph></section></title><title id="HBF1FA5BB7C7C483584EEA6AE01D5CDD6"><enum>II</enum><header>Limitation on Executive overreach</header><section id="H7C337C3BF1E9417DBF2DBC3338B24096"><enum>201.</enum><header>Denial of funds for implementation of unauthorized actions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no funds or fees made available to the Secretary of Homeland Security, or to the head of any other Federal agency, may be used to implement, administer, enforce, or carry out (including through the issuance of any regulations) any of the policy changes set forth in the following memoranda:</text><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H05C0E78AA13045EB8440A1846E58746E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The memorandum from the Director of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement entitled <quote>Civil Immigration Enforcement: Priorities for the Apprehension, Detention, and Removal of Aliens</quote> (March 2, 2011).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEFF53096055D4170BB32936661DC81D1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The memorandum from the Director of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement entitled <quote>Exercising Prosecutorial Discretion Consistent with the Civil Immigration Enforcement Priorities of the Agency for the Apprehension, Detention, and Removal of Aliens</quote> (June 17, 2011).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9021F735D92442C88389C6CB734843BA"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The memorandum from the Director of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement entitled <quote>Prosecutorial Discretion: Certain Victims, Witnesses, and Plaintiffs</quote> (June 17, 2011).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD9BE3A8A9DDC45DC8B71D163F6F72FF7"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services policy memorandum entitled <quote>Revised Guidance for the Referral of Cases and Issuance of Notices to Appear (NTAs) in Cases Involving Inadmissible and Removable Aliens</quote> (November 17, 2011).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCD617C22C0D646E19FD88F5135E9AE08"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The memorandum from the Principal Legal Advisor of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement entitled <quote>Case-by-Case Review of Incoming and Certain Pending Cases</quote> (November 17, 2011).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H409D8432103E49969AD28036D14E5E84"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The recommendations included in the report from the Director of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement entitled <quote>ICE Response to the Task Force on Secure Communities Findings and Recommendations</quote> (April 27, 2012).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2E5D4E8DFD7D4CF3AB1DD88BADB468C5"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The memorandum from the Secretary of Homeland Security entitled <quote>Exercising Prosecutorial Discretion with Respect to Individuals Who Came to the United States as Children</quote> (June 15, 2012).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDCAD577558094E4794F617735CE70872"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The memorandum from the Director of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement entitled <quote>Civil Immigration Enforcement: Guidance on the Use of Detainers in the Federal, State, Local, and Tribal Criminal Justice Systems</quote> (December 21, 2012).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H30CA76C12AAD486E9D2B283B6682AFA2"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services policy memorandum entitled <quote>Adjudication of Adjustment of Status Applications for Individuals Admitted to the United States Under the Visa Waiver Program</quote> (November 14, 2013).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC69090F3F6B64BD6A206D1EB54F52C6A"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The memorandum from the Secretary of Homeland Security entitled <quote>Southern Border and Approaches Campaign</quote> (November 20, 2014).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H63EE7226F68E45919362CA33942B27C2"><enum>(11)</enum><text>The memorandum from the Secretary of Homeland Security entitled <quote>Policies for the Apprehension, Detention and Removal of Undocumented Immigrants</quote> (November 20, 2014).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA445A1566AC74DDC9A6EBD366AD4B3C7"><enum>(12)</enum><text>The memorandum from the Secretary of Homeland Security entitled <quote>Secure Communities</quote> (November 20, 2014).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA2300E0DC2994D7DB095030DE1D424EC"><enum>(13)</enum><text>The memorandum from the Secretary of Homeland Security entitled <quote>Exercising Prosecutorial Discretion with Respect to Individuals Who Came to the United States as Children and with Respect to Certain Individuals Who Are the Parents of U.S. Citizens or Permanent Residents</quote> (November 20, 2014).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5D64D89C496A493AB67CD13057725DC8"><enum>(14)</enum><text>The memorandum from the Secretary of Homeland Security entitled <quote>Expansion of the Provisional Waiver Program</quote> (November 20, 2014).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H629BCFDDC95948D6928273E94916F5DD"><enum>(15)</enum><text>The memorandum from the Secretary of Homeland Security entitled <quote>Policies Supporting U.S. High-Skilled Businesses and Workers</quote> (November 20, 2014).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H78A585386BBA4954AF8B72AF2E291B12"><enum>(16)</enum><text>The memorandum from the Secretary of Homeland Security entitled <quote>Families of U.S. Armed Forces Members and Enlistees</quote> (November 20, 2014).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAC4F5A3B24B34DAE9F2E6A0D306D5AF4"><enum>(17)</enum><text>The memorandum from the Secretary of Homeland Security entitled <quote>Directive to Provide Consistency Regarding Advance Parole</quote> (November 20, 2014).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBB2BA3D0F0CA49ADA7FCD1D27D951BBE"><enum>(18)</enum><text>The memorandum from the Secretary of Homeland Security entitled <quote>Policies to Promote and Increase Access to U.S. Citizenship</quote> (November 20, 2014).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0D0328F214E64F709909D5E3F2EF73DB"><enum>(19)</enum><text>The memorandum from the President entitled <quote>Modernizing and Streamlining the U.S. Immigrant Visa System for the 21st Century</quote> (November 21, 2014).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H58726E87E25442209E03A981E8423CF8"><enum>(20)</enum><text>The memorandum from the President entitled <quote>Creating Welcoming Communities and Fully Integrating Immigrants and Refugees</quote> (November 21, 2014).</text></paragraph></section><section id="idC1065077578B430390F5C91FE16B0A1A"><enum>202.</enum><header>Prohibition on hiring by U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The head of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services may not appoint an individual to any position in U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services until after the date that the President rescinds each memorandum described in paragraphs (10) through (20) of section 201.</text></section></title><title id="H50EE646F9A144D3B88CAD86E724A6176"><enum>III</enum><header>Unaccompanied alien children</header><section id="H56F5DE975F6A48B7B7AE938A73BC2370"><enum>301.</enum><header>Repatriation of unaccompanied alien children</header><subsection id="H2762710B2F7F49A4A6EDE3D0629BE79E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 235 of the William Wilberforce Trafficking Victims Protection Reauthorization Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1232">8 U.S.C. 1232</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HC86E191B0E3A47AD9CEC95884886A132"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text><subparagraph id="H47F54F8138014AB086DC5B5B356CCF19"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text><clause id="HC12F16D9FE3D43D6BE12EEFC5A16FDD1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by amending the heading to read as follows: <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">Rules for unaccompanied alien children.</header-in-text></quote>;</text></clause><clause id="H932A322D61854D828555F3E9C605317D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A);</text><subclause id="HFD02D2342AE745FA9DE02F32D08FFABF"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in the matter preceding clause (i), by striking <quote>who is a national or habitual resident of a country that is contiguous with the United States</quote>;</text></subclause><subclause id="HA6D4E25A78B14C6A9969519B22D087CB"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in clause (i), by inserting <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></subclause><subclause id="H0203F8346E1A4AACB280EA2556A9B7D2"><enum>(III)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a period; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H83F7437CEB9040DCB1E8EC2580DFDFC8"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>by striking clause (iii);</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H6FC48F6D0827419E8A83E27BFA95D1C6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)—</text><subclause id="HEC0DDFC93EE147CDBF06E8B4732FDC91"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in the matter preceding clause (i), by striking <quote>(<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>) may—</quote> and inserting <quote>(<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>)—</quote>;</text></subclause><subclause id="HC69FE3CA1B9944939E6C63A8002EFF8D"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in clause (i), by inserting before <quote>permit such child to withdraw</quote> the following: <quote>may</quote>; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HF81228B730D54BC8B32772BB83F1B0A8"><enum>(III)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by inserting before <quote>return such child</quote> the following: <quote>shall</quote>; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H6323D73FE3664ABE949B7472AF87ECAC"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C)—</text><subclause id="H73E9E7DF311E40C0B92001B33722C502"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by amending the heading to read as follows: <quote><header-in-text level="subparagraph" style="OLC">Agreements with foreign countries</header-in-text>.</quote>; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H9C6CABFF9B254C478B6E866DBE123898"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in the matter preceding clause (i), by striking <quote>The Secretary of State shall negotiate agreements between the United States and countries contiguous to the United States</quote> and inserting <quote>The Secretary of State may negotiate agreements between the United States and any foreign country that the Secretary determines appropriate</quote>; and</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF58A8624D9E84844B9D394746409996B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (5)(D)—</text><clause id="H486FE360CDB74D2882773C3531842B56"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the matter preceding clause (i), by striking <quote>, except for an unaccompanied alien child from a contiguous country subject to the exceptions under subsection (a)(2),</quote> and inserting <quote>who does not meet the criteria listed in paragraph (2)(A)</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="H653A2F07C72A462FA12467538CF0BFB4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in clause (i), by inserting before the semicolon at the end the following: <quote>, which shall include a hearing before an immigration judge not later than 14 days after being screened under paragraph (4)</quote>;</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAD2C94FCDFAB4685AC37C9A92523D76D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text><subparagraph id="HECB675932BDA489EAF39D6CFC35439A1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text><clause commented="no" id="H40076D95DFB1412EB5D27F146ADEE0F5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>48 hours</quote> and inserting <quote>7 days</quote>;</text></clause><clause id="H07A8EE531657478CB1BBB1EF9CFC24FB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by inserting before the semicolon the following: <quote>believed not to meet the criteria listed in subsection (a)(2)(A)</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="HF82F174B088648F5B3448C577E4081D9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by inserting before the period the following: <quote>and does not meet the criteria listed in subsection (a)(2)(A)</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0288F53598834DD38AAE01510222C9AF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>an unaccompanied alien child in custody shall</quote> and all that follows, and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HDF8534EE767E4E9FBE16CB10DF3DAA92" style="OLC"><text>an unaccompanied alien child in custody—</text><subparagraph id="HA67709A376784A0DA756A0640B518B4F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a child who does not meet the criteria listed in subsection (a)(2)(A), shall transfer the custody of such child to the Secretary of Health and Human Services not later than 30 days after determining that such child is an unaccompanied alien child who does not meet such criteria; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H006766508991459EB682A6C123F219DB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of child who meets the criteria listed in subsection (a)(2)(A), may transfer the custody of such child to the Secretary of Health and Human Services after determining that such child is an unaccompanied alien child who meets such criteria.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCA182518D8E943959C9E9140E0F6FF8B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB4CAB6D76A2546F3A504CCBA66596E80" style="OLC"><paragraph id="HCD3FAD8F76004BE5BD1E9DA4B99DA62B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Information sharing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall share with the Secretary of Homeland Security any information requested on a child who has been determined to be an unaccompanied alien child and who is or has been in the custody of the Secretary of Health and Human Services, including the location of the child and any person to whom custody of the child has been transferred, for any legitimate law enforcement objective, including enforcement of the immigration laws.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H9328D751E63D4122964C84DB75B83C8B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text><subparagraph id="H62DBD1814B8249F88145F19A9D0BE569"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by inserting at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HCF91ABD4D93646C0A6019BE99584D256" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="HD31920C932404D4995BBE79D799503B6"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Information about individuals with whom children are placed</header><clause id="HB3F56D455021447CB05CB2C57E9E2D9D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Information to be provided to homeland security</header><text>Before placing a child with an individual, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall provide to the Secretary of Homeland Security, regarding the individual with whom the child will be placed, the following information:</text><subclause id="H6571B30A81E64A3088652DC5A07DA606"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The name of the individual.</text></subclause><subclause id="H496163AF64D94F2E9EBA75FB5FC04524"><enum>(II)</enum><text>The social security number of the individual.</text></subclause><subclause id="HD67976BF441D419EBD175B8B5D764409"><enum>(III)</enum><text>The date of birth of the individual.</text></subclause><subclause id="HED77AB8A94444FD8974B41D45C2AF921"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>The location of the individual’s residence where the child will be placed.</text></subclause><subclause id="HA799A9FD7A044F7C9C4942C6C6CB7E2B"><enum>(V)</enum><text>The immigration status of the individual, if known.</text></subclause><subclause id="H21080181A6E9433CA4763444A3B3818C"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>Contact information for the individual.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H0BDCB1DDB4D94A42AC185FDB1B469348"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Special rule</header><text>In the case of a child who was apprehended on or after June 15, 2012, and before the date of the enactment of the Repeal Executive Amnesty Act of 2015, who the Secretary of Health and Human Services placed with an individual, the Secretary shall provide the information listed in clause (i) to the Secretary of Homeland Security not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of the Repeal Executive Amnesty Act of 2015.</text></clause><clause id="H29AD4C75B21043EBAEA32537B204BBC3"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Activities of the secretary of homeland security</header><text>Not later than 30 days after receiving the information listed in clause (i), the Secretary of Homeland Security shall—</text><subclause id="H39C4B713EC934DD8AB8D165BCA86E1F7"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in the case that the immigration status of an individual with whom a child is placed is unknown, investigate the immigration status of that individual; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H927F2982096F41B49E05C8A49D7AAA5C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>upon determining that an individual with whom a child is placed is unlawfully present in the United States, initiate removal proceedings pursuant to chapter 4 of title II of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1221">8 U.S.C. 1221 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2D6F009195BC4ED9AD21398DF416C418"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (5)—</text><clause id="H8433E57F26C546D58DA1B6989DAEE854"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by inserting after <quote>to the greatest extent practicable</quote> the following: <quote>(at no expense to the Government)</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="H350E0B2C97254BFD9E36F3F9A82A3BA4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>have counsel to represent them</quote> and inserting <quote>have access to counsel to represent them</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H79352CEB531D4A689394DB2F4CB090ED"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to any unauthorized alien child apprehended on or after June 15, 2012.</text></subsection></section><section id="H684A3BE6B91E45548CBD87FB3C52B261"><enum>302.</enum><header>Special immigrant juvenile status for immigrants unable to reunite with either parent</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 101(a)(27)(J)(i) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(27)(J)(i)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>1 or both of the immigrant’s parents</quote> and inserting <quote>either of the immigrant’s parents</quote>.</text></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H833E703356EB441AA54B0C1F1F392066"><enum>303.</enum><header>Modifications to preferential availability for asylum for unaccompanied alien minors</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 208 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1158">8 U.S.C. 1158</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H7762BE546F664A12B6E2C860FF678CD2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking subsection (a)(2)(E); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7D490FF423174B418AD05DC6DEFF463E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking subsection (b)(3)(C).</text></paragraph></section><section id="H5B51E0D3E70D4EFDA54250FFD01A902B"><enum>304.</enum><header>Unaccompanied alien child defined</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 462(g)(2) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/279">6 U.S.C. 279(g)(2)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H01287259C85D466BA96EDA42BFC21E26" style="OLC"><paragraph id="HC027CCBD0D9B4181B16DAF79B794A1CD"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>unaccompanied alien child</term>—</text><subparagraph id="H8AB27FB3F40B4ABE9E36B028872FC5B3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means an alien who—</text><clause id="H0455786E54BB403BAFC9C5BC1F6413F6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has no lawful immigration status in the United States;</text></clause><clause id="H5E497B1810F2418A87D6E4D6E5EC7638"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has not attained 18 years of age; and</text></clause><clause id="HF23E464E42D04BC796B33CBAD45263A2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>with respect to whom—</text><subclause id="HB66A2A4E65B04B2983F577A01F9C32F4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>there is no parent or legal guardian in the United States;</text></subclause><subclause id="H3D7C450684BF4A46969F10D22E933A82"><enum>(II)</enum><text>no parent or legal guardian in the United States is available to provide care and physical custody; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H179B4E65A6A3433FBB46035005067996"><enum>(III)</enum><text>no sibling over 18 years of age, aunt, uncle, grandparent, or cousin over 18 years of age is available to provide care and physical custody; except that</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H24D38EBF5E9A47F8A077EAFE2F5AED13"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such term shall cease to include an alien if at any time a parent, legal guardian, sibling over 18 years of age, aunt, uncle, grandparent, or cousin over 18 years of age of the alien is found in the United States and is available to provide care and physical custody (and the Secretary of Homeland Security and the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall revoke accordingly any prior designation of the alien under this paragraph).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></title><title id="H84A6B0E898E645D4A18D3A6DBA5A7165"><enum>IV</enum><header>Eligibility criteria for aliens to receive certain benefits</header><section id="HC8B8694A6CB94AA2ADAFA49D6BA328BC"><enum>401.</enum><header>Aliens without lawful status ineligible to receive social security and medicare benefits</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 401(b) of the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1611">8 U.S.C. 1611(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H3CC4D1E91742435AB0E1F7EFF0F6782E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by adding at the end the following: <quote>For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>alien who is lawfully present in the United States</term> means an alien who has been admitted to the United States, and whose period of lawful admission has not expired, and does not include an alien who is present in the United States pursuant to a grant of parole under section 212(d)(5) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(d)(5)</external-xref>).</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8F18AB63F2664EA8AE80F99463C65059"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (3), by adding at the end the following: <quote>For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>alien who is lawfully present in the United States</term> has the meaning given such term in paragraph (2).</quote>.</text></paragraph></section><section commented="no" id="H4A2590DF234D444B8F8BA7C5001C9ECC"><enum>402.</enum><header>Applying citizenship and immigration status eligibility criteria for Federal programs to Affordable Care Act benefits</header><subsection commented="no" id="H69B8EEA279EE4464967BB7B04DBE5838"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Applying qualified alien eligibility criteria to ACA benefits</header><paragraph commented="no" id="H7C88CD7F3AAE4D9FB63D31CE161683D0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Temporary high risk health insurance pool program</header><text>Section 1101(d)(1) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18001">42 U.S.C. 18001(d)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>or is lawfully present</quote> and all that follows through <quote>section 1411)</quote> and inserting <quote>or is a qualified alien (as defined in section 431 of the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1641">8 U.S.C. 1641</external-xref>)), as determined in accordance with section 1411</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H7791830161C9423D866A164147089CE8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligibility to participate in Exchanges</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1312(f)(3) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18032">42 U.S.C. 18032(f)(3)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H07FA1EF4A50348CAA1E8650CC893492E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the paragraph heading, by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">certain</header-in-text></quote> after <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">limited to</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H00D0BA9AF5264057A07055F5853329A0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>an alien lawfully present in the United States</quote> and inserting <quote>an alien who is a qualified alien (as defined in section 431 of the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1641">8 U.S.C. 1641</external-xref>))</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HD38D956FACF24C4F807BB2B0D7FE30A9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>State health programs for low-income individuals not eligible for Medicaid</header><text>Section 1331(e)(1)(B) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18051">42 U.S.C. 18051(e)(1)(B)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>lawfully present in the United States</quote> and inserting <quote>who is a qualified alien (as defined in section 431 of the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1641">8 U.S.C. 1641</external-xref>))</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H37DD7075C3884DACA7F4F2CEB2BB5673"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Tax credit providing premium assistance for coverage under qualified health plans</header><text>Section 36B of the Internal Revenue of 1986 is amended—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="HE06DB13B167E406FAEAE863579B6B2AE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (c)(1)(B)—</text><clause commented="no" id="H2C75CB0BF177432BA1C4D7E5DB275774"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subparagraph" style="OLC">individuals lawfully present in the United States</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subparagraph" style="OLC">qualified aliens</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H4A0149B0756C489C9D4C6BD3D2E903C6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by striking <quote>an alien lawfully present in the United States</quote> and inserting <quote>an alien who is a qualified alien (as defined in section 431 of the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1641">8 U.S.C. 1641</external-xref>))</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H4B507D927F6646C68F3C00174885865F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (e)(2), by striking <quote>lawfully present in the United States</quote> and inserting <quote>who is a qualified alien (as defined in section 431 of the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1641">8 U.S.C. 1641</external-xref>))</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H9439A532C9D843AAAB64559E60703146"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Reduced cost-sharing for certain individuals under qualified health plans</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1402(e)(2) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18071">42 U.S.C. 18071(e)(2)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>lawfully present in the United States</quote> and inserting <quote>who is a qualified alien (as defined in section 431 of the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1641">8 U.S.C. 1641</external-xref>))</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HF465F5655368413E9B6F2143BB95DC74"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Eligibility determinations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1411 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18081">42 U.S.C. 18081</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H79BBAF30DBA14BF88216C6C903772D76"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(1), by striking <quote>an alien lawfully present in the United States</quote> and inserting <quote>a qualified alien (as defined in section 431 of the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1641">8 U.S.C. 1641</external-xref>))</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H7DFF586DA49A409EA3C324E8006BBD43"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (c)(2)(B)—</text><clause commented="no" id="H499956B033AB466885A0BFBB65D1ADAF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in clause (i)(I), by striking <quote>an alien lawfully present in the United States</quote> and inserting <quote>a qualified alien (as defined in section 431 of the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1641">8 U.S.C. 1641</external-xref>))</quote>; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H49AA09602A674650AA9F257A2D470A28"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in clause (ii)(II), by striking <quote>an alien lawfully present in the United States</quote> and inserting <quote>a qualified alien (as defined in section 431 of the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1641">8 U.S.C. 1641</external-xref>))</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H5FBFAF92C5954F4FA8A3509EDF77E238"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Advance determination and payment of premium tax credits and cost-sharing reductions</header><text>Section 1412(d) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18082">42 U.S.C. 18082(d)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H6CB16798EF9D4BF79E046CC1F16EF314"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Lawfully Present</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">citizens, nationals, or qualified aliens</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H0867912D87414B05A32897EBB035D1FA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>not lawfully present in the United States</quote> and inserting <quote>not citizens or nationals of the United States or aliens who are qualified aliens (as defined in section 431 of the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1641">8 U.S.C. 1641</external-xref>))</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H399FAEC7D0774858AB095F356C77454D"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Minimum essential coverage requirement</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/5000A">Section 5000A(d)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="HFB3584D7F81F46808FA3EED154C64A6D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">lawfully present</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">citizens, nationals, or qualified aliens</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H3AA46E18AD22472AAD9231F28FF56AF8"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>an alien lawfully present in the United States</quote> and inserting <quote>a qualified alien (as defined in section 431 of the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1641">8 U.S.C. 1641</external-xref>))</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H3628137546AD47B2A6F7238255C872BB"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Medicaid population</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1903(v)(1) of the Social Security Act is amended by striking <quote>who is not lawfully admitted for permanent residence or otherwise permanently residing in the United States under color of law</quote> and inserting <quote>who is not a qualified alien (as defined in section 431 of the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1641">8 U.S.C. 1641</external-xref>))</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H9116E45A744C4464AE44C17A50B6293D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clarification that certain ACA benefits treated as Federal public benefits</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 401(c) of the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1611">8 U.S.C. 1611(c)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF47B98FF985B4688AE5A1ECDF01492FD" style="OLC"><paragraph commented="no" id="H78BBC83E7E77453DA6D05BF658A7F75D"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In applying paragraph (1), the following assistance and benefits are treated as health benefits described in paragraph (1)(B):</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H9E4E8A5AED3B459B881A9D022F4B0D4F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Enrollment under the temporary high risk health insurance pool program under section 1101 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18001">42 U.S.C. 18001</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HF72B21D65B4246B8A19E65A4A8CCCB80"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Participation in an Exchange established under title I of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H658AA86321C24DCD9E36262B8A6C86D4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Participation in the health program established under section 1331(a) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18051">42 U.S.C. 18051</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HABC3EBCBFEC44D5EB0123EDC18B4C3D1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Allowance of a tax credit under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/36B">section 36B</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H0598274126A748249E369FCCC2C92735"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Reduction of cost-sharing under qualified health plans under section 1402 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18071">42 U.S.C. 18071</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H4160C66C68A64F67BFC71A737AC17342"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Provision of advance payments under section 1412 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18082">42 U.S.C. 18082</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H3C43C4684EE34E2F89ACEAA3FCFC4941"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clarification That Certain ACA Benefits Treated as Federal Means-Tested Public Benefits</header><text>Section 403(c) of the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1613">8 U.S.C. 1613(c)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6B3697FB981B4435891AF37650AC13A8" style="OLC"><paragraph commented="no" id="HFB363DD94C9A4BDAB88629268E3DD60F"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In applying this section, assistance and benefits described in section 401(c)(3) are treated as Federal means-tested public benefits to which subsection (a) applies.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H50EE40EE6CCE49D6AB987A4108968061"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><paragraph commented="no" id="HCD2A0F463B1647E082650A86D7BD68DC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to paragraph (2), the amendments made by this section shall apply to coverage months beginning more than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HCFE297B8AFA947B3B3E5548A3986C9F9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Transition for current enrollees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an individual who is being provided assistance or benefits described in paragraph (3) of section 401(c) of the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1611">8 U.S.C. 1611(c)</external-xref>), as added by subsection (b), as of the date of the enactment of this Act, the amendments made by this section (other than the amendments made by subsection (a)(8)) shall not apply with respect to such assistance or benefits provided to such individual for coverage months before January of the year after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H964D0AF6D11C4CBBA3B8B4A076DB4390"><enum>403.</enum><header>Aliens paroled into the United States ineligible for Federal public benefits</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 431(b) of the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1641">8 U.S.C. 1641(b)</external-xref>) is amended by striking paragraph (4).</text></section></title><title commented="no" id="HDE36039EA2454DB2A889C15A1805AB03"><enum>V</enum><header>State and local enforcement of the immigration laws</header><section id="H942DDC7713F2420FAA84565052F22E85"><enum>501.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this title:</text><paragraph id="HF5127C83D8DF4535A02D34B81FEB306C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Homeland Security.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id776DA0018C334047A40582C82A881AD0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> has the meaning given to such term in section 101(a)(36) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(36)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section><section id="H7744F86267894538ACAC67D73B4797F1"><enum>502.</enum><header>Immigration law enforcement by States and localities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Law enforcement personnel of a State, or of a political subdivision of a State, may investigate, identify, apprehend, arrest, detain, or transfer to Federal custody aliens for the purposes of enforcing the immigration laws of the United States to the same extent as Federal law enforcement personnel. Law enforcement personnel of a State, or of a political subdivision of a State, may also investigate, identify, apprehend, arrest, or detain aliens for the purposes of enforcing the immigration laws of a State or of a political subdivision of State. Law enforcement personnel of a State, or of a political subdivision of a State, may not remove aliens from the United States.</text></section><section id="H86D0B138A4D0441A80D5ADB97BD5A7A0"><enum>503.</enum><header>Immunity</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a law enforcement officer of a State or local law enforcement agency who is acting within the scope of the officer’s official duties shall be immune, to the same extent as a Federal law enforcement officer, from personal liability arising out of the performance of any duty described in this title, including the authorities to investigate, identify, apprehend, arrest, detain, or transfer to Federal custody, an alien for the purposes of enforcing the immigration laws of the United States (as defined in section 101(a)(17) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(17)</external-xref>)) or the immigration laws of a State or a political subdivision of a State.</text></section><section id="H3FB03AC5D7B643DDBA22B3CB41650C64"><enum>504.</enum><header>Federal custody of inadmissible and deportable aliens in the United States apprehended by State or
 local law enforcement</header><subsection id="H2996003A99A54A3B9A7EB07ECAAC1A91"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Title II of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1151">8 U.S.C. 1151 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 240C the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H74E03B82F94E4CDEA0AC5467AACBA6B1" style="OLC"><section id="HF0E1149F9EE7485B9A2C7464D3A87EA4"><enum>240D.</enum><header>Custody of inadmissible and deportable aliens present in the United States</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H26FB756936B94A5DA1FCF8C999EB3E8C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Transfer of custody by State and local officials</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a State, or a political subdivision of a State, exercising authority with respect to the apprehension or arrest of an inadmissible or deportable alien submits to the Secretary of Homeland Security a request that the alien be taken into Federal custody, notwithstanding any other provision of law, regulation, or policy the Secretary—</text><paragraph commented="no" id="HF07924BC659A419490AA51C08BE631FE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall take the alien into custody not later than 48 hours after the request has been issued following the conclusion of the State or local charging process or dismissal process, or if no State or local charging or dismissal process is required, the Secretary shall issue a detainer and take the alien into custody not later than 48 hours after the alien is apprehended, in order to determine whether the alien should be detained, placed in removal proceedings, released, or removed; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H2B02159076C241958C2EEE46AB220220"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall request that the relevant State or local law enforcement agency temporarily hold the alien in their custody or transport the alien for transfer to Federal custody.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFC23781B933E4D50BC606454D91D9C87"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Policy on detention in Federal, contract, State, or local detention facilities</header><text>In carrying out section 241(g)(1), the Attorney General or Secretary of Homeland Security shall ensure that an alien arrested under this title shall be held in custody, pending the alien’s examination under this section, in a Federal, contract, State, or local prison, jail, detention center, or other comparable facility. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, regulation or policy, such facility is adequate for detention, if—</text><paragraph id="H01084BFFC57041FE99B56695C0B8BFE4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>such a facility is the most suitably located Federal, contract, State, or local facility available for such purpose under the circumstances;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H58EA7571C5454E209C9270244261F751"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an appropriate arrangement for such use of the facility can be made; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE628D621A2EE4132AD45721E8EC4C218"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the facility satisfies the standards for the housing, care, and security of persons held in custody by a United States Marshal.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCEA5E020774C417CAD087B8FFDBB0380"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reimbursement</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall reimburse a State, or a political subdivision of a State, for all reasonable expenses, as determined by the Secretary, incurred by the State, or political subdivision, as a result of the incarceration and transportation of an alien who is inadmissible or deportable as described in subsections (a) and (b). Compensation provided for costs incurred under such subsections shall be the average cost of incarceration of a prisoner in the relevant State, as determined by the chief executive officer of a State, or of a political subdivision of a State, plus the cost of transporting the alien from the point of apprehension to the place of detention, and to the custody transfer point if the place of detention and place of custody are different.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF72C48AEB4804888BC6014939C2C6FBD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Secure facilities</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall ensure that aliens incarcerated pursuant to this title are held in facilities that provide an appropriate level of security.</text></subsection><subsection id="HFC819EFA9938495B907605E0608E0973"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Transfer</header><paragraph id="HCEF3368EF5EB44718090866DB3AC6B38"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall establish a regular circuit and schedule for the prompt transfer of apprehended aliens from the custody of States, and political subdivisions of a State, to Federal custody.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H64E23636ADAA47C9B233F599811EABA1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contracts</header><text>The Secretary may enter into contracts, including appropriate private contracts, to implement this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H0962701072464C6082E633D7ED041343"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents of such Act is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 240C the following new item:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H70B7B1F9896A4839A070B793FED9025A" style="traditional"><toc container-level="quoted-block-container" idref="H74E03B82F94E4CDEA0AC5467AACBA6B1" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration"><toc-entry idref="HF0E1149F9EE7485B9A2C7464D3A87EA4" level="section">Sec. 240D. Custody of inadmissible and deportable aliens present in the United States.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="H300D5FDC3A0F418CB8E811BD86F72E94"><enum>505.</enum><header>State Criminal Alien Assistance Program (SCAAP)</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subparagraph (A) of section 241(i)(3) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1231">8 U.S.C. 1231(i)(3)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>charged with or</quote> before <quote>convicted</quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" id="H4F76D24815D140D18A6E0B5B3BE6EB1D"><enum>506.</enum><header>Limitation on State receipt of Federal funding</header><subsection commented="no" id="H729A516FFC774516AA5FF20C0E4110D7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State or political subdivision of a State that has in place a law or policy described in subsection (b) may not receive—</text><paragraph commented="no" id="H321213FCA52B431F9E73E496551CD8E7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">grants made under subpart 1 of part E of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3750">42 U.S.C. 3750 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H5AC29C3CA43A4F8893C715B60E139546"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">grants made under part Q of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3796dd">42 U.S.C. 3796dd et seq.</external-xref>); or</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HE9B701C5D2BE415CBBACB88A6AC71E1B"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">compensation under section 241(i) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1231">8 U.S.C. 1231(i)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HA2F77C42A50D40EC9DEE87C65BFB67D8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Law or policy described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A law or policy is described in this subsection if the law or policy—</text><paragraph commented="no" id="H0EEEF0A676FC463DA156D473691283BC"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is in contravention of section 642(a) of the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1373">8 U.S.C. 1373(a)</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H32E7CEED52D7431CAEC2EF68CA56178F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>prohibits or restricts law enforcement officers of that State or political subdivision from collecting information relating to an individual’s immigration status; or</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H96795EE6F1804483B83563D5310F02EE"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prohibits or restricts compliance with, or the honoring of detainers issued by Immigration and Customs Enforcement.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3D03B239E50146B49D1A32996AC99BB5" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>507.</enum><header>ICE detainers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 287(d) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1357">8 U.S.C. 1357(d)</external-xref>) is amended in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by striking <quote>law relating to controlled substances,</quote> and inserting <quote>law,</quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" id="H8A4012E2D9644D1FB7B8817830B3A741"><enum>508.</enum><header>Preservation of the Secure Communities program and removal of deportable aliens identified under
 the interoperable law enforcement and intelligence electronic data system</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 202 of the Enhanced Border Security and Visa Entry Reform Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1722">8 U.S.C. 1722</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H80C3E4B7D4FA4BDD85DF498E519FA57C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (a)(2), by adding at the end the following: <quote>Compliance with the requirements of this paragraph shall include, at a minimum, the operation of the Secure Communities program, as in effect on November 19, 2014.</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEC3EFA99720F41B4A1DBD5AC3D81D58C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1AF4B231EF39411D84E713C5E0083DC4" style="OLC"><subsection id="HACDDE31AE57D41278AAA2589ADAB7E7E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Required action</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon receiving notice under the interoperable law enforcement and intelligence electronic data system established under subsection (a) that a deportable alien is in the custody of Federal, State, or local law enforcement, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall, following the conclusion of the charging process, dismissal process, or completion of the alien’s sentence, as appropriate, issue a detainer, take the alien into custody, and initiate removal proceedings under section 238 or 240 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1228">8 U.S.C. 1228</external-xref>, 1229a), as appropriate.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></title><title id="H5F94F5AA61E34DA8B832616DD451D066"><enum>VI</enum><header>Asylum Reform and Border Protection</header><section id="H7C663A556DFE4F4BA78B6D141E4CC83D"><enum>601.</enum><header>Clarification of intent regarding taxpayer-provided counsel</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 292 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1362">8 U.S.C. 1362</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HEBF2BB78F7EE4EE08225763ADDA4122F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>(a) <header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">In general</header-in-text>.—</quote> before <quote>In any removal</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idBEA41E81691C47F08843A81AD1B0AC07"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(at no expense to the Government)</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8EF6D8A7EBA74583AFC4B79784ECAEC7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8E27B4B9036C4EB1A685100F246DE737" style="OLC"><subsection id="idA9264CCFE6E845B0AF2D4207CEE87B54"><enum>(b)</enum><header>No expense to the Government</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, in no instance shall the Government bear any expense for counsel for any person in removal proceedings or in any appeal proceedings before the Attorney General from any such removal proceedings.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="H8AF7441D42D640FD8CC3253B4C575EE6"><enum>602.</enum><header>Credible fear interviews</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 235(b)(1)(B)(v) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1225">8 U.S.C. 1225(b)(1)(B)(v)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>208.</quote> and inserting <quote>208, and it is more probable than not that the statements made by the alien in support of the alien’s claim are true.</quote>.</text></section><section id="H404877D7126B4ACEB41BDAA3F498C0A0"><enum>603.</enum><header>Recording expedited removal and credible fear interviews</header><subsection id="H4C4B2B00DCAF40C39B0BBC32F369645C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall establish quality assurance procedures and take steps to effectively ensure that questions by employees of the Department of Homeland Security exercising expedited removal authority under section 235(b) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1225">8 U.S.C. 1225(b)</external-xref>) are asked in a uniform manner, and that both these questions and the answers provided in response to them are recorded in a uniform fashion.</text></subsection><subsection id="H6FB637A5C05B4D22AF1C4A71BF108B5A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Factors relating to sworn statements</header><text>Where practicable, any sworn or signed written statement taken of an alien as part of the record of a proceeding under section 235(b)(1)(A) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1225">8 U.S.C. 1225(b)(1)(A)</external-xref>) shall be accompanied by a recording of the interview which served as the basis for that sworn statement.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD6503C3D809F40108D003619CAC28882"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Interpreters</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that a competent interpreter, not affiliated with the government of the country from which the alien may claim asylum, is used when the interviewing officer does not speak a language understood by the alien and there is no other Federal, State, or local government employee available who is able to interpret effectively, accurately, and impartially.</text></subsection><subsection id="H6BB7B422A75A46D4A1173555619EC439"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Recordings in immigration proceedings</header><text>Recordings of interviews of aliens subject to expedited removal shall be included in the record of proceeding and shall be considered as evidence in any further proceedings involving the alien.</text></subsection><subsection id="H0AAD1F4896084E4A9D71D944D6269676"><enum>(e)</enum><header>No private right of action</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to create any right, benefit, trust, or responsibility, whether substantive or procedural, enforceable in law or equity by a party against the United States, its departments, agencies, instrumentalities, entities, officers, employees, or agents, or any person, nor does this section create any right of review in any administrative, judicial, or other proceeding.</text></subsection></section><section id="H5A6C167DE7654AABBFE8B55C3410FB4A"><enum>604.</enum><header>Safe third country</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 208(a)(2)(A) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1158">8 U.S.C. 1158(a)(2)(A)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HBC3BB8CC4C624E9294AB4F35015E8B7D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Attorney General</quote> and inserting <quote>Secretary of Homeland Security</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE6B810EAF01D4D5E95E66CF59C48CF2B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>removed, pursuant to a bilateral or multilateral agreement, to</quote> and inserting <quote>removed to</quote>.</text></paragraph></section></title><title id="HDCF9440B05404B0C8BD605636B7D41FE"><enum>VII</enum><header>Miscellaneous</header><section id="H7AF2CCAE57834F27BD6E008549D39E9F"><enum>701.</enum><header>Suspension of effectiveness of certain laws</header><subsection id="H8A8A868D83B54DC38464BDBC611704F0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Waiver of inadmissibility of aliens unlawfully present</header><text>Section 212(a)(9)(B)(v) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(a)(9)(B)(v)</external-xref>) is suspended during the period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act and ending on January 20, 2017.</text></subsection><subsection id="H068B55AEA1C04447B286944F88F7AC79"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Designation for temporary protected status</header><text>No foreign state may be designated or redesignated under section 244(b) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1254a">8 U.S.C. 1254a(b)</external-xref>) during the period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act and ending on January 20, 2017. The preceding sentence shall not be construed to affect any extension of a designation under paragraph (3)(C) of such section, if the designation was made prior to the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="H198462755EF5433D8916AD702D9A0233"><enum>702.</enum><header>Temporary protected status reform</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 244 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1254a">8 U.S.C. 1254a</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H4EF80DD2EE3A4FCEA90336290961F4C9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text><subparagraph id="HF41BEFD61DAA4C22AE8A9766CCF3953A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking subparagraphs (B) and (C) and redesignating subparagraph (D) as subparagraph (B); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC53B16C56AE2414CA98AFDEF539F4240"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (5), by striking <quote>to deny temporary protected status to an alien based on the alien’s immigration status or</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3BCBF7790AFE4C489DB26CCD76736B77"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text><subparagraph id="H656C54BE326F45A4901EE3CCA2F0AF02"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)—</text><clause id="H6849E338968C4A27817C130E7B815673"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>, and any extended period of designation,</quote>;</text></clause><clause id="HB7750981796A4D6A9DEB1A5483B3F29C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>or, if later, the expiration of the most recent previous extension under subparagraph (C)</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="HA6C823D78C1A4FD2A6F8B4472BDF3109"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>is extended for</quote> and all that follows, and inserting <quote>may be extended for one additional period of up to 18 months, in the discretion of the Attorney General.</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE10B0174F36C49E58BD44F41FAB61831"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (5)(B), by striking the second sentence;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBD2A221F68C747AEB3DDFD4FE488B982"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (c)(1)(A)—</text><subparagraph id="H4300447EE3A04464B74C75531EDECDED"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in clause (iii), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H41C0970948D94332B18B5958617EB4A7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in clause (iv), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H41CBC7B69E6F4DE4B3542E2988C154A0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding after clause (iv) the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H00374ECEF48743E8864DEA9CE343EA53" style="OLC"><clause id="H330E16BE87124FC195EE23070CC07F19"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the alien had lawful immigration status in the United States on the effective date of the most recent designation of that state.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8FF00774FC7B4611A3A579A79C07C745"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (g), by striking <quote>aliens who are or may become otherwise deportable or have been paroled into the United States</quote> and inserting <quote>aliens who may become otherwise deportable</quote>.</text></paragraph></section></title></legis-body></bill> 

