<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S2170 IS: Veterans E-Health and Telemedicine Support Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-10-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2170</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20151008">October 8, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S376">Mrs. Ernst</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S287">Mr. Cornyn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S326">Mr. Udall</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S384">Mr. Tillis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S261">Mr. Sessions</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S343">Mr. Boozman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S381">Mr. Rounds</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S340">Ms. Ayotte</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S153">Mr. Grassley</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S359">Mr. Heinrich</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSVA00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend title 38, United States Code, to improve the ability of health care professionals to treat
			 veterans through the use of telemedicine, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H680C21C3F89A43E5B673ED53E8D34E35" style="OLC">
 <section id="HFFD5D79D766D45DDBAD26C7D663D445C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Veterans E-Health and Telemedicine Support Act of 2015</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>VETS Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H3504770C6ABD4172BD9FFC31B6CBF68D" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Licensure of health care professionals of the Department of Veterans Affairs providing treatment via telemedicine</header> <subsection id="HAEC68DD7328448DCB6561AE3C0DBFA22"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/17">Chapter 17</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/1730A">section 1730A</external-xref> the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3A0F2A6884944545BB2C6A07E57697D2" style="USC">
					<section id="HAC877CCDB5FB4B38842E58BD8CCA470E"><enum>1730B.</enum><header>Licensure of health care professionals providing treatment via telemedicine</header>
 <subsection id="H85A6AED6CC80442E8270978EF7AEC69E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any provision of law regarding the licensure of health care professionals, a covered health care professional may practice the health care profession of the health care professional at any location in any State, regardless of where such health care professional or the patient is located, if the health care professional is using telemedicine to provide treatment to an individual under this chapter.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2FB3A3BBE90147AF8B727181796F0D11"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Property of Federal Government</header><text>Subsection (a) shall apply to a covered health care professional providing treatment to a patient regardless of whether such health care professional or patient is located in a facility owned by the Federal Government during such treatment.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4F0D1F17A61C4CB2969EEC55A7C371BD"><enum>(c)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section may be construed to remove, limit, or otherwise affect any obligation of a covered health care professional under the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/801">21 U.S.C. 801 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H359367D2F31E40B59BAB15E1BAF6A530"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H1BDDD442FA1A45A185EED7575382D683"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>covered health care professional</term> means a health care professional who is—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HDF4B718B46BA488380895355E9A3C5AE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>authorized by the Secretary to provide health care under this chapter, including a private health care professional who provides such care under a contract entered into with the Secretary, including a contract entered into under section 1703 of this title; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8440A74E22574ACF91A7B62C6B303EEB"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">licensed, registered, or certified in a State to practice the health care profession of the health care professional.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2A3A8A5411D94EC3B81E408C319CF610"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>telemedicine</term> means the use of telecommunication technology and information technology to provide health care or support the provision of health care in situations in which the patient and health care professional are separated by geographic distance.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H441430050EF54B75ADB1383749AFA924"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of chapter 17 of such title is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 1730A the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAD1FFF21DCE1493DA07D8C52192C00D6" style="USC"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">1730B. Licensure of health care professionals providing treatment via telemedicine.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="id8CDF633F773D419DBB18CF60098DBC7E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report on telemedicine</header>
 <paragraph id="id40867C520786478C9DCF3016528C8026"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on the effectiveness of the use of telemedicine by the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idB25805825CA34C3AAD72EB5B6712FA36"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report required by paragraph (1) shall include an assessment of the following:</text> <subparagraph id="idE2737EE29EA74E949E3383AA66FB77E9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The satisfaction of veterans with telemedicine furnished by the Department.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id95fafcbd4fa54a2789c42e9f60b6ef49"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The satisfaction of health care providers in providing telemedicine furnished by the Department.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id37d619ef39bc486d84ec6878dcf41585"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The effect of telemedicine furnished by the Department on the following:</text>
 <clause id="id4D1F5E7EF5084E2691B51B95067BD16E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The ability of veterans to access health care, whether from the Department or from non-Department health care providers.</text>
 </clause><clause id="idf68a125a88ed44b6b8fe1c368b105c23"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The frequency of use by veterans of telemedicine.</text> </clause><clause id="id6422a4eeaeb84694b2cbac591fee5b26"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The productivity of health care providers.</text>
 </clause><clause id="id590ea1a07f904c878f89d5c238d4fae4"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Wait times for an appointment for the receipt of health care from the Department.</text> </clause><clause id="id94BD7809E2CE419FA8B141AD06BEC604"><enum>(v)</enum><text>The reduction, if any, in the use by veterans of services at Department facilities and non-Department facilities.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8241034e2dca4f14bb15e6de28c8038a"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The types of appointments for the receipt of telemedicine furnished by the Department that were provided during the one-year period preceding the submittal of the report.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id735fb5416b074d8f89488da933aba874"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The number of appointments for the receipt of telemedicine furnished by the Department that were requested during such period, disaggregated by Veterans Integrated Service Network.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD8F2847BDC3A44EBA5348EA4362A62C5"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Savings by the Department, if any, including travel costs, of furnishing health care through the use of telemedicine during such period.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB8578E3C427145F5B5C0CB1734BC79E0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Telemedicine defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the term <term>telemedicine</term> has the meaning given that term in section 1730B(d)(2) of title 38, United States Code, as added by subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


