<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S2372 IS: Requiring Reporting of Online Terrorist Activity Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-12-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 2372</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151208">December 8, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S221">Mrs. Feinstein</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S300">Mr. Burr</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To require reporting of terrorist activities and the unlawful distribution of information relating
			 to explosives, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Requiring Reporting of Online Terrorist Activity Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="id2EC64946CC354E65B56A49F2CFBA53F4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Requirement  to  report  terrorist  activities and  the  unlawful distribution	of information
			 relating to explosives</header>
 <subsection id="id85E6D31708F4466B82B36BF807DFFBEE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Duty To report</header><text>Whoever, while engaged in providing an electronic communication service or a remote computing service to the public through a facility or means of interstate or foreign commerce, obtains actual knowledge of any terrorist activity, including the facts or circumstances described in subsection (c), shall, as soon as reasonably possible, provide to the appropriate authorities the facts or circumstances of the alleged terrorist activities.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id6751DA1CB4D14A9D9856ADE1C6D20311"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Attorney general determination</header><text>The Attorney General shall determine the appropriate authorities referred to in subsection (a).</text> </subsection><subsection id="idEB31CFF2786A48B0B25B158E2FA09C6D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Facts or circumstances</header><text>The facts or circumstances described in this subsection, include any facts or circumstances from which there is an apparent violation of section 842(p) of title 18, United States Code, that involves distribution of information relating to explosives, destructive devices, and weapons of mass destruction.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id252F81BF089F4DF8BEFB5B3FCC8A45E6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Protection of privacy</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to require the provider of an electronic communication service or of a remote computing service—</text>
 <paragraph id="id2B5BBB92726946168A78C799FC1CB23A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to monitor any user, subscriber, or customer of that provider; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id44DC9D2644724D93B91464A9F3938303"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to monitor the content of any communication of any person described in paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idE7DF8E46AB6749B5BA2AFA215B31F792"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section, the terms <quote>electronic communication service</quote> and <quote>remote computing service</quote> have the meaning given those terms in section 2258E of title 18, United States Code (regarding sexual exploitation and other abuse of children).</text></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


