<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S723 IS: Utility Energy Service Contracts Improvement Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 723</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150312">March 12, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S353">Mr. Schatz</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S289">Mr. Alexander</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S212">Mr. Coats</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the National Energy Conservation Policy Act to provide guidance on utility energy service
			 contracts used by Federal agencies, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body>
 <section id="idE8C2701BD40E43239AF8E8C7F0F81435" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Utility Energy Service Contracts Improvement Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </section><section id="idcb0dbe8db2974dff8396d3826fc8799c"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text> <paragraph id="id0d38dace164849c9b932899fa3e285b3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Federal Government is the largest consumer of energy in the United States;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idade6ef2b0faf4bd5a775faa2992f6341"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Federal agencies are expected to meet, by law, Executive order, and mandate, stringent energy efficiency and conservation targets;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ida3c20bb4071e417cb0aedfeb60c0e5b9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the utility energy service contract (referred to in this section as <quote>UESC</quote>) was developed to provide Federal agencies an effective means to implement energy efficiency, renewable energy and water efficiency projects, and has been used successfully to invest nearly $2,700,000,000 in property at Federal facilities;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id54db2128a2d046599ae25b5205a07d08"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the General Services Administration, which manages more than 9,600 Federal properties and is the lead agency for procuring utility services for the Federal Government, has determined that UESCs may extend beyond a 10-year period under the law;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id748477d72780403fba2f94df93a22550"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the Federal Energy Management Program, which oversees the UESC program and is a principal office guiding agencies to use funding more effectively in meeting Federal and agency-specific energy and resource management objectives, has determined that UESCs may extend beyond a 10-year period under the law;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idf780449f348343f6944dcb1120069892"><enum>(6)</enum><text>extensive precedent exists for Federal agencies to contract for energy saving services using contracts with term limits of more than 10 years but not to exceed 25 years;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idd60e3a351d9c4d10a2bf9f7ecb51f1e4"><enum>(7)</enum><text>a number of Federal agencies, contrary to congressional intent, have sought to limit UESC term limits to periods of less than 10 years; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id60553385cf1849bdaa3c98393bd11385"><enum>(8)</enum><text>greater flexibility with UESCs will help reduce the operational cost of Federal agencies, ultimately saving money for taxpayers.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="id7d2f552425f042aba0877b429ca13100"><enum>3.</enum><header>Utility energy
 service contracts</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part 3 of title V of the National Energy Conservation Policy Act is amended by adding after section 553 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/8259b">42 U.S.C. 8259b</external-xref>) the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3C235D2030F440828DD71171BF824CC8" style="OLC">
				<section id="id1B74809C3A894654B99641978FDE4BF6"><enum>554.</enum><header>Utility energy
				service contracts</header>
					<subsection id="id2ee3332b889a4eebbe108b8cb4961456"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>Each Federal agency may use, to the maximum extent practicable, measures provided by law to meet energy efficiency and conservation mandates and laws, including through utility energy service contracts.</text>
					</subsection><subsection id="id4b6ad0bff4504ec7acbb3b5078cce52a"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contract
 period</header><text>The term of a utility energy service contract entered into by a Federal agency may have a contract period that extends beyond 10 years, but not to exceed 25 years.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id195c8428e322489dbf3fdb587002c873"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The conditions of a utility energy service contract entered into by a Federal agency shall include requirements for measurement, verification, and performance assurances or guarantees of the savings.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill>


