<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1372 IS: American Crude Oil Export Equality Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 1372</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150519">May 19, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S360">Ms. Heitkamp</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S288">Ms. Murkowski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S338">Mr. Manchin</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S310">Mr. Corker</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To repeal the crude oil export ban, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>American Crude Oil Export Equality Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </section><section id="ided0ef7ca983d4116a310c87b82cb85b7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text> <paragraph id="ideef44b5541f4411287030091440c1130"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the United States has enjoyed a renaissance in energy production—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idF6CAE7F18EC74E2B8CD1493F5E4A030E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>increasing domestic investment and jobs; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id36C031816509483081568E28B99661D7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>establishing the United States as a world leader in crude oil production;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9c958b15a31a4984a39c7cfeb52c4f25"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the United States upholds a commitment to free trade and open markets and has consistently opposed attempts by other nations to restrict the free flow of energy;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idf22a5746f88d417c99664015ea3673b6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>independent studies have concluded that allowing the export of domestically produced crude oil—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idC4AE70ABEA074075B1D997C11FA18AFC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>will increase the globally available supply of crude oil; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2C7C270BB0DE400E86CE0D0F30119CFD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>will tend to reduce domestic prices for gasoline and other refined petroleum products in the United States;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idBF19C4615F7F4BCC81871B25C411552D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>gasoline and other refined petroleum products are already eligible for export from the United States without restriction;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id6CF58BF887CE4A36A7E43769338D4B4A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>gasoline prices in the United States reflect the price paid on the global market for crude oil and not a separate crude oil price in the United States;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id1e8a6d8677a84b6cb31ad51dfd5738b5"><enum>(6)</enum><text>exports of crude oil produced in the United States would provide an alternative stable supplier for crude oil to allies of the United States around the world—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id5fb345aa5f3f43e7aefb34942287cd71"><enum>(A)</enum><text>allowing United States crude oil exports to compete on equal footing with other international crudes;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3EFC44EF3AFA445283C6C247AE419CE4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>allowing United States crude oil exports to compete with and potentially displace crude oil exports from Iran, as potential easing of sanctions could lead to Iran regaining market share;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id21F005F2DB354349AC059B394960CA90"><enum>(C)</enum><text>facilitating assistance to the countries of Europe and Eurasia to diversify their energy sources and achieve energy security by providing another option to protect against possible unstable supply flows; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1837b49fc42249cdaa71175798387812"><enum>(D)</enum><text>allowing the United States to use national energy policy to further United States interests abroad; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id7511df34d0c84914ac9c6180435d3c81"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the United States should remove all restrictions on the export of domestically produced crude oil or crude oil of any origin, which will increase economic benefits, enhance energy security, improve the trade deficit, and promote key national security interests of the United States domestically and around the world.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="idc59f9a42366b4d4290cc7dc3ac4fd339"><enum>3.</enum><header>Crude oil exports</header>
			<subsection id="id0540d750a6044965b4bfa591e7ed28d3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Repeal of presidential authority To restrict oil exports</header>
 <paragraph id="id8452b2b9946f4f2abd0ebf4f31ee7903"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 103 of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6212">42 U.S.C. 6212</external-xref>) is repealed.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id44f24760eaca4adabd4a936b783a9e74"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header> <subparagraph id="idfff4baa864614a7eab4bc12865f18783"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The table of contents for the Energy Policy and Conservation Act is amended by striking the item relating to section 103.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idefdf2348363443239da5edd2357724d1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Energy Policy and Conservation Act is amended—</text> <clause id="id8f66e65fcfa7449fb814fb3ae231c2ab"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in section 251 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6271">42 U.S.C. 6271</external-xref>)—</text>
 <subclause id="idd77abab24f914301893eca4b5773a330"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by striking subsection (d); and</text> </subclause><subclause id="idfd14ea486d6c4ab39ce068ad092deeb3"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (e) as subsection (d); and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id95f4dafa30874b5db0ccfd3ae8bf4877"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in section 523(a)(1) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6393">42 U.S.C. 6393(a)(1)</external-xref>), by striking <quote>(other than section 103 thereof)</quote>.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3C6111540FE7475CA46382EA2A080A41"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Section 12 of the Alaska Natural Gas Transportation Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/719j">15 U.S.C. 719j</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <clause id="idb0d48caaabd44a6a8156fe995b30e45a"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and section 103 of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act</quote>; and</text> </clause><clause id="id9b83169ad39945728fea8fad39a2239f"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>such Acts</quote> and inserting <quote>that Act</quote>.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id251f29f01bbc438f89ed0e792bc3f745"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Repeal of limitations on exports of oil</header>
 <paragraph id="id99ac282b87f14290a3c596e5c30c5246"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 28 of the Mineral Leasing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/185">30 U.S.C. 185</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="id3303c0a9ae4c4453b7abb6744a879673"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking subsection (u); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6a148b10cdc34ff2b40ee6bf422ad5a3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (v) through (y) as subsections (u) through (x), respectively.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id401e0686a60544ed94c7fc4ae410281f"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header> <subparagraph id="idc622af0248e44f678a4dc631a54a206d"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Section 1107(c) of the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/3167">16 U.S.C. 3167(c)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>(u) through (y)</quote> and inserting <quote>(u) through (x)</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6199c6033c1544c0a6aeed8449573615"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Deepwater Port Act of 1974 is amended—</text> <clause id="idEA4F5A0E9ED94AC3AF2451B7E9A9E8AC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in section 3(9)(A) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1502">33 U.S.C. 1502(9)(A)</external-xref>), by striking <quote>except as otherwise provided in section 23,</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idD9946E76CA0442D1BB84FF6122596C7B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking section 23 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1522">33 U.S.C. 1522</external-xref>).</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id355b919580494f8fa57f36b737f2ee57"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Section 203(c) of the Trans-Alaska Pipeline Authorization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1652">43 U.S.C. 1652(c)</external-xref>) is amended in the first sentence by striking <quote>(w)(2), and (x))</quote> and inserting <quote>(v)(2), and (w))</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id296391a3dc83403698cc6aa215cc6f36"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Section 509(c) of the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/2009">43 U.S.C. 2009(c)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>subsection (w)(2)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (v)(2)</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idbb29aa7b03304b618f6feeeaed4f3744"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Repeal of limitations on export of OCS oil or gas</header><text>Section 28 of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1354">43 U.S.C. 1354</external-xref>) is repealed.</text> </subsection><subsection id="idf6194d6ba3324d1d8b8fdfcff26e08d1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Termination of limitation on exportation of crude oil</header><text>Section 7(d) of the Export Administration Act of 1979 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc-appendix" parsable-cite="usc-appendix/50/2406">50 U.S.C. App. 2406(d)</external-xref>) (as continued in effect pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>)) shall have no force or effect.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="ide1e3f49d27364c5c9be26eb2638669e5"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Clarification of crude oil regulation</header>
 <paragraph id="idebfa397d08e9464d81fe1c352bfd1940"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), section 754.2 of title 15, Code of Federal Regulations (relating to crude oil) shall have no force or effect.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id96669ACE63E54299AC97AEEEB60C4CC0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>With respect to the export of crude oil from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve, the regulation referred to in paragraph (1) (as in effect on the date that is 1 day before the date of enactment of this Act) shall continue in full force and effect.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ide0fc30d954e34523946dc851c6eeecbe"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Crude oil license requirements</header><text>A license to export to a country crude oil (as the term is defined in subsection (a) of the regulation referred to in paragraph (1)) (as in effect on the date that is 1 day before the date of enactment of this Act), shall be required from the Bureau of Industry and Security of the Department of Commerce, after consultation with other relevant agencies, only if—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id728c6f718e48418eb66d2d7b09e284bf"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the country is subject to sanctions or trade restrictions imposed by the United States;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id508cc79aab1b4bbf9d74d4f99edd60c2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the President or Congress has designated the country as subject to exclusion for reasons of national security; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id68FD2193901E46459AC49B642817D775"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the export concerns the withdrawal of crude oil from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id655a817d84d44835895d96d555fed4a9"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Effect</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in section 4, any provision of law or regulation that curtails, limits, delays, or otherwise restricts the export of crude oil shall have no force or effect.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="id07fb16ea3aa841a4b3eddb713f4d6490"><enum>4.</enum><header>Exceptions and presidential authority</header>
 <subsection id="idc8aea47d1e864c1f99e72484e8c7c2e0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President may impose export licensing requirements or other restrictions on the export of crude oil from the United States for a period of not more than 1 year, if—</text>
 <paragraph id="ide8a04fd6c9e54f1c981a377da4b6ecff"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the President declares a national emergency and formally notices the declaration of a national emergency in the Federal Register;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id050a37001c9b43419521eb0cbf1dd9fd"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the export licensing requirements or other restrictions on the export of crude oil from the United States under this section apply to 1 or more countries, persons, or organizations in the context of sanctions or trade restrictions imposed by the United States for reasons of national security by the Executive authority of the President or by Congress; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id16956797CD8D48FF9136FF4471996E24"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Secretary of Commerce, in consultation with the Secretary of Energy, finds and reports to the President that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id4D7AC74EAC174798B68C135892CBEB8E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the export of crude oil pursuant to this Act has caused sustained material oil supply shortages or sustained oil prices significantly above world market levels that are directly attributable to the export of crude oil produced in the United States; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5983A3390D864A4FBFB811C22EDDD3EF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>those supply shortages or price increases have caused or are likely to cause sustained material adverse employment effects in the United States.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id893e3771615845ad8587b86ed6347c17"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Renewal</header><text>Any requirement or restriction imposed pursuant to paragraph (1) may be renewed for 1 or more additional periods of not more than 1 year each.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="id3B8B2A4C598D4C96BDC1EE83B8E3BFF5"><enum>5.</enum><header>GAO review and report</header>
 <subsection id="id796DF09FB6CC476889021E769CF3D1EE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter for 2 years, the Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a review of—</text>
 <paragraph id="id894363BCB4494DEFABA984D085A10DF1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>energy production in the United States; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id2F714B61750848ED9437CDFC29B75CEA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the effects, if any, of crude oil exports from the United States on consumers, independent refiners, and shipbuilding and ship repair yards.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idf0eb28e0492d43db912a60be67820219"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents of report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after commencing each review under subsection (a), the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Committees on Energy and Natural Resources, Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs, Commerce, Science, and Transportation, and Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committees on Natural Resources, Energy and Commerce, Financial Services, and Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives a report that includes—</text>
 <paragraph id="id22F053374D464AF8974BFF5D0BAE7A45"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a statement of the principal findings of the review; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id8F3F00B7A7894FA6B263030C039572C1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recommendations for Congress and the President to address any job loss in the shipbuilding and ship repair industry or adverse impacts on consumers and refiners that the Comptroller General of the United States attributes to unencumbered crude oil exports in the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


