<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S990 IS: Breaking Down Barriers to Innovation Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 990</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150416">April 16, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To improve the process by which the Librarian of Congress considers requests for exemptions to
			 section 1201(a)(1)(A) of title 17, United States Code, and to ease
			 restrictions on the use of certain statutory exemptions to the Digital
			 Millennium Copyright Act.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Breaking Down Barriers to Innovation Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </section><section id="id408884AEA0894B52AABC96F765817766"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text> <paragraph id="idc509683e98e94c92a1104e3cf80750c7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Librarian of Congress (referred to in this section as the <quote>Librarian</quote>) should ensure that noninfringing uses of copyrighted works, as well as activities unrelated to the copyrighted works, are not unduly burdened by the application of section 1201 of title 17, United States Code;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id781adf406d994a5997bafd5bd21fc482"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Librarian should apply section 1201 of title 17, United States Code, in a manner that strikes a balance between the ability of persons to make noninfringing use of copyrighted works and the legitimate protection of intellectual property rights;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ide23d2436c9d64026b8f60a09b0e56427"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Librarian, in considering whether to grant exemptions to the prohibition on the circumvention of technological protection measures, should recognize that such measures prevent persons from undertaking activities unrelated to the use of copyrighted works; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id8dab470f90784f3080b7bb28134b6935"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the Librarian—</text> <subparagraph id="idC606DFBD22104DBABC4A58E9014A9A9E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>should not impose undue burdens on proponents of exemptions; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9417100FB57549608F9BC2F633C27201"><enum>(B)</enum><text>should ensure that the rulemaking process for considering exemptions is responsive to changes in the technological landscape.</text>
				</subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="id2317F88035EE4B0480942BCB3197321F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Circumvention of copyright protection systems</header>
			<subsection id="id063E54896354457599704C9CA49B1BF5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Violations regarding circumvention of technological measures</header>
 <paragraph id="id98584E722BAF41B2A63AD4DDC40A8451"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1201(a)(1) of title 17, United States Code, is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="idBF925EACC78240FFBA28436CD05931D6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking the second sentence;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id07FDC0C48D1E440481785640583374EA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C)—</text> <clause id="id702BA2360D484A8C864A468020980D43"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the matter preceding clause (i)—</text>
 <subclause id="id57E2A9B4B7E5460FA86426CA62070361"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by striking <quote>During the 2-year period described in subparagraph (A), and during each succeeding 3-year period,</quote> and inserting <quote>Every 3 years,</quote>; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="id75F304D38C5A4F0D9A65674779FC4D4A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by striking <quote>the Librarian shall examine</quote> and inserting <quote>the Librarian shall consider, if applicable</quote>;</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="idF6D199855D384B58B367296063A16357"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in clause (i), by striking <quote>the availability for use of copyrighted works</quote> and inserting <quote>any reduction in the availability for use of copyrighted works as a result of the prohibition on the circumvention of technological measures</quote>;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6F7764EB1DBC49DEB6E2B3921C76887F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in clause (iii), by striking <quote>or research</quote> and inserting the following: <quote>repair, recycling, research, or other fair uses, and on access to information not subject to copyright protection</quote>;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idD6738DC980734CB3872D02AAD0C2DC74"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>by redesignating clauses (iv) and (v) as clauses (vi) and (vii), respectively; and</text> </clause><clause id="idB936BE0E6342454DA871DACD3FC7B824"><enum>(v)</enum><text>by inserting after clause (iii) the following:</text>
							<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id77010712E77B4C64B5EFD8D71664CE65" style="OLC">
 <clause id="idc59bdd51d48e458e88c7bc51c44780fc"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the impact that the prohibition on the circumvention of technological measures has on the accessibility of works and technologies for persons with disabilities;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id7539348512c44e5ea2e1be7d7c1eb31d"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the impact that the prohibition on the circumvention of technological measures has on the furtherance of security research;</text></clause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0CFF54B71656481A91D590AF3C0B8CE1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (D) as subparagraph (F);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id58DFDBF00A004C279A55B5C6330A1D04"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (E);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE4DF60A9FA24474693B82ED44DA80EBD"><enum>(E)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (C) the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2CACD0E8A4904D5D8CBC02B7DE2366C1" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="id6159849bdb42436882a394cc9d71bde9" indent="up2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>In making a determination under subparagraph (C), the Librarian—</text>
 <clause id="idA2F64ACD64784FE7A63C444A47DF7341"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall consider the totality of the evidence available to the Librarian; and</text> </clause><clause id="idFA83667084F845BC9F7E865E13AC93BB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>may not assign the burden of proof to a proponent of an exemption.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id540da1eac68e492c914893fe5b48dd82" indent="up2"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The Librarian, at the discretion of the Librarian, may conduct a rulemaking proceeding under subparagraph (C) outside of the 3-year review process described in that subparagraph if the Librarian determines that it is substantially likely that persons who are users of a copyrighted work which is in a particular class of works are, or are likely to be in the succeeding 3-year period, adversely affected by virtue of the prohibition under subparagraph (A) in their ability to make noninfringing uses of that particular class of works under this title.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6618E5949855489C92279B5B5CBA059B"><enum>(F)</enum><text>in subparagraph (F), as redesignated—</text> <clause id="id09AE8CBFF04141C180B68A0339ABF125"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>The Librarian</quote> and inserting <quote>(i) The Librarian</quote>;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id2A6D4B5C46734C008956DEB3A9939AC7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>adversely affected, and the prohibition</quote> and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id8F08D283801549E98B5B49EE2D050F13"> <text>adversely affected.</text><clause id="id41F1B485C8244851890400136F6E120E" indent="up3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The prohibition</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </clause><clause id="idCAF5F07CF46343558CCC172260BB5D5F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
							<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idEE9B9150A34D4D4F9514EA7E0E5B496F" style="OLC">
 <clause id="id56EB725D90F24B1ABCC4C9091F381064" indent="up3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>At the end of each 3-year period described in subparagraph (C), the Librarian shall renew for the ensuing 3-year period each exemption granted under subparagraph (C) unless the Librarian determines that, as a result of changed circumstances, it is unlikely that any persons who are users of a copyrighted work in the class of copyrighted works to which the exemption relates will be adversely affected by virtue of the prohibition under subparagraph (A) in their ability to make noninfringing uses of that particular class of works under this title.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6621107B8A874DC3AB9A92171EB0AADF"><enum>(G)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (F), as redesignated, the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8D357BEF60BD4F4D86071390B6FA3149" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="idb6d2df2b78264b5ea653ab2624646a3c" indent="up2"><enum>(G)</enum><text>For purposes of this paragraph—</text>
 <clause id="idF4EAE0F310494E658099125CB8C3D7D3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>persons are <term>adversely affected</term> if a technological measure that effectively controls access to a work which is in a particular class of copyrighted works diminishes the ability of the persons to make noninfringing uses of that particular class of works under this title;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id58d8b9ba94e14061a4278f1937325d41"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if a technological measure inhibits noninfringing uses of a work which is in a particular class of copyrighted works relating to improving accessibility of works or technologies for persons with disabilities, there shall be a presumption that persons who use that particular class of work are likely to be adversely affected; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id94CB7592BB36449A93493F0CE4BBD8F4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the Librarian may find that a use of a work is noninfringing based upon the totality of the circumstances, including—</text>
 <subclause id="id91c48bad188e48bda388622dbb6f334a"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the presence of supporting judicial precedent;</text> </subclause><subclause id="id79e64971dc3e4479afa98c9511407a8c"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the absence of contrary judicial precedent;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id83927b5b524c48f9a36693d39fbcc87d"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the intent of Congress; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="id8814b1e3cf2d46a2bd0df4888eef343d"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>any other factors relevant to—</text>
 <item id="idFE591C22F190409FBEEAE28F58B64728"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>assessing the applicability of copyright protection; or</text> </item><item id="idCB16E1FA7C7848A089EFD83882DB4A09"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>exceptions to or limitations on copyright protection.</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idc875f58b4d6240ad85855a5fbfe7ab24"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Librarian of Congress, in consultation with the Register of Copyrights and the Assistant Secretary for Communications and Information of the Department of Commerce, shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idDEB220D45BAB4C3682CF539AE8F4E52F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>conduct a study, including by soliciting public comment, on—</text> <clause id="id205043F2BDC44A02AF97FBA9EF497CC8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>ways to ease the burden on persons requesting an exemption under section 1201(a)(1)(C) of title 17, United States Code, as amended by paragraph (1);</text>
 </clause><clause id="id72E5F1091E054AA5842674F6C27765BB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>how the process for requesting and granting exemptions described in clause (i) can be used to foster security research; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idDCF1FBB64ADD48B0AEA305767DF1E6BE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>how the process for requesting and granting exemptions described in clause (i) can be expanded to enable the sale and dissemination of circumvention tools, as described in subsections (a)(2) and (b)(1) of section 1201 of title 17, United States Code, for the sole purposes of enabling circumventions with respect to the classes of copyrighted works that the Librarian has published under subparagraph (F) of subsection (a)(1) of such section, as redesignated by paragraph (1); and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id45533116FCE64876B618FBC93BB60519"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall submit to Congress a report on the study conducted under subparagraph (A) that includes—</text> <clause id="id54954671c0264e7f97a19cbb4e71af3b"><enum>(i)</enum><text>proposed legislation to achieve the goals described in clauses (i) and (ii) of subparagraph (A); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idf843c59d135a4a05ba3c9f6117f2c117"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a description of any obstacles to the expansion described in clause (iii) of subparagraph (A) and proposed legislation for achieving such an expansion.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idA9BA1C5A459142CDA705D656BF4745AF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reverse engineering</header><text>Section 1201(f) of title 17, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="id7A9BABBE84E041B2B2C83497E596DE3F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>for the sole purpose</quote> and all that follows through <quote>engaging in the circumvention</quote> and inserting the following: <quote>for the sole purpose of undertaking activities aimed at achieving interoperability of an independently created computer program with other programs</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id7389423BC1284F85A5F39AFA5417CD10"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>in order to enable</quote> and all that follows through <quote>achieve such interoperability</quote> and inserting the following: <quote>for the activities described under paragraph (1), or for the purpose of enabling interoperability of an independently created computer program with other programs</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idA9B615AC660D40E5B35385501DAA67DC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>if the person</quote> and all that follows through <quote>other programs, and</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idA0B7DC7BCE78445E8DC0002EBC0EAE8E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Encryption research</header><text>Section 1201(g) of title 17, United States Code, is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="idCEB5545138A44531A04EAF6CA2BA6AE0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)(A)—</text> <subparagraph id="id8630C3D6209243C6AE056EC95A42BF0D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>activities necessary to identify and analyze flaws</quote> and inserting <quote>activities relating to the identification and analysis of flaws</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5e77f658b6cb41268152456b696c615b"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>to advance the state of knowledge in the field of encryption technology</quote> and inserting <quote>for research purposes</quote>;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id37CFD602A31B49AA8E4321D07A920852"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id829F6D40B32E4BE282232409AE9AEF6F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>necessary to conduct</quote> and inserting <quote>undertaken in the course of conducting</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC46C3DDDB2374A7C9A058C62CECC5B02"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D), by striking all that follows <quote>infringement under this title</quote> and inserting a period;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id79EFD758A54D485FB3B7C9CC2C8F1161"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking paragraphs (3) and (5);</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idFC84C4CAAA5649B7B3F206F4A3239B4F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (4) as paragraph (3); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id8B258AF15817498EB57394192C58B7DC"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)(B), as redesignated, by striking <quote>with whom he or she is working collaboratively</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id478CC4C42A614CED916E96BC9D06F81C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Protection of personally identifying information</header><text>Section 1201(i)(1)(D) of title 17, United States Code, is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="id193CF6744DD44D168A1021FA1A3DD854"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>solely</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idC4C2E5FC98FC432DB22D0D6E551C2E1D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>who seeks to gain access to the work protected, and is not in violation of any other law</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id8A193BE1F1FD4696BF98928FDEBAB8E0"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Security testing</header><text>Section 1201(j) of title 17, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="id804FB51088B247EEBB6C405708AC1FD7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking all that follows <quote>infringement under this title</quote> and inserting a period;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id33606F355168472398CB6E8720689FB0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (3);</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id4F7F839AB04B4D6092A3D98AE82A5FFD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (4) as paragraph (3); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idC98C9823F6FB4E448B9669791B2D0529"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), as redesignated, by striking <quote>subsection (2)</quote> and all that follows and inserting <quote>paragraph (2)</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body> </bill> 

