<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1633 IS: Celebrating the First Woman in Congress Currency Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-06-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1633</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150618">June 18, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S375">Mr. Daines</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require that the face of Federal Reserve Notes bear the likeness of Jeannette Rankin before the
			 likeness of any other woman appears on a Federal Reserve Note, and for
			 other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body>
 <section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Celebrating the First Woman in Congress Currency Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="id400DB4DA8455437EA8192AC254C02BA0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Likeness of Jeannette Rankin required to be included on the face of Federal
 Reserve Notes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The eighth undesignated paragraph of section 16 of the Federal Reserve Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/418">12 U.S.C. 418</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new sentence: <quote>Beginning on the date of enactment of this Act, if the Secretary of the Treasury determines that the face of one of the foregoing denominations shall bear the likeness of a woman, the face of any Federal Reserve Note may not bear the likeness of any other woman until after the date on which Federal Reserve Notes bearing the likeness of Jeannette Rankin are first printed.</quote>.</text></section></legis-body></bill>


