<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S267 IS: General of the Army Omar Bradley Property Transfer Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 267</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150127">January 27, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S351">Mr. Toomey</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To authorize the transfer of certain items under the control of the Omar Bradley Foundation to the
 descendants of General Omar Bradley.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="idA82DF5972F594087A03A8411B4CF5E37" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>General of the Army Omar Bradley Property Transfer Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id69D22BAD211F4EF4BD9637D8F1F30501" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Transfer of certain items of the Omar Bradley Foundation to the descendants of General Omar Bradley</header><subsection id="id1C044288A35242E5B5680F0AA68D1467"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Transfer authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Omar Bradley Foundation, Pennsylvania, may transfer, without consideration, to the child of General of the Army Omar Nelson Bradley and his first wife Mary Elizabeth Quayle Bradley, namely Elizabeth Bradley, such items of the Omar Bradley estate under the control of the Foundation as the Secretary of the Army determines to be without historic value to the Army.</text></subsection><subsection id="id82B41A5B19104EFD9551971741CEC29C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Time of submittal of claim for transfer</header><text>No item may be transferred under subsection (a) unless the claim for the transfer of such item is submitted to the Omar Bradley Foundation during the 180-day period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


