<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S2429 IS: Ending Iran’s Nuclear Weapon Program Before Sanctions Relief Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-12-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 2429</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151218">December 18, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S340">Ms. Ayotte</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S300">Mr. Burr</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S339">Mr. Kirk</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S293">Mr. Graham</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S376">Mrs. Ernst</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S318">Mr. Wicker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S350">Mr. Rubio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S260">Mr. Roberts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S288">Ms. Murkowski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S303">Mr. Thune</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S236">Mr. Inhofe</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To require a report on the military dimensions of Iran's nuclear program and to prohibit the
			 provision of sanctions relief to Iran until Iran has verifiably ended all
			 military dimensions of its nuclear program, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
 <section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Ending Iran’s Nuclear Weapon Program Before Sanctions Relief Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="id1E0A799DF33C403998D4F26A431BAF42" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Report on military dimensions of Iran’s nuclear program; limitations on sanctions relief</header> <subsection id="id6e8d8591baf14b65804ac7cc9a4eedd7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of National Intelligence, in coordination with the Secretary of Energy, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that—</text>
 <paragraph id="id1BD6A939AC2442249204A66C5718C55B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>at a minimum, provides a detailed assessment of the nature, scope, and duration of each activity specified in subsection (b);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idBB18A8658D664B888CE8B93DB6D054A6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>with respect to each activity specified in subsection (b), assesses—</text> <subparagraph id="id36a1bc7686bd40fab656b89c29791560"><enum>(A)</enum><text>whether the activity continues or when the activity ended;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8DFA251CA401422C8FF104D77DFF2B0C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>whether Iran consulted, cooperated, or collaborated with any foreign entity in the activity and, if so, a full description of the nature, scope, and duration of such consultation, cooperation, or collaboration;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id775e75b3d79b4304bbd5c74856ec0b06"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the differences between the conclusions of the International Atomic Energy Agency and the most recent determination of the intelligence community (as defined in section 3(4) of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3003">50 U.S.C. 3003(4)</external-xref>));</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id58f755105c62423ca8dca0f52333136a"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the ability of Iran to quickly resume the activity, if the activity has ended, and to advance beyond the current stage of development; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id80cc68e0cee245c5b888c48c17e5e42b"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the credibility of Iran’s arguments related to dual-use technology; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0067880C7D8A42B28C16E42349E6FE98"><enum>(3)</enum><text>includes—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idda05ed4cb8e840f1ad27726385232633"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a summary of refusals by Iran to cooperate with International Atomic Energy Agency inspectors and requests since January 2003;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9ca813f4c7cc4ba7b3033c15d674bab2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a list of any Iranian institutes or other entities involved in nuclear weapon activities or research;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id92d7bab336e44200ba5ca47d8a91698c"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a list of Iranian scientists or other experts who worked on Iran’s nuclear weapon program; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2cbb0048f2034e01be3b140c26127774"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a list of sites where Iranian nuclear weapon related activities are occurring or have occurred.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idE1C7BEEF4EF9432687110DC27BA001DA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Activities specified</header><text>The activities specified in this subsection are the following:</text> <paragraph id="idd01f0a9743e049408240d8f75ed96d09"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The existence of management and organization structures to facilitate the development of a nuclear explosive device.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id837deaadc90b4fc29bdc08f63196451d"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Procurement activities associated with a nuclear weapon program.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id6d88b0ccf85d40b28515e2e36d67ae68"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Covert acquisition of uranium or plutonium, covert uranium conversion, covert uranium reconversion, and covert uranium enrichment activities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id8168b20cc3b04abd9ba3e82cb6f73923"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Attempted or actual acquisition of nuclear weapon design information.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idf9f22bb895ab48c29baa80a422d378d9"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Metallurgical work associated with nuclear devices.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id95a1246fdc374a988909f147c81b6489"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Development of detonators and associated equipment for a nuclear weapon.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idf5917061d69c44f28bb60a6e9269e484"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Possession of multipoint initiation technology relevant to a nuclear explosive device.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id390f1ef15a524e56b205656a51c0b8ac"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Use of multipoint initiation technology for experiments associated with a nuclear explosive device.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id14957cb981c74ccfa3ef2269bae40959"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Development of simulated components for a nuclear explosive device, including components relevant to the dynamic compressive testing of those components.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id22327b33d6bf47b99d3cb927f1cf5d2b"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Computer modeling studies of component arrangements specific to nuclear explosive configurations based on implosion technology and studies relating to high explosives modeling.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id1a8dd98af8f34f0cbf3c4ee3d3ae3561"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Experiments with materials and configurations that could generate neutrons under shock compression for the purpose of initiating an implosion-type nuclear explosive device.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id1a64483a578e40e6a71f5bd632d30002"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Planning, preparation, and execution of experiments relevant to testing a nuclear explosive device, specifically, but not limited to, tests to determine whether detonator firing components would function over a long distance between the firing point and a test device located down a deep shaft.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idb12f78a941024158a4082e6b20623ec1"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Activities related to the integration of a new spherical payload into the existing payload chamber of the re-entry vehicle for a ballistic missile.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idcdd352aee3dc47ddbaaa1406ba597b5f"><enum>(14)</enum><text>Activities related to a fuzing, arming, and firing system for a heavy spherical ballistic missile payload.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id6a72d05b3cd24e6f8daba5e52dedc64e"><enum>(15)</enum><text>Activities at Parchin Military Complex related to nuclear weapons.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id8ac44c535c1b4b2b972d9201f5bf059a"><enum>(16)</enum><text>Nuclear weapon related activities at the Physics Research Center and subsequent organizations, and the purpose of such activities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id50a0c0829e3a433c8aec4e9d03073473"><enum>(17)</enum><text>Activities associated with the research, development, testing, or fielding related to ballistic missiles capable of carrying a nuclear weapon.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id69c9fbe572fa40cca25cce62bcc691ec"><enum>(18)</enum><text>Activities by Iran to conceal nuclear weapon related activities.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id065487614013446C8429E5001B5EA9E9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Limitations on provision of sanctions relief to Iran</header><text>Notwithstanding section 135 of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2160e">42 U.S.C. 2160e</external-xref>) or any other provision of law, the United States Government shall not provide any sanctions relief to Iran until the date that is 90 days after—</text>
 <paragraph id="id51891a07900949e4a8b11fc7d717babe"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the submission of the report required by subsection (a);</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idc913a9793f494013be444a3a66bf8963"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Director of National Intelligence, the Secretary of Energy, the Secretary of State, and the Secretary of Defense jointly certify to the appropriate congressional committees that Iran has verifiably ended all military dimensions of its nuclear program, including research, development, testing, or fielding related to ballistic missiles capable of carrying a nuclear weapon; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id53AB1FA6E1DA48A584922284F8B5C2E5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>there is enacted into law a joint resolution approving the provision of sanctions relief.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id3889C67169A34ABABD821E7022435DEB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text>
 <paragraph id="idfe487f43456940c78659ba098061e8d2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="id713975AF9560486690DF4144225FDE68"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs, the Committee on Finance, the Committee on Foreign Relations, and the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id65D4655A5EA04C1D839CE1B10C80E9A1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Financial Services, the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Ways and Means, and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idC5B87B2092E44A0EAFFA8BE729D912D4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Foreign person</header><text>The term <term>foreign person</term> means a person that is not a United States person.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idbb687ab5a2844a44af40aac060f3c1e7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Person</header><text>The term <term>person</term> means an individual or entity.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id72AC1F9E634C43658FA12EE05240ADA8"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Sanctions relief</header><text>The term <term>sanctions relief</term> means the termination, waiver, deferral, or other suspension of any sanctions imposed by the United States with respect to Iran pursuant to a statute, executive order, or regulation, including sanctions applicable to United States persons and sanctions applicable to foreign persons.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id3BE586BE0F354A649BFAB12CE991E9FE"><enum>(5)</enum><header>United States person</header><text>The term <term>United States person</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="idf30370a24e9c4ae5ab8cd086e3f0b485"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a United States citizen or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence to the United States; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5dc50206f7634a81b31d3dd78a960e17"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an entity organized under the laws of the United States or of any jurisdiction within the United States, including a foreign branch of such an entity.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


