<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S2278 IS: Promoting Unlicensed Spectrum Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-11-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 2278</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151110">November 10, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S353">Mr. Schatz</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To promote the availability of additional unlicensed spectrum for innovation and investment, and
			 for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Promoting Unlicensed Spectrum Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="id979961938D054D6B8825C7AAE2461578"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act—</text> <paragraph id="idF5DC9E746DF242A69B5F593814CE5B6E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id4CECA0B59C7E491697956527D4CD1E75"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0669D7CCBC7C41249872D48CC1EC0573"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id6C5F2016AE954133A65EB92127C8CB5B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>Assistant Secretary</term> means the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Communications and Information;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id1C2457E4FBAB493CA22C3A3B203457AA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>Commission</term> means the Federal Communications Commission;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id65AC7C672E804BB9BC74D98B3B557E61"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the term <term>Federal entity</term> has the meaning given the term in section 113(l) of the National Telecommunications and Information Administration Organization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/923">47 U.S.C. 923(l)</external-xref>);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idB72AFF7769684EAEB0DFD532D23C1740"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the term <term>Spectrum Relocation Fund</term> means the Fund established under section 118 of the National Telecommunications and Information Administration Organization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/928">47 U.S.C. 928</external-xref>); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id2ED2F21C149545819FE9E8C604239E69"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the term <term>unlicensed operations</term> means the use of spectrum on a nonexclusive basis and without the expectation of protection from interference under—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id106674D531FA4B5AA1EE0F5D2CC040A1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>part 15 of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idDCBBBAF4D0D34BEFAA77BCA0B696D645"><enum>(B)</enum><text>licensing by rule under part 96 of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations.</text>
				</subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="id12E2A9AEAD9E46199D05EA0774225C13"><enum>3.</enum><header>Federal Communications Commission allocation and allotment of spectrum</header>
 <subsection id="id1F4D76984B8A45DF87D0D70168C36F5A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission shall ensure that spectrum allocation and assignment produce a balance between radio frequency bands available for—</text>
 <paragraph id="id9B1FDE0A2D104932B86C30137527E76A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>exclusive licensing through an auction; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id0B8C2E7C5F164EE284C3D1C9083233DF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>unlicensed operations.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idAF46D6412F654874AD16D3E5CD227538"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commission shall—</text> <paragraph id="id6A3B95192AF84EBA8807F7F24D639AE3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>promulgate rules to implement subsection (a), including establishing a process that will achieve the mandate under subsection (a) in the future allocation and assignment of radio frequency bands; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id3811C04CB45C473AA8BB63344CF52546"><enum>(2)</enum><text>consider whether to adopt rules that permit unlicensed operations in spectrum assigned by auction until the licensee brings the spectrum into use by initiating commercial service.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idB0B72422403D43EE9EBEE85316CE892A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Inclusion in service rules</header><text>The Commission shall include in the service rules of an auction for spectrum any rules promulgated under subsection (b).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id0F9B8EDC6FD045A3AC3EAF4CF7290FDD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Inclusion in reports</header><text>The Commission shall ensure that each report submitted to Congress under section 1006 of the Bipartisan Budget Act of 2015 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/74">Public Law 114–74</external-xref>; 129 Stat. 584) reflects the rulemaking required under this section.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="id26438FBA7580403798E13C47D65C9539"><enum>4.</enum><header>National strategy for unlicensed spectrum</header>
 <subsection id="idD08DB48B60FC402A967B8AC79DDE3244"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text>It is the policy of the United States to—</text> <paragraph id="id0959B48EA7D24F82B26CFDA6B7A98796"><enum>(1)</enum><text>maximize the utility of the spectrum resources of the United States;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id33C3E9A45AB24CF5AB2DB870DF52D006"><enum>(2)</enum><text>advance innovation and investment in wireless broadband services; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idDBAB141016314802B62EFC65CFF77D1B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>promote a balanced spectrum policy that makes adequate spectrum resources available for both licensed and unlicensed technologies.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id9C9DF29D7C4E45A5BB0F51DABF6AC619"><enum>(b)</enum><header>National strategy</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commission, in consultation with the Assistant Secretary, shall develop a national strategy for making additional radio frequency bands available for unlicensed operations.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idFEA9B1A62D73481EABBCF9686A36B884"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>The strategy developed under subsection (b) shall include—</text> <paragraph id="id6A7B0EA926EB4C049FCD59D7EF8B333D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identification of proposed radio frequency bands to be cleared of incumbent users to permit use by devices conducting unlicensed operations;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id9C047BAC11C3485AB1F368A672E288F1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>consideration of a balanced approach that ensures that consumers have access to additional low-, mid-, and high-band radio frequency spectrum to conduct unlicensed operations;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id3CB6149FD375497A8DA3C8828BBC8C3B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>consideration of rules to permit spectrum sharing to make available additional radio frequency ranges for unlicensed operations, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id9CA72B5CDD234DBA8A281053AF31362A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>expanding utilization of the spectrum sharing model implemented by the Commission for the spectrum between 3550 and 3650 megahertz;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE4CCC587633A4BCE9BF61B5823C8D458"><enum>(B)</enum><text>allowing underlay unlicensed operations in spectrum allocated for other services in a manner that does not cause harmful interference to licensees; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idCB4DE6D00CA64E1EA4570C7244886253"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any other spectrum sharing approach that the Commission finds will—</text> <clause id="id4C6C8A0D232247AB87A66F8CA0BDA7EE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>expand opportunities for unlicensed operations in a spectrum band; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="idC8D9AE9A26C24A038A46549B3C04BFB0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>otherwise improve spectrum utilization;</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idCE5595DC0B944CD887DAC732009ADCE8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>examination of additional ways to improve the accuracy and efficacy of existing and planned databases or spectrum access systems designed to promote spectrum sharing and access to spectrum for unlicensed operations; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idB958C27D1A234EB5AB7844C1EAA8EED4"><enum>(5)</enum><text>consideration of the extent to which additional bands used for unlicensed operations may be harmonized to achieve greater economies of scale.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4463AEA1D39844CB88DE429BBC7D8D8E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report required</header>
 <paragraph id="id4C52C9D311784FC68380271F50FBC4D5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commission shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report that describes the strategy developed under subsection (b), including any recommendations for legislative change.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idFAA1FE3AE4504E378A671F202587F884"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Publication on Commission website</header><text>Not later than the date on which the Commission submits the report under paragraph (1), the Commission shall make the report publicly available on the website of the Commission.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id3950FAD5D27648E483BB1A64C03D7449"><enum>5.</enum><header>Making Federal spectrum available for unlicensed operation</header>
 <subsection id="id382F1ED6A5124663A5F4C390D945361B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 270 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Assistant Secretary, in conjunction with the Commission and the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on the steps necessary to designate additional radio frequency bands used by Federal entities for unlicensed operations in a manner that does not cause harmful interference to Federal Government operations.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id447750DE22CC490F9D6863F2D7D3AC6E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>The report required under subsection (a) shall consider—</text> <paragraph id="id6D6FA1117A67406C9D2ACBE5B29CBBD8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recommendations on how to reform the Spectrum Relocation Fund to address costs incurred by Federal entities related to sharing radio frequency bands with radio technologies conducting unlicensed operations;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id6B094DFC9F8A4FA9B03549CB0387DA7F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recommendations for ensuring the solvency of the Spectrum Relocation Fund if the Spectrum Relocation Fund is used to cover the costs described in paragraph (1);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idEB3C0F6F7FAD4A53A0F2655DE27FB3FD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>whether it may be possible for unlicensed operations to be permitted on an underlay basis in spectrum bands used by Federal entities without causing harmful interference to Federal Government operations, including impacting homeland security or national security communications needs; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id9FCD0E6263294132BD082F4DF5811B9B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>whether other spectrum sharing techniques may be used to facilitate access by radio technologies conducting unlicensed operations to Federal spectrum, such as with the access system used by the Commission for the spectrum between 3550 and 3650 megahertz.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


