<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S175 IS: Economic Development Through Tribal Land Exchange Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 175</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150113">January 13, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S223">Mrs. Boxer</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SLIA00">Committee on Indian Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for certain land to be taken into trust for the benefit of Morongo Band of Mission
 Indians, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HAE072B6FCC5B486B8716D750058ACA07" style="OLC"><section id="HC012532023A94E90BEC46745ED677364" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Economic Development Through Tribal Land Exchange Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H7ED790BAA1264F19BDC458A082CAA5E1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For the purposes of this Act, the following definitions apply:</text><paragraph id="H20770679CE854BE6A472E6E82F3E0EDE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Banning</header><text>The term <term>Banning</term> means the City of Banning, which is located in Riverside County, California adjacent to the Morongo Indian Reservation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H476762F2612E4517B3461393BAB8DDB2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Fields</header><text>The term <term>Fields</term> means Lloyd L. Fields, the owner of record of Parcel A.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFDA59BA808A047A8B51655635D61C47A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Map</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>map</quote> means the map entitled ‘Morongo Indian Reservation, County of Riverside, State of California Land Exchange Map’, and dated May 22, 2014, which is on file in the Bureau of Land Management State Office in Sacramento, California.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8B1AA769D2D140F2A8F1BA469F23510E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Parcel A</header><text>The term <term>Parcel A</term> means the approximately 41.15 acres designated on the map as <quote>Fields lands</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA4E9680F23E9482498BBFE5524CBD74A"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Parcel B</header><text>The term <term>Parcel B</term> means the approximately 41.15 acres designated on the map as <quote>Morongo lands</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4FA4AEA08E0949B0BD4DF5999ECD7E26"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Parcel C</header><text>The term <term>Parcel C</term> means the approximately 1.21 acres designated on the map as <quote>Banning land</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE1C6DEEA5E604A47AFD707085AD807A6"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Parcel D</header><text>The term <term>Parcel D</term> means the approximately 1.76 acres designated on the map as <quote>Easement to Banning</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H775212F9062541FAA99904B21E879989"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H271DC00A976945F0B0258E8F4166742D"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Tribe</header><text>The term <term>Tribe</term> means the Morongo Band of Mission Indians, a federally recognized Indian tribe.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HBEB6750673864B2F82B82652DADCFB18"><enum>3.</enum><header>Transfer of lands; trust lands, easement</header><subsection id="H086E004EC8D74129A77FFD6254320501"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Transfer of Parcel A and Parcel B and easement over Parcel D</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to any valid existing rights of any third parties and to legal review and approval of the form and content of any and all instruments of conveyance and policies of title insurance, upon receipt by the Secretary of confirmation that Fields has duly executed and deposited with a mutually acceptable and jointly instructed escrow holder in California a deed conveying clear and unencumbered title to Parcel A to the United States in trust for the exclusive use and benefit of the Tribe, and upon receipt by Fields of confirmation that the Secretary has duly executed and deposited into escrow with the same mutually acceptable and jointly instructed escrow holder a patent conveying clear and unencumbered title in fee simple to Parcel B to Fields and has duly executed and deposited into escrow with the same mutually acceptable and jointly instructed escrow holder an easement to the City for a public right-of-way over Parcel D, the Secretary shall instruct the escrow holder to simultaneously cause—</text><paragraph id="H99201734885546F6AC7EA251997AF622"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the patent to Parcel B to be recorded and issued to Fields;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1490011074404842ADA10F082820D784"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the easement over Parcel D to be recorded and issued to the City; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB01BD0DDAC1A4C5FBDB5A21394004E22"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the deed to Parcel A to be delivered to the Secretary, who shall immediately cause said deed to be recorded and held in trust for the Tribe.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H94FC72B76B63412DAA544F4B5C46786C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Transfer of Parcel C</header><text>After the simultaneous transfer of parcels A, B, and D under subsection (a), upon receipt by the Secretary of confirmation that the City has vacated its interest in Parcel C pursuant to all applicable State and local laws, the Secretary shall immediately cause Parcel C to be held in trust for the Tribe subject to—</text><paragraph id="H1E441E2392A547EE931A64C863FB7269"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any valid existing rights of any third parties; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAC50DD6CF1414A3993B34FE3995B29C0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>legal review and approval of the form and content of any and all instruments of conveyance.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

