<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S2412 IS: Tule Lake National Historic Site Establishment Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-12-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 2412</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151217">December 17, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S223">Mrs. Boxer</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S221">Mrs. Feinstein</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To establish the Tule Lake National Historic Site in the State of California, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Tule Lake National Historic Site Establishment Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </section><section id="id063b7399fc644a2999260666270cddac"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="idbcc49c3a00eb4765a38614428879054c"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Historic site</header><text>The term <quote>Historic Site</quote> means the Tule Lake National Historic Site established by section 3(a).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idFAEC01B6C6AA4021B87C7074717687ED"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Map</header><text>The term <quote>Map</quote> means the map entitled <quote>Tule Lake National Historic Site Proposed Boundary</quote>, numbered 501/128,313, and dated March 2015.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id0D95733A560D4EE584CFB43720EF423E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Monument</header><text>The term <quote>Monument</quote> means the World War II Valor in the Pacific National Monument.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ida4f826e9fd654440b53ef61b5b8da9b8"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idF20E4880FDC348DF98F9C238FD30F2B0"><enum>(5)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <quote>State</quote> means the State of California.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="ideb906121bbe54b15874ca19c9ab456e3"><enum>3.</enum><header>Tule lake national historic site</header>
 <subsection id="id8f781be3342048ab8d21ba0c65c04429"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>To preserve, protect, and interpret for the benefit of present and future generations the historic site of incarceration and segregation of United States citizens of Japanese descent and resident immigrants of Japanese citizenry at Tule Lake during World War II, there is established the Tule Lake National Historic Site in the State as a unit of the National Park System.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id721ec612bac447d6a8ed26cdd5617ffd"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Boundaries</header><text>The boundaries of the Historic Site shall be the boundaries generally depicted on the Map.</text> </subsection><subsection id="id12acbf8348de49a8888646293e9ef5e6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Availability of map</header><text>The Map shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the National Park Service.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="idfecc2d313a16493f8453cc7b635d8034"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Administration</header>
 <paragraph id="id3c8a499f1fbd4275a4ebd9b9e88444f2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall administer the Historic Site in accordance with—</text> <subparagraph id="id253530c814f54a0da8ead943e3d429ed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>this Act; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9513e32ec174444a912a089b6dd9bb3c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the laws generally applicable to units of the National Park System, including—</text> <clause id="idd9fbe09783f04bebbcdfd75dbbb127de"><enum>(i)</enum><text>section 100101(a), chapter 1003, and sections 100751(a), 100752, 100753, and 102101 of title 54, United States Code; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idf0df1137ebe04d729bc912ee9bce9911"><enum>(ii)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/54/3201">chapter 3201</external-xref> of title 54, United States Code.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idb59f3c3a9e064fb78c5fae96e4d78601"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Interagency agreement</header><text>The Director of the National Park Service and the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service shall enter into an agreement to allow the Director of the National Park Service to manage and interpret the resources of the portions of the Historic Site, as depicted on the Map, that are located within the boundary of the Tule Lake National Wildlife Refuge, consistent with the management requirements of the Refuge.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id6e882f4927594407bd0527bf4800876b"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Shared resources</header><text>To the maximum extent practicable, the Secretary may use the resources of the Lava Beds National Monument to administer the Historic Site.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="id91ed6d634a4b43dc967ae026e900d7d7"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Management  plan</header>
 <subparagraph id="idA0386EAF18B64A5EA43664A06F97F450"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date on which funds are made available to prepare a general management plan for the Historic Site, the Secretary shall prepare the general management plan in accordance with section 100502 of title 54, United States Code.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8FFD7A1D53CE4289B371206A25652153"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>The Secretary shall coordinate the preparation and implementation of the general management plan under subparagraph (A) with the Tule Lake National Wildlife Refuge.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idbe20af3f924b45dea4a549e3646871ee"><enum>4.</enum><header>Removal of tule lake unit from the world war ii valor in the  pacific national monument</header>
 <subsection id="id03b5cbd8b304429997b86f9222e88e8e"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Boundaries</header><text>The boundaries of the Monument are revised to exclude from the Monument the land and interests in land known as the <quote>Tule Lake Unit</quote>, consisting of portions of the Tule Lake Segregation Center National Historic Landmark and Camp Tule Lake, as depicted on the Map.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="idAF96A97753B14823BF9A07CF773533AF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Incorporation into Historic Site</header>
 <paragraph id="idFA8002B020644720825070020100C896"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The land and interests in land excluded from the Monument under subsection (a) are incorporated in and made part of the Historic Site in accordance with section 3.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id22a8a221ddcc4a20930fab0646ce84ae"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>Any funds for the purposes of the land and interests in land excluded from the Monument under subsection (a) shall be made available for the purposes of the Historic Site.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idf00f503043114aff96d2a5c31b6036fe"><enum>(c)</enum><header>References</header><text>Any reference in a law, regulation, document, record, map, or other paper of the United States to the Tule Lake Unit of World War II Valor in the Pacific National Monument shall be considered to be a reference to the Tule Lake National Historic Site.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="id92e206356a994ddb8262f613e09db9f0"><enum>5.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as are necessary to carry out this Act.</text> </section></legis-body> </bill> 

