<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S2221 IS: Ensuring Access to Affordable and Quality Home Care for Seniors and People with Disabilities Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-10-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2221</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20151029">October 29, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S260">Mr. Roberts</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S289">Mr. Alexander</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S305">Mr. Isakson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S254">Mr. Enzi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S287">Mr. Cornyn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S323">Mr. Risch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S118">Mr. Hatch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S357">Mrs. Fischer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S358">Mr. Flake</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S197">Mr. McCain</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S299">Mr. Vitter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S212">Mr. Coats</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S347">Mr. Moran</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To preserve the companionship services exemption for minimum wage and overtime pay, and the live-in
			 domestic services exemption for overtime pay, under the Fair Labor
			 Standards Act of 1938.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HF5C5E33423B2426E9E4D7842ED134FAB" style="OLC">
 <section id="HE19B38A6F2664ACB8986DB4E94FCDBC7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Ensuring Access to Affordable and Quality Home Care for Seniors and People with Disabilities Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H94F13D7799D34E7BBE5761F7CAE470A0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 3 of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/203">29 U.S.C. 203</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H10BFCDD6E1AB44EF880EB29D66B92965" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H6422584259FF44199E9ABC12402FA919"><enum>(z)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id3DADD632F7E849B79C4BF7538787846D"><enum>(1)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H4141E030CBE54E2EAC76615FBA8AAF1D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), <term>companionship services</term> as used in section 13(a)(15), means services that provide fellowship, care, and protection for individuals who, because of advanced age or physical or mental infirmity, are unable to care for themselves, including non-medical in-home personal care (which includes assistance with activities of daily living and instrumental activities of daily living) and household work related to the care of the aged or infirm individuals (such as meal preparation, bed making, washing of clothes, errands, assistance to appointments, laundry, medication reminders, bathing, assistance with incontinence and grooming, and other similar services). Such term may include the performance of general household work, provided that such work does not exceed 20 percent of the total weekly hours worked.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H77CF7EB5CF0646E9B0CB7337C064ADE1" indent="up2"><enum>(B)</enum><text><term>Companionship services</term> does not include services relating to the care and protection of the aged or infirm that require and are performed by trained medical personnel, such as a registered or practical nurse.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEC931327F31D44F9A5C40E2E439137B5" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><term>Domestic service</term> as used in subsections (a)(15) and (b)(21) of section 13, means services of a household nature performed by an employee in or about a private home (permanent or temporary), including employees such as cooks, waiters, butlers, valets, maids, housekeepers, nannies, nurses, janitors, laundresses, caretakers, handymen, gardeners, certified nursing assistants, home care aides, home health aides, personal care aides, chauffeurs of automobiles for family use, and babysitters employed on other than a casual basis.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB3C578AF52C5454182719B0595F8E005" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><term>Third-party employment</term> as used in subsections (a)(15) and (b)(21) of section 13, means the employment of any employee who is engaged in providing companionship services or live-in domestic services and who is employed by an employer other than the family or household using the services of the employee, whether or not such employee provides services to more than one family or household in the same workweek.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="H466E3F4DA9D04570BBE8B4E1E953CE3B"><enum>3.</enum><header>Preservation of the companionship services exemption</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Paragraph (15) of section 13(a) of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/213">29 U.S.C. 213(a)(15)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H08D04053B7FD4431ADE3D937D5AAA7DA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>(including through third-party employment)</quote> after <quote>companionship services</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H39D1BCFCD7744DDA8FE3F594C98FD53F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(as such terms are defined and delimited by regulations of the Secretary)</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H4DF7E23408154B02AADE27ED480FAB02"><enum>4.</enum><header>Preservation of the live-in domestic services exemption</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Paragraph (21) of section 13(b) of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/213">29 U.S.C. 213(b)(21)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>(including through third-party employment)</quote> after <quote>domestic service</quote>.</text></section></legis-body></bill>


