<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S242 IS: Wounded Warriors Federal Leave Act of 2015 </dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 242</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150122">January 22, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S314">Mr. Tester</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S347">Mr. Moran</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend title 5, United States Code, to provide leave to any new Federal employee who is a veteran
			 with a service-connected disability rated at 30 percent or more for
			 purposes of undergoing medical treatment for such disability, and for
 other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H572445D621FC4D14BB0F557BDD11215C" style="OLC"><section id="HCB0F31EF9F39471EB252FB0AC6C45260" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Wounded Warriors Federal Leave Act of 2015 </short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HF19FA9E70FB648D59E1B4A61884BABB3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Additional leave for Federal employees who are disabled veterans</header><subsection id="H3E55D3BD0F304B8F950E55271B43EB65"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/63">chapter 63</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0AE534872009402AA91771B5CC2750D8" style="USC"><section id="H47411602E08F4B959F155C82C43AC58B"><enum>6329.</enum><header>Disabled veteran leave</header><subsection id="H60E2680E381D429AA9CBD4E9E3E0AADF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text><paragraph commented="no" id="id1B5550AAC27B40658E23D79BDDB4F8AD"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">notwithstanding section 6301, the term <quote>employee</quote>—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="id7AE8C4E64F41465F891AC0A0CD6BAC78"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has the meaning given such term in section 2105; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id76DEDE5A3CD94CAFA6F8D2290E36DBC3"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes an officer or employee of the United States Postal Service or of the Postal Regulatory Commission;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id00EF9FB815D34493AACEEA07DF5B162C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <quote>service-connected</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 101(16) of title 38; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idBA36F5CCC3DF4034A3FACA5516E43BC7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <quote>veteran</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 101(2) of title 38.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id7C33FD86FB55406DB1FD0B14EE659A54"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Leave credited</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the 12-month period beginning on the first day of the employment of an employee who is a veteran with a service-connected disability rated as 30 percent or more disabling, the employee is entitled to leave, without loss or reduction in pay, for purposes of undergoing medical treatment for such disability for which sick leave could regularly be used.</text></subsection><subsection id="H0D81480DFA084C89ABE56F5CAF7A26E3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Limitations</header><paragraph id="idFB3D8F60E03A4EA2AEA646F4F32E553A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Amount of leave</header><text>The leave credited to an employee under subsection (b) may not exceed 104 hours.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEEA8C195DF8A4C039F881A463CEC324E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No carry over</header><text>Any leave credited to an employee under subsection (b) that is not used during the 12-month period described in such subsection may not be carried over and shall be forfeited.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H42A9E0A1A6024A7E85A769DEB2950FCC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Certification</header><text>In order to verify that leave credited to an employee under subsection (b) is used for treating a service-connected disability, the employee shall submit to the head of the employing agency a certification, in such form and manner as the Director of the Office of Personnel Management may prescribe, that the employee used the leave for purposes of being furnished treatment for the disability by a health care provider.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H60DEBEC2FD65430F8C456A1C345C5A51"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/63">chapter 63</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding after the item relating to section 6328 the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H21579C60E76641D196C54BD4ABC513C0" style="USC"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">6329. Disabled veteran leave.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HBBC1FB8EB5764749B75C327384F454E3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (a) shall apply with respect to an employee (as that term is defined in section 6329(a)(1) of title 5, United States Code, as added by subsection (a)) hired on or after the date that is 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB86B2AC988AF420093F8519904A33CAD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Regulations</header><paragraph id="idD9983713C6BC4F8B841BE9688E7222B9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act—</text><subparagraph id="id03A1F18CE9594DE8A2DD435B767580E4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Postmaster General shall prescribe regulations with respect to the leave provided under the amendment made by subsection (a) for employees of the United States Postal Service and the Postal Regulatory Commission; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF0EDF3545297459281DE8142048EDE11"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Director of the Office of Personnel Management shall prescribe regulations with respect to the leave provided under the amendment made by subsection (a) for all other employees.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idB2EA2705ADAD4140B293BDD09F1274A8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Briefing requirement</header><text>Not later than 3 months after the date of enactment of this Act, and every 3 months thereafter until the date on which the Director of the Office of Personnel Management prescribes final regulations under paragraph (1)(B), the Director shall brief the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives regarding the development of such regulations.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


