<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S49 IS: To include a question to ascertain United States citizenship and immigration status in each questionnaire used for a decennial census of population, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 49</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150107">January 7, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S299">Mr. Vitter</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To include a question to ascertain United States citizenship and immigration status in each
			 questionnaire used for a decennial census of population, and for other
 purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="idCED17CB0BD5144E7837A85B6051B5E28" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Ascertaining citizenship and immigration status in decennial census of population</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 141 of title 13, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="id358098FE45644A78911853B256AA839E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (g) as subsection (h); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idBB81F77FD53E490FA0320F1E4BCFAA45"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (f) the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id97CF872FD4174DB1817F7B2316AE19E1" style="OLC"><subsection id="id426D89A6FC194C1BA39192880F3226BE"><enum>(g)</enum><text>Notwithstanding section 5 of this title, the Secretary shall include in each questionnaire used for the conduct of a decennial census of population under subsection (a) a question to ascertain United States citizenship and immigration status.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


