<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S571 IS: Pilot’s Bill of Rights 2</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 571</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150225">February 25, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S236">Mr. Inhofe</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S338">Mr. Manchin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S343">Mr. Boozman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S375">Mr. Daines</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S309">Mr. Casey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S318">Mr. Wicker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S360">Ms. Heitkamp</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S347">Mr. Moran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S314">Mr. Tester</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S260">Mr. Roberts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S317">Mr. Barrasso</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S363">Mr. King</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Pilot's Bill of Rights to facilitate appeals and to apply to other certificates issued
			 by the Federal Aviation Administration, to require the revision of the
			 third class medical certification regulations issued by the Federal
			 Aviation Administration, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body>
 <section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Pilot’s Bill of Rights 2</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="idcb5735bedb994d65994f834470522c37"><enum>2.</enum><header>Medical certification of certain small aircraft pilots</header>
 <subsection id="id3e10ee33e47448e2b66ff78bb1a204bf"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall issue or revise medical certification regulations to ensure that an individual may operate as pilot in command of a covered aircraft without regard to any medical certification or proof of health requirement otherwise applicable under Federal law if—</text>
 <paragraph id="id567b5996a2134d8090e053cf0d731eca"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the individual possesses a valid State driver's license and complies with any medical requirement associated with that license;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id39fcfa09c0db439f8625e3ff5cb92684"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the individual is transporting not more than 5 passengers;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id48712f3d14564d74a07054714efd03c0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the individual is operating under visual flight rules or instrument flight rules; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id26b6a61d70a344e68cf35f2be3d9f065"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the relevant flight, including each portion thereof, is not carried out—</text> <subparagraph id="idb05bc6bc759f4d3d973e186bc6fbbe6f"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for compensation, including that no passenger or property on the flight is being carried for compensation;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbd454e312d354aaab4b264ffcf3ee7cf"><enum>(B)</enum><text>at an altitude that is more than 14,000 feet above mean sea level;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id746213fb644f4bdfa848d3405b0cfee3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>outside the United States, unless authorized by the country in which the flight is conducted; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6f8423a2e2fe434f9769457507b79b91"><enum>(D)</enum><text>at an indicated air speed exceeding 250 knots.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id09692d6ad26441418985383a89cae559"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Covered aircraft defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>covered aircraft</term> means an aircraft that—</text>
 <paragraph id="idc49bedf235c142bc99023d37c5106bab"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is not authorized under Federal law to carry more than 6 occupants; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idada74ea317da46e7824fdeddcbec47e0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>has a maximum certificated takeoff weight of not more than 6,000 pounds.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id7422758b026547838a48a17b09e66e36"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report required</header><text>Not later than 5 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall submit to Congress a report that describes the effect of the regulations issued or revised under subsection (a) and includes statistics with respect to changes in small aircraft activity and safety incidents.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id7781f03bfb3e4e5badb4c426689d1bee"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Prohibition on enforcement actions</header><text>On and after the date that is 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator may not take an enforcement action for not holding a valid third-class medical certificate against a pilot of a covered aircraft for a flight if the pilot and the flight meet the applicable requirements under paragraphs (1) through (4) of subsection (a) unless the Administrator has published final regulations in the Federal Register under subsection (a).</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="idaa8aa2764cc940dc8a7221de32ce255e"><enum>3.</enum><header>Expansion of Pilot's Bill of Rights</header>
			<subsection id="id84d411d434a4465da39ec94d5fa257d7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Appeals not subject to exhaustion of administrative remedies</header>
 <paragraph id="idAB5E0C71A472477CBBAB15A7B757887D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 2(d)(1) of the Pilot’s Bill of Rights (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/153">Public Law 112–153</external-xref>; 126 Stat. 1159; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/44703">49 U.S.C. 44703</external-xref> note) is amended to read as follows:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idCB42EA1F5FA942C18D1F1720B956B445" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="idDDE68CF657164735A246436406BE43E2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Upon a decision by the Administrator denying a covered certificate, or imposing a punitive civil action or an order of revocation under section 44709 of title 49, United States Code, a person substantially affected by the decision may, at the person’s election, file an appeal with the National Transportation Safety Board or, without further administrative review, in the United States district court in which the person resides or in which the action in question occurred, or in the United States District Court for the District of Columbia.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id387A48545F8D4F308720875E106E4435"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 2(d)(2) of such Act is amended by striking <quote>Federal district court</quote> and inserting <quote>United States district court</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id9029f8deda4b47ce84f531c1f159d554"><enum>(b)</enum><header>De novo review by district court; burden of proof</header><text>Section 2(e) of such Act is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="idCEDBBB84ADBE46F3B38D21B86DB638D6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by amending paragraph (1) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc06f505685e3448097975bcf7a7b9a70" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="id5A2C9D9671304D45AC0429C3C1544BDA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In an appeal filed under subsection (d) in a United States district court with respect to a denial, suspension, or revocation of a covered certificate by the Administrator—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idbbffd99116d542d584aabd9251f83396"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the district court shall review the denial, suspension, or revocation de novo, including by—</text> <clause id="id53A18543CF91475BB0AAB3FAB5709259"><enum>(i)</enum><text>conducting a full independent review of the complete administrative record of the denial, suspension, or revocation;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id4704FFF1515A4A219C23FFB9DAA02145"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>permitting additional discovery and the taking of additional evidence; and</text> </clause><clause id="idC101AD1F270C40C6AFEE3D2A23374D4B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>making the findings of fact and conclusions of law required by Rule 52 of the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure without being bound to any facts found by the Administrator or the National Transportation Safety Board; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idEFC6D5D1A9924B1DA412DC37B168BD9C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Administrator shall bear the burden of proof.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idE97052F6004E46199507F7972875AB7A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id720852C102C74A5CB842E9448D6ED0D7" style="OLC"> <paragraph commented="no" id="idCB76F48F3E944D11B51006DC949F94EC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Applicability of Administrative Procedure Act</header><text>Notwithstanding paragraph (1)(A) or subsection (a)(1) of section 554 of title 5, United States Code, that section applies to adjudications of the Administrator and the National Transportation Safety Board to the same extent as that section applied to such adjudications before the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Pilot’s Bill of Rights 2</short-title>.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idda48d357a30c4fa0809ecb7d6fb2810a"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Expansion to all certificates issued by Federal Aviation Administration</header>
 <paragraph id="id9faf173e41474e58b744cd6a0186be79"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 2 of such Act is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="id5e78b3ff622f4ecb9dcabbd36f0a5952"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text>
 <clause id="id69211a02b1114b1d9df3b6565a059e81"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>subpart C, D, or F of</quote>; and</text> </clause><clause id="id1B68478314134EA3884B3D762558BC4D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>an airman certificate</quote> and inserting <quote>a covered certificate</quote>; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb428f4cf71d142fea90547e7af7dfad7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(1), by striking <quote>an airman certificate under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/447">chapter 447</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code</quote> and inserting <quote>a covered certificate</quote>.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id323a5835d35e456d9048a94b0349300c"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered certificate defined</header><text>Section 2 of such Act is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id59a45ed22e6748e8a0edd9aca61066db" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="iddd8f83d8dc1f4a759320a78e756a046c"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Covered certificate defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>covered certificate</term> means an airman certificate, design organization certificate, holder of type certificate, production certificate, airworthiness certificate, air carrier operating certificate, airport operating certificate, air agency certificate, air navigation facility certificate, medical certificate, or any other authorization issued by the Administrator under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/447">chapter 447</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ideff156ff048f43a7ad6a92c41515ce3a"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text>Section 2 of such Act, as amended by this subsection, is further amended—</text> <subparagraph id="idf3639f2b8ec3447e8fe7b5f63a78ad0c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(4)(C)—</text>
 <clause id="ida3f573e50683431ea13bdf2581f04949"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in clause (i), by striking <quote>Any individual</quote> and inserting <quote>Any person</quote>;</text> </clause><clause id="id48ACA80374254982A3D23E6BA181A76C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in clauses (ii) and (iii), in the clause headings, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="clause" style="OLC">individual</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="clause" style="OLC">person</header-in-text></quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id2a31106affe1463a9b9392a577f41dad"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in clause (iii)(II), by striking <quote>the requesting individual</quote> and inserting <quote>the requesting person</quote>;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id149ca55fe35747afb864fe69aa7a5b2e"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>the individual’s</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>the person’s</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd5ad690a2d2e46a49910ae4d7c53f846"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking <quote>the individual</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>the person</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb49bd5be1f484a46854489c5330085c6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by striking <quote>an individual</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>a person</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id8017162c034b4a8a9fc08cdea1c26846"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Notification of investigation</header><text>Section 2 of such Act is further amended—</text> <paragraph id="id6E7B9B316C5545DCBECE9BABEDAE66AC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking subsection (c);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idAA909F6F1A624B86A0A5E12ED66156B7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (5) of subsection (b) as subsection (c), and by moving such subsection, as so redesignated, two ems to the left;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id8D5F364FC6FF4AB48F2A3B62A7A6A04F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text> <subparagraph id="idD9637837B0FB4490BB77560D8A67626D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)(A), by inserting <quote>and the specific incident or incidents on which the investigation is based</quote> after <quote>nature of the investigation</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4fb513d9e67a4ce798ecfdcdb39b0a5c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>timely</quote>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idAF0E99F9E78D4E2C83D2A6A0C3CDE6A6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (4) as paragraph (5); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idca7ed580d5894e418455caddc80b4c8b"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (3) the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4d90df026a9f4f998afc11968f273289" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="id398534df87fc4484ae872ee3e38c3a1e"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Failure To Provide Information</header><text>If the Administrator does not provide a person with the notification required by paragraph (1) with respect to an investigation relating to the approval, denial, suspension, modification, or revocation of a covered certificate, including all of the information required under paragraph (2), the Administrator may not—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id34b9b41334874b9195330c8454bf50ec"><enum>(A)</enum><text>retain records of the investigation;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8a482b228c4744e485e99e5a5413fb80"><enum>(B)</enum><text>deny, suspend, or revoke the covered certificate;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd86077cce746478a9b5090bd7c9fef40"><enum>(C)</enum><text>seek a civil penalty or other punitive action against the person; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id42690d35d79f4fdbb427a44a4fa26a61"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in any way take action, including issuance of a warning letter or letter of correction or any other administrative action, with regard to the matter that was the subject of the investigation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id57748582df0444e996a2c0a59687424a"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (c), as redesignated by paragraph (2), by striking <quote>section 44709(c)(2)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 44709(e)(2)</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="id942D83BE7CE74F8BB893A7CF4D4904C0"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Release of investigative reports</header><text>Section 2 of such Act is amended by inserting after subsection (e) the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idDD09FB158DAA4AC98935008FCCA56062" style="OLC">
					<subsection commented="no" id="id089deb7092564f6e9218067c79d41b72"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Release of investigative reports</header>
						<paragraph commented="no" id="id12a936a7f8304ea3a2f6b09e29b60413"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="id19F7C69C2C034C64821A72C90848F918"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Emergency orders</header><text>In any proceeding conducted under part 821 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, relating to denial, amendment, modification, suspension, or revocation of a covered certificate, in which the Administrator issues an emergency order of revocation under subsections (d) and (e) of section 44709 of title 49, United States Code, an emergency order under section 46105(c) of such title, or another order that takes effect immediately, the Administrator shall provide to the person holding the covered certificate the releasable portion of the investigative report before issuing the order.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id552EC49DF9154D08B562BAB461929F0A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Other orders</header><text>In any proceeding conducted under part 821 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, relating to denial, amendment, modification, suspension, or revocation of a covered certificate, in which the Administrator notifies the holder of the covered certificate of a proposed action under subsections (b) and (c) of section 44709 of title 49, United States Code, the Administrator shall, upon request of the holder of the covered certificate and at any time after that notification, provide to the holder of the covered certificate the releasable portion of the investigative report.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idC861793911064854B732B49F5AC4542E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Motion for dismissal</header><text>If the Administrator does not provide the investigative report to the person holding the covered certificate subject to the proceeding referred to in paragraph (1) by the time required by that paragraph, the person may move to dismiss the complaint of the Administrator or for other relief and, unless the Administrator establishes good cause for the failure to provide the investigative report, the administrative law judge shall order such relief as the judge considers appropriate.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idcbf76bc25d314ee999a8765215828687"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Releasable portion of report</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1), the releasable portion of an investigative report is all information in the report, except for the following:</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="idaef624ba057f40b2a374547514eba9dd"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Information that is privileged.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id406b01444a6545958429e48e3bb0afbc"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Information that constitutes work product or reflects internal deliberative process.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id06c0c4dca7b14068be712d6176cb7f2e"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Information that would disclose the identity of a confidential source.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id6e2aabfd27d541ecaa3a93de63a85803"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Information the disclosure of which is prohibited by any other provision of law.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id9d6d091ac0784bbfb5d99f59a0232870"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Information that is not relevant to the subject matter of the proceeding.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id033B99B612BD47A0ADFEAA278934A4E2"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Information the Administrator can demonstrate is withheld for good cause.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id66fa65f488f2444bac9f9b00c891323b"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Sensitive security information, as defined in section 15.5 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations (or any corresponding similar ruling or regulation).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id8be39c87529c45389494212c9f50c5c5"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to prevent the Administrator from releasing to a person subject to an investigation described in subsection (b)(1)—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="idC7011BF6AB754B28A17F1387F5642CF3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>information in addition to the information included in the releasable portion of the investigative report; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id6FDE94EB271648B8B69B5ECA386E35E7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a copy of the investigative report before the Administrator issues a complaint.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="id27b3e77d1c4147778fb29535a4dfb392"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Limitation on document requests</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2 of such Act, as amended by subsection (e), is further amended by inserting after subsection (f) the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idda998b09dc3248fc92b367b3c5faa6e3" style="OLC">
 <subsection commented="no" id="idb0774324f85b4f0396dec12885f9c2c6"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Limitation on document requests</header><text>In any case in which the Administrator initiates an investigation described in subsection (b)(1) with respect to a person, the Administrator and the investigating officials may request documents from the person only if the request is limited and narrowly tailored to issues in the investigation.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="idfb35cf2f34c647c3aac79a1887d268e0"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Response to Requests by Repair Stations To Settle or Withdraw</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2 of such Act, as amended by subsections (e) and (f), is further amended by inserting after subsection (g) the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idA901CA4A6EFD4492B0570F5254EA29C5" style="OLC">
 <subsection commented="no" id="idA0611C7CD5CF417B9C3FC0AC89DCAF7E"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Response to Requests by Repair Stations To Settle or Withdraw</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall respond to a written request by a repair station holding a certificate under part 145, Code of Federal Regulations, that is subject to an investigation described in subsection (b)(1) to withdraw from or settle a proceeding relating to the investigation not later than 30 calendar days after receiving the request.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="id8B3F0915BEA44802B33AE76DA0C33A4A"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Limitation on retention of records</header><text>Section 2 of such Act, as amended by subsections (e), (f), and (g), is further amended by inserting after subsection (h) the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id82B4579935E4453BA23197CF6093863C" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="id7c0df380f8b849f3af8d416dea8a9af4"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Limitation on retention of records</header><text>The Administrator shall expunge the record of any investigation described in subsection (b)(1) with respect to a covered certificate that does not lead to the denial, suspension, modification, or revocation of the certificate not later than 90 days after the Administrator determines not to deny, suspend, modify, or revoke the certificate.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idea577f8253244b7c891256e78748ae94"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Prohibition on publicizing pending enforcement actions</header><text>The Administrator may not indicate in the publicly accessible records of a person holding a covered certificate who is the subject of an investigation described in subsection (b)(1) any information that is different from information in such records of an airman who is not under such an investigation.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section id="idFA66EB619529475DB53143BE51FB540E"><enum>4.</enum><header>Limitations on reexamination of certificate holders</header>
 <subsection id="id1113780E804A4D1E8DE8E4AF5578CDBB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 44709 of title 49, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="idB7697B15EA0E4A96BADE25037FB2AD0F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (a)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id6874A6FF2A354294B692021E6CC06D48"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the subsection heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">and reexamination</header-in-text></quote>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7588097F74544D00A01B8263C24A093E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>The Administrator</quote> and inserting the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id249FB80B6CA24FC4A443F8A0DB552CCE" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="idEBD98DCF9C814399B3CAE0ABCB3A5357"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8A4CFDB6210A43C6916B4885289945EB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking <quote>, or reexamine an airman holding a certificate issued under section 44703 of this title</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1170F020EBC746068750DB051A17B0B3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idA85079EB3D314092AE9204B12D82A7DE" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="id552ffc53a7f140aa8a71816dc7c46c19"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reexamination of airmen certificates</header> <subparagraph id="idCA988B7D72AF4A9C8C3BCDE924878D26"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator may reexamine an airman holding a certificate issued under section 44703 of this title only if the Administrator has reasonable grounds—</text>
 <clause id="idE9C65FD41BD74CC3A2219525D4AB34E2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to question the airman’s lack of competence based on acts or omissions committed while the airman was exercising the privileges of the certificate; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="idb2943993f2ec44fb8a534350c7abe51e"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to believe the airman obtained the certificate through fraudulent means.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id34083D6C2ADD4B10BFC6DE2895BEF017"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Notification requirements</header><text>Before taking any action to reexamine an airman holding a certificate issued under section 44703 of this title, the Administrator shall provide to the airman—</text>
 <clause id="id61C01ABD675343059587BBE705F5373B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the specific justification for the reexamination; and</text> </clause><clause id="id03588EFAD0D74B20A6BE57B06AC297F4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any releasable information gathered by the Federal Aviation Administration that form the basis for that justification.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id11005dc34fc64916a87e952a8be495dc"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Modification, suspension, or revocation of airmen certificates after reexamination</header><text>Section 44709(b) of such title is amended—</text> <paragraph id="id1D12BE38D13941A4B47150EB5E77B846"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (A) and (B) as clauses (i) and (ii), and by moving such clauses, as so redesignated, two ems to the right;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id4F3D36F164DD4A82A672D01040F75E42"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (1) and (2) as subparagraphs (A) and (B), and by moving such subparagraphs, as so redesignated, two ems to the right;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idCCA7E9D3BBC14514ADE9062CC21C650F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking <quote>The Administrator</quote> and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3E0C4DF5A7834C309F0C2755874F0A2A" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="idD0BFEE5471AA41E286E1BAD84B19269A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and </after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id0D322330CAD54AD7A1A20B11CC835009"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idFE976DAA34D24DEFAF46A7F9FAF4C67F" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="id7ffe2d3a3b734a1b960190136c165070"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Modification, suspension, or revocation of airmen certificates after reexamination</header><text>The Administrator may not amend, modify, suspend, or revoke an airman certificate issued under section 44703 of this title after a reexamination of the airman holding the certificate unless the Administrator demonstrates by a preponderance of the evidence that the airman—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idd164a5fba3854b65b79ccb8f86012001"><enum>(A)</enum><text>lacks the skills and competency, or care, judgment, and responsibility, necessary to hold the certificate; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id59180868336f4ea18431352f48fdf84a"><enum>(B)</enum><text>materially contributed to the issuance of the certificate by fraudulent means.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id3585CBC1BE1942928BC53879EC3B6357"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Appeals</header><text>Section 44709(f) of such title is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="id9BE5DBCC53544E498B706155CC83EA8B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>A person</quote> and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id878520E40E76496F9363904FE1FA8DDD" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="id081689D387604416B059A2B4CAD099D1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A person</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id852506A8D9B7457383DE77151085A056"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB74DEAFCFB4E48B0B7247D2FF3EB2C50" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="idACE9326C531F40FE8546A49BC4A908C5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appeals relating to reexamination of airmen certificates</header><text>If the Administrator amends, modifies, suspends, or revokes an airman certificate after reexamination of the airman holding the certificate in violation of subsection (a)(2), the airman may elect to file an appeal in the United States district court in which the airman resides or in which the action in question occurred, or in the United States District Court for the District of Columbia, instead of filing an appeal with the Board under subsection (d).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id2629979975B347C1918DE5AB5E5E632F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text>Section 44709(d)(1) of such title is amended—</text> <paragraph id="idDC9F3E21065D4A68AE70A7C404B75448"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>subsection (b)(1)(A)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (b)(1)(A)(i)</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id883A171373E64A2FAF629FE6C7E81643"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>subsection (b)(1)(B)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (b)(1)(A)(ii)</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ide8069c59beed4c6b9c38ab127263d073"><enum>5.</enum><header>Expediting updates to NOTAM program</header> <subsection id="id4ED6AC40BAB8403E97F3CC36569329E0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration may not take any enforcement action, on or after the date that is 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, against any individual for a violation of a NOTAM (as defined in section 3 of the Pilot's Bill of Rights (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/44701">49 U.S.C. 44701</external-xref> note)) until the Administrator certifies that the Administrator has complied with the requirements of section 3 of the Pilot's Bill of Rights, as amended by this section, to—</text>
 <paragraph id="id05F7811AFDB643B39FB6F63BC8BDFA38"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Appropriations and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id4E93A9A685B54217BF234E6EAFFB0728"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Appropriations and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="id9ed7084eeda045399299273d7bdbc2b6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Amendments</header><text>Section 3 of the Pilot's Bill of Rights (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/153">Public Law 112–153</external-xref>; 126 Stat. 1162; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/44701">49 U.S.C. 44701</external-xref> note) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="idDAAC1E8D192C4CDF8F1B47E1F5B31497"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(2)—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="idCA6831B876864F3B93453E1B9325BFFA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A)—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="id73AA7EBA86444591A71C8575CB03D202"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>this Act</quote> and inserting <quote>the <short-title>Pilot’s Bill of Rights 2</short-title></quote>; and</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="id5892960FFFBB47CCB512449922052435"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>begin</quote> and inserting <quote>complete the implementation of</quote>;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="idE4023E2C98BB47DEBA795A8376F43EB4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by amending subparagraph (B) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3B77E84D014941A1B1F9D469382EC70F" style="OLC"> <subparagraph commented="no" id="id5466F808C74B4EE898C8F1913953E824"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to establish a repository, in a public central location, to maintain and archive all NOTAMs, including the original content and form of the notices, the original date of publication, and any amendments to such notices with the date of each amendment, in a manner that is Internet-accessible, machine-readable, and searchable;</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id49708F03FD974AF4B5C9F18BB8EE6096"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id7A850F19CFE54102954D55502968A425"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id112EECC79149475F98B5424FF48A1D3E" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="idD5ED2FC6F99C45748D73A795636E12AC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to establish a rating system to prioritize each NOTAM by the urgency and importance of the NOTAM; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idAA30F0982AEF4124A89CFCC384F92810"><enum>(E)</enum><text>to specify the times during which temporary flight restrictions are in effect and the duration of a designation of special use airspace in a specific area.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id9B26EF22848F4DCC98627F8BFC9ADB96"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by amending subsection (d) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id790F5E47E86F47019C3D29E7913B0B46" style="OLC"> <subsection commented="no" id="idcd45a0e0aca44c2b80ecacd4fbfab29a"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Designation of repository as sole source for NOTAMs</header> <paragraph commented="no" id="id47F5E8307388402CA1187225CB0CD323"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="idA668BA320E5440CE8ED9A15CD3AC85D8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall consider the repository for NOTAMs established under subsection (a)(2)(B) to be the sole location for airmen to check for NOTAMs; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="idD07D03A0B80145A8800738C3B81BBE59"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may not consider a NOTAM to be announced and published until the NOTAM is included in the repository.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id2F87ADF7B3A34EEA95C0CCEBE02F1D18"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prohibition on taking action for violations of NOTAMs not in repository</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="id625E391219C24656887782F02344E25A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (A), on and after the date on which the repository established under subsection (a)(2)(B) is final and published, the Administrator may not take any enforcement action against an airman for a violation of a NOTAM during a flight if that NOTAM is not available through the repository before the commencement of the flight and reasonably accessible and identifiable to the airman.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="idCC321725A378472A8C89DB8827064484"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception for national security</header><text>Subparagraph (A) shall not apply in the case of an enforcement action for a violation of a NOTAM that directly relates to national security.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id1ccaa40760e8478d96c6442255acd234"><enum>6.</enum><header>Accessibility of certain flight data</header>
 <subsection id="idbc82e3feda63412f9bdacd3d9ebe3829"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/471">chapter 471</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/47124">section 47124</external-xref> the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5c93aae713684e47b79c0ed120e7f945" style="USC">
					<section id="id5b4fba7b6a114c35a27e1549ff80df47"><enum>47124a.<?LEXA-Enum 47124a.?></enum><header>Accessibility of certain flight data</header>
 <subsection id="id82530bde888f4a3c8a8190e611baa84d"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="id89451d3543974819bb3e73ecaa33bee3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Contract tower</header><text>The term <term>contract tower</term> means an air traffic control tower providing air traffic control services pursuant to a contract with the Federal Aviation Administration under the Contract Tower Program under section 47124(b)(3).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id61061049acf948e78fcef861992852bf"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered flight record</header><text>The term <term>covered flight record</term> means any flight data, including air traffic data (as defined in section 2(b)(4)(B) of the Pilot's Bill of Rights (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/44703">49 U.S.C. 44703</external-xref> note)), created, maintained, or controlled by any program of the Federal Aviation Administration, whether carried out by employees or contractors of the Federal Aviation Administration, including contract towers, flight service stations, and controller training programs.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1fbc8abff5ff411f9a19af8e59db26f5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Provision of covered flight data to Federal Aviation Administration</header>
 <paragraph id="id7BCBFFAA14C54D3D9274ECC8522862A3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Request from Federal Aviation Administration</header><text>When the Federal Aviation Administration receives a request, pursuant to section 552 of title 5, United States Code, for a covered flight record that is not in the possession of the Federal Aviation Administration, the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall request the record from the contract tower or other contractor of the Federal Aviation Administration that possesses the record.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id55C929238BC54D098E0622F9296BDCD2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Provision of records to Federal Aviation Administration</header><text>Any covered flight record created, maintained, or controlled by a contract tower or another contractor of the Federal Aviation Administration that maintains covered flight records shall be provided to the Federal Aviation Administration if the Federal Aviation Administration requests the record pursuant to paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ided5c161a1a8044c39a32680c99ad4d57"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applicability of FOIA</header><text>After the Federal Aviation Administration receives a covered flight record under subsection (b), that record shall be—</text>
 <paragraph id="idB7A327E69F3F41AA9F4A23B13F92273B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>considered an agency record of the Federal Aviation Administration for purposes of section 552(f)(2) of title 5, United States Code; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id8c5c03d7c8e34fb0952ab116b41db8b0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>subject to section 552 of title 5, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Freedom of Information Act</quote>), to the same extent as if the record was created, maintained, and controlled by the Federal Aviation Administration.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0C48D6E51E16445D8B897CFFF6EBF311"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Withholding of information</header><text>The Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration may withhold information that would otherwise be required to be made available under this section only if—</text>
 <paragraph id="idE008F3A3ECA545CD805774BE41D7F9EE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Administrator determines, based on information in the possession of the Administrator, that the Administrator may withhold the information in accordance with section 552(b) of title 5, United States Code; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id1873C0A6B623407D949BE7441A38300B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the information is voluntarily provided safety- or security-related information covered by section 40123.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id3b81b384769c481b9ecc66ac7a733b61"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Format of records</header><text>Each contract tower or other contractor of the Federal Aviation Administration that maintains covered flight records shall maintain records relating to covered flight records in formats that are readily reproducible and reasonably searchable by the Federal Aviation Administration.</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="idd49715dd28c445cfa7bd61a2d9067da9"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Regulations</header>
 <paragraph id="id0c9676629cc6451b997db0fb495f5867"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Pilot’s Bill of Rights 2</short-title>, the Administrator shall promulgate regulations or guidance to ensure compliance with this section by the Federal Aviation Administration, contract towers, and other contractors of the Federal Aviation Administration that maintain covered flight records.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="id903c23fd1a83443f8d76eb35bdf74700"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Compliance by applicable entities</header>
 <subparagraph id="id7ef5338ae219456da2b33dcaaeb95f50"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Compliance with this section by a contract tower or other contractor of the Federal Aviation Administration that maintains covered flight records shall be included as a material term in any contract between the Federal Aviation Administration and the contract tower or contractor entered into or renewed on or after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Pilot’s Bill of Rights 2</short-title>.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide404e17b81bd448f89ec14a6413062da"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Modification of contract or agreement</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Pilot’s Bill of Rights 2</short-title>, the Administrator shall secure a modification to include compliance with this section by each contract tower and other contractor of the Federal Aviation Administration that maintains covered flight records as a material term in any contract between the Federal Aviation Administration and the contract tower or contractor that will not otherwise be renegotiated, renewed, or modified before the date that is one year after such date of enactment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="id1b97b1f4c2604bbf90ca29eba45199e3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/471">chapter 471</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/47124">section 47124</external-xref> the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="idfd33f562-6625-4196-885c-c7e01976dbfe" style="USC"><toc><toc-entry idref="id5b4fba7b6a114c35a27e1549ff80df47" level="section">47124a. Accessibility of certain flight data.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section id="idC1262878F5AD4931A1224D894D6495F2"><enum>7.</enum><header>Limitation of liability for certain individuals designated as representatives of the Federal
			 Aviation
			 Administration</header>
 <subsection id="id150E02ABAAF24DE19749D2A9491763BF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any individual designated by the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration under subpart C of part 183 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, to act as a representative of the Administrator, including an aviation medical examiner, pilot examiner, or designated airworthiness representative, shall, when carrying out duties pursuant to that designation and without regard to the individual's employer—</text>
 <paragraph id="id58A91A06A7F147E08FC6AE4EAFCF9608"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be considered to be performing an activity necessary to safeguard a uniquely Federal interest; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id975A00DD5B6748A08F56AED50A1E4328"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not be liable in a civil action for actions performed with reasonable care in connection with those duties.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idAFF7F12B7174467ABDACD4F679018671"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Fraudulent misconduct</header><text>This section does not relieve an individual described in subsection (a) that causes harm to any person through intentional or fraudulent misconduct while carrying out duties pursuant to that subsection from any penalty applicable under any provision of law for that misconduct.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="id1B0E4E39969041BAA467844F71A0DC93"><enum>8.</enum><header>Authority for legal counsel to issue certain notices</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall revise section 13.11 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, to authorize legal counsel to close enforcement actions covered by that section with a warning notice, letter of correction, or other administrative action.</text>
		</section><section id="idff0b554d101448368b0499981169a278"><enum>9.</enum><header>Liability protection for volunteer pilots that fly for the public benefit</header>
			<subsection id="id6486a939f14a4e4b83d17cbd4342952e"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings and purpose</header>
 <paragraph id="id011b92cc04134fe1943a29590612ca2c"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds the following:</text> <subparagraph id="id014a3d89532744af916df78ebe836369"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Many volunteer pilot nonprofit organizations fly for public benefit and provide valuable services to communities and individuals.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id6525d1b3cd2b4188929acb5244a3c4a1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>In each calendar year, volunteer pilot nonprofit organizations provide long-distance, no-cost transportation for tens of thousands of people during times of special need.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id01feebe9988849b5ab406fa0a4590bc7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Such nonprofit organizations are no longer able to purchase liability insurance for aircraft they do not own to provide liability protection at a reasonable price, and therefore face a highly detrimental liability risk.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd33e18776b2d4bbc8ae286af9a5a594f"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Such nonprofit organizations have supported the homeland security of the United States by providing volunteer pilot services during times of national emergency.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idebc882d8aa464a5e88f940bb61b1a252"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of this section is to promote the activities of volunteer pilot nonprofit organizations that fly for public benefit and to sustain the availability of the services that such nonprofit organizations provide, including the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="id417c435ae8f545a496c48be9a4a37118"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Transportation at no cost to financially needy medical patients for medical treatment, evaluation, and diagnosis.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc9203ecbc95a4d78b637377fc17dca96"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Flights for humanitarian and charitable purposes.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2917c4d8a3c0400fa16313ff0ad3efe7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Other flights of compassion.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id78a45f2b6a164fe79ce620c3bf02fed1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Liability protection for volunteer pilot nonprofit organizations that fly for public benefit and to
 pilots and staff of such nonprofit organizations</header><text>Section 4 of the Volunteer Protection Act of 1997 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/14503">42 U.S.C. 14503</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="id3cfc5da11844446ba8a8047f894f7f41"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(4)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idFED80B29AF844435B016353703C54129"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (A) and (B) as clauses (i) and (ii), respectively;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id073408815a834ccb9da571c697745d90"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>the harm</quote> and inserting <quote>(A) except in the case of subparagraph (B), the harm</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5d6380daeb91423181cac9ba44c8399e"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)(ii), as redesignated by this paragraph, by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6e4a68be93e846c48fe3f3a58204ceb4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id58c943a2ca9647d9a0ba5cecf67b8ba7" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="idc68fc68a3c2c43beab0cd445933638da"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the volunteer—</text>
 <clause id="id3d1bae46bb2d434dab5c6963e4d84a3d"><enum>(i)</enum><text>was operating an aircraft in furtherance of the purpose of a volunteer pilot nonprofit organization that flies for public benefit; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id2d8eda7995fb4b0d96fb484b5cb3e8d8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>was properly licensed and insured for the operation of such aircraft.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id2943ec2738614f2398810128dba09d1f"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idca0c51296ce340ecb9e7c3675976bd0e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Nothing in this section</quote> and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id27c8b1c8d76f44048012e061c4b465e5" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="id35e4515b45724961a26ba82d33c3a81b"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), nothing in this section</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id229c2277f8e740b2b644a088cef5e848"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8da3f064385a46549637384cdaa1dca7" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="id23d5adf525684f20a55121bbc7747dc7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>A volunteer pilot nonprofit organization that flies for public benefit, the staff, mission coordinators, officers, and directors (whether volunteer or otherwise) of that nonprofit organization, and a referring agency of that nonprofit organization shall not be liable for harm caused to any person by a volunteer of the nonprofit organization while the volunteer—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idab877eba1f7e4c508831454d18f56c9b"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is operating an aircraft in furtherance of the purpose of the nonprofit organization;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida21da77b994b4e22956048c776801e51"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is properly licensed for the operation of the aircraft; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8a31214839d846eca9285bc2f1553982"><enum>(C)</enum><text>has certified to the nonprofit organization that the volunteer has insurance covering the volunteer's operation of the aircraft.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


