<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S989 IS: Residue Entries and Streamlining Trade Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 989</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150416">April 16, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S212">Mr. Coats</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S360">Ms. Heitkamp</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States to exempt from duty residue of bulk
			 cargo contained in instruments of international traffic previously
			 exported from the United States.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HB1E2E662048A46DEBFC2B0DEA596001B" style="OLC">
 <section commented="no" id="H8E6A3DB841994221BDE479F0BF1E4E86" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Residue Entries and Streamlining Trade Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H085C399C65A24B51A6DEFB2A50041851"><enum>2.</enum><header>Exemption from duty of residue of bulk cargo contained in instruments of international traffic previously exported from the United States</header> <subsection id="HB015A4C2CBF143299F26ED0CD3AAE072"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">General Note 3(e) of the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H0D41A7B5EF7E49E2B92A16748C28A472"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (v), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H215B15470FA140A28DD4929EA3E13FA2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (vi), by adding <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFDEB54E2CE594BA0A721594EECFC4F22"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (vi) (as so amended) the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H94B44FC97B3B486A9977DEAE0601A770" style="OLC"> <clause id="H43B1600BEF814FDE84F5435B82BEC0FD" indent="up1"><enum>(vii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">residue of bulk cargo contained in instruments of international traffic previously exported from the United States,</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H48F3C0508ED745ADBED759C30B83E310"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by adding at the end of the flush text following subparagraph (vii) (as so added) the following: <quote>For purposes of subparagraph (vii) of this paragraph: The term <term>residue</term> means material of bulk cargo that remains in an instrument of international traffic after the bulk cargo is removed, with a quantity, by weight or volume, not exceeding 7 percent of the bulk cargo, and with no or de minimis value. The term <term>bulk cargo</term> means cargo that is unpackaged and is in either solid, liquid, or gaseous form. The term <term>instruments of international traffic</term> means containers or holders, capable of and suitable for repeated use, such as lift vans, cargo vans, shipping tanks, skids, pallets, caul boards, and cores for textile fabrics, arriving (whether loaded or empty) in use or to be used in the shipment of merchandise in international traffic, and any additional articles or classes of articles that the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection designates as instruments of international traffic.</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF5403DD5650A443C89ACF8A8FFB7BF9D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by subsection (a) take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act and apply with respect to residue of bulk cargo contained in instruments of international traffic that are imported into the customs territory of the United States on or after such date of enactment and that previously have been exported from the United States.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


