<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1553 IS: Pain-Capable Unborn Child Protection Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-06-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1553</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150611">June 11, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S293">Mr. Graham</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S197">Mr. McCain</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S174">Mr. McConnell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S355">Mr. Cruz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S375">Mr. Daines</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S379">Mr. Perdue</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S118">Mr. Hatch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S236">Mr. Inhofe</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S381">Mr. Rounds</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S212">Mr. Coats</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S384">Mr. Tillis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S373">Mr. Cassidy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S299">Mr. Vitter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S374">Mr. Cotton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S350">Mr. Rubio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S323">Mr. Risch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S376">Mrs. Ernst</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S378">Mr. Lankford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S305">Mr. Isakson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S347">Mr. Moran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S153">Mr. Grassley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S303">Mr. Thune</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S357">Mrs. Fischer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S342">Mr. Blunt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S382">Mr. Sasse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S260">Mr. Roberts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S365">Mr. Scott</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S346">Mr. Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S136">Mr. Cochran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S261">Mr. Sessions</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S266">Mr. Crapo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S184">Mr. Shelby</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S310">Mr. Corker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S318">Mr. Wicker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S348">Mr. Paul</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S317">Mr. Barrasso</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S254">Mr. Enzi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S287">Mr. Cornyn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S343">Mr. Boozman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S300">Mr. Burr</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S349">Mr. Portman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S344">Mr. Hoeven</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S345">Mr. Johnson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S383">Mr. Sullivan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S358">Mr. Flake</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S351">Mr. Toomey</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend title 18, United States Code, to protect pain-capable unborn children, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body style="OLC">
 <section id="H82491442EABA47E29A532E51CA7BA3C1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Pain-Capable Unborn Child Protection Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HF35155FE1C1B48FF96D1DF7B7327FF3B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Legislative findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds and declares the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HC8869F635B684A81ABD499B4C41F6473"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Pain receptors (nociceptors) are present throughout the unborn child’s entire body and nerves link these receptors to the brain’s thalamus and subcortical plate by no later than 20 weeks after fertilization.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H06397A97D919411E98D20A4D97ABA10D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>By 8 weeks after fertilization, the unborn child reacts to touch. After 20 weeks, the unborn child reacts to stimuli that would be recognized as painful if applied to an adult human, for example, by recoiling.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC115AACC479E4E5CBC226CEBB355842B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In the unborn child, application of such painful stimuli is associated with significant increases in stress hormones known as the stress response.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0A27541BFE434E758D6F974ED9538A42"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Subjection to such painful stimuli is associated with long-term harmful neurodevelopmental effects, such as altered pain sensitivity and, possibly, emotional, behavioral, and learning disabilities later in life.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H143E70105717469EB2804FFBD12AA5E0"><enum>(5)</enum><text>For the purposes of surgery on unborn children, fetal anesthesia is routinely administered and is associated with a decrease in stress hormones compared to their level when painful stimuli are applied without such anesthesia. In the United States, surgery of this type is being performed by 20 weeks after fertilization and earlier in specialized units affiliated with children’s hospitals.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H31E09B05D08E48D7B6E656401AD5B2D9"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The position, asserted by some physicians, that the unborn child is incapable of experiencing pain until a point later in pregnancy than 20 weeks after fertilization predominately rests on the assumption that the ability to experience pain depends on the cerebral cortex and requires nerve connections between the thalamus and the cortex. However, recent medical research and analysis, especially since 2007, provides strong evidence for the conclusion that a functioning cortex is not necessary to experience pain.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5DC7670ECF7F4CE5A30BA00275534180"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Substantial evidence indicates that children born missing the bulk of the cerebral cortex, those with hydranencephaly, nevertheless experience pain.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H484B976B195041339B7B32DDAD0B804F"><enum>(8)</enum><text>In adult humans and in animals, stimulation or ablation of the cerebral cortex does not alter pain perception, while stimulation or ablation of the thalamus does.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6DD5120A2F76482D9FE1E231E23459E2"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Substantial evidence indicates that structures used for pain processing in early development differ from those of adults, using different neural elements available at specific times during development, such as the subcortical plate, to fulfill the role of pain processing.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2DD4628BB962477A95B2FCAC60736C07"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The position, asserted by some commentators, that the unborn child remains in a coma-like sleep state that precludes the unborn child experiencing pain is inconsistent with the documented reaction of unborn children to painful stimuli and with the experience of fetal surgeons who have found it necessary to sedate the unborn child with anesthesia to prevent the unborn child from engaging in vigorous movement in reaction to invasive surgery.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1176F38FB583433FA246945A9E163570"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Consequently, there is substantial medical evidence that an unborn child is capable of experiencing pain at least by 20 weeks after fertilization, if not earlier.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1C937356A87842F29A03D9A622E19750"><enum>(12)</enum><text>It is the purpose of the Congress to assert a compelling governmental interest in protecting the lives of unborn children from the stage at which substantial medical evidence indicates that they are capable of feeling pain.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4F7401CD67244E71AAA0A5DF70CF0431"><enum>(13)</enum><text>The compelling governmental interest in protecting the lives of unborn children from the stage at which substantial medical evidence indicates that they are capable of feeling pain is intended to be separate from and independent of the compelling governmental interest in protecting the lives of unborn children from the stage of viability, and neither governmental interest is intended to replace the other.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HA1FCFFB031194BFEA751E1B3D231FB29"><enum>3.</enum><header>Pain-capable unborn child protection</header>
 <subsection id="H27223868191E46C3954CD5FC907E8040"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/74">Chapter 74</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/1531">section 1531</external-xref> the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H71DDDAE9D0CF4B74B1CB121CA5C79A40" style="USC">
					<section id="H10EB2449E34A4DBCA69423DCD3064AA0"><enum>1532.</enum><header>Pain-capable unborn child protection</header>
 <subsection id="H6B568CDBB1CB49EB9055A9671F37AC30"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Unlawful conduct</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, it shall be unlawful for any person to perform an abortion or attempt to do so, unless in conformity with the requirements set forth in subsection (b).</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="H9BAA0382DD9A4F319D0FAF4BF0B21193"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements for Abortions</header>
 <paragraph id="HAB674116AA6347FEB1F414097D4ABE1F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Assessment of the age of the unborn child</header><text>The physician performing or attempting the abortion shall first make a determination of the probable post-fertilization age of the unborn child or reasonably rely upon such a determination made by another physician. In making such a determination, the physician shall make such inquiries of the pregnant woman and perform or cause to be performed such medical examinations and tests as a reasonably prudent physician, knowledgeable about the case and the medical conditions involved, would consider necessary to make an accurate determination of post-fertilization age.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="H3C56B865BE784762AE10EE7B697D83C6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prohibition on performance of certain abortions</header>
 <subparagraph id="HEF5724D551BE41619BA39771AC3CDDF9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Generally for unborn children 20 weeks or older</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the abortion shall not be performed or attempted, if the probable post-fertilization age, as determined under paragraph (1), of the unborn child is 20 weeks or greater.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H160146571DA848A6AAE1EEF6D6CF829B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>Subparagraph (A) does not apply if—</text> <clause id="H01C6016EB5764A388441F95F691F9DE6"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in reasonable medical judgment, the abortion is necessary to save the life of a pregnant woman whose life is endangered by a physical disorder, physical illness, or physical injury, including a life-endangering physical condition caused by or arising from the pregnancy itself, but not including psychological or emotional conditions;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD4B9CD8A320C43778EEE8C07355DA105"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the pregnancy is the result of rape against an adult woman, and at least 48 hours prior to the abortion—</text>
 <subclause id="H1681B611B5124D1FB0B40266BB287CBC"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">she has obtained counseling for the rape; or</text> </subclause><subclause id="HFC181FD4CB754D8F8F53F5E7E2C2FF5C"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">she has obtained medical treatment for the rape or an injury related to the rape; or</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H3499311C95BD4E9DBEBB35CC1EBCD205"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the pregnancy is a result of rape against a minor or incest against a minor, and the rape or incest has been reported at any time prior to the abortion to either—</text>
 <subclause id="H5D37F3BCE8044BEE9CABC3236D8C3136"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a government agency legally authorized to act on reports of child abuse; or</text> </subclause><subclause id="H89B181903CC24B969F5475DD4F570C28"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a law enforcement agency.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5339E6511042476E9E72C991F156A381"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Requirement as to manner of procedure performed</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding the definitions of <quote>abortion</quote> and <quote>attempt an abortion</quote> in this section, a physician terminating or attempting to terminate a pregnancy under an exception provided by subparagraph (B) may do so only in the manner which, in reasonable medical judgment, provides the best opportunity for the unborn child to survive.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4F226ED90B08443FBF52FE1AB12AE11D"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Requirement that a physician trained in neonatal resuscitation be present</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If, in reasonable medical judgment, the pain-capable unborn child has the potential to survive outside the womb, the physician who performs or attempts an abortion under an exception provided by subparagraph (B) shall ensure a second physician trained in neonatal resuscitation is present and prepared to provide care to the child consistent with the requirements of subparagraph (E).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HAD4212B38DC14357AADBAFB882F17F98"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Children born alive after attempted abortions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">When a physician performs or attempts an abortion in accordance with this section, and the child is born alive, as defined in section 8 of title 1 (commonly known as the Born-Alive Infants Protection Act of 2002), the following shall apply:</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="H124173E3A4EA4ADDA85C9D59D60D20BC"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Degree of care required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any health care practitioner present at the time shall humanely exercise the same degree of professional skill, care, and diligence to preserve the life and health of the child as a reasonably diligent and conscientious health care practitioner would render to a child born alive at the same gestational age in the course of a natural birth.</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HE74FEFC6294948C78F91833372FAD51B"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Immediate admission to a hospital</header><text>Following the care required to be rendered under clause (i), the child born alive shall be immediately transported and admitted to a hospital.</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H59D8C25C62144895934782156646678C"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Mandatory reporting of violations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A health care practitioner or any employee of a hospital, a physician’s office, or an abortion clinic who has knowledge of a failure to comply with the requirements of this subparagraph must immediately report the failure to an appropriate State or Federal law enforcement agency or both.</text>
									</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD6CE21AB6E144648902556F5D501C2FE"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Documentation requirements</header>
 <clause id="H81B56332DEBA4B069F978DFD2FC4F17D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Documentation pertaining to adults</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A physician who performs or attempts to perform an abortion under an exception provided by subparagraph (B)(ii) shall, prior to the abortion, place in the patient medical file documentation from a hospital licensed by the State or operated under authority of a Federal agency, a medical clinic licensed by the State or operated under authority of a Federal agency, from a personal physician licensed by the State, a counselor licensed by the State, or a victim’s rights advocate provided by a law enforcement agency that the adult woman seeking the abortion obtained medical treatment or counseling for the rape or an injury related to the rape.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4F553C30288149AC8A93E06670A6182E"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Documentation pertaining to minors</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A physician who performs or attempts to perform an abortion under an exception provided by subparagraph (B)(iii) shall, prior to the abortion, place in the patient medical file documentation from a government agency legally authorized to act on reports of child abuse that the rape or incest was reported prior to the abortion; or, as an alternative, documentation from a law enforcement agency that the rape or incest was reported prior to the abortion.</text>
									</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5AED7D9A0AD845ABA71CA87DD15C31D9"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Informed consent</header>
 <clause id="H2BA32FC2CCD741419B6683D5D4BCCC04"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Consent form required</header><text>The physician who intends to perform or attempt to perform an abortion under the provisions of subparagraph (B) may not perform any part of the abortion procedure without first obtaining a signed Informed Consent Authorization form in accordance with this subparagraph.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HFC223B0021524BCC8C206B246D65EB05"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Content of consent form</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Informed Consent Authorization form shall be presented in person by the physician and shall consist of—</text>
 <subclause id="H07DF3BB3BB82463CACF187275D6536BA"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a statement by the physician indicating the probable post-fertilization age of the pain-capable unborn child;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H1069D8F4B4474E56B6D93F6E89D95311"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a statement that Federal law allows abortion after 20 weeks fetal age only if the mother’s life is endangered by a physical disorder, physical illness, or physical injury, when the pregnancy was the result of rape, or an act of incest against a minor;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H2299BEB9ADA642C2BF856F43BBBB61A3"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a statement that the abortion must be performed by the method most likely to allow the child to be born alive unless this would cause significant risk to the mother;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H7105994D98844D22B3304D9B7C992067"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a statement that in any case in which an abortion procedure results in a child born alive, Federal law requires that child to be given every form of medical assistance that is provided to children spontaneously born prematurely, including transportation and admittance to a hospital;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H63503E8C3A8F478FA91307208B56E579"><enum>(V)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a statement that these requirements are binding upon the physician and all other medical personnel who are subject to criminal and civil penalties and that a woman on whom an abortion has been performed may take civil action if these requirements are not followed; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HF351F45DFD13442E93241E197F06D4CF"><enum>(VI)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">affirmation that each signer has filled out the informed consent form to the best of their knowledge and understands the information contained in the form.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H8EC9B68E4B3A48AE8D8714EDDD77E8E7"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Signatories required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Informed Consent Authorization form shall be signed in person by the woman seeking the abortion, the physician performing or attempting to perform the abortion, and a witness.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H47FBF66F368344BEB2DA38B499262E73"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Retention of consent form</header><text>The physician performing or attempting to perform an abortion must retain the signed informed consent form in the patient’s medical file.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3D4E173657014406AD38E938A01D900A"><enum>(H)</enum><header>Requirement for data retention</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (j)(2) of section 164.530 of title 45, Code of Federal Regulations, shall apply to documentation required to be placed in a patient’s medical file pursuant to subparagraph (F) of subsection (b)(2) and a consent form required to be retained in a patient’s medical file pursuant to subparagraph (G) of such subsection in the same manner and to the same extent as such paragraph applies to documentation required by paragraph (j)(1) of such section.</text>
								</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5BA5E52705D54943BA4A581F348DFB5A"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Additional exceptions and requirements</header>
 <clause id="H363F105E5CD54FCB9C560E0653B7378B"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In cases of risk of death or major injury to the mother</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subparagraphs (C), (D), and (G) shall not apply if, in reasonable medical judgment, compliance with such paragraphs would pose a greater risk of—</text>
 <subclause id="HFB07A39BD0624095AD4FF1346714244C"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the death of the pregnant woman; or</text> </subclause><subclause id="H0992F5140C824C98B1E2EF7179A3E5D5"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the substantial and irreversible physical impairment of a major bodily function, not including psychological or emotional conditions, of the pregnant woman.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H4C0B0EE7DF14489E9304B00A20F54C60"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Exclusion of certain facilities</header><text>Notwithstanding the definitions of the terms <quote>medical treatment</quote> and <quote>counseling</quote> in subsection (g), the counseling or medical treatment described in subparagraph (B)(ii) may not be provided by a facility that performs abortions (unless that facility is a hospital).</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7DCDB9D5A70441C2A0267A8FE416EC9B"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Rule of construction in cases of reports to law enforcement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirements of subparagraph (B)(ii) do not apply if the rape has been reported at any time prior to the abortion to a law enforcement agency or Department of Defense victim assistance personnel.</text>
									</clause><clause id="H98E98F9727854CBC93EBE8A313191045"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Compliance with certain State laws</header>
 <subclause commented="no" id="H93AA44B72FD1408FA6F81C44806D18BC"><enum>(I)</enum><header>State laws regarding reporting of rape and incest</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The physician who performs or attempts to perform an abortion under an exception provided by subparagraph (B) shall comply with such applicable State laws that are in effect as the State’s Attorney General may designate, regarding reporting requirements in cases of rape or incest.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HAD3EC9F05534412E9B70BE183AD077A5"><enum>(II)</enum><header>State laws regarding parental involvement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The physician who intends to perform an abortion on a minor under an exception provided by subparagraph (B) shall comply with any applicable State laws requiring parental involvement in a minor’s decision to have an abortion.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA8805B346B5A4CCBAA975D7D330D4A72"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Criminal penalty</header><text>Whoever violates subsection (a) shall be fined under this title or imprisoned for not more than 5 years, or both.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC14B889E68F34671822FAE679B03B189"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Bar to prosecution</header><text>A woman upon whom an abortion in violation of subsection (a) is performed or attempted may not be prosecuted under, or for a conspiracy to violate, subsection (a), or for an offense under section 2, 3, or 4 of this title based on such a violation.</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="H4D448D3D8FD8405D8F259FE39DC94C5D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Civil remedies</header>
 <paragraph id="HACF9023437C646BF9637E02113F44DB9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Civil action by a woman on whom an abortion is performed</header><text>A woman upon whom an abortion has been performed or attempted in violation of any provision of this section may, in a civil action against any person who committed the violation, obtain appropriate relief.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9FBA01CE801A410F9681E5BEE9D1E92D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Civil action by a parent of a minor on whom an abortion is performed</header><text>A parent of a minor upon whom an abortion has been performed or attempted under an exception provided for in subsection (b)(2)(B), and that was performed in violation of any provision of this section may, in a civil action against any person who committed the violation obtain appropriate relief, unless the pregnancy resulted from the plaintiff’s criminal conduct.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H053D615074084F00896F3E3AA8939519"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Appropriate relief</header><text>Appropriate relief in a civil action under this subsection includes—</text> <subparagraph id="H27848D26EACC49DEBCDA86E3A834D6B1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>objectively verifiable money damages for all injuries, psychological and physical, occasioned by the violation;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4AD86A9323A742979E5DC94618D566F9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>statutory damages equal to three times the cost of the abortion; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC16FA5ADA3034DCC94406903FAE9C47C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>punitive damages.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDACAF45982C94205B93700FA2B934138"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Attorneys fees for plaintiff</header><text>The court shall award a reasonable attorney’s fee as part of the costs to a prevailing plaintiff in a civil action under this subsection.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8C2F145452974E3C9129C6BCB3CDC4C9"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Attorneys fees for defendant</header><text>If a defendant in a civil action under this subsection prevails and the court finds that the plaintiff’s suit was frivolous, the court shall award a reasonable attorney’s fee in favor of the defendant against the plaintiff.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H65BAD3DB0BA44594B8119FD8537F2F58"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Awards against woman</header><text>Except under paragraph (5), in a civil action under this subsection, no damages, attorney’s fee or other monetary relief may be assessed against the woman upon whom the abortion was performed or attempted.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFCC1E7A38A054849A7FBC54FF59D55E6"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Data collection</header>
 <paragraph id="HD5FFEC8AFD2B4F12904D39C50C572BC0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Data submissions</header><text>Any physician who performs or attempts an abortion described in subsection (b)(2)(B) shall annually submit a summary of all such abortions to the National Center for Health Statistics (hereinafter referred to as the <quote>Center</quote>) not later than 60 days after the end of the calendar year in which the abortion was performed or attempted.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1E6BBC73AEBA4D11B620B45C5F340DA1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents of summary</header><text>The summary shall include the number of abortions performed or attempted on an unborn child who had a post-fertilization age of 20 weeks or more and specify the following for each abortion under subsection (b)(2)(B):</text>
 <subparagraph id="HCD2DE3FDE71241C68897C2D7E7F65810"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the probable post-fertilization age of the unborn child;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAE34464C11574319989B12A539686010"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the method used to carry out the abortion;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8ED1DBF683424294B0A5699115797107"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the location where the abortion was conducted;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H96AE715B6947452BA4AC458848C9823F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the exception under subsection (b)(2)(B) under which the abortion was conducted; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H775261148DB74C67B1C46C6AA765A2C1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any incident of live birth resulting from the abortion.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB989C31CBB4B48AC83A327A5809896E3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exclusions from data submissions</header><text>A summary required under this subsection shall not contain any information identifying the woman whose pregnancy was terminated and shall be submitted consistent with the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1320d-2">42 U.S.C. 1320d–2</external-xref> note).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCAA4E97FE91A4EC48803CC666205E082"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Public report</header><text>The Center shall annually issue a public report providing statistics by State for the previous year compiled from all of the summaries made to the Center under this subsection. The Center shall take care to ensure that none of the information included in the public reports could reasonably lead to the identification of any pregnant woman upon whom an abortion was performed or attempted. The annual report shall be issued by July 1 of the calendar year following the year in which the abortions were performed or attempted.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3F3F82E606EA479895EFE5D3E3CC7C95"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section the following definitions apply:</text> <paragraph id="HE3B9F6B821A94244B5A94D83C307C289"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Abortion</header><text>The term <term>abortion</term> means the use or prescription of any instrument, medicine, drug, or any other substance or device—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H599FAADF92F24C5FA55920F784242B71"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to intentionally kill the unborn child of a woman known to be pregnant; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCABC6E4539904B84B7B43F6602D86946"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to intentionally terminate the pregnancy of a woman known to be pregnant, with an intention other than—</text>
 <clause id="H932ECE485AB7450B94EEDAE920372FFF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>after viability to produce a live birth and preserve the life and health of the child born alive; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE3FEEA71749F46328840B897911CCB8F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to remove a dead unborn child.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H38D252E8B2F949C691FF2FFEE4DE88FF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Attempt</header><text>The term <term>attempt</term>, with respect to an abortion, means conduct that, under the circumstances as the actor believes them to be, constitutes a substantial step in a course of conduct planned to culminate in performing an abortion.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFCA207E26EEC43279753E1E7B4548210"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Counseling</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>counseling</term> means counseling provided by a counselor licensed by the State, or a victims rights advocate provided by a law enforcement agency.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4B31C27F9ADC417FB9AE5A334848BC5B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Facility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>facility</quote> means any medical or counseling group, center or clinic and includes the entire legal entity, including any entity that controls, is controlled by, or is under common control with such facility.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H812CC837C50D4E4295ABA021FA78FDC2"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Fertilization</header><text>The term <term>fertilization</term> means the fusion of human spermatozoon with a human ovum.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7538BC00B9B74CAD865286589695B6A8"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Medical treatment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>medical treatment</term> means treatment provided at a hospital licensed by the State or operated under authority of a Federal agency, at a medical clinic licensed by the State or operated under authority of a Federal agency, or from a personal physician licensed by the State.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEAD27561B5DF4909821B41ADB81BC92D"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Minor</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>minor</quote> means an individual who has not attained the age of 18 years.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC7C1A41538AB491D98F879DD1C08AC04"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Perform</header><text>The term <term>perform</term>, with respect to an abortion, includes inducing an abortion through a medical or chemical intervention including writing a prescription for a drug or device intended to result in an abortion.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF7BBA86B56304B6793FBCC84A4F411B4"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Physician</header><text>The term <term>physician</term> means a person licensed to practice medicine and surgery or osteopathic medicine and surgery, or otherwise legally authorized to perform an abortion.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA803314846584F688706C2D6EDFDA287"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Post-fertilization age</header><text>The term <term>post-fertilization age</term> means the age of the unborn child as calculated from the fusion of a human spermatozoon with a human ovum.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3B195FA516B94D80AEF3898872EC8694"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Probable post-fertilization age of the unborn child</header><text>The term <term>probable post-fertilization age of the unborn child</term> means what, in reasonable medical judgment, will with reasonable probability be the post-fertilization age of the unborn child at the time the abortion is planned to be performed or induced.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H40582EEFB83F4D6B8ACBECA89FE7C620"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Reasonable medical judgment</header><text>The term <term>reasonable medical judgment</term> means a medical judgment that would be made by a reasonably prudent physician, knowledgeable about the case and the treatment possibilities with respect to the medical conditions involved.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6BF5E3B3812C4EE292038F5C240948EA"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Unborn child</header><text>The term <term>unborn child</term> means an individual organism of the species homo sapiens, beginning at fertilization, until the point of being born alive as defined in section 8(b) of title 1.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9873C6B189AC41128182EE826B85C307"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Woman</header><text>The term <term>woman</term> means a female human being whether or not she has reached the age of majority.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="H174AD127B8A2428F8F17ADD3E3E42B65"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/74">chapter 74</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block id="HDFDB8E65E2C640DFB1C7462352CE9CDB" style="USC"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">1532. Pain-capable unborn child protection.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="HA2DCB1A5A9F946B5A4C4B685EED8BF6D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Chapter heading amendments</header>
 <paragraph id="H72FDCAD0BCA04D3ABD9CFC1D9DE99B8A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Chapter heading in chapter</header><text>The chapter heading for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/74">chapter 74</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="USC">Partial-Birth Abortions</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="USC">Abortions</header-in-text></quote></text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA659F26C05E24090B58804E09C0313B7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Table of chapters for part i</header><text>The item relating to chapter 74 in the table of chapters at the beginning of part I of title 18, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8A291ECC3C5A4A259D3B4AD10EB231F5" style="OLC"><toc><multi-column-toc-entry bold="off" level="section"><toc-enum>74. </toc-enum><level-header level="section">Abortions</level-header><target>1531</target></multi-column-toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


