<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S530 IS: To require the president of the Federal Reserve Bank of New York to be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 530</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150223">February 23, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S259">Mr. Reed</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the president of the Federal Reserve Bank of New York to be appointed by the President,
			 by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Federal reserve bank governance</header>
 <subsection id="idEF6C45387EAA44B3A1AB4EFF813EDC9C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 4 of the Federal Reserve Act (12 U.S.C. 301 through 308; 341) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id53AB6614B39C4FD7B316BFFC15173B32" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="id61b18d8efa554f1090f70ef7c0ee973c"><enum>(25)</enum><header>Selection of the president of the Federal Reserve Bank of New York</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, the president of the Federal Reserve Bank of New York shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, for terms of 5 years.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id8061BF7BD02C47E3BD02DE0D26B0F791"><enum>(26)</enum><header>Testimony</header><text>The president of the Federal Reserve Bank of New York, on an annual basis, shall provide testimony to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="idc871ff4f068f4e0fabc6cf9e11787ab5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (a) shall take effect on the date of enactment of this Act and apply to appointments for the president of the Federal Reserve Bank of New York made on and after that effective date.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


