<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1867 IS: International Megan’s Law to Prevent Child Exploitation Through Advanced Notification of Traveling Sex Offenders</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1867</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150727">July 27, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S184">Mr. Shelby</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S182">Ms. Mikulski</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S339">Mr. Kirk</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To protect children from exploitation by providing advance notice of intended travel by registered
			 sex offenders outside the United States to the government of the country
			 of destination, requesting foreign governments to notify the United States
			 when a known sex offender is seeking to enter the United States, and for
			 other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body style="OLC">
		<section id="H9BC43FD553B24919B7816894DEE19D49" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title and table of contents</header>
 <subsection id="H2117D261E78C44DB960652285BFFD5D0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>International Megan’s Law to Prevent Child Exploitation Through Advanced Notification of Traveling Sex Offenders</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0FA13A1F33AE47F8BE4E84AE6A2CE2F8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text><toc><toc-entry idref="H9BC43FD553B24919B7816894DEE19D49" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title and table of contents.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H2EC8A7612ED446A7BC6059DAE2E71427" level="section">Sec. 2. Definitions.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="HDDB3FFACCD4F41968E2D67D151B3455A" level="section">Sec. 3. Angel Watch Center.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="HC89ADC47E3F44C24B226095130E20051" level="section">Sec. 4. Notification by the United States Marshals Service.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H91D1B3A54EBD4ECBA656D4528601F33B" level="section">Sec. 5. International travel.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id6089EE935E134155BC3D72A21AE51A41" level="section">Sec. 6. Unique passport identifiers for covered sex offenders.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id4318FB737999453B95C8611A307D8D8C" level="section">Sec. 7. Access to National Crime Information Center files.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id3753943C02C34B498BF37AE32C372FFA" level="section">Sec. 8. Rules of Construction.</toc-entry> </toc> </subsection></section><section commented="no" id="H2EC8A7612ED446A7BC6059DAE2E71427"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
 <paragraph id="H413BCF4673A747CB8209C13069C3A858"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Center</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Center</term> means the Angel Watch Center established pursuant to section 3(a).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idB99C390A8B4F49949285C916A1703595"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Convicted</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>convicted</term> has the meaning given the term in section 111 of the Adam Walsh Child Protection and Safety Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/16911">42 U.S.C. 16911</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idB2FCE4C83F59428C82F2064C6FF91448"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered sex offender</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered sex offender</term> means an individual who is a sex offender by reason of being convicted of a sex offense against a minor.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idE52362C85726416DB141FC03CAC19252"><enum>(4)</enum><header>INTERPOL</header><text>The term <term>INTERPOL</term> means the International Criminal Police Organization.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H5BC352D7CA714A40BAF09CEB7624D8A6"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Jurisdiction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>jurisdiction</term> means any of the following:</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HEA7B0F135A3049C4A5913E49B254F643"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A State.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HD6EAD357ED8E4C46895956A1B517F755"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The District of Columbia.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HBCE75B055E9A4D2BB727E1F60BC82A99"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Commonwealth of Puerto Rico.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HD97D625A7C6A4874859E273F0B305449"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Guam.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HE8A2E72BDC384C32949B8A2C133683E5"><enum>(E)</enum><text>American Samoa.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H59BF38FEB7DF44F699330EC94C7DB55A"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The Northern Mariana Islands.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H5FD9FF662EAB414590BAF8D99B36447C"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The United States Virgin Islands.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H1A7D44E3AF1F47E4AC95677C6E91D04E"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To the extent provided in, and subject to the requirements of, section 127 of the Adam Walsh Child Protection and Safety Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/16927">42 U.S.C. 16927</external-xref>), a federally recognized Indian tribe.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H08A9D5F531C847BC92CD610DFFF92E93"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Minor</header><text>The term <term>minor</term> means an individual who has not attained the age of 18 years.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id76F1A315579445F48C09FE843352A5D8"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Official notification</header><text>The term <term>official notification</term> means a notification developed by the Attorney General, in coordination with the Secretary of Homeland Security and INTERPOL, to provide notification of travel by convicted sex offenders.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id9D82492260FB4D4A84D9F1BEC4886291"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Sex offender</header><text>The term <term>sex offender</term> has the meaning given the term in section 111 of the Adam Walsh Child Protection and Safety Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/16911">42 U.S.C. 16911</external-xref>).</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="id362C6640CE2045F389051E51056DE834"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Sex offense against a minor</header>
 <subparagraph id="idFAA059C53014441294D3B44E16E54278"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>sex offense against a minor</term> means a specified offense against a minor, as defined in section 111 of the Adam Walsh Child Protection and Safety Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/16911">42 U.S.C. 16911</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF2C0DD52E8CF47DEA0BE9B3AD204CA49"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Other offenses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>sex offense against a minor</term> includes a sex offense described in section 111(5)(A) of the Adam Walsh Child Protection and Safety Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/16911">42 U.S.C. 16911(5)(A)</external-xref>) that is a specified offense against a minor, as defined in paragraph (7) of such section.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA2D6C25CE26C42D09E12E40B086E59DC"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Foreign convictions; offenses involving consensual sexual conduct</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The limitations contained in subparagraphs (B) and (C) of section 111(5) of the Adam Walsh Child Protection and Safety Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/16911">42 U.S.C. 16911(5)</external-xref>) shall apply with respect to a child-sex offense for purposes of this Act to the same extent and in the same manner as such limitations apply with respect to a sex offense for purposes of the Adam Walsh Child Protection and Safety Act of 2006.</text>
				</subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="HDDB3FFACCD4F41968E2D67D151B3455A"><enum>3.</enum><header>Angel Watch Center</header>
 <subsection commented="no" id="H55F1BD0E74854437939654E8CE57EF32"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall establish within the Child Exploitation Investigations Unit of U.S. Immigrations and Customs Enforcement a Center, to be known as the <quote>Angel Watch Center</quote>, to carry out the activities specified in subsection (e).</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="idCB615EC61D1148D6BD117347476C071A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Designation</header><text>In accordance with section 128 of the Adam Walsh Child Protection and Safety Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/16928">42 U.S.C. 16928</external-xref>), the Attorney General shall designate the Center as the central repository for incoming notifications.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H69F1452098424638B87CAEF0970B7199"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Leadership</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Center shall be headed by the Director of Immigration and Customs Enforcement, in collaboration with the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection and in consultation with the Attorney General.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H928E5E5232D7487CBA9B9E6CCE70ED9D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Members</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Center shall consist of the following:</text> <paragraph id="H98BFE4439C8348BE8B0FE206024119D7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of Immigration and Customs Enforcement.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H54F60E34618948ED860A3B59BD7CEF29"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commissioner of Customs and Border Protection.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idCA588AF2A67A48A5BA66E735DFC6ECB0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Attorney General (or a designee of the Attorney General).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5E31A8A28A1347D4A9AC7365A8EE9E1C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Individuals who are designated as analysts in U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement or U.S. Customs and Border Protection.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCA11BC048BA649A9B7E4566D842C25FD"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Individuals who are designated as program managers in U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement or U.S. Customs and Border Protection.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id6D2566D154F14F9CB3F4496A39B3CF40"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Individuals who are designated as analysts or program managers in the United States Marshals Service's National Sex Offender Targeting Office.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6F4660AE6FA849F8AFE336680191F0DA"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Activities</header>
 <paragraph id="H07991748DE9847FB8F3B0D4753B7074D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Center shall, using all relevant databases and systems, not later than 48 hours before scheduled departure—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id1BE28528F2034DCC95EB330F330035A4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>determine if individuals traveling abroad are convicted sex offenders (as defined in section 111 of the Adam Walsh Child Protection and Safety Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/16911">42 U.S.C. 16911</external-xref>));</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id07E2AF2E0C114369A0774ACBDB397DB6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>review United States Marshals Service's National Sex Offender Targeting Center case management system to determine if the individuals described in subparagraph (A) are in such system and create a list of those individuals not in such system; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idACCF7A97EA6F4BAE8376052E94E6B13D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provide the list described in subparagraph (B) to the United States Marshals Service's National Sex Offender Targeting Center for additional inquiry under section 2250 of title 18, United States Code.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5E1D5C84D96A4FA0B77A289B16E728E7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Transmission of information to Center</header><text>Not later than 18 hours before the intended travel, the United States Marshals Service's National Sex Offender Targeting Center shall transmit, to the Center, information pertaining to any covered sex offender described in subparagraph (B) or (C) of paragraph (1) in accordance with the Sex Offender Registration and Notification Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/16901">42 U.S.C. 16901 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="idB1191B8D341E44E5BCAFABF685402CF5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Advance notice to destination countries</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="idFFDDDF0285DF4931B2ABE583CFF711CE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Upon receipt of information pertaining to a covered sex offender transmitted under paragraph (2), the Center may transmit relevant information to the destination countries after completing the activities described in paragraph (1).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id18704BFE1BAD470E9CD3AC34D933D93F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Short-notice travelers</header><text>If an individual traveling abroad, who is a covered sex offender and is not in the United States Marshals Service's National Sex Offender Targeting Center case management system, is departing the United States within 24 hours of the travel becoming known to the Center, the Center may simultaneously transmit information on travel to destination countries while completing activities described in paragraph (1).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA53E3972B7974A43B68ABB12E027B0E6"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>The Center may immediately transmit relevant information on the covered sex offender to the destination countries if—</text>
 <clause id="idE16E6AC2E2DF45E4AFC215D96A9E519C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Center becomes aware that a covered sex offender is traveling outside of the United States within 24 hours of intended travel; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="idB48085D965744C91A29F2650E8FC5799"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Center has not received a transmission pursuant to paragraph (2), provided it is not more than 18 hours before the intended travel.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3491865C46C94C38B9E6EE228EF36456"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Collection of data</header><text>The Center shall collect all relevant data, including—</text> <subparagraph id="idc8ab71e11f924eca93b44d319ac02aa1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the response of destination countries to notifications under paragraph (3) and to the transmittal of other relevant information on covered sex offender travel described therein, where available;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb02a823c49bd493792b822376933742a"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any decision not to transmit a notification abroad;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb4588df03d1342e890305de4a1c466a0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the number of transmissions made under subparagraphs (A), (B), and (C) of paragraph (3) and the countries to which they are transmitted, respectively;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0820de84211a4297812f6a12d3ba9a87"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the countries to which notifications under paragraph (3) are sent and the category of notification based upon subparagraphs (A) through (C) of paragraph (3); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id32ce2dd199c24955951ab453f8afa958"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any other information deemed necessary and appropriate by the Attorney General and the Secretary of Homeland Security.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idC48B75D4B3D2476090A5E43E3AF533AC"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Complaint review</header><text>The Center shall establish a mechanism to receive complaints from covered sex offenders affected by notifications or the sharing of relevant information with destination countries of such covered sex offenders under paragraph (3).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id6D8C68424D6749D5841CFA3BFF1537D7"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Annual review process</header><text>The Center shall establish, in coordination with the Attorney General, the Secretary of State, and INTERPOL, an annual review process in to ensure that there are consistent procedures on whether to provide notification to destination countries under this subsection.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H9E032B1EC5D7406D849008D2BFAFC7BE"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Information required</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Center shall make available to the United States Marshals Service’s National Sex Offender Targeting Center information on travel by convicted sex offenders in a timely manner.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HC89ADC47E3F44C24B226095130E20051"><enum>4.</enum><header>Notification by the United States Marshals Service</header>
 <subsection id="HA15A9BDCD01A454CA197C50EE3DC56FA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The United States Marshals Service’s National Sex Offender Targeting Center may transmit an official notification of impending or current international travel of a convicted sex offender to the country or countries of destination of the convicted sex offender, including to the visa-issuing agent or agents in the United States of the country or countries.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id0D89ADFBF8B242B09F5EDD57E3E8828F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Information required</header><text>The United States Marshals Service’s National Sex Offender Targeting Center shall make available to the Center and the Department of State, information on travel by covered sex offenders in a timely manner for purposes of carrying out this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF757BB863CAB4ACE86532D0828942917"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The official notification under this subsection may be transmitted through such means as determined appropriate by the United States Marshals Service’s National Sex Offender Targeting Center, including through the INTERPOL notification system and a U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement attaché.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id5ED5825EC680447BB4773DD403DD5715"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Collection of data</header><text>The United States Marshals Service’s National Sex Offender Targeting Center shall collect all relevant data, including—</text>
 <paragraph id="idf2c63764493641fca577e5ee31719dc8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the response of destination countries to notifications under subsection (a) and to the transmittal of other relevant information on convicted sex offender travel, where applicable;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id0f9ef88456bf4e2385d9ccfbaf8cbba3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any decision not to transmit a notification abroad, to the extent practicable;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idca7a559a9e3b447baa473e78cfa965fc"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the number of transmissions made under subsection (a) and the countries to which they are transmitted, respectively; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id77cc70b66e9f4352bf2a93a12354dd49"><enum>(4)</enum><text>any other information deemed necessary and appropriate by the Attorney General and the Secretary of Homeland Security.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H11E7143A16D94622ABD8F3D36EDFBBF7"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Complaint review</header><text>The United States Marshals Service’s National Sex Offender Targeting Center shall establish a mechanism to receive complaints from convicted sex offenders affected by notifications of destination countries of such convicted sex offenders under this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HA51C7FEED32F415193CB914CE50A0E22"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text>The Secretary of State, in consultation with the Attorney General and the Secretary of Homeland Security, may provide technical assistance to foreign authorities in order to enable such authorities to participate more effectively in the notification program system established under this section.</text>
			</subsection></section><section commented="no" id="H91D1B3A54EBD4ECBA656D4528601F33B"><enum>5.</enum><header>International travel</header>
			<subsection commented="no" id="id41B5E2DA9D3047069F35BBB6E695FC54"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement that sex offenders provide international travel related information to sex offender
 registries</header><text>Section 114(a) of the Adam Walsh Child Protection and Safety Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/16914">42 U.S.C. 16914(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="id8DBF646567524AD29FD5A4A87C10700F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (7) as paragraph (8); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idCC4F3AF2217644488EA47357C4A2489C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (6) the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9CEE6E71A1C941F5B29B8532B5C01376" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="idC1D8FA5C3EB3463DADD17A34BC9F4933"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Any information relating to intended travel of the sex offender outside the United States.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="idAB302685B0AD4465AEA23BEDFFC932E4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Notification of other countries</header> <paragraph commented="no" id="id04CB4E7BF541427E827D426DB631B4E2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Attorney General may notify another country relating to travel outside of the United States by a sex offender.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idD9C03AC410AA49399E535B70E1D26C1A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Definition of <term>sex offender</term></header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the Attorney General may determine which individuals shall be considered <term>sex offenders</term> and may include any individual required to register under Federal law or under the law of any jurisdiction.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="id7626EA23A959427E97D843CFB274B98B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming amendments to section 2250 of title 18, United States Code</header><text>Section 2250 of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="idD15AE297F73B440FA21D42C7907F2E1E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (b) and (c) as subsections (c) and (d), respectively;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id1467A6341B4D4539AEBB5F4686BA416B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (a) the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idEDF08027E9AE42E9983C403ACDDF04EA" style="OLC"> <subsection id="id88EC1DF1DC3549F0A0156AEF3850D4CA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>International travel reporting violations</header><text>Whoever—</text>
 <paragraph id="id585539B73DBD4F80A926E2DDE3AF11E6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is required to register under the Sex Offender Registration and Notification Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/16901">42 U.S.C. 16901 et seq.</external-xref>);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id7C8FFB29B6B24E91A952E1498A0D4BF8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>knowingly fails to provide information required by the Sex Offender Registration and Notification Act relating to intended travel in foreign commerce; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id70A186B21350457482AB96AECB61DF4D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>engages or attempts to engage in the intended travel in foreign commerce,</text> </paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">shall be fined under this title, imprisoned not more than 10 years, or both.</continuation-text></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph id="id411D51536810454E8C3017E3E9BBFA94"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsections (c) and (d), as redesignated, by striking <quote>subsection (a)</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>subsection (a) or (b)</quote> .</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id58F368C60C39423FAB16691B007F06AE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Attorney General and the Secretary of Homeland Security, should seek international agreements or arrangements to further the purposes of this Act and the Sex Offender Registration and Notification Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/16901">42 U.S.C. 16901 et seq.</external-xref>). Such agreements or arrangements may establish mechanisms and undertakings to receive and transmit notices concerning international travel by sex offenders, through the INTERPOL notification system and such other means as may be appropriate, including notification by the United States to other countries relating to the travel of sex offenders from the United States and notification by other countries to the United States relating to the travel of sex offenders to the United States.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id0E1677A894984F4080EE688520EA295D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>In carrying out this Act and the amendments made by this Act, the Attorney General may use the resources and capacities of any appropriate agencies of the Department of Justice, including the Office of Sex Offender Sentencing, Monitoring, Apprehending, Registering, and Tracking, the United States Marshals Service, INTERPOL United States Central Bureau, the Federal Bureau of Investigation, the Criminal Division, and the United States Attorneys' Offices.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id5188D0911BF54353B8198CE17B031361"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit international information sharing or law enforcement agency cooperation relating to any person pursuant to any authority of the Department of Justice or any other department or agency by whatever means necessary.</text>
 </subsection></section><section commented="no" id="id6089EE935E134155BC3D72A21AE51A41"><enum>6.</enum><header>Unique passport identifiers for covered sex offenders</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title II of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/457">Public Law 110–457</external-xref> is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idBA893F5726F64448B9918C7F220F09E0" style="OLC"> <section commented="no" id="id372B0AF4372C4DBC8FA97F2C09A62D13"><enum>240.</enum><header>Unique passport identifiers for covered sex offenders</header> <subsection commented="no" id="id60B205F65D5B441CA6955C4BA4DE7A9D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Immediately after receiving confirmation from the United States Marshals Service’s National Sex Offender Targeting Center that a passport applicant is a covered sex offender, the Attorney General shall notify the Secretary of State, who shall take appropriate action in accordance with subsection (b).</text>
					</subsection><subsection commented="no" id="id8B010C87E29C4AFC85F2561979525F39"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authority To use unique passport identifiers</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="idDE1A44382E12492296278B17E582D4F7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided under paragraph (2), the Secretary of State may not issue a passport or a passport card to a covered sex offender unless the passport or passport card contains a unique identifier.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idD4D5904C79544AD5A56F75D5A5A35CFE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authority to reapply</header><text>Notwithstanding paragraph (1), a covered sex offender may reapply for a passport that does not include a unique identifier if the United States Marshals Service’s National Sex Offender Targeting Center confirms that the individual is no longer required to be listed on the applicable sex offender registry.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="idD25E0831A6D241D7A7C0C31D7E4E174E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Defined term</header><text>In this section—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="idCEB969D0EC954829822F294E08F9AC4D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>covered sex offender</term> has the meaning given the term in section 2 of the <short-title>International Megan's Law to Provide International Notification of Traveling Sex Offenders</short-title>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id6AA8A99C798648EAA1F4CD338CC631B0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>unique identifier</term> means any visual designation affixed to a conspicuous location on the passport or passport card indicating that the individual is a covered sex offender.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="idC121199E6E6E48D3A533E063055DB9FE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed to require the Department of State to affix a unique identifier to a passport card.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section><section commented="no" id="id4318FB737999453B95C8611A307D8D8C"><enum>7.</enum><header>Access to National Crime Information Center files</header>
 <subsection commented="no" id="idFE75664E9C364AEE91F9B086E2CC7A8E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General and the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation shall provide the Secretary of State with access to the criminal history record information contained in the National Crime Information Center's Interstate Identification Index (NCIC–III), National Sex Offender Registry, and to any other files maintained by the National Crime Information Center that may be mutually agreed upon by the Attorney General and the Secretary of State, for the purpose of determining whether a passport applicant is a convicted sex offender indexed in any such file.</text>
			</subsection><subsection commented="no" id="id6A462F04CAD24C98ABBB06F3953BC5F7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Access</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="idCA011B6C21F542688E4BE025F7E610F2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the access authorized under subsection (a) shall be provided by means of extracts of the records for placement in the automated Consular and Lookout Support System (CLASS) or other appropriate database.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idD7FFD9EA9F0148369DDCE7F5292BCC81"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reconsideration of means of access</header><text>The provision of extracts under paragraph (1) may be reconsidered by the Attorney General and the Secretary of State upon the development and deployment of a more cost-effective and efficient means of sharing such information.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="id5F027A6D5EC34209A925ADA23916D628"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Updates</header><text>The Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation shall provide periodic updates of the extracts at intervals mutually agreed upon with the Secretary of State. Upon receipt of such updated extracts, the Secretary of State shall make corresponding updates to its databases and destroy the previously provided extracts.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="idDCDB06C189214A0783123DF8DB2869D9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Access to an extract under this section does not entitle the Secretary of State to obtain the full content of the corresponding automated criminal history record.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="id9736A0186FB145A4A207CC3D97C40554"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>For purposes of administering this section, the Secretary of State, before receiving access to National Crime Information Center data, and not later than 4 months after the date of enactment of this Act, shall promulgate final regulations to establish the conditions for the use of the information received from the Federal Bureau of Investigation—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="ide8fd805c228843ceadfa4e802b571458"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to limit the redissemination of such information;</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id72cd31b923b34e1aa7e5361a97b9857d"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to ensure that such information is used solely to determine whether an individual is listed as a convicted sex offender;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id4b9c4e60ad914789896261694fb7a371"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to ensure the security, confidentiality, and destruction of such information; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idf2f4d3fba9414139881c0ade06449d00"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to protect any privacy rights of individuals who are subjects of such information.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="id0DF06DCF7847404D809C28F4BAE3A320"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Determination if passport applicant is covered sex offender</header><text>If a check of the National Crime Information Center, National Sex Offender Registry shows that a passport applicant is a registered sex offender, the Secretary of State shall transmit all relevant information about the applicant to the United States Marshals Service’s National Sex Offender Targeting Center pursuant to an agreement between the Attorney General and the Secretary of State requesting a determination of whether the applicant is a covered sex offender.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="id5D06234D2F064ED3947CFB6581D66A27"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Reporting requirement</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General and the Secretary of State shall jointly report to Congress on the implementation of this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="idFA4B623AD5C641F89C296225822715A6"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of State, the Attorney General , and the Secretary of Homeland Security such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9479B1F384014DDB8352F0553A295022"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section, or in any other law, may be construed to limit the authority of the Attorney General or the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation to provide access to the criminal history record information contained in the National Crime Information Center's Interstate Identification Index (NCIC–III), or to any other information maintained by the National Crime Information Center, to any Federal agency or officer authorized to enforce or administer the Act of July 3, 1926 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/211a">22 U.S.C. 211a</external-xref>), for the purpose of such enforcement or administration, upon terms that are consistent with National Crime Prevention and Privacy Compact Act of 1998 (subtitle A of title II of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/105/251">Public Law 105–251</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/14601">42 U.S.C. 14601 et seq.</external-xref>) and section 552a of title 5, United States Code.</text>
			</subsection></section><section commented="no" id="id3753943C02C34B498BF37AE32C372FFA"><enum>8.</enum><header>Rules of Construction</header>
 <subsection commented="no" id="H20E4794F2123404F94B5832CAEFE10CB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Department of Justice</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed to preclude or alter the jurisdiction or authority of the Department of Justice under the Adam Walsh Child Protection and Safety Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/16901">42 U.S.C. 16901 et seq.</external-xref>), including section 113(d) of such Act, or any other provision law, or to affect the work of the United States Marshals Service with INTERPOL.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H4A42583E7BE24B82B3D5BE8BF13A6455"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Angel Watch Center</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed to preclude the Angel Watch Center from transmitting notice with respect to any covered sex offender.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


