<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1526 IS: Construction Consensus Procurement Improvement Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-06-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 1526</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150608">June 8, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S349">Mr. Portman</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend title 10 and title 41, United States Code, to improve the manner in which Federal
			 contracts for construction and design services are awarded, to prohibit
			 the use of reverse auctions for design and construction services
			 procurements, to amend title 31 and title 41, United States Code, to
			 improve the payment protections available to construction contractors,
			 subcontractors, and suppliers for work performed, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header>
			<subsection id="idD16E2B3C534B474EB6C473815B8787AB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Construction Consensus Procurement Improvement Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id31e7c7528ded416fba0c8a74a6e81ce7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text><toc><toc-entry idref="S1" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id8a1eef7adf9346b68c145e3e988a0b64" level="section">Sec. 2. Congressional findings.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id5ccded643f8d423bb7a55870498bb71f" level="section">Sec. 3. Design-build construction process improvement.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id403B89AAA94949B79EED69B073C0A588" level="section">Sec. 4. Prohibition on the use of a reverse auction for the award of a contract for design and construction services.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id8f9ed98759f2488cbb59196e0c7f3e6d" level="section">Sec. 5. Assuring payment protections for construction subcontractors and suppliers under an alternative to a Miller Act payment bond.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id24F1D50867434D4C819D02FD6C57F47A" level="section">Sec. 6. SBA surety bond guarantee program.</toc-entry> </toc> </subsection></section><section id="id8a1eef7adf9346b68c145e3e988a0b64"><enum>2.</enum><header>Congressional findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text>
 <paragraph id="idb46947eaee3847169e82186d59ca79dd"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The acquisition procedures that are often used effectively to procure products and other forms of services are not always appropriate for procurement of design and construction services.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idf64c4bf4fd1c4b0ca11cc9ee10575de4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Federal procurement officials often adopt contracting techniques from the private sector and have used those techniques effectively to procure products and services.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id44de466ad872462caac8ea4bdd5a2714"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Design-build is a procurement technique Federal officials have adopted from the private sector that has worked well for procurement of design and construction services.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ide6853c9e7eb5439e936b78bb3450b3b7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The current statutory framework for design-build could benefit from legislative refinement.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id219d55c6dbba44c998402a870c4b147c"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Reverse auctions are another procurement technique Federal officials have adopted from the private sector and used successfully to award contracts for the purchase of products that are commercially equivalent to commodities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id5eb67905f4344a68a81766d24baa329e"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Despite their success in other contexts, reverse auctions are generally inappropriate for procurement of design and construction services, given the unique nature of each such project.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idcc058ed816a848f5a4ef1adc018c3629"><enum>(7)</enum><text>To ensure payment protection for contractors, subcontractors, and suppliers working on Federal construction projects, bonds backed by individual sureties must be placed in the care and custody of the Federal Government and be supported by assets that are real, sufficient, verifiable, and readily convertible into cash.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="id5ccded643f8d423bb7a55870498bb71f"><enum>3.</enum><header>Design-build construction process improvement</header>
			<subsection id="idf4b0985d99f84e71b21d230e32935c43"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Civilian contracts</header>
 <paragraph id="idA790D695911B48B8889B6D7E28437CD1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 3309 of title 41, United States Code, is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="id3ADB83486B7D447486F4AD88E13FDB9C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by amending subsection (b) to read as follows:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idFB57CA5CFE0A4CCAA0AE9A1980F06260" style="OLC">
							<subsection id="idea7c2d7e29264c2eba2b48c9c88b3542"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Criteria for use</header>
 <paragraph id="idfc6af4c846a348f2a1460238c47c79d1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Contracts with a value of at least $750,000</header><text>Two-phase selection procedures shall be used for entering into a contract for the design and construction of a public building, facility, or work when a contracting officer determines that the contract has a value of $750,000 or greater, as adjusted for inflation in accordance with section 1908 of this title.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id184dc8817ca3419188936d187f7a9107"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contracts with a value less than $750,000</header><text>For projects that a contracting officer determines have a value of less than $750,000, the contracting officer shall make a determination whether two-phase selection procedures are appropriate for use for entering into a contract for the design and construction of a public building, facility, or work when—</text>
 <subparagraph id="ida029292c16a34da2b3c93884dca6b2d2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the contracting officer anticipates that 3 or more offers will be received for the contract;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc8893f8e4d96447199d8ac17fe864b60"><enum>(B)</enum><text>design work must be performed before an offeror can develop a price or cost proposal for the contract;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc8f1108cbc5c4f08a69f400d848b07a5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the offeror will incur a substantial amount of expense in preparing the offer; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc34f088b6bbc44779afc7d947017dcb4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the contracting officer has considered information such as—</text>
 <clause id="idc07695265bb34b429d07e9c515a58bb5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the extent to which the project requirements have been adequately defined;</text> </clause><clause id="id8667db467ebb4e2984857bb71fc3b669"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the time constraints for delivery of the project;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id3effbcbd019a4ba383fcf0cabf265a81"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the capability and experience of potential contractors;</text> </clause><clause id="id2aaec359b5b74386a1ac490bfd7cff45"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the suitability of the project for use of the two-phase selection procedures;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id8ab6668d62dd422ba5c242b23f429a1e"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the capability of the agency to manage the two-phase selection process; and</text> </clause><clause id="id3369b6738fe94a899e814d69aa97f2fc"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>other criteria established by the agency.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id077542d56d644723ab1e897b1539e41e"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (d), by striking <quote>The maximum number specified in the solicitation shall not exceed 5 unless the agency determines with respect to</quote> and all that follows through the period at the end and inserting the following: <quote>The maximum number specified in the solicitation shall not exceed 5 unless the head of the contracting activity, delegable to a level no lower than the senior contracting official within the contracting activity, approves the contracting officer's justification that an individual solicitation must have greater than 5 finalists to be in the Federal Government’s interest. The contracting officer shall provide written documentation of how a maximum number of offerors exceeding 5 is consistent with the purposes and objectives of the two-phase selection process.</quote>.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id852630d955904093b9883c1d09d1952f"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Annual reports</header>
 <subparagraph id="id3d885b69c6284d94be86f5a85e1c2fa8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than November 30 of 2016, 2017, 2018, 2019, and 2020, the head of each agency shall compile an annual report of each instance in which the agency awarded a design-build contract pursuant to section 3309 of title 41, United States Code, during the fiscal year ending in such calendar year, in which—</text>
 <clause id="id8e01b36bccc74f999ae0ba21c6e288df"><enum>(i)</enum><text>more than 5 finalists were selected for phase-two requests for proposals; or</text> </clause><clause id="idea642669e3ee44689f80b7d1f9984e1f"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the contract was awarded without using two-phase selection procedures.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id549462d7229a4371b3d12e640171d7de"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall facilitate public access to the reports, including by posting them on a publicly available Internet website. A notice of the availability of each report shall be published in the Federal Register.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4d9ef691e103440c9898cef7bdc0edf1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Defense contracts</header>
 <paragraph id="idB54038CCB6454002911BD4DB14381295"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 2305a of title 10, United States Code, is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="idAD41DD5079604657A440F4254044211F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by amending subsection (b) to read as follows:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7146937A9B96462B8F9CD431B5245F86" style="OLC">
							<subsection id="idB887BAF799FB480980D5C48886B4C864"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Criteria for use</header>
 <paragraph id="id186E3676F33A4057BB6EBBDE76F58973"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Contracts with a value of at least $750,000</header><text>Two-phase selection procedures shall be used for entering into a contract for the design and construction of a public building, facility, or work when a contracting officer determines that the contract has a value of $750,000 or greater, as adjusted for inflation in accordance with section 1908 of title 41, United States Code.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id4D77EED9BD2845C7AFDFA103436068B1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contracts with a value less than $750,000</header><text>For projects that a contracting officer determines have a value of less than $750,000, the contracting officer shall make a determination whether two-phase selection procedures are appropriate for use for entering into a contract for the design and construction of a public building, facility, or work when—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idB046C0C08F7B4E3A9275132A015860F0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the contracting officer anticipates that 3 or more offers will be received for the contract;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idCD834489360E4B07AA9D9E080A32861D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>design work must be performed before an offeror can develop a price or cost proposal for the contract;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id14C115BCF46B440F81FE56F2D51BD53D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the offeror will incur a substantial amount of expense in preparing the offer; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idEAC1B00B71134B34B5542B444E513B3E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the contracting officer has considered information such as—</text>
 <clause id="id0E6C361AB09C4516AC32D3D6EBC8BBC7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the extent to which the project requirements have been adequately defined;</text> </clause><clause id="idFDC62EDC16714CE8A2E810F7AA1C941C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the time constraints for delivery of the project;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id248C1F19E8F44C7181A6E8179F88CDC9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the capability and experience of potential contractors;</text> </clause><clause id="id8CC698D61CAF413F9F9ED91F0274B1AA"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the suitability of the project for use of the two-phase selection procedures;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id59392EA27CC24BBBB14C0E787A2F9895"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the capability of the agency to manage the two-phase selection process; and</text> </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id43E855E1FA6F40869201BFD1EA114479"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>other criteria established by the Department of Defense.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5CD349118224412BA5FD513EFAEED618"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (d), by striking <quote>The maximum number specified in the solicitation shall not exceed 5 unless the agency determines with respect to</quote> and all that follows through the period at the end and inserting the following: <quote>The maximum number specified in the solicitation shall not exceed 5 unless the head of the contracting activity approves the contracting officer's justification that an individual solicitation must have greater than 5 finalists to be in the Federal Government’s interest. The contracting officer shall provide written documentation of how a maximum number of offerors exceeding 5 is consistent with the purposes and objectives of the two-phase selection process.</quote>.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1A4B47F19949414BA9C9F9255C8B1AF1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Annual reports</header>
 <subparagraph id="id537AA760E689415AA10434D586B44A36"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than November 30 of 2016, 2017, 2018, 2019, and 2020, the Secretary of Defense shall compile an annual report of each instance in which the Department awarded a design-build contract pursuant to section 2305a of title 10, United States Code, during the fiscal year ending in such calendar year, in which—</text>
 <clause id="idDD16F656CF72401D85B184EAC4E66B7C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>more than 5 finalists were selected for phase-two requests for proposals; or</text> </clause><clause id="idEF6FB97640B9435283899EAD9E3BE507"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the contract was awarded without using two-phase selection procedures.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB4BDA5CF024D4A07BF4540894FC7015D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall facilitate public access to the reports, including by posting them on a publicly available Internet website. A notice of the availability of each report shall be published in the Federal Register.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id948185582A14402BBB89295866654C8E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>GAO reports</header>
 <paragraph id="id505c7498be994efeb992c10846c044fc"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Civilian contracts</header><text>Not later than 270 days after the deadline for the final reports required under subsection (f) of section 3309 of title 41, United States Code, as added by subsection (a)(1), the Comptroller General of the United States shall issue a report analyzing the compliance of the various Federal agencies with the requirements of such section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB6FE50F61B27414DA490D738888CAF45"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Defense contracts</header><text>Not later than 270 days after the deadline for the final reports required under subsection (f) of section 2305a of title 10, United States Code, as added by subsection (b)(1), the Comptroller General of the United States shall issue a report analyzing the compliance of the Department of Defense with the requirements of such section.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id403B89AAA94949B79EED69B073C0A588"><enum>4.</enum><header>Prohibition on the use of a reverse auction for the award of a contract for design and construction
			 services</header>
 <subsection id="idBE9EB1C2FE0240E488A35120DE9C9646"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Federal Acquisition Regulatory Council, in consultation with the Administrator for Federal Procurement Policy, shall amend the Federal Acquisition Regulation to prohibit the use of reverse auctions for awarding contracts for construction and design services.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H51E9ED3C3076434194DE912D09614E39"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section—</text> <paragraph id="H733DB3A22FEC4712961898BB284A34C7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>design and construction services</term> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H4E945295FD0A40A8A7F519CB97F40F57"><enum>(A)</enum><text>site planning and landscape design;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF5F37805253144EFAC1CDAE955B6B00E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>architectural and engineering services (including surveying and mapping defined in section 1101 of title 40, United States Code);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H63D9BAC088A6483FACE1E3CE0D4A42F4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>interior design;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF5BB31ACE7334184886A802D2DAF2AF8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>performance of construction work for facility, infrastructure, and environmental restoration projects;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC6C50A3D1CA04B7F963AE791CD6F8DA5"><enum>(E)</enum><text>delivery and supply of construction materials to construction sites; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H89207B86F13E49A1848BD3252933D54E"><enum>(F)</enum><text>construction or substantial alteration or repair of public buildings or public works; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4BCE2CEDA7AF465C9FB0CB0DED26D500"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>reverse auction</term> means, with respect to procurement by an agency—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3F89B0E443CA49CEBEAB8FAE60332711"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a real-time auction conducted through an electronic medium between a group of offerors who compete against each other by submitting bids for a contract or task order with the ability to submit revised bids throughout the course of the auction; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF0973004835B4FACB74A89F90D2A1289"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the award of the contract or task order to the offeror who submits the lowest bid.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id8f9ed98759f2488cbb59196e0c7f3e6d"><enum>5.</enum><header>Assuring payment protections for construction subcontractors and suppliers under an alternative to
			 a Miller Act payment bond</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Chapter 93 of subtitle VI of title 31, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="id39ac3e6d74a0482c9a546cb171cd38c5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf036956785494d22a1bd9ef46a59f7bf" style="USC">
 <section id="idad72cd8026c54136b810954195fd7f51"><enum>9310.</enum><header>Individual sureties</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If another applicable law or regulation permits the acceptance of a bond from a surety that is not subject to sections 9305 and 9306 and is based on a pledge of assets by the surety, the assets pledged by such surety shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="id89d6819fa34043f786ec0efb0540f91d"><enum>(1)</enum><text>consist of eligible obligations described under section 9303(a); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id07ddcdf077aa45d19c90789574255075"><enum>(2)</enum><text>be submitted to the official of the Government required to approve or accept the bond, who shall deposit the assets with a depository described under section 9303(b).</text></paragraph></section><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id2cb3c673907145f58cef85dce400cdb8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the table of sections for such chapter, by adding at the end the following new item:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idFB98FE05ABC24B5EAE84684B3FBEAF50" style="OLC"><toc><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">9310. Individual sureties.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id24F1D50867434D4C819D02FD6C57F47A" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>6.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">SBA surety bond guarantee program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 411(c)(1) of the Small Business Investment Act of 1958 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/694b">15 U.S.C. 694b(c)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>70</quote> and inserting <quote>90</quote>.</text>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


