<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1742 IS: Rural Postal Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 1742</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150709">July 9, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S360">Ms. Heitkamp</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S314">Mr. Tester</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S312">Mrs. McCaskill</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S380">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To improve the provision of postal services to rural areas of the United States.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header>
			<subsection id="id2E3E85F6C3C94BBAA683DA1863CF7F78"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Rural Postal Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idA20DA64BD4E94DA98C112B6D2C51ADD6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text><toc><toc-entry idref="S1" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id0974ffc3-a84d-4be5-8503-4e624b888faa" level="section">Sec. 2. Definitions.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="idF57F616B036E4F06A0414B2C8E099BA6" level="section">Sec. 3. Maintenance of delivery service standards.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id0CA4AF1318E04371B23534548425B99D" level="section">Sec. 4. Preservation of 6-day delivery.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id8518eadc88e54211a7c3eb69cc743e95" level="section">Sec. 5. Protection of rural post offices.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id6971F490331F4D7BA7776CCC13AD1345" level="section">Sec. 6. Protection of workforce rights.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id99ED2787F5DE43A684F807BFB3D1935D" level="section">Sec. 7. Alternative Means of Transportation contracts.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id027eb029-e1f0-4503-b250-01df11776408" level="section">Sec. 8. Rural Postal Service Advisory Commission.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="idF28D272C3289469A82C0AE23116C405C" level="section">Sec. 9. Equipping delivery vehicles for rural areas.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="idDDCD5FA572714F78AA273305869540EF" level="section">Sec. 10. Wi-Fi in rural post offices.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="idd7a71a19-2ba6-456b-b915-458164c7bfaf" level="section">Sec. 11. Protection of door and curbside delivery.</toc-entry> </toc> </subsection></section><section id="id0974ffc3-a84d-4be5-8503-4e624b888faa"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the following definitions shall apply:</text>
 <paragraph id="id79ae145f-4d38-492f-b638-c555b1dcaa9d"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Postal Regulatory Commission.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id12d5a597-f4d3-409b-9a9b-55292a69f432"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Postal Service</header><text>The term <term>Postal Service</term> means the United States Postal Service.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="idF57F616B036E4F06A0414B2C8E099BA6"><enum>3.</enum><header>Maintenance of delivery service standards</header>
			<subsection id="idce0adb7b4f9343cdb2c31d4a55413301"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Preserving mail processing capacity; review of discontinuances, closings, and consolidations</header>
 <paragraph id="idC2EA91D7C0FA4F87BDF0D33871DCB4AD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Moratorium on closing or consolidating postal facilities</header><text>During the 2-year period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act, the Postal Service may not close or consolidate any postal facility (as defined in section 404(f) of title 39, United States Code, as added by this subsection).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id12d4b9fcb4af4b57b5b21ccefda9c8b5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Procedures for closing or consolidation of postal facilities</header><text>Section 404 of title 39, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id98d9511cae494481abe7f1b677896fa9" style="OLC"> <subsection id="idce4d163ac77648f6bebd8cee53559898"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Closing or consolidation of certain postal facilities</header> <paragraph id="id7c2eece8ff4247c9a4a475eb44048c6b"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>postal facility</term> means a processing and distribution center, processing and distribution facility, network distribution center, or other facility that is operated by the Postal Service, the primary function of which is to sort and process mail.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="idecfa682047bc40c1bb975ede35c12ae4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Area mail processing studies</header>
 <subparagraph id="id5974c2e70b3345e791d6e5771a7334ed"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>In this paragraph—</text> <clause id="id444643a4ac9f4915bc8f26b4cf707e94"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the term <term>area mail processing study</term> means an area mail processing feasibility study described in section 2–1 of Handbook PO–408 of the Postal Service, entitled <quote>Area Mail Processing Guidelines</quote>, as in effect on October 1, 2013;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id1f7b26a3b9ba4b698c04e591f47eb520"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the term <term>closing</term>, with respect to a covered postal facility, means the transfer of all incoming and outgoing mail sortation and processing operations of the covered postal facility to a different covered postal facility;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id6585850b80ff4e02bfcfa400711d311b"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the term <term>consolidate</term>, with respect to a covered postal facility, means the transfer of either all incoming or all outgoing mail sortation and processing operations of the covered postal facility to a different covered postal facility; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="ide54b18052632406eba37453742d3bc4f"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the term <term>covered postal facility</term> means a postal facility, the primary function of which is to sort and process first-class mail originating or designating within a defined geographic area.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idefddf025271e49dba56556d0d0d374b7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>New area mail processing studies</header><text>Before making a determination under subsection (a)(3) as to the necessity for the closing or consolidation of a covered postal facility, the Postal Service shall—</text>
 <clause id="idc3077a5a3d03436fa2164a9b77bed92c"><enum>(i)</enum><text>conduct an area mail processing study relating to the covered postal facility that includes consideration of a plan to reduce the capacity of the covered postal facility without closing the covered postal facility; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id70ea393a4e8c4f08a7bf3c39c030bcb0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>upon completing the study under clause (i)—</text> <subclause id="id83c7dd6bd260453784beda9b107bbbb7"><enum>(I)</enum><text>publish the results of the study on the website of the Postal Service; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id6f75182e4aa44da7bb7ca62611165118"><enum>(II)</enum><text>publish a notice that the study is complete and the results of the study are available to the public, including on the website of the Postal Service.</text>
										</subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd7331152f4154a0583c3e8a649b78c0e"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Completed or ongoing area mail processing studies</header>
 <clause id="ide6b564b906fc4694a510feb26c058238"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of a covered postal facility described in clause (ii), the Postal Service shall—</text> <subclause id="idada6dd5f484d40e6a37c4c47bbcfc922"><enum>(I)</enum><text>consider a plan to reduce the capacity of the covered postal facility without closing the covered postal facility; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idacf5d6b7af0d49e2912ac2af2182a426"><enum>(II)</enum><text>publish the results of the consideration under subclause (I) with or as an amendment to the area mail processing study relating to the covered postal facility.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="id768cdf61e5d84a12b5046f59f1feebd9"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Postal facilities</header><text>A covered postal facility described in this clause is a covered postal facility—</text> <subclause id="id3e47c431662b46429c43673f67693fd1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>for which, as of the date of enactment of this subsection, an area mail processing study—</text>
 <item id="idda9e07487a0544d990be81dfc8ddbd49"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>has been completed but does not include a plan to reduce the capacity of the covered postal facility without closing the covered postal facility; or</text>
 </item><item id="id43944db09e2149a18d6176eaa29f2dbe"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>is in progress; and</text> </item></subclause><subclause id="id36db29e159684b5ca1729ea781f5fb39"><enum>(II)</enum><text>which, as of the date of enactment of this subsection, has not been closed or consolidated.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="iddc0e09729a3b47c38832a94a4312df18"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Notice, public comment, and public hearing</header><text>If the Postal Service makes a determination under subsection (a)(3) to close or consolidate a postal facility, the Postal Service shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idd5f034afe7f842eb8dc0141ea204c7da"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide notice of the determination to—</text> <clause id="id4cec715a5f464feba2b09d62829a34fa"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Congress; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idbbe1104ffd1c49468d9bee615934d422"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Postal Regulatory Commission;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2f673cfabc324656a341553343226b03"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide adequate public notice of the intention of the Postal Service to close or consolidate the postal facility;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id94f1c79758554ba2a99b295a7da232d7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>ensure that interested persons have an opportunity to submit public comments during a 45-day period after the Postal Service provides the notice of intention under subparagraph (B);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc1ae53a141354806bd8d4138e4a6cbf4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>before the 45-day period described in subparagraph (C), provide public notice of the opportunity under subparagraph (C) to submit public comments during that period by—</text>
 <clause id="id8bfa41b37bf049f6ae574f2a9b852870"><enum>(i)</enum><text>publication on the website of the Postal Service;</text> </clause><clause id="ide658925479e0478195408ddcf9031807"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>posting at the affected postal facility; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id3fcbb3e033af43ce8cd5986c0e2a4d17"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>publicizing the date and location of the public community meeting under subparagraph (E); and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida36b3edfd3bb48a889709ec76bb1d0cc"><enum>(E)</enum><text>during the 45-day period described in subparagraph (C), conduct a public meeting that provides an opportunity for comments to be submitted verbally or in writing.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idcc78e240c45a4eb297d02b9ebd0cc820"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Further considerations</header><text>The Postal Service, in making a determination under subsection (a)(3) to close or consolidate a postal facility, shall consider—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id080637370bec401b89a5c87616c0b789"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the views presented by interested persons under paragraph (3);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id23ee7fbdbb8149598f13a1b33fe34b5d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the effect of the closing or consolidation on the affected community, including the impact the closing or consolidation may have on a State, region, or locality;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2c11c0929939451babae310edc07d993"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the effect of the closing or consolidation on the travel times and distances for affected customers to access services under the proposed closing or consolidation;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide4a373e30c464646893e22acc68a0dd0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the effect of the closing or consolidation on delivery times for all classes of mail and packages;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb5ffc976b922451fbc04e1b4cddd74dc"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any characteristics of certain geographical areas, such as remoteness, broadband internet availability with a lower rates of access than the average rate of access in other geographical areas of the United States, and weather-related obstacles, that may result in the closing or consolidation having a unique effect;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfa58a090df8843bfb51cd880eeb149fd"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the effect of the closing or consolidation on small businesses in the area, including shipping and communications with customers and suppliers and the corresponding impact on revenues, operations, and growth;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4fa7a573ef5548d5a00673145ac7ef97"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the extent to which significant changes in delivery service resulting from the closure or consolidation of the postal facility would affect the ability of individuals and businesses in the region served by the postal facility to participate in the national economy;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2ad3f93353de47dd8af65e448a0ebf3e"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the ability of the Postal Service to maintain a safe working environment at each postal facility that, as a result of the closing or consolidation, would process the mail that had been processed by the closed or consolidated postal facility, including by examining—</text>
 <clause id="id7e3ef14f77ec47a9af304169f6e2a8cf"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the capacity of each affected postal facility to process a greater volume of mail;</text> </clause><clause id="id1a4c0a6b476b45ed969858d007aa2eb7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the ability of the workforce at each affected postal facility to handle a larger workload; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id840966438b5941b69c4abe4ab1389fe1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>whether the Postal Service would need to hire additional employees at affected postal facilities to process the increased volume of mail;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idedf73c9c77f54167be47e03831a7c78c"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the extent to which the Postal Service can take action to mitigate significant negative impacts identified through the considerations under this paragraph; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id846F7007A7144FBAB887D9B832DB2B75"><enum>(J)</enum><text>any other factor the Postal Service determines is necessary.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idfa3d0ab6c9284f7e853dbd67c6804b07"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Notice of final determination; justification statement</header><text>If the Postal Service determines to close or consolidate a postal facility, the Postal Service shall post on the website of the Postal Service—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id9ffe13cc105d47edbccb0818c008e1ab"><enum>(A)</enum><text>notice of the final determination to close or consolidate the postal facility; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7ec01aee87584df1964eb9f144c1e7fc"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a closing or consolidation justification statement that includes—</text>
 <clause id="idfc6c63b87fb044bf9cfe3f89ac27cfe2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a response to the public comments received with respect to the considerations described under paragraph (4);</text>
 </clause><clause id="idbdd068700bdc4bf590fee3ce2fbc74ff"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a description of the considerations made by the Postal Service under paragraph (4); and</text> </clause><clause id="idb909ce1d096a49f8bac3f4e89cd8e90e"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the actions that the Postal Service will take to mitigate any significant negative effects identified under paragraph (4).</text>
									</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5d3dec962fc2488bb2a2d373c22ace27"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Closing or consolidation of postal facilities</header>
 <subparagraph id="id8aa9f386b2d64a5db5fb0245a1762f35"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not earlier than 15 days after the date on which the Postal Service posts notice of a final determination and a justification statement under paragraph (5) with respect to a postal facility, the Postal Service may close or consolidate the postal facility.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id50aa189451754467984977ed12279b74"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Alternative intake of mail</header><text>If the Postal Service closes or consolidates a postal facility under subparagraph (A), the Postal Service shall make reasonable efforts to ensure continued mail receipt from customers of the closed or consolidated postal facility at the same location or at another appropriate location in close geographic proximity to the closed or consolidated postal facility.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idaae065339124471a9d303527fe4b909c"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Protection of certain information</header><text>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to require the Postal Service to disclose any—</text> <subparagraph id="idfdde6fe492a94716ae17f34a6adf63ac"><enum>(A)</enum><text>proprietary data;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5bbfb387ee124fd28c8205f6ce6c5a67"><enum>(B)</enum><text>information relating to the security of a postal facility; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6652933f358c455688fb9466f83c13a6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>information that is exempt from disclosure under section 552 of title 5.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="iddf6b99b836b841bca18f9ff8a8a4a6eb"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Postal Regulatory Commission appeals</header>
 <subparagraph id="id0d89f91db4e84a34875d12d94cbc7b56"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Right to appeal</header><text>A determination of the Postal Service to close or consolidate any postal facility may be appealed by any person served by the postal facility to the Postal Regulatory Commission not later than 30 days after the date on which the determination is posted on the Postal Service website under paragraph (5).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcf52e59ab0f44639bdbd61d732686a4b"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Review based on record</header><text>The Commission shall review a determination appealed under this paragraph on the basis of the record before the Postal Service in the making of the determination.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2370bd0ba02c4073aa5958f09db4d8d0"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Deadline for Commission determination</header><text>The Commission shall make a determination based upon a review conducted under subparagraph (B) not later than 90 days after the date on which the Commission receives the appeal of the determination under subparagraph (A).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id47e9d00586d142afad38a46e60a48e1a"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Bases for setting aside Postal Service determinations</header><text>In making a determination under subparagraph (C), the Commission shall set aside any determination, finding, or conclusion of the Postal Service that the Commission determines—</text>
 <clause id="id14513c323edc40c6a3e625f131f53a5b"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is arbitrary, capricious, an abuse of discretion, or otherwise not in accordance with the law;</text> </clause><clause id="id81a378faaa854a33899d538dc906192c"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is without observance of the procedures required under this subsection or any other applicable law; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="idcef49741c4c84d75b5da638ea4b19859"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is unsupported by substantial evidence on the record.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9c908bd7a4f345338eb38c8234e16c6a"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Option to affirm or remand</header><text>The Commission—</text>
 <clause id="idB7E770FE61F24061A92EE4654B97C920"><enum>(i)</enum><text>may affirm a determination of the Postal Service appealed under this paragraph or order that the entire matter be returned for further consideration; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id7267D03343B7438394AD73D0299211BA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>may not modify the determination of the Postal Service.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf979734fc5684077af9117b86b909d3a"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Temporary suspension</header><text>The Commission may suspend the effectiveness of a determination of the Postal Service appealed under this paragraph until the final disposition of the appeal.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8bb20a4ee62842128daa3a1a16babf2e"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Applicability of other laws</header><text>The provisions of section 556, section 557, and <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/7">chapter 7</external-xref> of title 5 shall not apply to any review carried out by the Commission under this paragraph.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id721dcdd6f44e4887a2dc8118bc9a86c9"><enum>(H)</enum><header>Date of receipt of appeal</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A), any appeal received by the Commission shall—</text> <clause id="id5837d2540b0a455bbdc1c1dc77cfad2e"><enum>(i)</enum><text>if sent to the Commission through the mails, be considered to have been received on the date of the Postal Service postmark on the envelope or other cover in which the appeal is mailed; or</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1f7218b6a046440cb55805c5daf0f6fe"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if otherwise lawfully delivered to the Commission, be considered to have been received on the date determined based on any appropriate documentation or other indicia (as determined under regulations of the Commission).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4DB485A04F644EA299A380BCEDEDF6F4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Maintenance of delivery service standards</header>
				<paragraph id="idc68b3afc853644cbad04f912f9fa5ac9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Reinstatement of overnight service standards</header>
 <subparagraph id="ida01adacd6c8948b4bc784beba1758d05"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this paragraph, the term <term>market-dominant product</term> means a product subject to subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/39/36">chapter 36</external-xref> of title 39, United States Code.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf7f669744e5d44709561131e6445863d"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Standards for market-dominant products</header><text>The Postal Service shall apply the service standards for market-dominant products under part 121 of title 39, Code of Federal Regulations, that were in effect on July 1, 2012.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide98e33ac758c4f8bacb53f628238cf1d"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Commission study and report</header>
 <subparagraph id="id9bbaddf6a8734bb98bc29bccb1da7f55"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Study</header><text>The Commission shall conduct a study that assesses—</text> <clause id="id712b8590b80f4c9f889bd4763ea4c06f"><enum>(i)</enum><text>how the Postal Service measures delivery times for the purpose of determining whether service standards have been met; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="ida9f2baa0b33b45b5bc1e92d9ac8c7741"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>whether the method used by the Postal Service to measure delivery times reflects the total period of time beginning when a mailed item is transferred from a postal customer and ending when the mailed item arrives at its final destination.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb00d5105e4f448b8a3c8a6d2f8a9d82f"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Report</header>
 <clause id="id97b85cb553d8459d8ee01a0cfc717a10"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and after conducting the hearing under clause (ii), the Commission shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives a report on the findings of the study conducted under subparagraph (A) that includes recommendations as to whether the Postal Service should use additional or improved methods to—</text>
 <subclause id="id50f34f0003d44e94bd3bfb7189144ed3"><enum>(I)</enum><text>measure the actual delivery times experienced by postal customers; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="idcf7ed6eb945e4f78b1dc70233a91a5c6"><enum>(II)</enum><text>assess compliance with the service standards promulgated under section 3691 of title 39, United States Code.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="iddac0321b75a146f685ad13899ad9352a"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Hearing</header><text>Before the Commission submits the report under clause (i), the Commission shall—</text> <subclause id="id835de8b43f86434da52e72bbbaa8aeae"><enum>(I)</enum><text>conduct a hearing on the record under sections 556 and 557 of title 5, United States Code, to provide the Postal Service, users of the mail, and an officer of the Commission required to represent the interests of the general public the opportunity to present views on the proposed report; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id080e2157469740dc9f842240918f403f"><enum>(II)</enum><text>revise the report as the Commission determines appropriate to incorporate the views presented at the hearing conducted under subclause (I).</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id63bd0b61b2a24da68f4d05b17295eafd"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In conducting the study under subparagraph (A), the Commission shall consult with the Inspector General of the Postal Service.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id0CA4AF1318E04371B23534548425B99D"><enum>4.</enum><header>Preservation of 6-day delivery</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 403 of title 39, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id334490F3427D4931BB199DD071A1EE7A" style="OLC"> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idC73088900EE14513A9689A2A0A6FDE0A"><enum>(d)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Postal Service shall provide 6-day delivery and rural delivery of mail at not less than the level required under the second proviso under the heading <quote><header-in-text level="appropriations-small" style="appropriations">Payment to the Postal Service Fund</header-in-text></quote> under the heading <quote><header-in-text level="appropriations-intermediate" style="appropriations">United States Postal Service</header-in-text></quote> under title V of division E of the Consolidated and Further Continuing Appropriations Act, 2015 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/235">Public Law 113–235</external-xref>; 128 Stat. 2373) (commonly referred to as the <quote>1983 level</quote>).</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="id8518eadc88e54211a7c3eb69cc743e95"><enum>5.</enum><header>Protection of rural post offices</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 404(d) of title 39, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="id9B7FD576C2544AF29FA56A0F72799ED2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(6) For purposes of paragraph (5)</quote> and inserting the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id65A50B5BB1EA45A2B8B9DBD36DC8B13B" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="idF74FDFCFF51D4D8A9B576F95C7BDC295"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Date of receipt of appeals</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (7)</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph id="id5E14CBF5C4C14C72B7B09EC53A95B810"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(5) A determination</quote> and inserting the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idA7331FE661A94B188052D39B38504C3D" style="USC">
 <paragraph id="id0780634BB6674E338144429ED2F57C9A"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Appeals</header><text>A determination</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph id="id4e77c1db9d7b46f39362d7617a730efe"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(d)(1) The Postal Service</quote> and all that follows through the end of paragraph (4) and inserting the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id803777a10e5145cfacda119c1b686a2d" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="id90A1CF721AEE4091A408825760865597"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Discontinuance of post offices</header>
 <paragraph id="id301E46046C414792857BBBDFCF96D850"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection—</text> <subparagraph id="id043F09E8BB7245A883ADF18BEF521B9A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the term <term>discontinuance</term> has the meaning given the term in section 241.3 of title 39, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on November 1, 2013;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3FDBF1336D3044849EC1A1EBBF3BE6AC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the term <term>local government</term> means—</text> <clause id="id4262C17ECB9946AD9F306F8421E33352"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a county, municipality, city, town, township, local public authority, special district, intrastate district, council of government, or regional or interstate government entity;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id4DF6C789706E4839805C46F9C2D1973E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an agency or instrumentality of an entity described in clause (i); or</text> </clause><clause id="id632E7D14BAF74545A726C8C92AD1E1D6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a rural community, an unincorporated town or village, or an instrumentality of a rural community or an unincorporated town or village;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id637121EE5B88471DB6BC2C38527A586A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the term <term>post office</term> means a post office, post office branch, post office classified station, or other facility that is operated by the Postal Service, the primary function of which is to provide retail postal services; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb583f24c70974a2685c793fcea6f0658"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the term <term>rural post office</term> means a post office that is—</text> <clause id="id2667fb25933c4a639cd6ada547833502"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in a rural area, as defined by the Census Bureau; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idf85f2735fa2346dd95cd298735007c02"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>within the K or L cost ascertainment grouping, as classified by the Postal Service.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9ec9659cf3bb459e8fae6616a9555b23"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Preliminary considerations</header><text>The Postal Service, prior to making a determination under subsection (a)(3) of this section as to the necessity for the discontinuance of any post office, and, with respect to a determination to discontinue a rural post office, prior to making the determinations required under paragraph (5), shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id4e4e68074d8541de9f6bde62163974c6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>consider whether—</text> <clause id="id5473c9eef8d44e198ca1e0beb90fe3a8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to discontinue the post office and combine it with another post office located within a reasonable distance;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id3e7aa7dbf1ca4f1a824237084ca9e9c8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>instead of discontinuing the post office—</text> <subclause id="id4532f2bc3cbb4528b8f67f08b4431761"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to reduce the number of hours a day that the post office operates; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idc1b179c4ed3c466db864db7b0b61991f"><enum>(II)</enum><text>to continue operating the post office for the same number of hours a day;</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="id1f53e224b7d742eaa463bef9de18528d"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to procure a contract providing full, or less than full, retail postal services in the community served by the post office; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="id46689cf89ec1448d83e55e4d317a194e"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>to provide postal services to the community served by the post office—</text> <subclause id="id1b242377af3848069b2490152966900c"><enum>(I)</enum><text>through a letter carrier or by Alternate Means of Transportation delivery contract;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id96ec272a629847eb9d90c6d9129a424a"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by colocating postal services at a commercial or government entity; or</text> </subclause><subclause id="id6447A5E653C74DD3953EE36A117BF515"><enum>(III)</enum><text>by implementing an alternative proposal made by a local government under subparagraph (B)(iii);</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5F8B4212B14D404F8F6E41F883CBD169"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide—</text> <clause id="id5D2C2ECE670749578DE1129A2502DC74"><enum>(i)</enum><text>relevant information on financial costs associated with the operations of the post office to postal customers and local governments served by the post office;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id3ABC61CD053F444EB340AB389C2D0B01"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>postal customers served by the post office an opportunity to present their views, which may be by nonbinding survey conducted by mail; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idD1ADF2CEE2BC4D5288CCEB7D591131C1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>local governments served by the post office an opportunity to present alternative proposals for providing postal services to the community; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3CDEEEBF92904A16BD27EB54ED775CF8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>if the Postal Service determines to discontinue the post office, provide adequate public notice of its intention to discontinue the post office at least 60 days prior to the proposed date of the discontinuance to persons and local governments served by the post office.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id4fcaf603e7724bc09078ff7842f2f5f8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>The Postal Service, in making a determination whether or not to discontinue a post office—</text> <subparagraph id="id63059d25880448df98b9da8536f31c92"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall consider—</text>
 <clause id="idace921587b4b4d47b4bb45b76654facb"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the effect of the discontinuance on the community served by the post office;</text> </clause><clause id="id185b27ec1981408bbe5e9ad17db41bbf"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the effect of the discontinuance on businesses, including small businesses, in the area;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id2e0cf31b9a974e269567e7e69f9d0fe1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the effect of the discontinuance on employees of the Postal Service employed at the post office;</text> </clause><clause id="idb63e24b982cd4528909a200f7a254543"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>whether the discontinuance would have a significant adverse effect on regular postal services to rural areas, communities, and small towns where post offices are not self-sustaining;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id9c94eb97da074b36b78e111c0aced401"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the extent to which the community served by the post office lacks access to Internet, broadband, or cellular telephone service;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id2b2624b6114941a59828a696c49cdc97"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the extent to which postal customers served by the post office would continue after the discontinuance to receive substantially similar access to essential items, such as prescription drugs and time-sensitive communications;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id02ed645fb0c54ec19f13f0e985f247de"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>the proximity and accessibility of other post offices;</text> </clause><clause id="id5eab5b9d5d83457ab876de0fc4768bb0"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>whether substantial economic savings to the Postal Service would result from the discontinuance; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id73f01e2ef80d421a854139ec6bbb1a55"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>any other factors that the Postal Service determines are necessary; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id95cd46be0d194c54a6854b6be56fbaa0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may not consider compliance with any provision of the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/651">29 U.S.C. 651 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide7554f6c55a44689b77db431bd44684e"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Written determination and findings</header>
 <subparagraph id="idE3185C79B4274D43B73E8EC2F5536CDD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any determination of the Postal Service to discontinue a post office shall—</text> <clause id="id22F8EEB3D4694C70BE52D06053FFA909"><enum>(i)</enum><text>be in writing;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id825A09DEFCBF4297A5BF3DB39FF05080"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>include the findings of the Postal Service with respect to the considerations required to be made under paragraph (3); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idD695D7E240D24345A1760E5C67E6EEED"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>with respect to a determination to discontinue a rural post office, include a summary of the determinations required under paragraph (5).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9DD48397BD0742BEBFB3A197F3CA73A2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Availability of findings</header><text>The Postal Service shall make available, to persons served by a post office that the Postal Service determines to discontinue, any determination and findings under subparagraph (A) with respect to that post office.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idda7d383028c84935b95eefad8500d190"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Notice before discontinuance</header><text>The Postal Service may not take any action to discontinue a post office until 60 days after the date on which the Postal Service makes available, to persons served by the post office, the written determination and findings with respect to the post office as required under subparagraph (B).</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9cb2be0a5ffd45bf94c99990abbd3ef1"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Rural post offices</header>
 <subparagraph id="idDE3D8D15CDBF4BE896F3E94F454232D1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Moratorium on discontinuance of rural post offices</header><text>The Postal Service may not discontinue a rural post office during the 1-year period beginning on the date of enactment of the <short-title>Rural Postal Act of 2015</short-title>.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA6FF831421024E0CB92366FD8D53B277"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirements for discontinuance of rural post offices</header><text>The Postal Service may not make a determination under subsection (a)(3) to discontinue a rural post office unless the Postal Service—</text>
 <clause id="idf7e6c7d7854e4536be54f1423c45bed2"><enum>(i)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id70CC7B72AFDF452DA7D944D0F29FAA39"><enum>(I)</enum><text>determines that postal customers served by the post office would continue after the discontinuance to receive substantially similar access to essential items, such as prescription medications and time-sensitive communications, that are sent through the mails; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="ide112f151a77640379faebdf384515bea" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>takes action to substantially ameliorate any projected reduction in access to essential items described in subclause (I); and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="id47852beac4974ca884aa6682123f4073"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>determines that—</text> <subclause id="id37b5252bc3e4438cae1c2daf8d916e72"><enum>(I)</enum><text>there is unlikely to be substantial economic loss to the community served by the post office as a result of the discontinuance;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id4c6debe231ad4e35a6d4cda208382736"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the area served by the post office has adequate access to broadband Internet service, as identified on the National Broadband Map of the National Telecommunications and Information Administration; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id72892ec9dc7142948bb84c058e6b417c"><enum>(III)</enum><text>there is a road with year-round access connecting the community to another post office that is within 10 miles from the post office proposed to be discontinued.</text>
									</subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id00958004FD7845C69035C138BE0664AD"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Study and Report</header>
 <clause id="id4B874D8032AD458CB4DB888ACA007934"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Study</header><text>The Inspector General shall conduct a study after the discontinuance of a rural post office under this section, which shall include—</text>
 <subclause id="id1A56B4B1B2F144D3B3BD84686440A05E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the actual cost savings resulting from the discontinuance; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="idFD09C017A0BE410C9512A9B7475BB622"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a comparison between the findings described in subclause (I) and the cost savings that the Postal Service predicted would result from the discontinuance.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="id24D2DA4479E244F08229815CD41A7293"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the discontinuance of a rural post office under this section, the Inspector General shall submit a report on the findings of the study conducted under clause (i) with respect to the rural post office to—</text>
 <subclause id="id01B1235748614CB18612662EF1A072D9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the Postal Regulatory Commission;</text> </subclause><subclause id="idF8914CB2517347728BC8492612BA45BB"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the Board of Governors;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id9F5B551BAAE84DFC8FEA4BB35A9AE07D"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate;</text> </subclause><subclause id="id86B3CD18242D4F7A93627BC16C3EAE9C"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idAC74700E433C4699AAC3E9A54BC8412C"><enum>(V)</enum><text>the Member of the House of Representatives in whose district the rural post office was located; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="idE8B882446F7342E5B8D54D2A48196498"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>the Senators in whose State the rural post office was located.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="id42AB9E68D577411B9B70F8841737C87D"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>This subparagraph is repealed effective 10 years after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Rural Postal Act of 2015</short-title>.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id3b6aee30eeb240e9b38332e2c81bcb5f"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Reductions in hours of operation</header> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB60FA2C347414435AFBAC54334C75B29"><enum>(A)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Moratorium on reduction of hours of operation of rural post offices</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Postal Service may not reduce the hours of operation of a rural post office during the 2-year period beginning on the date of enactment of the <short-title>Rural Postal Act of 2015</short-title>.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD94B8E658DC04E20A494D6ECBF1688DE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>The Postal Service, prior to making a determination under paragraph (2)(A)(ii)(I) to reduce the number of hours per day that a post office operates, shall consider—</text>
 <clause id="id3b7d630a96de42bda84bc522e65f0bca"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the impact of the proposed reduction in hours on local businesses;</text> </clause><clause id="ida20f7c7bbfa243338efd9a8cad2919f0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the effect of the proposed reduction in hours on the community served by the post office;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id097cdea998c5431d9cf674622856f9af"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the ability of the Postal Service to hire qualified employees to operate the post office during the reduced hours;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id0746e67a3ef148e1bc8aabe9b457042c"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the proximity and accessibility of other post offices within 15 miles of the post office, and the hours those post offices are open;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id0bc24ff8101d460784650fb75436b3c2"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the impact of the proposed reduction in hours on the elderly and other vulnerable populations; and</text> </clause><clause id="idd6432cdabb1941fb88cecaca98b9fca8"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the impact of alternative schedules on the community served by the post office, including consideration of which schedules would most effectively mitigate any negative impacts identified under clauses (i) through (v).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6c1a8b9bd4f74ca2b87b285ced3aef40"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>If the Postal Service determines, after considering the factors under subparagraph (B), to reduce the number of hours per day that a post office operates, the Postal Service shall make available to persons served by the post office—</text>
 <clause id="idcfd8853a538a4e1a8e5765ce982cbace"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a summary of the findings of the Postal Service under subparagraph (B);</text> </clause><clause id="id201dde829d1145cfad7bcfcbce549e8c"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the hours during which the post office will be open; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id74349ab522c74394b05b984a86553b30"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an explanation of the change in hours referred to in clause (ii).</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0660099D559846FA992B3E12D7884035"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Review period after reduction in hours</header> <clause id="id0DCFF7C8B5BC4D6FA61AF22CA03366B0"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>During the 1-year period beginning on the date on which the Postal Service implements a reduction in hours for a post office under paragraph (2)(A)(ii)(I), the community served by the post office may submit a complaint to the Inspector General if the community finds that the reduction in hours has significantly impacted the community in a negative manner.</text>
 </clause><clause id="id576478D0B88049C88856317DAD915664"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Sufficiency of complaint</header><text>A complaint submitted by a community under clause (i) shall be sufficient if the community demonstrates that—</text>
 <subclause id="idBB016884B8164CA0B1E9ACA576456FED"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a majority of the members of the community oppose the reduction in hours, which may be demonstrated with a signed petition; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id965D8FE332854885BF6CDA61F134A599"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the findings of the Postal Service under subparagraph (B) upon which the Postal Service based the determination to reduce the hours of the post office are no longer valid, which the community may demonstrate using evidence of—</text>
 <item id="id576873884c9245c2ab0694a566857056"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>lobbies in disarray;</text> </item><item id="idcbbef852db65407b8309c32285ce76f2"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>long wait times in line;</text>
 </item><item id="id96035f09bd854f27a27e2293d1af0232"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>insufficient mail acceptance options;</text> </item><item id="idfba2c145419f4ef184e561c7f1148df3"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>unaccommodating post office box service and window times, including any negative impact on regional businesses;</text>
 </item><item id="id8609fbd91bca43eea8cd0228ef8ea7ca"><enum>(ee)</enum><text>retail units closing at times other than the posted hours;</text> </item><item id="idf48ff10bda154622a2cd0e29097361cc"><enum>(ff)</enum><text>inadequate staffing;</text>
 </item><item id="idf95f935259e04e1784572e5783625853"><enum>(gg)</enum><text>running out of postal supplies;</text> </item><item id="ida42207df40434f70a0427a0f29c2eb86"><enum>(hh)</enum><text>unprofessional employees or an unfriendly atmosphere; and</text>
 </item><item id="id7d2c5a7df4e44404b8c7cb7c8fc95930"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any other factors that the community believes are relevant.</text> </item></subclause></clause><clause id="idE307AEBD8846493EAB678FE4F37E2610"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Inspector General determination</header> <subclause id="idB8C133D52E5A4839A5389AC9E2C6316D"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the Inspector General determines that a complaint submitted under clause (i) is sufficient, in accordance with clause (ii), not later than 6 months after the date on which the Inspector General receives the complaint, the Inspector General shall analyze the validity of the complaint.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id439502D0AFC844EA93A008D788FF76BB"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Submission to Postal Service</header><text>If the Inspector General, in analyzing a complaint under subclause (I), determines that the community that submitted the complaint has been disproportionately impacted by the reduction in hours, the Inspector General shall submit to the Postal Service a report that includes—</text>
 <item id="id29D2340C39D34326A0A75BFB24DC2836"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the determination; and</text> </item><item id="idB985361525A44C8798A43F72578A974E"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>a recommendation on the number of additional hours of operation per day that would be sufficient for the postal customers served by the post office to have access to fair and reliable service.</text>
 </item></subclause></clause><clause id="id5FB07DBFC28942158AE84C0ECB99D6CE"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Implementation of recommendations</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date on which the Postal Service receives a report under clause (iii)(II) relating to a post office, the Postal Service shall adjust the hours of operation of the post office in accordance with the recommendation of the Inspector General in the report.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idDAC99E47C9F64B7CB2540D32C13191B0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in paragraph (7), as so designated—</text> <subparagraph id="idE3716262653C41DF8CF719E472684D8C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>close or consolidate</quote> and inserting <quote>discontinue</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD24B44049FB2481B80663BBBE075967E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>under paragraph (3)</quote> and inserting <quote>under paragraph (4)</quote>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1A8B4C5312B54256ACCE380450FFF750"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by moving subparagraphs (A), (B), and (C) 2 ems to the right; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id38ACEF68BEFD40B2BA1843D2103CA855"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by moving the flush text following subparagraph (C) 2 ems to the right;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id85D5CD0CC6064E8B8126D603DC127D08"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in paragraph (8), as so designated, by moving subparagraphs (A) and (B) 2 ems to the right; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idC17519B8CB4147CAA66A33ECADCF3554"><enum>(6)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3F584FA356B4458AA06C45065C20FE19" style="OLC"> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idDCF436C3D00F45F698619CC5DDF32BFA"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Minimum retail standards</header><text>The Postal Service shall establish minimum standards for retail postal services.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section><section id="id6971F490331F4D7BA7776CCC13AD1345"><enum>6.</enum><header>Protection of workforce rights</header>
 <subsection id="idD5C5274062D048808C4FECEA1D15E394"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Right of appeal to Merit Systems Protection Board</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1005(a)(4)(A)(ii)(I) of title 39, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id940D26640AB640D5A5DBCDCE28D6C44B" style="OLC">
 <subclause id="idEB80F98C660D437098BDC3F0B79AD184" indent="up2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is an officer or employee of the Postal Service who—</text>
 <item id="id4DDE7FC4AF304DEAB70694A9AC8EF4C7"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>is not represented by a bargaining representative recognized under section 1203; and</text>
 </item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id70ADED0EB9A7492E8BF2C72A60F88822"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>is in a supervisory, professional, technical, clerical, administrative, or managerial position covered by the Executive and Administrative Schedule; and</text></item></subclause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="id21769FD5617040C98A9046F0C48609C9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Supervisory and other managerial organizations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1004 of title 39, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="id8A328DC6E0F146359685742AFE758062"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by inserting <quote>and fringe benefits</quote> after <quote>differentials in rates of pay</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id473317D7CB564AE99C981BA27D4395CA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b), in the second sentence, by inserting <quote>as provided under subsection (d) and any changes in, or termination of, pay policies and schedules and fringe benefit programs for members of the supervisors' organization as provided under subsection (e). Such pay policies and fringe benefit programs shall reflect adequate differentials in rates of pay and fringe benefits as provided under subsection (a)</quote> before the period; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idC9D2E801C6A64F37A4690BB79F2B7C68"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (e)(1), by inserting <quote>, or termination of,</quote> after <quote>any changes in</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idde6be830-f2a4-410e-b06d-c0cb2a9bfdbb"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Chief Morale Officer</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8305313f-ba72-40d3-b7b1-9b0829d69da6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/39/2">Chapter 2</external-xref> of title 39, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4746e49a-75a7-4c34-800d-7df9b299397a" style="USC">
						<section id="idd715e3ba-724f-4df9-ad22-6a7e25064ff7"><enum>209.</enum><header>Chief
				Morale Officer</header>
 <subsection id="id8c1350a3-bebe-4216-b234-a0a97b667ad2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There shall be in the Postal Service a Chief Morale Officer appointed by the Postmaster General.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="id813ffddc-caec-4a81-9221-3cd84a78a380"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Qualifications</header><text>The Chief Morale Officer shall have—</text> <paragraph id="id4239860ac9ab40b08b062af56f171c7e"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognized and significant experience in such fields as human resources, leadership training, and public administration;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ida73beac632d94a749fdb9de83fe37a2d"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a documented record of innovative thinking;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idd99ecf9029d9482db6c8519f50fa84d1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>significant experience working with employees and managers; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id3ee7c6c5f6b64f788670664f174bea94"><enum>(4)</enum><text>experience with revitalizing and improving the morale of organizations, corporations, or communities that have experienced significant financial challenges or other challenges.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1dba3452-7b73-40a2-872f-ab14702bf33d"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text>The Chief Morale Officer shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="id6B9AB7EBF7D549189CFD42134F8AA87E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>oversee the employees of the Postal Service, including managers, who work in post offices and postal facilities (as defined in section 404(f)); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id0C3AD636AB104DFABBAE7BE83A52B6BF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>oversee and develop national initiatives that address—</text> <subparagraph id="id57436b9a481a4078b405e8a9e1547497"><enum>(A)</enum><text>working conditions, including—</text>
 <clause id="idc6193ab0804d4d4cbc21a1a1258e53bb"><enum>(i)</enum><text>employee morale;</text> </clause><clause id="idb890acadca3a48e3a2ceb3a008b01442"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the physical strain of work;</text>
 </clause><clause id="iddc388024742d417d86720c88d36408bb"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>handling of overtime;</text> </clause><clause id="idd2218dd3579543fdb8aaa1aa0ec9ac1e"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>consistency of workday hours;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id6b9b938f49e641008ddae2cc2b903419"><enum>(v)</enum><text>flexibility in schedules;</text> </clause><clause id="idfd79054eccc04ff5ab8104a37e663207"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>break schedules;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id0e92165c5cae4aef8a107bf0dc8185b5"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>adequate pay;</text> </clause><clause id="id2ad96a38d2104f158835550c6081fc2d"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>the time of mail delivery;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id270133b8b56e4ba88150efbe9a5da29a"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>the safety of mail delivery;</text> </clause><clause id="idc81a978068bf4f5794f3976f9a4b9b98"><enum>(x)</enum><text>work environment;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idcaa3fc3ae2b442cbbc6be046681dce0a"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>work-life balance;</text> </clause><clause id="id06065100ab9c45f0ad26a9225f56f626"><enum>(xii)</enum><text>leadership and management; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id88e70140198742229f693d4cdb4752a3"><enum>(xiii)</enum><text>management accountability;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6318eb68d9ce46b0a2c7b693199ef989"><enum>(B)</enum><text>staffing, including—</text>
 <clause id="idebefc9e5ddb34519b7f01305ac624402"><enum>(i)</enum><text>sufficient staffing;</text> </clause><clause id="id3ec2016d31b54fcda235c1add5e21f5a"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>hiring strategies;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id18a554d121e443899c10969bb1c6035e"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>wages;</text> </clause><clause id="idd9b17757a6874daea738102e7ca06546"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>turnover rate; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="iddb41b598d12e41248ddc29bab0c6db6e"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the balance between temporary and career employees;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1af0bfb9b4334e678731bef0f1213d88"><enum>(C)</enum><text>communication, including—</text>
 <clause id="id4724262f20e744429b41ec27f4f21b04"><enum>(i)</enum><text>employee feedback process;</text> </clause><clause id="iddc2233e9e0b74d458d9502d778ad90c2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>communication between employees and management; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id2348f9f2f3a84db0a7d983546e32f55b"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>protections from retribution; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddce366f0959940d093b3c79bb11b59ad"><enum>(D)</enum><text>training, including—</text>
 <clause id="idcd799d7f8f49465c8b1c3f871d752edc"><enum>(i)</enum><text>sufficient training for new employees;</text> </clause><clause id="id5bd48e8aa675417a91752fd665d4aa14"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the structure of the training program; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idcb1833657bdd431398a3098b8ea5c535"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>addressing frustrations of new employees.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="id69B82C06D6AD4A7D8814174DE9F447F2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Regional Morale Officers</header> <paragraph commented="no" id="id621603E6B1E5453281F0743C882B1B0F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appointment</header><text>The Chief Morale Officer shall appoint a Regional Morale Officer for each area, as that term is used in section 221.6 of title 39, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor thereto.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id2360651B0F07469BBAE6D0EC654012F4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text>Each Regional Morale Officer shall—</text> <subparagraph id="id0d84107d987e4dab9c3ae06af250ecdf"><enum>(A)</enum><text>implement the national initiatives of the Chief Morale Officer at a regional level;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id603fd21929f346beb031d4adae2ca42e"><enum>(B)</enum><text>hold monthly morale roundtables with employees of the Postal Service at which the employees can discuss concerns relating to working conditions, staffing, communication, and training;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7b861010d42241e3b7c2f6a9c56ff8cf"><enum>(C)</enum><text>conduct annual regional training sessions for employees;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf7f063c05de24f0aa16f5781c1e6de5f"><enum>(D)</enum><text>submit biannual feedback reports to the Chief Morale Officer; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5cb18d861e5a4d4ab79e494012db874e"><enum>(E)</enum><text>participate in regular conference calls with other Regional Morale Officers and the Chief Morale Officer to provide feedback on how initiatives are progressing.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id39e1724c-86d1-4603-88f3-c6e0cf086e8a"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deadline for initial appointment</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Postmaster General shall appoint a Chief Morale Officer under section 209 of title 39, United States Code, as added by paragraph (1).</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="id5F5C914FB75B43879AAE5477913A41A0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Technical and
 conforming amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/39/2">chapter 2</external-xref> of title 39, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf467c9c3-daf1-448c-97ca-4c10c51b3693" style="OLC"><toc><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">209. Chief Morale
				Officer.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id99ED2787F5DE43A684F807BFB3D1935D"><enum>7.</enum><header>Alternative Means of Transportation contracts</header>
 <subsection id="idF1C6D4137D504064ACE4E0437BC08B6F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Restriction on discontinuance of Alternate Means of Transportation contracts</header><text>Section 404 of title 39, United States Code, as amended by section 3, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idD5DAD113D0974491AE4B3EAA1C4078E5" style="USC">
					<subsection id="idB9F6CD379D5B413290408E1624E12619"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Alternative Means of Transportation contracts</header>
 <paragraph id="id90ABDCB217CF4C4183BCFE9BA266C06D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>covered route</term> means a route on which first-class mail and periodicals are transported under an Alternate Means of Transportation contract.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id96FF1469B123408484B7DCC3A6D06A23"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements before changing to other means of transportation</header><text>The Postal Service, prior to making a determination under subsection (a)(1) to transport first-class mail or periodicals on a covered route using a means other than under an Alternate Means of Transportation contract, shall consider—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id9EB0411232564E53998F4EF66F0B22A1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the effect of the change on—</text> <clause id="id14A2114EB72A43749BACC5F23637EBB3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>each community served by the covered route;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idFF9621C7F02E42B7AF8D57B9268364A8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>businesses, including small businesses, in the area served by the covered route; and</text> </clause><clause id="id35F69E0A79CA4B77A8711DD043A57820"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>employees of the Postal Service involved in transportation on the covered route;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5d57d72d-afc1-47e3-a120-06d8ec433778"><enum>(B)</enum><text>whether the change is consistent with the policy of the Government, as stated in section 101(b), that the Postal Service shall provide a maximum degree of effective and regular postal services to rural areas, communities, and small towns where post offices are not self-sustaining;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfa2cd198-5ee1-490a-b8f7-a6feeaa2dfb3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the extent to which each community served by the covered route lacks access to Internet service;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id51ace3c3-b4a2-4ac2-a897-edade54dc5ac"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the extent to which postal customers served by the covered route would continue after the change to receive substantially similar access to essential items and time-sensitive communications;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb11ac1c3-f393-4d18-aba4-0c39252b94b0"><enum>(E)</enum><text>whether substantial economic savings to the Postal Service would result from the change;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idFD99F9FF7E414D8CB9FE37E9C5B04CA3"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the average daily volume of mail transported on the covered route;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2230D98B032641FBB409E7DEDB29F572"><enum>(G)</enum><text>any change in the volume of mail transported on the covered route during the preceding 12 months;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id36AC20612F004EB58558F30AC0D83087"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the capacity of available transportation service providers to meet the volume needs of the Postal Service on the covered route;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idBA847E6F55DC4F248D4D3B9FA64EFA41"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the ability of the Postal Service to procure and access additional transportation capacity to meet the volume needs of the Postal Service on the covered route;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3A4AAFC7AD6547988F260E005F6A9F30"><enum>(J)</enum><text>the impact of the change on postal facilities (as that term is defined in subsection (f)) that use the covered route;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id245C0962226B4CC18573E01FA81EFBA1"><enum>(K)</enum><text>the ability of postal facilities described in subparagraph (J) to continue to provide service that complies with applicable service standards after the change; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida74f7614-6c55-49c3-a7f1-79518199751d"><enum>(L)</enum><text>any other factors that the Postal Service determines are necessary.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id8793f397-d29b-4755-9ef2-b13ed32c8cb3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Determinations</header><text>Any determination of the Postal Service to transport first-class mail or periodicals on a covered route using a means other than under an Alternate Means of Transportation contract shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id44F21AB8A5C2434D8586E625F671EBD9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be in writing;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idEC7A449E2B7646AC8FAE6E2BAEA4EB17"><enum>(B)</enum><text>include the findings of the Postal Service with respect to the considerations required to be made under paragraph (2); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idAFE19AEF5B4C4DE2974475867542968C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>be made available by public notice to persons served by the covered route.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id70d4db41-a4a0-4f74-96f0-2ad50716d107"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Advance notice of determinations</header><text>The Postal Service shall take no action to transport first-class mail or periodicals on a covered route using a means other than under an Alternate Means of Transportation contract until 60 days after the date on which the Postal Service makes available to persons served by the covered route a written determination under paragraph (3).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="idEDF30E578BFC45B39A16092CD0A3C04C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Postal Service shall submit to Congress a report on potential cost savings resulting from any decision made during the 2-year period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act—</text>
 <paragraph id="id04AE875AE6A34843B6E1D34E9A14FEB7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to transport first-class mail or periodicals on a covered route (as defined in section 404(g)(1) of title 39, United States Code, as added by this section) using a means other than under an Alternate Means of Transportation contract; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9DD578AA1B7847CE8642DF6FE04C4994"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to discontinue a post office.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id027eb029-e1f0-4503-b250-01df11776408"><enum>8.</enum><header>Rural Postal Service Advisory Commission</header> <subsection id="id6fc39364-a9a8-441f-b725-cf97a4708dad"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header> <paragraph id="id90a1c356-97a1-46ef-9325-cca32a243461"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is established in the executive branch a Rural Postal Service Advisory Commission (referred to in this section as the <term>Advisory Commission</term>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id20a71db8-b637-4ff6-9695-36924c6d8af9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Independence</header><text>The Advisory Commission shall not be subject to the supervision of the Board of Governors of the Postal Service (referred to in this section as the <term>Board of Governors</term>), the Postmaster General, or any other officer or employee of the Postal Service.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id82b9b2a9-66af-4140-8d78-ffcad7849428"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of the Advisory Commission is to—</text>
 <paragraph id="id6ebe780b-64d6-4721-96cf-b8d207744756"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide strategic guidance to the President, Congress, the Board of Governors, and the Postmaster General on enhancing and protecting the provision of postal services to rural areas of the United States (referred to in this section as <term>rural postal services</term>); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id08e0552b-c6a9-4da1-bb1d-e46bf95cfe2e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>foster innovative thinking to address the challenges facing the Postal Service in enhancing and protecting rural postal services.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id852b9523-3b1e-490c-8c1c-f6e2d66f1d94"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Membership</header>
 <paragraph id="idb7369e00-5bbc-4c0c-a193-0b5c58bdb678"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Composition</header><text>The Advisory Commission shall be composed of 7 members, of whom—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id1b00b2e5-cec2-4e7b-86da-c5a4e2d195c2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>3 members shall be appointed by the President, who shall designate 1 member appointed under this subparagraph to serve as Chairperson of the Advisory Commission; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id38d4b171-e8a5-46cb-8974-b2d3d0927f17"><enum>(B)</enum><text>1 member shall be appointed by each of—</text>
 <clause id="id53adb622-d91e-48db-a26f-93a6748ab06e"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the majority leader of the Senate;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idea94df6f-7938-4f28-858f-bbf29ab77f82"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the minority leader of the Senate;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idaa486915-b29d-47ca-bff4-39e7772957f1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the Speaker of the House of Representatives; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id9097f2e1-694b-4100-b8f3-1c09c454269e"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the minority leader of the House of Representatives.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idb557b3de-6942-4f30-8d2e-a4fee3c2233e"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualifications</header><text>Members of the Advisory Commission shall have—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id1e06c9b1-fc8b-4feb-8da2-90f4434f47fc"><enum>(A)</enum><text>recognized and significant experience in such fields as business, technology, and public administration;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id490e0f0d-ad41-4c6d-8306-fc189490b7a6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a documented record of innovative thinking;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id08e6e0f9-52e2-4af6-9843-ed3678cab4d0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>familiarity with new and emerging technologies;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id470ff4ce-bdf9-4c15-9996-470424a3cf5c"><enum>(D)</enum><text>experience with rural areas of the United States; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idEFF56944DEAD4E1DBA5EDA5EEC3140C9"><enum>(E)</enum><text>experience with revitalizing and improving the morale of organizations, corporations, or communities that have experienced significant financial challenges or other challenges.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide10a9df7-9e6d-4205-b218-d040710514f7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Incompatible
 offices</header><text>An individual who is appointed to the Advisory Commission may not serve as an elected official or an officer or employee of the Federal Government while serving as a member of the Advisory Commission, except in the capacity of that individual as a member of the Advisory Commission.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="id6e402bad-5fb0-49c1-bbe2-d7a91c417703"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Deadline for
 appointment</header><text>Each member of the Advisory Commission shall be appointed not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="ideed12f87-040b-4908-b212-97fe89f509d3"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Meetings;
			 quorum; vacancies</header>
 <subparagraph id="idfa7e2ed4-f201-4885-b44a-35ec164e563c"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text>The Advisory Commission shall meet at the call of the Chairperson or a majority of the members of the Advisory Commission.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide923f662-19aa-4b53-932a-90ae13126ff1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Quorum</header><text>Four members of the Advisory Commission shall constitute a quorum.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id09a23b61-2926-4c1d-a89c-941f6e511185"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Vacancies</header><text>Any vacancy in the Advisory Commission shall not affect the powers of the Advisory Commission, but shall be filled as soon as practicable in the same manner in which the original appointment was made.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0c2fa840-15cc-4469-ac8b-c354831ccf99"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Duties and
			 powers</header>
 <paragraph id="idc20b2725-6268-4562-b9df-845da6ccc9ec"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Advisory Commission shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id2cbd4040-6b1f-4aaf-867f-d54852512cbb"><enum>(A)</enum><text>study matters that the Advisory Commission determines are necessary and appropriate to improve and protect rural postal services and develop a strategic blueprint to improve and protect rural postal services, including—</text>
 <clause id="id9457ee02-31bf-4361-9e6f-55a9c400b6d5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the financial, operational, and structural condition of the Postal Service;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id6d737723-cb5f-4e8a-a8aa-7ccf32f71122"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>alternative strategies and business models that the Postal Service could adopt that would improve and protect rural postal services;</text>
 </clause><clause id="ida2579c6d-79cd-43de-9191-398c11d3bddc"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>opportunities for additional postal and nonpostal services that the Postal Service could offer that would assist the mission of the Postal Service in rural areas of the United States;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id8f4ebc5b-a26b-4feb-b70e-d2aa13d96b0d"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the comparative postal practices of other countries in rural areas, including innovative products and services that postal services in other countries have offered;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id0a17c62a-012e-473c-ae3d-cf3e885f903f"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the governance and organizational and management structures of the Postal Service;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idA64E52E0155E4B9E9C735302956E6C0E"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>efforts by the Postal Service to recruit and retain a workforce in rural areas that is capable of meeting the strategic needs of the Postal Service regarding innovation, nationwide service standards, and nationwide delivery schedules;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id73e427e176394edcb3eea3122e73fda7"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>the morale of the workforce of the Postal Service, including strategies to improve the morale of the workforce, with a focus on the workforce that serves rural areas; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id6d72314b2a7640918a5cb79818e5edfa"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>technology that could enhance and protect rural postal services; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida394f42a-7e47-4794-83c9-1a8ad8d29ee4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>submit the report required under subsection (h).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id09906efc-b71c-4c3c-b584-ec7234a16768"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Hearings</header><text>The Advisory Commission may hold such hearings, take such testimony, and receive such evidence as is necessary to carry out this section.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="id7d4906eb-56b7-430e-992f-99175104f368"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Access to
 information</header><text>The Advisory Commission may secure directly from the Postal Service, the Board of Governors, the Postal Regulatory Commission, and any other Federal department or agency such information as the Advisory Commission considers necessary to carry out this section. Upon request of the Chairperson of the Advisory Commission, the head of the department or agency shall furnish the information described in the preceding sentence to the Advisory Commission.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id35ab96d72fef45e7a5bab52bda335d20"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Applicability of laws</header><text>The Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.) and section 552a of title 5, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Privacy Act of 1974</quote>) shall apply to the Advisory Commission.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="idc860c14af6cf46239c110f0753f78d45"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Assistance from Federal agencies</header>
 <paragraph id="id47a013921e7b45c384a6e622d0392792"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Postal Service</header><text>The Postmaster General shall provide to the Advisory Commission administrative support and other services for the performance of the functions of the Advisory Commission.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id37b6661814aa491e9e5001c0702c448b"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Other departments and agencies</header><text>An agency of the Federal Government may provide to the Advisory Committee such services, funds, facilities, staff, and other support services that the agency determines to be advisable or is otherwise authorized under law.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idf912cb5d-5ddb-49f7-affb-091102195ca0"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Personnel
			 matters</header>
				<paragraph id="idbad9235a-269c-46d3-8cf0-927cfa5baaa9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Advisory
			 Commission members</header>
					<subparagraph id="id46bcf828-16ed-4382-9710-fa20cc697e22"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Compensation of
 members</header><text>Each member of the Advisory Commission shall be compensated at a rate equal to the daily equivalent of the annual rate of basic pay prescribed for level IV of the Executive Schedule under section 5315 of title 5, United States Code, for each day during which the member is engaged in the actual performance of the duties of the Advisory Commission.</text>
					</subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7a621595-374f-4450-a329-808235babc53"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Travel
 expenses</header><text>Each member of the Advisory Commission shall be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, at the rate authorized for employees serving intermittently in the Government service under section 5703 of title 5, United States Code, while away from home or regular place of business in the performance of services for the Advisory Commission.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idd947a24a-4dea-4514-9c0c-16d5a5c18c56"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Staff</header>
					<subparagraph id="id9eef71af-1080-4f64-abad-68ca5775ab9b"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Appointment and
 compensation</header><text>The Chairperson, in accordance with rules agreed upon by the Advisory Commission, shall appoint and fix the compensation of an executive director and such other personnel as may be necessary to enable the Advisory Commission to carry out the functions of the Advisory Commission, without regard to the provisions of title 5, United States Code, governing appointments in the competitive service, and without regard to the provisions of chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of such title relating to classification of positions and General Schedule pay rates, except that a rate of pay fixed under this subparagraph may not exceed the annual rate of basic pay prescribed for level V of the Executive Schedule under section 5316 of title 5, United States Code.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9c280b58-c1d2-4670-a39f-c61b17ee0905"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Detailees</header><text>Any Federal employee, including an employee of the Postal Service, may be detailed to the Advisory Commission without reimbursement, and such detail shall be without interruption or loss of the civil service rights, status, or privilege of the employee.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idf08a566f-8831-40c2-a4a9-c7121d764b75"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Strategic
			 blueprint for rural postal services</header>
				<paragraph id="id2beb635e-75f8-4ccd-b9ae-a028b2786021"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>Not later than 9 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Advisory Commission shall submit a report that contains a strategic blueprint for rural postal services to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id30b5b548-5d5d-42ff-a6d5-86c0acdd06d5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the President;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf75fddae-b772-4bb3-9ace-017c7e2076ff"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf4576391-da73-4388-8c3c-ac0591ff071c"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9a4f8113-0874-46ce-add5-6d90feb9bb00"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Board of Governors; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6129bfdb-a2e1-474f-a772-5ba719e7546d"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Postmaster General.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id63ce9bf0-f7fa-4b35-84ab-7d2c3e1e0159"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The strategic blueprint contained in the report submitted under paragraph (1) shall include—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id839fd0e9-4a76-4778-a0cb-e4e3aa3d612b"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an assessment of the effectiveness of the business model of the Postal Service for protecting rural postal services as of the date on which the report is submitted;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5b771fe2-eaa1-4790-9e7b-b790c5bbc98f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an assessment of potential future business models for the Postal Service and the impact of those business models on rural postal services, including an evaluation of the impact of—</text>
 <clause id="id5d5bdfbb-a340-433f-a740-f92f04c6c526"><enum>(i)</enum><text>reductions of service on revenue; and</text> </clause><clause id="ide7d64159-4804-4511-bb8c-4c18297edb7c"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>additional opportunities for growth and revenue;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id37c21293-0a16-478b-ae9b-02eecfdd6417"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a strategy for addressing challenges and costs in protecting rural postal services;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6cd61c0a-fd66-47e8-a8c7-26fb74934b78"><enum>(D)</enum><text>identification of opportunities for new and innovative products and services that would help protect and enhance rural postal services;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc5a9eaff-04ba-4021-9b7b-1bf52a4879db"><enum>(E)</enum><text>an enumeration of steps that the Postal Service needs to take to ensure that, 20 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Postal Service can continue to offer postal services in rural areas;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idCDC0BFB1050543959CA676565847A576"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a strategy for ensuring that the Postal Service has a sufficient workforce to comply with service standards for, and meet the needs of postal customers in, rural areas; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida6acbc0f-cb76-4a94-8d3e-08ebbb4d77ce"><enum>(G)</enum><text>recommendations for any legislative changes necessary to implement the strategic blueprint described in this paragraph.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idbabf0bac-81c6-41ba-9446-9f7176b67e75"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Termination of
 the Commission</header><text>The Advisory Commission shall terminate on the earlier of—</text> <paragraph id="id0F21224E758E48788E12E7FA7987A225"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the date that is 60 days after the date on which the Advisory Commission submits the report on the strategic blueprint for rural postal services under subsection (h); or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idCA46EE85F7C0462386CFF2780358C9B9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the date that is 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3152fb84-aacb-4ab5-bc24-ec961b456b6d"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated out of the Postal Service Fund a total of not more than $3,000,000 for fiscal years 2015 and 2016.</text>
			</subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF28D272C3289469A82C0AE23116C405C"><enum>9.</enum><header>Equipping delivery vehicles for rural areas</header>
 <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id220DB4FDB610414892C5225D976B06EA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7A634CECE11B488C82597451538C26C5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">while it may be too late for the Postal Service to consider rural mail delivery as part of its Next Generation Delivery Vehicles (commonly known as <term>NGDV</term>) initiative, the Postal Service should consider options for a rural delivery truck prototype in the future, as rural letter carriers currently must use their own vehicles due to the unique terrain challenges across the United States; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idC7C233E17923437DBA04723523ED60E2"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Postal Service should consider the feasibility of equipping delivery vehicles that can not only handle the challenges described in paragraph (1), but can also handle severe weather conditions.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idC0B65B4FA77D45389B2692C0DD775F1E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>GAO study</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="id3DD8F2D2AD3A461C9A01188942C49877"><enum>(1)</enum><text>study the feasibility of the Postal Service designing mail delivery vehicles that are equipped for rural areas; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idAD09A4B9EA0547C6AB5DD83535D278A1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submit to Congress a report on the findings of the study conducted under paragraph (1).</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idDDCD5FA572714F78AA273305869540EF"><enum>10.</enum><header>Wi-Fi in rural post offices</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4C840A933CCB4140A052C3D9516327A6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0F8A10DFF8A949278629428774EABD05"><enum>(1)</enum><text>because post offices still serve as a central point in many rural communities where people congregate and connect with the rest of the world, the Postal Service should consider providing wireless broadband Internet access service at all rural post offices as a method of incentivizing individuals to use their community post office as much as possible; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3D2C075156D94F65BA3A4FB172AF13CA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>because of the challenges that implementing wireless broadband Internet access service at all rural post offices would pose, the Postal Service should first consider implementing a pilot program under which the Postal Service would provide wireless broadband Internet access service at 4 rural post offices in diverse areas of the United States for a 2-year period in order to determine whether the addition of such service in those post offices has an impact on the amount of business or revenue generated by each post office.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idDAB616549EF043A58228FDA7BB60C576"><enum>(b)</enum><header>GAO study</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="id9806DAD8351E483887070F50B294B4B2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>study the feasibility of the Postal Service providing wireless broadband Internet access service at all rural post offices; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idCBEAF7E663264C8EA92022B6102697A5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submit to Congress a report on the findings of the study conducted under paragraph (1).</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idd7a71a19-2ba6-456b-b915-458164c7bfaf"><enum>11.</enum><header>Protection of door and curbside delivery</header> <subsection id="id17EC9476B8CA47E8B5F34A076FEB0F52"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text>
 <paragraph id="idEF782A1CA4FD46AA94DFCD1BA83C61DB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>centralized delivery</term> means a primary mode of mail delivery whereby mail is delivered to a group or cluster of mail receptacles at a single location;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id603F3B1B595C4C618D232AD017D0EDC5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>curbside delivery</term> means a primary mode of mail delivery whereby mail is delivered to a mail receptacle that is situated at the edge of a public sidewalk abutting a road or curb, at a road, or at a curb;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id909DFD458A194CD387B0B24FED123CD3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>delivery point</term> means a mailbox or other receptacle to which mail is delivered;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id459BAB29FC3141698662D87D445E7AEC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the term <term>door delivery</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="idE0B4ACEC15A442018A6DAB237155A4D1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means a primary mode of mail delivery whereby mail is—</text>
 <clause id="id69605A80568944F283FABEBD625931A5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>delivered to a mail receptacle at or near a postal customer’s door; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="id897F2E4CFD484BEFB1C957846FACFF9B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>hand-delivered to a postal customer; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8326BEEA35FA4182A549BE1A193BAB31"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include curbside or centralized delivery; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id488E9782694C4F74A43E9971F3E9E28C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the term <term>primary mode of mail delivery</term> means the typical method by which the Postal Service delivers mail to the delivery point of a postal customer.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id7196804352A749D68E704A75ADDE4641"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that the Postal Service should not convert existing residential or business addresses to centralized delivery from door delivery or curbside delivery.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


