<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1391 IS: Cerebral Cavernous Malformations Clinical Awareness, Research, and Education Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>S. 1391</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150520">May 20, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S326">Mr. Udall</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S359">Mr. Heinrich</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To increase research, education, and treatment for cerebral cavernous malformations.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H9A655D013A5849D69B0CCC6DDE430158"> 
<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Cerebral Cavernous Malformations Clinical Awareness, Research, and Education Act of 2015</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>CCM–CARE Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="id3B78926E03F14BC695873EAB9FF9970A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds as follows:</text> 
<paragraph id="id22504c9924284b48859c45ad53d74b51"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Cerebral cavernous malformations (referred to in this section as <quote>CCM</quote>), also known as cavernous angioma, or cavernoma, is a devastating blood vessel disease characterized by vascular lesions that develop and grow within the brain and spinal cord.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="id60b736da628342baa80dedfdfdd733b6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Detection of CCM lesions is achieved through costly and specialized medical imaging techniques, often not accessible or convenient to patients who need them.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="id3207690cfec94700b02d65e37809e22a"><enum>(3)</enum><text>While CCM is a common type of vascular anomaly, many individuals are not aware they have the disease until the onset of serious clinical symptoms. CCM is often inherited unknowingly.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="id78dcbffae5494329927c772fe4c54600"><enum>(4)</enum><text>CCM affects an estimated 1,500,000 people in the United States.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="id74677c2d2b5f48399db5eb34fae09af8"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Individuals diagnosed with CCM may experience neurological deficits, seizure, stroke, or sudden death.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="id23bb93c966a0432f9c82bdc33912de39"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Due to limited research, there is currently no treatment for CCM other than brain and spinal surgery, and only for certain patients. There is also a shortage of trained physicians to provide skilled and timely diagnosis and appropriate treatment for CCM.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="ide7ab7efe160e4cd887dc27cb27d17593"><enum>(7)</enum><text>While the hereditary form of CCM may occur among any ethnicity, the presence of a mutation called the <quote>common Hispanic mutation</quote>, has passed through 17 or more generations of American descendants from the original Spanish settlers of the Southwest in the 1590s. New Mexico has the highest population density of CCM in the world; Texas, Arizona, and Colorado also have high rates of CCM due to the common Hispanic mutation.</text> </paragraph></section> <section id="id6D3F6E4EE618476793B88647A6C6571E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Expansion and coordination of activities of National Institutes of Health with respect to cerebral cavernous malformations research</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part B of title IV of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/284">42 U.S.C. 284 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc0aa95f13b5f4588893a08647d961a16" style="OLC"> 
<section id="id2761c50562834cce85982782ed070cb6"><enum>409K.</enum><header>Cerebral cavernous malformations research activities</header> 
<subsection id="id56a6348bc3d248a1b6278e8638bebbfc"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Expansion and coordination of activities</header><text>The Director of NIH, in coordination with the directors of the National Institute of Neurological Disorders and Stroke, the National Center for Advancing Translational Sciences, the National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute, and other national research institutes, as appropriate, for the purpose of conducting research and related activities concerning cerebral cavernous malformations (referred to in this section as <quote>CCM</quote>)—</text> <paragraph id="id2A65AB9F201A447E9F68EA1DA81ED471"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall strengthen and coordinate efforts of the National Institutes of Health; and</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="id1D744F71672D4D02BD1F480DDC90E8F7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may award grants and cooperative agreements to public or nonprofit private entities (including State health departments, political subdivisions of States, universities, and other medical or educational entities).</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="idaea393c87df64478a45522d2aa7127b8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Activities</header><text>The research and related activities described in subsection (a) shall include the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="id26c185e9c2494695b866e083dc96ae84"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Basic, translational, and clinical research</header><text>The Director of NIH shall conduct or support, through funding opportunity announcements, grants, or cooperative agreements, basic, clinical, and translational research on CCM, including research on—</text> <subparagraph id="id5b83690a8c3d4fbdab6188235a76c788"><enum>(A)</enum><text>proteomic, pharmacological, and cell biological analysis of CCM molecules;</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="id68a654afb1dd4dd699f1dfd4cfd50828"><enum>(B)</enum><text>continued development and expansion of novel animal models for preclinical research relating to CCM;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idfa62a9916db74bcabc490ba4727401b5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>early detection, diagnosis, and treatment of CCM;</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="id9d2c200718fe44bc854f58ea7f0990bc"><enum>(D)</enum><text>biological mechanisms for lesion genesis, development, and maturation;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id9aca321a11be4b97b6f555500c8aa488"><enum>(E)</enum><text>biological mechanisms for lesion bleeding and symptomology;</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="id705e32ad2e984be7886eec80cee0d969"><enum>(F)</enum><text>novel biomedical and pharmacological interventions designed to inhibit new lesion development, lesion growth, and lesion bleeding;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id9017562e981e4d36b82f6f793ac7ccc4"><enum>(G)</enum><text>pre-clinical and clinical research related to repurposing currently approved drugs for treatment of CCM;</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="idf9ce8720d4094eb7a692099b56509c4c"><enum>(H)</enum><text>contributions of genetic variation to clinical presentation as targets for therapy;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idfc1b3b1f09064c89b7d54b1965d3c6f5"><enum>(I)</enum><text>identification and development of biomarkers to measure phenotypic variation;</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="id67c8a4d48d1042ecb566bc1879614671"><enum>(J)</enum><text>research related to improving the quality of life for individuals with CCM and their families; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id705be06316c749db9654f3bd6137248b"><enum>(K)</enum><text>clinical training programs aimed at increasing the number of scientists and clinicians who are trained to treat patients and carry out the research described in this paragraph.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="id45ffc4fadb1e43ef8e5380d2fd17e1a6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Facilitation of research resources; clinical trial preparedness</header> 
<subparagraph id="id5f58744ae2014e608cb7fe8984c674bb"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director of NIH shall award grants and contracts to public or nonprofit private entities to fund all or part of the cost of planning, establishing, and providing basic operating support for a network of CCM Clinical Research Centers, including Coordinating and Participating centers regarding research on various forms of CCM.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id3f56b3117f7e410d9d06a32458789bda"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Clinical and research coordination centers</header> <clause id="idBF1C760E161E484C832A170845C8DE7B"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director of NIH shall identify and support the development of 3 geographically distributed national clinical and research coordinating centers with unique clinical expertise and the potential for coordinating multi-site clinical drug trials with respect to CCM.</text> </clause>
<clause id="idE090BC78659E49639914E3B9E9C09FDC"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The coordinating centers identified under clause (i) shall provide a model for the participation centers described in paragraph (3), facilitate medical research to develop a cure for CCM, and enhance the medical care of individuals with CCM nationwide, including by—</text> <subclause id="id6a59a402dc6f476882375220c78cc899"><enum>(I)</enum><text>maintaining an institutional infrastructure capable of hosting clinical trials and facilitating translational research projects and collaborations for clinical trials;</text> </subclause>
<subclause id="id1963d32a6a7c43e698ff5927d1530ce4"><enum>(II)</enum><text>implementing the programs dedicated to patient education, patient outreach, and awareness developed by the Cerebral Cavernous Malformations Consortium under subsection (c)(3)(B);</text> </subclause> <subclause id="id0b4479fd356143dea404ea520c1e6424"><enum>(III)</enum><text>developing the capacity to establish and maintain communication with other major CCM research and care institutions internationally for information sharing and coordination of research activities;</text> </subclause>
<subclause id="ida94014dd500b4cbc8f930028d221bf4f"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>demonstrating clinical expertise in the management of CCM and appointing a director and support staff, including a trainee and patient representative, for CCM research programming;</text> </subclause> <subclause id="idcbf86e043e4b4ea797492f7fe2b96d34"><enum>(V)</enum><text>treating a sufficient number of eligible patients for participation with particular focus on unique subpopulations, such as patients with the common Hispanic mutation, Ashkenazi Jewish mutation, or CCM3 gene mutation carriers; and</text> </subclause>
<subclause id="id6754473be52547428389990752e67418"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>maintaining a telehealth infrastructure to support and provide clinical consultation for remote and underserved communities.</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="id9b416b8765274be69f3a4b8f114362d2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Participation centers</header> <subparagraph id="id6CDE0CA13B0343B792DB8BF8C78F5452"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director of NIH shall identify and support the development of 6 to 10 clinical and research participation centers to facilitate medical research to develop a cure for CCM and enhance the medical care of individuals with CCM, in partnership with the coordinating centers under paragraph (2) and other national and international entities, as appropriate.</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="idCE8AE716355E4DFC8DD41145E8350598"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>To qualify for selection as a participation center under subparagraph (A), an entity shall—</text> <clause id="idE816AE71E80449B89A7FA8FE5C5D483E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>at the time of selection—</text> 
<subclause id="id0F14C168F3E148ECAB71239987C82F24"><enum>(I)</enum><text>be affiliated with an established research network of the National Institutes of Health; and</text> </subclause> <subclause id="id1C71BC05F95D4953935509F1B884F629"><enum>(II)</enum><text>have the potential to participate in a multisite clinical drug trial with respect to CCM;</text> </subclause></clause>
<clause id="id8D471921F96D42D8AE9F11434D17AFC3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>demonstrate—</text> <subclause id="id39927221d10e4f8fa7b15ecbfee91dea"><enum>(I)</enum><text>an institutional infrastructure capable of hosting a clinical trial site and facilitating translational projects and collaborations for clinical trials;</text> </subclause>
<subclause id="id3f6a33d735a04a45a1883fbe5069940f"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the capacity to maintain communication with other major CCM research and care institutions internationally for information sharing and coordination of research activities, especially through health information technology; and</text> </subclause> <subclause id="id1397f9541e554279bf6fa325a86deb60"><enum>(III)</enum><text>clinical expertise in CCM management or complete the CCM clinical training program under subsection (c)(4); and</text> </subclause></clause>
<clause id="id186ead3b86bb4d71aaa30da1bcdaa4d8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>have a sufficient number of eligible patients with CCM.</text> </clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id7458fb4a68794760b42aacfe39f600fb"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Duration of support</header><text>The Director of NIH may provide support for participation centers under this section for a period not to exceed 5 years. The Director of NIH may extend the period of support for a center for 1 or more additional periods, not to exceed an additional 5 years, if the operations of such center have been reviewed by an appropriate technical and scientific peer review group established by the Director of NIH and if such group has recommended to the Director that such period should be extended.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="idddb55e8defc04828a4bc471877017310"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Cerebral cavernous malformations consortium</header> 
<paragraph id="id21132c0723ab48e9b8fdf8941bf3a891"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director of NIH shall convene a Cerebral Cavernous Malformations Research Consortium (referred to in this section as the <quote>consortium</quote>).</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="idB3EF726B4881495B8F6D6E71A6385601"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>The consortium—</text> 
<subparagraph id="id2828114586154AA38891F25ED20498B6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall include representatives of—</text> <clause id="idCB4D58926FA74E2E9D4A415D6126C11D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the coordinating centers selected under subsection (b)(2); and</text> </clause>
<clause commented="no" id="id974907494DCC4CDD8EF552193D2FC274"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>at least 1 national CCM patient advocacy organization, which may be an entity that receives a grant or contract under subsection (b)(2)(A); and</text> </clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idBF027DB0CE7F4E37A668D1D4EE9AB844"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may include representatives of the National Institutes of Health or the Food and Drug Administration, in an advisory or ex officio role.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="id3663747e39564b2cbeff346587f70486"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text>Through a consensus based decisionmaking model, the consortium shall divide assignments and be responsible for—</text> <subparagraph id="id635265fdfb984269b3235f9c930ad755"><enum>(A)</enum><text>developing and implementing training programs for clinicians and scientists in accordance with paragraph (4);</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="id51b690a6d38640e4994e71402d4ebb9a"><enum>(B)</enum><text>developing patient education, outreach, and awareness programs and materials, which may be tailored for specific regional needs at coordinating centers, including—</text> <clause id="idA9F1E2221CE844E4B7234257067A0F06"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a regional multimedia public awareness campaign;</text> </clause>
<clause id="idb96aae334c05482fb8ac88b58c3ea53d"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>patient education materials for distribution by regional physician and surgeon offices;</text> </clause> <clause id="idc72e6bae4a0f45ecb06992edfaf6482b"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an education program for elementary and secondary school nurses to facilitate early detection and diagnosis of CCM in areas in which there is a high density of cases of CCM;</text> </clause>
<clause id="idf9b1328e3bf64f60b571428a73c59248"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>regular regional patient and family-oriented educational conferences; and</text> </clause> <clause id="idcc4f62bcb98c4b0f8dfa628a4e6aac74"><enum>(v)</enum><text>nationally relevant electronic health teaching and communication tools and a network of professional capacity and patient and family support; and</text> </clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="id589771f5750b4addaa18c6a24460281d"><enum>(C)</enum><text>preparing a biannual report to Congress, in accordance with paragraph (5).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="idfa97664af03341138cf47ace5ec89f09"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Training program for clinicians and scientists</header> <subparagraph id="id65b5e8c85d3446cc9cb61cf7883a9d2a"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The consortium, in cooperation with the coordinating centers, shall establish or expand a physician training program, including information and education on advances in the diagnosis and treatment of CCM, and training and continuing education through programs for scientists, physicians, medical students, and other health professionals and care coordinators who provide care for patients with CCM, telehealth, and research relevant to CCM, for the purpose of supporting the development of new participation centers through educational programming to gain the expertise needed to become clinical and research participation centers with the potential to participate in clinical drug trials.</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="id97194C585FD9491F869513CF7302CEA5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Stipends</header><text>The Director of NIH may provide stipends for health professionals who are enrolled in the training programs described in subparagraph (A).</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idE16DF2F7A8C8448FA66FBA54E06AEAD9"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>To be eligible to participate in the training program, an individual shall be affiliated with an entity that is in an existing clinical research network of the National Institutes of Health.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="id3d7568ac0afd4dc88f1677038c77921b"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The consortium shall biennially submit to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives a report that describes the research, education, and other activities on CCM conducted or supported through the Department of Health and Human Services. Each such report shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="id03717e1f188a4586a74d6d891f081abd"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a research plan;</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="id07c8a46bfa684203a204a54d40e46e9b"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provisions specifying the amounts expended by the Department of Health and Human Services with respect to various forms of CCM, including those affected by the common Hispanic Mutation, Ashkenazi Jewish mutation, CCM3 gene mutations, and other familial and sporadic forms of cerebral cavernous malformation; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idf739ce4278674cfd89533cfbcf10dbd8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>recommendations for particular projects or types of projects that the national research institutes or other entities in the field of research should conduct on inherited or non-inherited forms of CCM.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </section>
<section id="id9e4aebc93d104529a7c9082f6ca6ecd8"><enum>4.</enum><header>Centers for Disease Control and prevention cerebral cavernous malformations surveillance and research programs</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part B of title III of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/243">42 U.S.C. 243 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 317T the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id435b9c317a7f4f5798334d675ef830d7" style="OLC"> <section id="id01d414bede8c414cbe234ae68363044a"><enum>317U.</enum><header>Cerebral cavernous malformations surveillance and research programs</header> <subsection id="id2a826f9820364e85865183bc6d0525d2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, may award grants in such sums as may be necessary and cooperative agreements to public or nonprofit private entities (including State health departments, political subdivisions of States, universities, and other medical or educational entities) for the collection, analysis, and reporting of data on cerebral cavernous malformations (referred to in this section as <quote>CCM</quote>).</text> </subsection>
<subsection id="idf50ea4c3ff3c47c08d7b528532f674cf"><enum>(b)</enum><header>National cerebral cavernous malformations epidemiology program</header> <text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall award grants and cooperative agreements, including technical assistance, to public or nonprofit private entities for—</text> <paragraph id="id6709460E47BC4F8EA71BD98F0D483A63"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the collection, analysis, and reporting of data on CCM; and</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="id1AC289D5ACB54366B6497EDFF4143B92"><enum>(2)</enum><text>epidemiological activities, including collecting and analyzing information on the number, incidence, correlates, and symptoms of cases and the clinical utility of specific practice patterns.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="idcbf1cc981d20462882b703ba2382dd58"><enum>(c)</enum><header>National surveillance program</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="id69c5134184d145159b7d694aa1be5793"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide for a national surveillance program for the purpose of carrying out epidemiological activities regarding CCM, including collecting and analyzing information on the number, incidence, correlates, and symptoms of cases of CCM and the clinical utility (including costs and benefits) of specific practice patterns; and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="id1b74e12d47c14ec3b3771d483e73dd08"><enum>(2)</enum><text>wherever possible, ensure that the surveillance program is coordinated with the data and sample collection activities of the National Institutes of Health under section 409K.</text> </paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="id2A737009592C44E5B702F9B603C6A100"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text>In making awards under this section, the Secretary may provide direct technical assistance, including personnel support.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="id91b52fa31e3f4660bfa4d85d93cac984"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Coordination with clinical centers</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that epidemiological information is made available to clinical centers as supported by the Director of the National Institutes of Health under section 409K.</text> </subsection>
<subsection id="ida9ea0f53be98426d96b26b2faa50f0c3"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </section> <section id="id312eb0aa2e0c45f8adfc667a2c514266"><enum>5.</enum><header>Food and Drug Administration cerebral cavernous malformations clinical trial preparedness and support program</header> <subsection id="idbc365393c7874aaf810e492d6d6b25be"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Investigational new drug application</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Commissioner of Food and Drugs, shall coordinate with clinical centers, investigators, and advocates to support appropriate investigational new drug applications under section 505(i) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355">21 U.S.C. 355(i)</external-xref>) in an effort to hasten the pace of clinical trials for cerebral cavernous malformation.</text> </subsection>
<subsection id="id8e15f13b8cfa4467b5b3f78703778171"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Orphan product development</header><text>Where applicable in rare subpopulations of cerebral cavernous malformation requiring unique pharmacological intervention, including subpopulations with the common Hispanic mutation or CCM3 gene mutations, the Commissioner of Food and Drugs shall support appropriate requests for designations of drugs as orphan drugs under section 526 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/360bb">21 U.S.C. 360bb</external-xref>).</text> </subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

