<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S998 IS: American Manufacturing Competitiveness Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 998</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150416">April 16, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S349">Mr. Portman</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S312">Mrs. McCaskill</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S351">Mr. Toomey</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To establish a process for the consideration of temporary duty suspensions and reductions, and for
			 other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>American Manufacturing Competitiveness Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="id33B576891F0742958F99AB1B7520B485"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress on the need for a miscellaneous tariff bill</header>
 <subsection id="idC8394768E64B4DC088685218E67377C6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text> <paragraph id="id9ed11dc6872d48169288201c9a970cb1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>As of the date of the enactment of this Act, the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States imposes duties on imported goods for which there is no domestic availability or insufficient domestic availability.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id8187c7356a1c43c58be3bfac92f67b3b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The imposition of duties on such goods creates artificial distortions in the economy of the United States that negatively affect United States manufacturers and consumers.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ide1a0c85a925d4026aaa462ced97bffc0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>It is in the interests of the United States to update the Harmonized Tariff Schedule every 3 years to eliminate such artificial distortions by suspending or reducing duties on such goods.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id209c362b1b384399b4b7304d1423159d"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The manufacturing competitiveness of the United States around the world will be enhanced if Congress regularly and predictably updates the Harmonized Tariff Schedule to suspend or reduce duties on such goods.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id8AB87A9E3D4E47DF873ADE9A6513858E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that, to remove the competitive disadvantage to United States manufactures and consumers resulting from an outdated Harmonized Tariff Schedule and to promote the competitiveness of United States manufacturers, Congress should consider a miscellaneous tariff bill not later than 180 days after the United States International Trade Commission and the Department of Commerce issue reports on proposed duty suspensions and reductions under this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="id09E8D91D373A4010B95819238CC34077"><enum>3.</enum><header>Process for consideration of duty suspensions and reductions</header>
 <subsection id="id7318ece4858e47f99a14c7ccb6125be9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>It is the purpose of this section to establish a process by the appropriate congressional committees, in conjunction with the Commission pursuant to its authorities under section 332 of the Tariff Act of 1930 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1332">19 U.S.C. 1332</external-xref>), for the submission and consideration of proposed duty suspensions and reductions.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id3ac03e71a8be480a82393e50801e58c1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than October 15, 2015, and October 15, 2018, the appropriate congressional committees shall establish and, on the same day, publish on their respective publicly available Internet websites a process—</text>
 <paragraph id="id0ce093b488db40debbe719b2efc9c880"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to provide for the submission and consideration of legislation containing proposed duty suspensions and reductions in a manner that, to the maximum extent practicable, is consistent with the requirements described in subsection (c); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idd39b7d3c8ee4449d89abd74876ef664a"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to include in a miscellaneous tariff bill those duty suspensions and reductions that meet the requirements of this Act.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idd7a5c854f1ff44c28a8529e80c916a3b"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Requirements of Commission</header>
 <paragraph id="id680dbbb9448141ebb74e18cb0736fcec"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initiation</header><text>Not later than October 15, 2015, and October 15, 2018, the Commission shall publish in the Federal Register and on a publicly available Internet website of the Commission a notice requesting members of the public to submit to the Commission during the 60-day period beginning on the date of such publication—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id75d8949e386c41f3a6dc44488953029c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>proposed duty suspensions and reductions; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id001b4351541d4b4db9386b982ad8a1d2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Commission disclosure forms with respect to such duty suspensions and reductions.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9c67d7153e7844c1a029801dcfa2c5e8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Review</header>
 <subparagraph id="idaab90e82846c4e39997f7dd5460838e4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Commission submission to Congress</header><text>As soon as practicable after the expiration of the 60-day period specified in paragraph (1), but not later than 15 days after the expiration of such 60-day period, the Commission shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees the proposed duty suspensions and reductions submitted under paragraph (1)(A) and the Commission disclosure forms with respect to such duty suspensions and reductions submitted under paragraph (1)(B).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9f34ee0dbd0945cca1271b0d5967e4a8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Public availability of proposed duty suspensions and reductions</header><text>Not later than 15 days after the expiration of the 60-day period specified in paragraph (1), the Commission shall publish on a publicly available Internet website of the Commission the proposed duty suspensions and reductions submitted under paragraph (1)(A) and the Commission disclosure forms with respect to such duty suspensions and reductions submitted under paragraph (1)(B).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id57228fc99d2b488da3fa992aa91225d3"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Commission reports to Congress</header><text>Not later than the end of the 90-day period beginning on the date of publication of the proposed duty suspensions and reductions under subparagraph (B), the Commission shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on each proposed duty suspension or reduction submitted pursuant to subsection (b)(1) or paragraph (1)(A) that contains the following information:</text>
 <clause id="id497689D24CF141FD86E19C03BAA01954"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A determination of whether or not domestic production of the article that is the subject of the proposed duty suspension or reduction exists and, if such production exists, whether or not a domestic producer of the article objects to the proposed duty suspension or reduction.</text>
 </clause><clause id="id82f62e54751648289614a3326e29202e"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Any technical changes to the article description that are necessary for purposes of administration when articles are presented for importation.</text>
 </clause><clause id="id859ec67d5be44b26af5640a73c82c959"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The amount of tariff revenue that would no longer be collected if the proposed duty suspension or reduction takes effect.</text>
 </clause><clause id="idbc50ce639548465abd39b3a401e9932e"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>A determination of whether or not the proposed duty suspension or reduction is available to any person that imports the article that is the subject of the proposed duty suspension or reduction.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id11f319e64f5b4c53bb2a5d18f8b0399a"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Procedures</header><text>The Commission shall prescribe and publish on a publicly available Internet website of the Commission procedures for complying with the requirements of this subsection.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idb996c05241aa4d5eb9c53ae207b1f5fc"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Authorities described</header><text>The Commission shall carry out this subsection pursuant to its authorities under section 332 of the Tariff Act of 1930 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1332">19 U.S.C. 1332</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idab4330dc576846a29b468ccaeb682172"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Department of Commerce report</header><text>Not later than the end of the 90-day period beginning on the date of publication of the proposed duty suspensions and reductions under subsection (c)(2)(B), the Secretary of Commerce, in consultation with U.S. Customs and Border Protection and other relevant Federal agencies, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on each proposed duty suspension and reduction submitted pursuant to subsection (b)(1) or (c)(1)(A) that includes the following information:</text>
 <paragraph id="idff6238f53d734eccbc9cf83d71ff2bef"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A determination of whether or not domestic production of the article that is the subject of the proposed duty suspension or reduction exists and, if such production exists, whether or not a domestic producer of the article objects to the proposed duty suspension or reduction.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id140a6de6932749dcbaa27f16d3ddb5f4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Any technical changes to the article description that are necessary for purposes of administration when articles are presented for importation.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="idfeb926c415eb4beeb18e25f927e83961"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>A proposed duty suspension or reduction submitted under this section by a Member of Congress shall receive treatment no more favorable than the treatment received by a proposed duty suspension or reduction submitted under this section by a member of the public.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="id62b4cfb01d0946afb66f5db7191ea631"><enum>4.</enum><header>Report on effects of duty suspensions and reductions on United States economy</header>
 <subsection id="idFB49F01B81F84A6387D646A293428904"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than May 1, 2018, and May 1, 2020, the Commission shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the effects on the United States economy of temporary duty suspensions and reductions enacted pursuant to this Act, including a broad assessment of the economic effects of such duty suspensions and reductions on producers, purchasers, and consumers in the United States, using case studies describing such effects on selected industries or by type of article as available data permit.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idB6A75236046D4B7C919F388199B8CD94"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Recommendations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall also solicit and append to the report required under subsection (a) recommendations with respect to those domestic industry sectors or specific domestic industries that might benefit from permanent duty suspensions and reductions or elimination of duties, either through a unilateral action of the United States or though negotiations for reciprocal tariff agreements, with a particular focus on inequities created by tariff inversions.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idE09BA857036849AEA7301E9FAA635E94"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Form of report</header><text>Each report required by this section shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="id2E44C73124764A6C9EDC271D254642D7"><enum>5.</enum><header>Judicial review precluded</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The exercise of functions under this Act shall not be subject to judicial review.</text> </section><section id="id4D7CF6E7670F482298FF3EC242316DBC"><enum>6.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
 <paragraph id="id78FB97CBE18B4E74BE1B6DC17F70DD52"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idD70ACD0A39724AE28D53C275C1D60405"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Commission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Commission</term> means the United States International Trade Commission.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idab97bbb7672442a1ab95ceb1e2bb4798"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Commission disclosure form</header><text>The term <term>Commission disclosure form</term> means, with respect to a proposed duty suspension or reduction, a document submitted by a member of the public to the Commission that contains the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="id91af21814b6340e7ba0a82af51276026"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The contact information for any known importers of the article to which the proposed duty suspension or reduction would apply.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id28330d8fe25242a4b92861c77621be38"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A certification by the member of the public that the proposed duty suspension or reduction is available to any person importing the article to which the proposed duty suspension or reduction would apply.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9f3d135525694c728bdf47467f3f3d88"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Domestic producer</header><text>The term <term>domestic producer</term> means a person that demonstrates production, or imminent production, in the United States of an article that is identical to, or like or directly competitive with, an article to which a proposed duty suspension or reduction would apply.</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="id74e63578129e4d95957780623d3e9b13"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Duty suspension or reduction</header>
 <subparagraph id="id8BBE14F2A5C74575A0EF2F64C2BEF729"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>duty suspension or reduction</term> means an amendment to subchapter II of chapter 99 of the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States that—</text>
 <clause id="id7C1AE7B414EF431CAEBD3D2A765CB4BE"><enum>(i)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idAB15C374ED244D59A36D7AABBF6EFE9E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>extends an existing temporary duty suspension or reduction of duty on an article under that subchapter; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id0FF37D5208B24C959BB87DA5396E5BDB" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>provides for a new temporary duty suspension or reduction of duty on an article under that subchapter; and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="id64a94ff3c5cd42f7b3a559b61d150c47"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>otherwise meets the requirements described in subparagraph (B).</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcb0d3875010246aebe0b41133fccb507"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>A duty suspension or reduction meets the requirements described in this subparagraph if—</text>
 <clause id="idb0171079663d452cb4619f5757304af3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the duty suspension or reduction can be administered by U.S. Customs and Border Protection;</text> </clause><clause id="id3873b9e559b14c59ac0b0d649a41087c"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the estimated loss in revenue to the United States from the duty suspension or reduction does not exceed $500,000 in a calendar year during which the duty suspension or reduction would be in effect, as determined by the Congressional Budget Office; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id40d58ce58ad64113a34029f1ccf2960b"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the duty suspension or reduction is available to any person importing the article that is the subject of the duty suspension or reduction.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id2eff22b705804210a192d32bc4e6fb08"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Member of Congress</header><text>The term <term>Member of Congress</term> means a Senator or a Representative in, or Delegate or Resident Commissioner to, Congress.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id2c88add202824445b56d1ac97e86e489"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Miscellaneous tariff bill</header><text>The term <term>miscellaneous tariff bill</term> means a bill of either House of Congress that contains only—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="id54c61eaba59c4d3cb9e4e59af458729b"><enum>(A)</enum><text>duty suspensions and reductions that—</text> <clause commented="no" id="id7005d6f30cce425b8453c29db17aea26"><enum>(i)</enum><text>meet the applicable requirements for—</text>
 <subclause commented="no" id="id57325ba617db495fbebe22574656060c"><enum>(I)</enum><text>consideration of duty suspensions and reductions described in section 3; or</text> </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="id3605471423954685966fd4650875670d"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any other process required under the Rules of the House of Representatives or the Senate; and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause commented="no" id="id85b305927942438b9b0c4cd138a4dd1b"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>are not the subject of an objection because such duty suspensions and reductions do not comply with the requirements of this Act from—</text>
 <subclause commented="no" id="idc124e065b3be4e50bd26d01509367ca1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a Member of Congress; or</text> </subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id80576417503d4f85ac87411df91f214c"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a domestic producer, as contained in comments submitted to the appropriate congressional committees, the Commission, or the Department of Commerce under section 3; and</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id667e7654140e4fdd91b836317291e57c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provisions included in bills introduced in the House of Representatives or the Senate pursuant to a process described in subparagraph (A)(i)(II) that correct an error in the text or administration of a provision of the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States.</text>
				</subparagraph></paragraph></section></legis-body>
</bill>


