<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1972 IS: Airline Access to Emergency Epinephrine Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-08-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 1972</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150805">August 5, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S339">Mr. Kirk</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To require air carriers to modify certain policies with respect to the use of epinephrine for
			 in-flight emergencies, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Airline Access to Emergency Epinephrine Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="id5D87F959E66B4C118F719551E8C9D6DE"><enum>2.</enum><header>Regulations relating to epinephrine on aircraft</header>
 <subsection id="idEE869280C6D249098568D73DBD78B542"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Clarification relating to use of epinephrine ampules</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall clarify, and shall require air carriers to clarify, that 1:1,000 epinephrine ampules included in emergency medical kits carried on aircraft before such date of enactment are intended to be used for the treatment of anaphylaxis.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id5641EA5CA1FE455FA2828297E413231D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirement for air carriers To carry epinephrine auto-Injectors on aircraft</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall require an air carrier—</text>
 <paragraph id="id1C8D71041ED648C0981D22177365F70B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to carry on each aircraft operated by the air carrier not fewer than 2 packs of epinephrine auto-injectors, one pack for use on individuals weighing less than 66 pounds and one pack for use on individuals weighing more than 66 pounds;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idA851CFF9D04845A6BCFEBC27364BA331"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to use those epinephrine auto-injectors as the initial treatment for anaphylaxis; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idD892F1095A074C52A34FA08DBD8F8951"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to replace those epinephrine auto-injectors upon expiration or use.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1A6F080746D34FB8BC59B13FE217CB45"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Training required</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall require air carriers to provide crewmembers with initial and recurrent training, developed based on the advice of experts, on how to recognize the symptoms of an acute allergic reaction and how to administer auto-injectable epinephrine.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="idC052F0C670FF4F079244FE1F0FA9F364"><enum>3.</enum><header>Report on air carrier policies relating to passengers with food allergies</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report describing—</text>
 <paragraph id="id12bda7385cb84a9d9ca68c832f55568a"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the policies of air carriers in effect as of the date of the report with respect to the accommodation of passengers with food allergies, including policies relating to communication with passengers, seating accommodations, food service, and emergency procedures;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id321a3550d9124236b61753c244240937"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the extent of variability of such policies within and among air carriers;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id555be8077525479ba312bed30a585fc4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the extent to which passengers can determine what the policies of an air carrier with respect to the accommodation of passengers with food allergies are before making a flight reservation on an aircraft operated by the air carrier;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idf3ac0cb080d343f2b6705d9f4cab4dc1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the extent to which employees of air carriers are trained on, aware of, consistently adhere to, and enforce such policies;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id903f97b492b04693aeff3b328a8e7469"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the efforts that would be necessary to develop a model policy with respect to the accommodation of passengers with food allergies that could be made available to and adopted by all air carriers;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id2f5ccf9060e545a981591e62b8ce3c44"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the incidence of requests made by passengers with food allergies for accommodation by air carriers;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id3399d4c13e6040f297337f629e5e2012"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the incidence of in-flight allergic reactions for which medical intervention is requested and the prevalence of the use of epinephrine for such incidents;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id7e034c135bb040b4b97690332ca95ff4"><enum>(8)</enum><text>the incidence of emergency landings made because of suspected or known allergic reactions in flight; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id4aaceda7aed6428e926d9847f793f564"><enum>(9)</enum><text>the approximate cost of such emergency landings to air carriers.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="id3F0E3749B0464163AA8597F67A87DE86"><enum>4.</enum><header>Air carrier defined</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <term>air carrier</term> means an air carrier or foreign air carrier, as those terms are defined in section 40102 of title 49, United States Code.</text>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


