<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1312 IS: Energy Supply and Distribution Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 1312</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150512">May 12, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S288">Ms. Murkowski</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S360">Ms. Heitkamp</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S344">Mr. Hoeven</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S317">Mr. Barrasso</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S197">Mr. McCain</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S310">Mr. Corker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S289">Mr. Alexander</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S323">Mr. Risch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S358">Mr. Flake</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S372">Mrs. Capito</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S236">Mr. Inhofe</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S350">Mr. Rubio</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S378">Mr. Lankford</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To modernize Federal policies regarding the supply and distribution of energy in the United States,
			 and for other purposes.  </official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Energy Supply and Distribution Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </section><section id="id8620F9111FD64D758BD7768ADCBD47FB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purposes of this Act are—</text> <paragraph id="id336547fd4ed44d099466ee59c79d74e7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to adopt certain recommendations of the Quadrennial Energy Review of 2015;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idb4390f57c8aa41d1bf646fe6aa437dfc"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to enhance the integration of energy markets;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id8cc59d15b6614ff990c9b0b26c88cb2b"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to improve the collection of energy data and analysis; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idbaf422cd1646451aa1765b85008577e7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to promote the production and distribution of energy in the United States.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="idC8CD90480FCF414294CD2C2FEAFB1593"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
 <subsection id="idA78DAC602ACF4806BB3DDB65D2E22BDB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Energy Information Administration.</text> </subsection><subsection id="id37904F2ECDAF4543A178928C11AAF528"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Energy.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="id6575011e9eba4ea180985498503ff50b"><enum>4.</enum><header>Sense of Congress relating to domestic energy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that the production and distribution of energy in the United States requires access to infrastructure and markets.</text>
		</section><section id="idd4c19023c9ae493fa0e89b345f6eb05c"><enum>5.</enum><header>Energy security</header>
 <subsection id="iddbff9894ce4049c683afc0813ab6aa8e"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary—</text> <paragraph id="id5020ce1c6c9949e0987529cd5c0fc0d2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall collaborate with the heads of other Federal agencies to improve the conceptual development of energy security; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idea0970a85195465686400d9924f0180f"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may consult with allies and key trading partners of the United States with respect to energy security issues resulting from changes in the energy marketplace.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id079684188382473a90ae9af26bac3e8e"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>At a minimum, the Secretary shall ensure that, as part of the collaboration required under subsection (a)(1), the following are considered:</text>
 <paragraph id="idfab54bd690ed4c369b8123f0f97405d4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The development of flexible, transparent, and competitive energy markets, including natural gas and oil markets</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id2e27d3b37c0b4c3e818d734f6ce3a032"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The diversification of energy fuels, sources, and routes.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id1efc9fca44344aa68a271cc9802070d3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The encouragement of indigenous sources of energy supply.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id67e15fa69f3d435eb5d69a0493d48a1d"><enum>6.</enum><header>Shared infrastructure</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary shall lead an interagency effort to improve and coordinate data collection and analytical and modeling capabilities for energy distribution on shared energy infrastructure.</text>
 </section><section id="id121f4b4bf55d49a7a661bc0420677709"><enum>7.</enum><header>Energy market integration</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary shall coordinate the training of, and enhanced dialogue among, technical staff in applicable Federal agencies that are responsible for evaluating and implementing cross-border energy projects.</text>
 </section><section id="id98E8D4520082447D95B5611066492392"><enum>8.</enum><header>Sense of Congress relating to hydrocarbon production</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that, as stated in the Annual Energy Outlook of 2015 of the Energy Information Administration, growth in crude oil and dry natural gas production varies significantly across oil and natural gas supply regions—</text>
 <paragraph id="id3E7F12D97CD24F5CB2A335B8C53004FB"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">forcing shifts in crude oil and natural gas flows between regions of the United States; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id6E54B0DEBDC6435E938F6FC6E24A08CD"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">requiring investment in or realignment of pipelines and other midstream infrastructure.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="id36620e29d9ef43e8b37384609bf46985"><enum>9.</enum><header>Energy data collaboration</header>
 <subsection id="id26606d9350ed4b0db948f6e0a01b6fdd"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator shall collaborate with the appropriate officials in Canada and Mexico, as determined by the Administrator, to improve—</text>
 <paragraph id="id15bf03f9436d46c2ad8efdf9aecea5a9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the quality and transparency of North American energy data through reconciliation of data on energy trade flows among the United States, Canada, and Mexico;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ida5fb9b3ca57b4e3493d15e7b240065a5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the extension of energy mapping capabilities in the United States, Canada, and Mexico; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="ide5cba94e9fe04c69afa6b31b5e07f1ba"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the development of common energy data terminology among the United States, Canada, and Mexico.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0f0cc797cf56453da8743fb1c96f4529"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Periodic updates</header><text>The Administrator shall periodically inform the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives regarding—</text>
 <paragraph id="id19d3965ec0ec43a6906e3cda9c8175ba"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the extent to which energy data is being shared under subsection (a); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idecc43e3f58864e80a3415d9be5b37f05"><enum>(2)</enum><text>whether forward-looking projections for regional energy flows are improving in accuracy as a result of the energy data sharing under that subsection.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id594f9e55d99940ed9efc801f0ef9182e"><enum>10.</enum><header>Sense of Congress relating to processed condensate</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that processed condensate is a petroleum product.</text> </section><section id="idbaf3d1e6744a409fa24b7a95ad02283b"><enum>11.</enum><header>Development of definition of condensate</header> <subsection id="idbc65e19922a9455f9e001b59cb928899"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="id05ef5ec508cd409aa8733e970d16f638"><enum>(1)</enum><text>develop a standard definition of the term <term>condensate</term>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="ide5bed0623c174f119c87a43c10455e05"><enum>(2)</enum><text>advise relevant Federal agencies to adopt that definition for the purpose of clarifying energy policy in the United States.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idf338c9dc0dd946a9bf3b7f1daa2d48ca"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Office of fossil energy assessment</header><text>The Assistant Secretary for Fossil Energy may assess the suitability of condensate separately from crude oil for use in strategic reserves, as determined necessary by the Secretary.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id60749edeff8d416286a2fa3e4d4a1c39"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Energy information administration data collection</header><text>The Administrator may collect data regarding condensate and crude oil production in the United States.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="idf037d21f17ab4fd9be1fd1f1d5cfff0b"><enum>12.</enum><header>Department of interior assessments</header>
 <subsection id="id344666f8b1d440f28d04ca7bc55c89f9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of the Interior shall direct the appropriate agencies within the Department of the Interior to assess condensate separately from crude oil, in accordance with this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id560acf528b8c4578b9738b7772574e9c"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Office of natural resources revenue</header><text>The Director of the Office of Natural Resources Revenue may collect data regarding condensate separately from crude oil produced in the United States.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id6b8f921988094d8c8f06d58700802191"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Bureau of ocean energy management</header><text>The Director of the Bureau of Ocean Energy Management may estimate condensate separately from crude oil as part of the resource assessments regarding geological formations in the United States.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id7d4a9c09f13e4a039419c752644c4de3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>United states geological survey</header><text>The Director of the United States Geological Survey may include estimates of condensate separately from crude oil as part of the resource assessments regarding geological formations in the United States.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="idf4f08b50ce754427af38ecceb01a6495"><enum>13.</enum><header>Access to markets</header>
 <subsection id="id01039d2161894e0f866d9d2c6bab3ef8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, to promote the efficient exploration, production, storage, supply, and distribution of energy resources, any domestic crude oil or condensate (other than crude oil stored in the Strategic Petroleum Reserve) may be exported without a Federal license to countries not subject to sanctions by the United States.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id8072861e0d2d442480768ab8c4e230bf"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Savings clause</header><text>Nothing in this section limits the authority of the President under the Constitution, the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>), the National Emergencies Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1601">50 U.S.C. 1601 et seq.</external-xref>), or part B of title II of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6271">42 U.S.C. 6271 et seq.</external-xref>) to prohibit exports.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


