<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S798 IS: Policyholder Protection Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 798</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150319">March 19, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S299">Mr. Vitter</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S314">Mr. Tester</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To provide for notice to, and input by, State insurance commissioners when requiring an insurance
			 company to serve as a source of financial strength or when the Federal
			 Deposit Insurance Corporation places a lien against an insurance company’s
			 assets, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HCD976EA7177749418993965D997CCD00" style="OLC">
 <section id="id21A7DE5FADE14800AF509ACC95EE8E92" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Policyholder Protection Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H9025D8113FBE4CAC95BECD08F1BDFB3A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Source of strength</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 38A of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1831o-1">12 U.S.C. 1831o–1</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H644B83D7266F4B3CBDB78156CB3E48D3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (c), (d), and (e) as subsections (d), (e), and (f), respectively; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE7D73F1DBB0A44B2BADD0026FCAF207C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (b) the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB8131C06F18C4F31B399A3436E7D150C" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="H9A528CE7234148609CD367EDF4D4D16C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authority of State Insurance Regulator</header>
 <paragraph id="H0B860354A9604FDC8F6A2116379E51C1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The provisions of section 5(g) of the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1844">12 U.S.C. 1844(g)</external-xref>) shall apply to a savings and loan holding company that is an insurance company, an affiliate of an insured depository institution that is an insurance company, and to any other company that is an insurance company and that directly or indirectly controls an insured depository institution, to the same extent as such section 5(g) applies to a bank holding company that is an insurance company.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE5FEDF7E20DA41629333097924DA5DAB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Requiring a bank holding company that is an insurance company, a savings and loan holding company that is an insurance company, an affiliate of an insured depository institution that is an insurance company, or any other company that is an insurance company and that directly or indirectly controls an insured depository institution to serve as a source of financial strength under this section shall be deemed an <quote>action of the Board that requires a bank holding company to provide funds or other assets to a subsidiary depository institution</quote> for purposes of such section 5(g).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H776A3FB32F30465F9180D12630A85BDF"><enum>3.</enum><header>Liquidation authority</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5301">12 U.S.C. 5301 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HDA54D278184A4BB0AFFD1CDEE25222F4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 203(e)(3), by inserting <quote>or rehabilitation</quote> after <quote>orderly liquidation</quote> each place such term appears; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7CB8C688128E4E569C4042E14DE1D66B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 204(d)(4), by inserting before the semicolon the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H872462A4B3954C299AABC0BD6C1CBD03" style="OLC"> <text>, except that, if the covered financial company or covered subsidiary is an insurance company or a subsidiary of an insurance company, the Corporation—</text><subparagraph id="H88203FCBA3D742AABF89603683C1EAD9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall promptly notify the State insurance authority for the insurance company of the intention to take such lien; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDC56498490804CACBB192EB2347979A3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may not take such lien if the State insurance authority notified under subparagraph (A) informs the Corporation, in writing, within 15 days of such notice, that the taking of the lien on the assets of such company would have a materially adverse effect on the policyholders of such company</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


