<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1289 IS: Defense Acquisition Contractor Workforce Improvement Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 1289</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150512">May 12, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S381">Mr. Rounds</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend title 10, United States Code, to provide for the inclusion of certain contractor personnel
			 in matters on the defense acquisition workforce in the
			 annual strategic workforce plan of the Department of Defense.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Defense Acquisition Contractor Workforce Improvement Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="id59956FC62B1845639602874B9F4499DE"><enum>2.</enum><header>Inclusion of certain contractor personnel in matters on the defense acquisition workforce in the
			 annual strategic workforce plan of the Department of Defense</header>
 <subsection id="id5F81A16AEBD5454C9C351E57125B39D8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Inclusion of certain contractor personnel</header><text>Section 115b(d)(1) of title 10, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>including both military and civilian personnel.</quote> and inserting <quote>including military, civilian, and contractor personnel that directly support the acquisition processes of the Department of Defense. For purposes of this subsection, contractor personnel shall be treated as directly supporting the acquisition processes of the Department if, and to the extent that, such contractor personnel perform functions that, if performed by civilian personnel, would be make such civilian personnel a part of the defense acquisition workforce.</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id8E09E16C412545C7850D6F7BA31DD67D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (a) shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act, and shall apply with respect to annual strategic workforce plans of the Department of Defense submitted to Congress after that date.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


