<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S285 IS: Aurora Veterans Affairs Hospital Financing and Construction Reform Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 285</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150128">January 28, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S377">Mr. Gardner</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSVA00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To authorize the construction of a replacement medical center of the Department of Veterans Affairs
			 in Aurora, Colorado, and to direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to
			 enter into an agreement with the Chief of Engineers to act as the
			 construction agent with respect to such construction, and for other
 purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0036A64B9DE04B8CB8E80A36547F3F87" style="OLC"><section id="H15B07BB8FF46488594CBB14AEC29B39D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Aurora Veterans Affairs Hospital Financing and Construction Reform Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id137AE5A5C68543EFBD758B91855E711C" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Authorization of major medical facility project to replace Department of Veterans Affairs medical center in Aurora, Colorado</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs may carry out a major medical facility project to replace the medical center of the Department of Veterans Affairs in Aurora, Colorado, in an amount not to exceed $1,100,000,000.</text></section><section id="H95AA45BB757A4BC78999EC1F0BE73B06"><enum>3.</enum><header>Construction agent for	construction of Department of Veterans Affairs Medical Center in
 Aurora, Colorado</header><subsection id="HFF50369581E4450BB509020FD266CA04"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Agreement for construction agent authority</header><paragraph id="idF228E445694C4869B4CCB9CC824A908E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall enter into an agreement with the Chief of Engineers to procure the services of the Chief of Engineers as the construction agent with respect to carrying out the Aurora medical facility project until the date on which the project is completed.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idE30A46436C2540CFB4CE969B142BAFCF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reimbursement</header><text>The Secretary shall reimburse the Chief of Engineers for services procured under paragraph (1) in accordance with section 1535 of title 31, United States Code (commonly referred to as the <quote>Economy Act</quote>), except that amounts required to carry out the Aurora medical facility project shall be obligated by the Secretary at the time a reimbursable order is accepted by the Chief of Engineers.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H92A4F01E88264D83B55B6EEF6B2806B9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><paragraph id="id36496C4DEEE94B81BF235FE7C9A05A36"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Pursuant to the agreement entered into under subsection (a), the Chief of Engineers shall, as the construction agent with respect to the Aurora medical facility project, be given the authority to perform the project, design, contract, and construction management necessary to complete such project.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6A576A541B394BE0A412E5D98127C127"><enum>(2)</enum><header>New contracts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The authority under paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text><subparagraph id="idB5559D559DDB43A0965AF0142F99358F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The authority to enter into new contracts in compliance with the Federal Acquisition Regulation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF828EF4E02E4433CB05C803A8702A2C3"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The authority to determine whether entering into a new contract with the prime contractor of the Aurora medical facility project as of the day before the date of the enactment of this Act is consistent with the Federal Acquisition Regulation and in the best interests of the Federal Government.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0B00622560614D11B80BB3891C049785"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Plans and reports</header><paragraph id="HF82C8F579EB34F4081540F7F6338A7B4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Completion plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after entering into the agreement under subsection (a), the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall, in consultation with the Chief of Engineers, submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a detailed plan, including estimated costs, to complete the construction of the Aurora medical facility project.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB90EA8A1F22D4E20A5CBE0F27EF72E26"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Progress reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after entering into the agreement under subsection (a), and not less frequently than once during each 180-day period thereafter until the date on which the Aurora medical facility project is completed, the Secretary shall, in consultation with the Chief of Engineers, submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a report detailing the progress of the Aurora medical facility project.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H67FA6C3D584F4575812A89E1116ACDB2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Cooperation</header><paragraph id="H7FC51472BC3F486DB6DA498723F71443"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall provide to the Chief of Engineers any documents or information that the Chief of Engineers considers necessary to carry out this section, including information relating to the successful operation of a medical facility.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1DA6BCD19DF64CB6A13E8E5A70F4C283"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon request by the Chief of Engineers, the Secretary shall provide to the Chief of Engineers, at no cost to the Chief of Engineers, any assistance that the Chief of Engineers considers necessary to carry out this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6D7B256392E3405E813C3272A6293D95"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Aurora medical facility project defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>Aurora medical facility project</term> means the major medical facility project planned for under section 213(1) of the Veterans Health Care, Capital Asset, and Business Improvement Act of 2003 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/108/170">Public Law 108–170</external-xref>; 117 Stat. 2049) and authorized by section 2 to replace the medical center of the Department of Veterans Affairs in Aurora, Colorado.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


