<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1886 IS: Coordinated Ocean Monitoring and Research Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 1886</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150729">July 29, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S318">Mr. Wicker</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S275">Ms. Cantwell</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To reauthorize the Integrated Coastal and Ocean Observation System Act of 2009 and for other
			 purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Coordinated Ocean Monitoring and Research Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </section><section id="id0C89F655F9404697A749B01C75159F91"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 12302 of the Integrated Coastal and Ocean Observation System Act of 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/3601">33 U.S.C. 3601</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id13E4804F3E894E43AB1B4824C975E90A" style="OLC">
 <section id="id167401FD2B634D80BDC2B04636E27473"><enum>12302.</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purposes of this subtitle are—</text> <paragraph id="idf9c3093d7b7f41e18ad35fde8c8be913"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to establish and sustain a national integrated System of ocean, coastal, and Great Lakes observing systems, comprised of Federal and non-Federal components coordinated at the national level by the Council and at the regional level by a network of Regional Coastal Observing Systems, and that includes in situ, remote, and other coastal and ocean observation and modeling capabilities, technologies, data management systems, communication systems, and product development systems, and is designed to address regional and national needs for ocean and coastal information, to gather specific data on key coastal, ocean, and Great Lakes variables, and to ensure timely and sustained dissemination and availability of these data—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idFEF0537C57B249ED9904F3671E175A5F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to the public;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7da19198ffd34a45ad0669f26a37826a"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to support national defense, search and rescue operations, marine commerce, navigation safety, weather, climate, and marine forecasting, energy siting and production, economic development, ecosystem-based marine, coastal, and Great Lakes resource management, public safety, and public outreach and education;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5d100a685b114040997556cde8c5560f"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to promote greater public awareness and stewardship of the Nation’s ocean, coastal, and Great Lakes resources and the general public welfare;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc37b4ed1142048a8826045d35291d04b"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to provide easy access to ocean, coastal, and Great Lakes data and promote data sharing between Federal and non-Federal sources and promote public data sharing;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3d84981377654a5b8f8ef9f68dd1197a"><enum>(E)</enum><text>to enable advances in scientific understanding to support the sustainable use, conservation, management, and understanding of healthy ocean, coastal, and Great Lakes resources; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1f19f23548ed433c80666d1a678e9ac6"><enum>(F)</enum><text>to monitor and model changes in ocean chemistry;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id2e95f7fd1312464093a9acedb58f9c71"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to improve the Nation’s capability to measure, track, observe, understand, and predict events related directly and indirectly to weather and climate change, natural climate variability, and interactions between the oceanic and atmospheric environments, including the Great Lakes; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idc376b9651fb94931ace31f7f9416a655"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to authorize activities—</text> <subparagraph id="id721d57882e2e40968713234b6d00db96"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to promote basic and applied research to develop, test, and deploy innovations and improvements in coastal and ocean observation technologies, including advanced observing technologies needed to address critical data gaps, modeling systems, other scientific and technological capabilities to improve the understanding of weather and climate, ocean-atmosphere dynamics, global climate change, and the physical, chemical, and biological dynamics of the ocean, coastal and Great Lakes environments; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id04888D7195DF4B2DA489ABC4668A87C4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to conserve healthy and restore degraded coastal ecosystems.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </section><section id="id73254EAC4ECD41A8AECEA99ECF4460FA"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 12303 of the Integrated Coastal and Ocean Observation System Act of 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/3602">33 U.S.C. 3602</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="id8E20B7F47F71473D81D0E4A62AC7FE43"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (5), by striking <quote>States, regional organizations, universities, nongovernmental organizations, or the private sector.</quote> and inserting <quote>the regional coastal observing systems, the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, or the Interagency Ocean Observation Committee.</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idE68AF144033742F087684CA8930F783C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by amending paragraph (6) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idC4EB6B8063864EBDA88E33978F7FF1C0" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="id9EF88238F25E4732A2CF8CB0693DD37B"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Regional Coastal Observing System</header><text>The term <quote>regional coastal observing system</quote> means an organizational body that is certified or established by contract or memorandum by the lead Federal agency designated in section 12304(c)(3) and coordinates State, Federal, local, tribal, and private interests at a regional level with the responsibility of engaging the private and public sectors in designing, operating, and improving regional coastal and ocean observing systems in order to ensure the provision of data and information that meet the needs of user groups from the respective regions.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id773F23704D4E4235809F926E9E0AC106"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (7), by striking <quote>National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</quote> and inserting <quote>Administrator.</quote>.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="idFAFBD52AD8B54D4180853091AEE5F36B"><enum>4.</enum><header>Integrated Coastal and Ocean Observation System</header> <subsection id="id0FBD44944EA84D3EB8DDC656ACEF0EED"><enum>(a)</enum><header>System elements</header> <paragraph id="id9814D58D3A0E4EF49A0CA57E7F4CE0D0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 12304(b) of the Integrated Coastal and Ocean Observation System Act of 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/3603">33 U.S.C. 3603(b)</external-xref>) is amended by striking paragraph (1) and inserting the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idD4E9A9C8D65A4EBF90290F2B6E6E726B" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="idB81682271A944B02924FC2309798E886"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In order to fulfill the purposes of this subtitle, the System shall be national in scope and consist of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id4879306DB36445DC8F7107F2BE40C0C0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Federal assets to fulfill national and international observation missions and priorities;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD515CA45DD224E878588D47E3E080C6C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>non-Federal assets, including a network of regional coastal observing systems identified under subsection (c)(4), to fulfill regional and national observation missions and priorities;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4EE5A2FC75BC4C4393F23E67F1238AB7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>data management, communication, and modeling systems for the timely integration and dissemination of data and information products from the System;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE04A18E432FE4B1FA5AB19B730487439"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a product development system to transform observations into products in a format that may be readily used and understood; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4C8B14226534479D84D4B0EFFF447253"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a research and development program conducted under the guidance of the Council, consisting of—</text> <clause id="id9ABE524F701643BFA873DDF48FCAACF7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>basic and applied research and technology development—</text>
 <subclause id="id8D0A157C792048A18D0DD2909E82FB28"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to improve understanding of coastal and ocean systems and their relationships to human activities; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idE401433FB6864C6381F5CA0A20D99152"><enum>(II)</enum><text>to ensure improvement of operational assets and products, including related infrastructure, observing technologies, and information and data processing and management technologies;</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="id74450CFA870E478088D119AD27F388D3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an advanced observing technology development program to fill gaps in technology;</text> </clause><clause id="idA9C0524FABA044F380390FE3DDBECCEA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>large scale computing resources and research to advance modeling of coastal and ocean processes;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idDE5E4CFC094B4BF4BD8CBF772E86AB9E"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>models to improve regional weather forecasting capabilities and regional weather forecasting products; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id80BCA26C36474E0E8F6E1179BA8D5592"><enum>(v)</enum><text>reviews of data collection procedures across regions and programs to make recommendations for data collection standards across the System to meet national ocean observation, applied research, and weather forecasting needs.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id26F6A282F6F443D6ADB0D446D1389580"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Availability of data</header><text>Paragraph (3) of section 12304(b) of the Integrated Coastal and Ocean Observation System Act of 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/3603">33 U.S.C. 3603(b)</external-xref>) is amended by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>for research and for use in the development of products to address societal needs.</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idF1230730493849569EE675D33AA29E6F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Coordination of non-Federal assets</header><text>Paragraph (4) of section 12304(b) of the Integrated Coastal and Ocean Observation System Act of 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/3603">33 U.S.C. 3603(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id5436D68AB3F342459EC505A86D266483"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the paragraph heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">Non-Federal</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">Coordination of non-Federal</header-in-text></quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC7294D9DCAC74A92A524090D7D6BBC0D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, the regional coastal observing system,</quote> after <quote>Interagency Ocean Observing Committee</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idD6ED9E91D4214386A06F5EA4D13B5572"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Policy oversight, administration, and regional coordination</header><text>Section 12304(c) of the Integrated Coastal and Ocean Observation System Act of 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/3603">33 U.S.C. 3603(c)</external-xref>) is amended by striking paragraphs (2), (3), and (4), and inserting the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idDB372B453EFC4361946F281C4E6C5F27" style="OLC">
					<paragraph id="idb447d3a25e9d446fb3e947b6533cc58e"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Interagency Ocean Observation Committee</header>
 <subparagraph id="id580b84cc179a4dc7b6aba0ff76d578aa"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Council shall establish or designate a committee which shall be known as the Interagency Ocean Observation Committee.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6f43cd1ff8f84f2083775b468b91ff81"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Interagency Ocean Observation Committee shall—</text> <clause id="id43fd1b14a4114383a8982c75d1b73a6b"><enum>(i)</enum><text>prepare annual and long-term plans for consideration and approval by the Council for the integrated design, operation, maintenance, enhancement, and expansion of the System to meet the objectives of this chapter and the System Plan;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idfa2a994517b94a91b39f073ff36b54c8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>develop and transmit to Congress, along with the budget submitted by the President to Congress pursuant to section 1105(a) of title 31, United States Code, an annual coordinated, comprehensive budget—</text>
 <subclause id="ida1500b05b1194fc29fed47775449302b"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to operate all elements of the System identified in subsection (b); and</text> </subclause><subclause id="id952056d6489b44879dbc8140d4b8b7a6"><enum>(II)</enum><text>to ensure continuity of data streams from Federal and non-Federal assets;</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="id6e6175f3b62344f5be06b0606ff8d393"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>establish requirements for observation data variables to be gathered by both Federal and non-Federal assets and identify, in consultation with regional information coordination entities, priorities for System observations;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idd4e9e9e821614d8e85e692389be88ada"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>establish and define protocols and standards for System data processing, management, collection, configuration standards, formats, and communication for new and existing assets throughout the Integrated Ocean Observing System network;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idbdc3e439bd5344a481bbf4bbc7ac33b5"><enum>(v)</enum><text>develop contract requirements for each Regional Coastal Observing System—</text> <subclause id="id9a09f1144db14d2cac10614d57815088"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to establish eligibility for integration into the System;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id891ac040518c4eaea37f9c7fa3323d3d"><enum>(II)</enum><text>to ensure compliance with all applicable standards and protocols established by the Council; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="idfafa4384a8e149179ad10e703532508d"><enum>(III)</enum><text>to ensure that regional observations are integrated into the System on a sustained basis;</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="id8eef4f0d108b4d55bd30f35f1d0eb0de"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>identify gaps in observation coverage or needs for capital improvements of both Federal assets and non-Federal assets;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idf074d028660347bc98049ecccc2ce0e7"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>subject to the availability of appropriations, establish through one or more participating Federal agencies, in consultation with the System advisory committee established under subsection (d), a competitive matching grant or other programs—</text>
 <subclause id="id994e1f5b6d2f4fabbf9b9d4223b54e0d"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to promote intramural and extramural research and development of new, innovative, and emerging observation technologies including testing and field trials; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idac1ebea1f6144499a3d62efd528f964b"><enum>(II)</enum><text>to facilitate the migration of new, innovative, and emerging scientific and technological advances from research and development to operational deployment;</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="idfbb0e34354344979a0c777bd477a1b13"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>periodically—</text> <subclause id="id5a2a8354659f40f39147b2e0403a5ba6"><enum>(I)</enum><text>review the System Plan; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id8a34a0f820a749c0989fbc35f960bef3"><enum>(II)</enum><text>submit to the Council such recommendations as the Interagency Ocean Observation Committee may have for improvements to the System Plan;</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="idb78e632209704c0495f338c9429b8ffd"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>ensure collaboration among Federal agencies participating in the activities of the Interagency Ocean Observation Committee; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id0189021b3b744a2da8a7c5de16d274bc"><enum>(x)</enum><text>perform such additional duties as the Council may delegate.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ida2125f6b30e3495fb4f19dd46c1491ef"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Lead Federal agency</header> <subparagraph id="id73e021d5c5eb4f1d935cc0bff96f79fc"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration shall function as the lead Federal agency for the implementation and administration of the System.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id160368e5973a4c7f8214e7c199802e8f"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Consultation required</header><text>In carrying out this paragraph, the Administrator shall consult with the Council, the Interagency Ocean Observation Committee, other Federal agencies that maintain portions of the System, and the Regional Coastal Observing Systems.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id89e0008ce44d4c9d9cd2daff2f4a84c1"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>In carrying out this paragraph, the Administrator shall—</text> <clause id="idc82a61dbe8724f3dabc73cb9ac5715a7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>establish and operate an Integrated Ocean Observing System Program Office within the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration—</text>
 <subclause id="id9650e71b83dc49818e2fec33b830574c"><enum>(I)</enum><text>that utilizes, to the extent necessary, personnel from member agencies participating on the Interagency Ocean Observation Committee; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id5046026325714e59bc189b25b5233ef1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>oversees daily operations and coordination of the System;</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="id8f23468ae18b4d7c8673543f80cc6a76"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>implement policies, protocols, and standards approved by the Council and delegated by the Interagency Ocean Observation Committee;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id6138309e9ae64c6fb9afa4e8ccb0aadf"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>promulgate program guidelines—</text> <subclause id="ide7f3c52f52f140129df45ab5e2289aaf"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to certify and integrate regional associations into the System; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id8668b7ff37b74647afad77b457ff94cf"><enum>(II)</enum><text>to provide regional coastal and ocean observation data that meet the needs of user groups from the respective regions;</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="idb6a44d35f5704ff895a4a37346e46511"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>have the authority to enter into and oversee contracts, leases, grants or cooperative agreements with non-Federal assets, including regional information coordination entities, to support the purposes of this chapter on such terms as the Administrator deems appropriate;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id683eeabc82e14b00b4143a62c8f8ea89"><enum>(v)</enum><text>implement and maintain a merit-based, competitive funding process to support non-Federal assets, including the development and maintenance of a network of Regional Coastal Observing Systems, and develop and implement a process for the periodic review and evaluation of the regional associations;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idd48d796cb2dd4182b47b6d4ca0c9e78d"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>provide opportunities for competitive contracts and grants for demonstration projects to design, develop, integrate, deploy, maintain, and support components of the System;</text>
 </clause><clause id="ide98ee31d4e3e4aaf98bfc7adef928aa9"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>establish and maintain efficient and effective administrative procedures for allocation of funds among contractors, grantees, and non-Federal assets, including regional associations in a timely manner;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id82b060faa00e407a8428a5b801eae1aa"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>develop and implement a process for the periodic review and evaluation of the Regional Coastal Observing Systems;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id979bce0539294ebdad46d48f5965f8ee"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>formulate an annual process by which gaps in observation coverage or needs for capital improvements of Federal assets and non-Federal assets of the System are—</text>
 <subclause id="idc5f3001918d14a04b9222fd2e739164c"><enum>(I)</enum><text>identified by the regional associations described in the System Plan, the Administrator, or other members of the System; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id43181d246e014000a0fa6dd8160a15db"><enum>(II)</enum><text>submitted to the Interagency Ocean Observing Committee;</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="idafaccdda90a94280a576c4d393f00579"><enum>(x)</enum><text>develop and be responsible for a data management and communication system, in accordance with standards and protocols established by the Interagency Ocean Observing Committee, by which all data collected by the System regarding ocean and coastal waters of the United States including the Great Lakes, are processed, stored, integrated, and made available to all end-user communities;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id59d3bddc292c41568700d4265b4c5eb7"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>not less frequently than once each year, submit to the Interagency Ocean Observing Observation Committee a report on the accomplishments, operational needs, and performance of the System to contribute to the annual and long-term plans prepared pursuant to paragraph (2)(B)(i);</text>
 </clause><clause id="id94516be0bbe64d73913ce93f8c009e7a"><enum>(xii)</enum><text>develop and periodically update a plan to efficiently integrate into the System new, innovative, or emerging technologies that have been demonstrated to be useful to the System and which will fulfill the purposes of this chapter and the System Plan; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id72afa98e656a471297a5ed6543ae931b"><enum>(xiii)</enum><text>work with users and Regional Associations to develop products to enable real-time data sharing for decisionmakers, including with respect to weather forecasting and modeling, search and rescue operations, corrosive seawater forecasts, water quality monitoring and communication, and harmful algal bloom forecasting.</text>
							</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ida4c7e6bb26b54563b48028977819cd1b"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Regional Coastal Observing Systems</header>
 <subparagraph id="id292237dd1e3d469d98b4f1a9694204b1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A Regional Coastal Observing System operated by a Regional Association described in the System Plan may not be certified or established under this subtitle unless it—</text>
 <clause id="id88fd824d04b444bbb4da6d7c529d25db"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has been or shall be certified or established by contract or agreement by the Administrator;</text> </clause><clause id="idc477c3d692c045fba3a4441a15a1969d"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>meets—</text>
 <subclause id="id8bea608f968648f2a8d76ebd99ff927c"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the certification standards and compliance procedure guidelines issued by the Administrator; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="idbe3b7dfd84974faa8cd9eaf2941ca101"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the information needs of user groups in the region while adhering to national standards;</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="idc69ff1c54a3d46a9879962e611cdc994"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>demonstrates an organizational structure, that under funding limitations is capable of—</text> <subclause id="idd6439fe638ce4b66930ca6103545babb"><enum>(I)</enum><text>gathering required System observation data;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idfb4636d34ad746cc912e6dfc45be929b"><enum>(II)</enum><text>supporting and integrating all aspects of coastal and ocean observing and information programs within a region; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id863329825f7f437ead3d0098af753282"><enum>(III)</enum><text>reflecting the needs of State, local, and tribal governments, commercial interests, and other users and beneficiaries of the System and other requirements specified under this subtitle and the System Plan;</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="id9feae889a4d24f979d8c1b6042dd44b3"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>identifies—</text> <subclause id="id08737e11df17418aacac28cc3cbd6fe2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>gaps in observation coverage needs for capital improvements of Federal assets and non-Federal assets of the System; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id33c58232d25c44c6a00501ac72e5f734"><enum>(II)</enum><text>other recommendations to assist in the development of the annual and long-term plans prepared pursuant to paragraph (2)(B)(i) and transmit such information to the Interagency Ocean Observation Committee via the Program Office established under paragraph (3)(C)(i);</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="id7ba03bd39f084f41a839d29a4c0fdf1b"><enum>(v)</enum><text>develops and operates under a strategic operational plan that will ensure the efficient and effective administration of programs and assets to support daily data observations for integration into the System, pursuant to the standards approved by the Council;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id0d1a0e69652c4693bb3926a0a8c98650"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>works cooperatively with governmental and nongovernmental entities at all levels to identify and provide information products of the System for multiple users within the service area of the regional coastal observing system; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id85fbae3d73fc488e8b754f7d9263500c"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>complies with all financial oversight requirements established by the Administrator, including requirements relating to audits.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5223891541ae4d66a0e1bdecbc5af3fa"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Participation</header><text>For the purposes of this title, employees of Federal agencies are permitted to be members of the governing body for the Regional Coastal Observing Systems and may participate in the functions of the regional information coordination entities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="idB7FE96B09C874F09ABE55C01DEA1B3AD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>System advisory committee</header><text>Section 12304(d) of the Integrated Coastal and Ocean Observation System Act of 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/3603">33 U.S.C. 3603(d)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="id5FFF31039B67473B810E99105B58AD04"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>or the Interagency Ocean Observing Observation Committee.</quote> and inserting <quote>the Council under this subtitle</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id5E400115599E46EA8356ECBF3D354A91"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idF0BC3397694C4553BFA94C304354E1C2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by inserting <quote>data sharing,</quote> after <quote>data management</quote>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id21D49DB99DA14119ABCE8D25131EA0BA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8D3046F258E0498AA3B85717226CD7DA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (D) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id04010711EF214FBC9849050F0E76B8D2" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="id2B1BC8F8509F4EE4A2ADA413BA1F3700"><enum>(D)</enum><text>additional priorities, including—</text>
 <clause id="id9A4CC502C3F343DFBB4431D5A4708B5C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a national surface current mapping network designed to improve fine scale sea surface mapping using high frequency radar technology and other emerging technologies to address national priorities, including Coast Guard search and rescue operation planning and harmful algal bloom forecasting and detection that—</text>
 <subclause id="id6FDD1EB36F6F4286B41A0B08B0429A40"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is comprised of existing high-frequency radar and other sea surface current mapping infrastructure operated by regional associations;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idE5EB48A2C92447C7BF78B3EAECFCFC45"><enum>(II)</enum><text>incorporates new high-frequency radar assets or other fine scale sea surface mapping technology assets, and other assets needed to fill gaps in coverage on United States coastlines; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id8E597234C580469A8B0DC2831E0DAA80"><enum>(III)</enum><text>follows a deployment plan that prioritizes closing gaps in high frequency radar infrastructure in the United States, starting with areas demonstrating significant sea surface current data needs, especially in areas where additional data will improve Coast Guard search and rescue models;</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="idCCF130E211E24D7E896741132D2AAAE0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>fleet acquisition for autonomous underwater and surface vehicles for deployment and data integration to fulfill the purposes of the Act;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id4F24707E6FB740758F71CA55079500A1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an integrative survey program for application of manned and unmanned vehicles to the real-time or near real-time collection and transmission of seafloor, water column, and sea surface data on biology, chemistry, geology, physics and hydrography;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id50AE78DF649E4D7E8888B7F7B1DB7A77"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>remote sensing and data assimilation to develop new analytical methodologies to assimilate data from the Integrated Ocean Observing System into hydrodynamic models;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idFFE18CD2BBFA43939DF9060C8C07C26A"><enum>(v)</enum><text>integrated, multi-State monitoring to assess sources, movement and fate of sediments in coastal regions; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idFA6E614DFE66401CB0D4D266632A59E8"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>a multi-region marine sound monitoring system to be—</text> <subclause id="id935C7500860146F9A909C3EA617A61F4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>planned in consultation with the International Ocean Observing Committee, the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, and academic research institutions; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idA4A911315FCB467C953F7A733A17AD83"><enum>(II)</enum><text>developed, installed, and operated in coordination with the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration and academic research institutions; and</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id08B340BA38424BD5B6D1EE859CEE82C1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any other purpose identified by the Administrator or the Council.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id67E11CA64E3F4126A32AE68B520250F6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)(B), by inserting <quote>The Secretary has the ability to stagger the terms of the System advisory committee members.</quote> before <quote>Members</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id217305D4A47A41C8B4CFBFF9911DF901"><enum>(E)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)—</text> <clause id="id0A69056836C94B979CDDC14A80BDDC9E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>and the Interagency Ocean Observing Committee</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idF4CD868469BE4D6C9CF01A0EFA78CB68"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>Observing</quote> and inserting <quote>Observation</quote>.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idACACCB4576054043A09D24C6101548D4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Civil liability</header><text>Section 12304(e) of the Integrated Coastal and Ocean Observation System Act of 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/3603">33 U.S.C. 3603(e)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="idF801F6DCBF4E4E7293B6435DCCCECBE1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>information coordination entity</quote> and inserting <quote>coastal observation system</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id3C68812806974EB18C49248B3FFA4183"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>non-Federal asset or regional information coordination entity</quote> and inserting <quote>Regional Coastal Observing System,</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id7D36356B78E144ACBC4A31C3EB5731F3"><enum>5.</enum><header>Interagency financing and agreements</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 12305(a) of the Integrated Coastal and Ocean Observation System Act of 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/3604">33 U.S.C. 3604(a)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4DD58A04287747E7AE21EEA60035D14E" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="idCA1C6D78DC984332A5767DA13D17062C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To carry out interagency activities under this subtitle, the Secretary of Commerce may execute an agreement, on a reimbursable or nonreimbursable basis, with any State or subdivision thereof, any Federal agency, or any public or private organization, or individual to carry out interagency activities under this subtitle.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="id595A26324AD149DB9DFE388C2500F48A"><enum>6.</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 12307 of the Integrated Coastal and Ocean Observation System Act of 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/3606">33 U.S.C. 3606</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idAD249A9BB5D64B6C96028F5A8108B550" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="id180DD1773FDF4A248BADC31B1A052CFD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>Not later than 2 years after March 30, 2009, and every 3 years thereafter, the Administrator shall prepare and the President acting through the Council shall approve and transmit to the Congress a report on progress made in implementing this subtitle.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id48F59AE051664078A7858162C3FB49B6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Each report required by subsection (a) shall include—</text> <paragraph id="idA398B26CD17C4DAFBFCD995139AF5C0B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a description of activities carried out under this subtitle and the System Plan;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id4C0DC17AA27740FE826567A47CC7CC02"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an evaluation of the effectiveness of the System, including an evaluation of progress made by the Council to achieve the goals identified under the System Plan;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id047E024713B341C583164AFFD964F7CC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>identification of Federal and non-Federal assets as determined by the Council that have been integrated into the System, including assets essential to the gathering of required observation data variables necessary to meet the respective missions of Council agencies;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id2ABE1DBFDF044BCB86E05078BC589584"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a review of procurements, planned or initiated, by each Council agency to enhance, expand, or modernize the observation capabilities and data products provided by the System, including data management and communication subsystems;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id0A6E7237F3E74BC79A0372765A9B97CB"><enum>(5)</enum><text>a summary of the existing gaps in observation infrastructure and monitoring data collection, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id512645A5F1F44AFBABAB4D8A7D21769C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>priorities considered by the System advisory committee;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide0b38875ea91466b8afc64776bb13ea7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the national sea surface current mapping network;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5a0c2db0c7e5421f891dc59d241bb2a1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>coastal buoys; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id641e7ab732ce40178d906ef05fc8cc71"><enum>(D)</enum><text>ocean chemistry monitoring;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idBBF3495986B34C59B5F9B3921BB01B5F"><enum>(6)</enum><text>an assessment regarding activities to integrate Federal and non-Federal assets, nationally and on the regional level, and discussion of the performance and effectiveness of regional information coordination entities to coordinate regional observation operations;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id5FA3A5B101E84A7BBAFA1953D91B72D2"><enum>(7)</enum><text>a description of benefits of the program to users of data products resulting from the System (including the general public, industries, scientists, resource managers, emergency responders, policy makers, and educators);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idAA3E323E6332497DA2C201CAF905BF14"><enum>(8)</enum><text>recommendations concerning—</text> <subparagraph id="idE72A98E560BF4AE3AAE2153F7DF0313C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>modifications to the System; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5B0BB94A6C1A4A0482E423356F5C0AE2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>funding levels for the System in subsequent fiscal years; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idF72111D6667A447EB21610483134711D"><enum>(9)</enum><text>the results of a periodic external independent programmatic audit of the System.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="idF77B9EDDFBDB42478BB05875F8F4E8D1"><enum>7.</enum><header>Public-private use policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 12308 of the Integrated Coastal and Ocean Observation System Act of 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/3607">33 U.S.C. 3607</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1FAE6127E40549ABB722CEEEFB2EA086" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="id3150fe94ae314f76a1511de2ad2bac4a"><enum></enum><text>The Council shall maintain a policy that defines processes for making decisions about the roles of the Federal Government, the States, regional information coordination entities, the academic community, and the private sector in providing to end-user communities environmental information, products, technologies, and services related to the System. The Administrator shall ensure that National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration adheres to the decisionmaking process developed by the Council regarding the roles of the Federal Government, the States, the Regional Coastal Observing Systems, the academic communities, and the private sector in providing the end-user communities environmental information, data products, technologies, and services related to the System.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="id9BCAFFB6D7F3436E8F4AB0634E217B45"><enum>8.</enum><header>Independent cost estimate</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Integrated Coastal and Ocean Observation System Act of 2009 is amended by striking section 12309 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/3608">33 U.S.C. 3608</external-xref>).</text>
 </section><section id="id7227124B4CDB4A46B70D0B3CB806ECF6"><enum>9.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 12311 of the Integrated Coastal and Ocean Observation System Act of 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/3610">33 U.S.C. 3610</external-xref>) is amended by striking section <quote>2013</quote> and inserting <quote>2019</quote>.</text>
 </section><section id="id1548E50D2D5B4DE1B960E84451460405"><enum>10.</enum><header>Reports and research plans</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 12404(c) of the Federal Ocean Acidification Research And Monitoring Act of 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/3703">33 U.S.C. 3703(c)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8E86933D39F34F02852C06828CC44A92" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="id2ED2EA7E2744459FAE21BC3DC5FC6E2D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Economic vulnerability report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the enactment of the <short-title>Coordinated Ocean Monitoring and Research Act</short-title>, and every 5 years thereafter, the Subcommittee shall transmit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives a report that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id3914d1999066422ea46ee02f3d89a353"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is named <quote>The Ocean Chemistry Coastal Community Vulnerability Assessment</quote>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3BA93DFAE549495A905FE55DEA703524"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identifies gaps in ocean acidification monitoring by public, academic, and private assets in the network of regional coastal observing systems;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9A3FA6C91B784ABEA06D3A5DF570A259"><enum>(C)</enum><text>identifies areas which have gaps in ocean acidification research;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3D1B49F6DD664558B69857623FD32BF6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>identifies United States coastal communities, including fishing communities, low-population rural communities, tribal and subsistence communities, and island communities, that may be impacted by ocean acidification;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6D4BD89F8116496287B358389D490521"><enum>(E)</enum><text>identifies impacts of changing ocean pH on the communities described in subparagraph (D), including impacts from changes in ocean and coastal marine resources that are not managed by the Federal Government;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id03117A888C274479813BE3E1B3F47396"><enum>(F)</enum><text>identifies gaps in understanding of the impacts of ocean acidification on economically or commercially important species, particularly those which support United States commercial, recreational, and tribal fisheries and aquaculture;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2cd049f978b740749cdc34920b9160fd"><enum>(G)</enum><text>identifies habitats that are particularly vulnerable to corrosive sea water, including areas experiencing multiple stressors such as hypoxia, sedimentation and harmful algal blooms;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id80D00692426B49409B6AF44B24766C00"><enum>(H)</enum><text>identifies areas in which existing Integrated Ocean Observing System assets, including buoys and gliders, that may be leveraged as platforms for the deployment of new sensors; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idAA2738B6F670461DA54CFA15BEFFE0B7"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is written in collaboration with the agencies responsible for carrying out this Act.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id30E694C185B04782B1D2DD1FC31B6EEC"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Monitoring prioritization plan</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the submission of the report required by paragraph (4), the Subcommittee shall transmit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives a report that develops a plan to deploy new sensors—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id20639EDCF7D34ACE862F55117CE10445"><enum>(A)</enum><text>based on the report required by paragraph (4);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id04113FB1BA604B7EAEBA36EC88439C63"><enum>(B)</enum><text>prioritized by—</text> <clause id="id86c0d9d1798d4d8083aab48eff11c6db"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the threat to coastal economies and ecosystems;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idc6d9b5e6931044a1ad7b6ef153fefffa"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>gaps in data; and</text> </clause><clause id="id07ffb91bf4cb4679831aa93720388bd6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>research needs; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id32952F1241E6479F86D10BBCF4F3DB7E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>that leverage existing platforms, where possible.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </section><section commented="no" id="ide497a91b19444f8e909318cc40f09935"><enum>11.</enum><header>Strategic research plan</header> <subsection commented="no" id="idF3533694B74849879F9ED5752E1D740C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 12405(b) of the Federal Ocean Acidification Research And Monitoring Act of 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/3704">33 U.S.C. 3704(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="id6F8F93024C0347F58DA687306BE60E45"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (8), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idE2FA48FA5FDC4E1FA2D4DC29880AB46B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (9), by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon and <quote>and</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id2764AF49C80546799446BA2F6D9A91AF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9063758bc5d547c2b12f2287bf1ae05d" style="OLC"> <paragraph commented="no" id="id8d5752efe4f14d16a9ba43e9e6f051dc"><enum>(10)</enum><text>make recommendations for research to be conducted, including in the social sciences and economics, to address the key knowledge gaps identified in the economic vulnerability report conducted under section 12404(c).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="idbe403a28d9984449b210b9fcd772d7e5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Program elements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 12405(c) of the Federal Ocean Acidification Research And Monitoring Act of 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/3704">33 U.S.C. 3704(c)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida0d433cc40614228a8fb00117bc7efe4" style="OLC">
 <paragraph commented="no" id="idd1dc47aa71ac4052a6f6e97cb55b1834"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Research to understand combined effects of changes in ocean chemistry, sediment delivery, hypoxia and harmful algal blooms and the impact these processes have on one another, and how these multiple stressors impact living marine resources and coastal ecosystems.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id3beb7db7ab0f481c9d80773a500d07c3"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Applied research to identify adaptation strategies for species impacted by changes in ocean chemistry including vegetation-based systems, shell recycling, species and genetic diversity, applied technologies, aquaculture methodologies, and management recommendations.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection></section><section id="idCC90FBEAE291437CB98C2DA4B06304DD"><enum>12.</enum><header>Stakeholder input on monitoring</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 12406(a) of the Federal Ocean Acidification Research And Monitoring Act of 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/3705">33 U.S.C. 3705(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="idD3B8B1F3118A4CCAAC2566DAC8960954"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id9AB14A26E5654E30BFAA174DF15B0529"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon and <quote>and</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idEA66159CA6864F5C9ACB565BDA7E7D8C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id369DF00DB4EF4058B087BB022D05DFB1" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="idFE776A11E05E4AD8BABA1D76B5E8C0B6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>includes an ongoing mechanism that allows potentially affected industry members, coastal stakeholders, fishery management councils and commissions, non-Federal resource managers, and scientific experts to provide input on monitoring needs that are necessary to support on the ground management, decisionmaking, and adaptation related to ocean acidification.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></section><section id="idd1c62f20d00440e0b729fd3aabba9a04"><enum>13.</enum><header>Research activities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 12407(a) of the Federal Ocean Acidification Research And Monitoring Act of 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/3706">33 U.S.C. 3706(a)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id475d5acbd2664635b4da3ab8644fa62d" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="id9862f3d5796a4db2a24d8b13830cc3c3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Research activities</header><text>The Director of the National Science Foundation shall continue to carry out research activities on ocean acidification which shall support competitive, merit-based, peer-reviewed proposals for research, observatories and monitoring of ocean acidification and its impacts, including—</text>
 <paragraph id="id384929acbb0840ceb39feb8f9385bff9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>impacts on marine organisms and marine ecosystems;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="iddc9fece9a6654e3b9d15745123a3e3a9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>impacts on ocean, coastal, and estuarine biogeochemistry;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id9252cd80113e4b83923df9d0f10b8b05"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the development of methodologies and technologies to evaluate ocean acidification and its impacts; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id0ffca475982c48eba2cb28fab8a688ec"><enum>(4)</enum><text>impacts of multiple stressors on ecosystems exhibiting hypoxia, harmful algal blooms, or sediment delivery, combined with changes in ocean chemistry.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


