<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1641 IS: Jason Simcakoski Memorial Opioid Safety Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-06-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 1641</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150622">June 22, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S354">Ms. Baldwin</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S372">Mrs. Capito</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S307">Mr. Brown</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S345">Mr. Johnson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S338">Mr. Manchin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S347">Mr. Moran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S229">Mrs. Murray</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S313">Mr. Sanders</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S314">Mr. Tester</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSVA00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To improve the use by the Department of Veterans Affairs of opioids in treating veterans, to
			 improve patient advocacy by the Department, and to expand availability of
			 complementary and integrative health, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header>
			<subsection id="id5D7F2BBBFAFF4ABCA7D464A8C1E85E74"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Jason Simcakoski Memorial Opioid Safety Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id851A4A3D64574F48A51AACAE05051820"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text><toc><toc-entry idref="S1" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id92B8E473B086498EACC5F946239C5AFA" level="title">TITLE I—Opioid Therapy and Pain Management</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="idDAAD69EB530D45D6A06CC73D02917A07" level="section">Sec. 101. Guidelines on management of opioid therapy by Department of Veterans Affairs and Department of Defense and implementation of such guidelines by Department of Veterans Affairs.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id57FB62B097584B20A2B67B3D024AB2BF" level="section">Sec. 102. Improvement of opioid safety measures by Department of Veterans Affairs.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id02e5e49b121f49f4aec78483b2f63f60" level="section">Sec. 103. Establishment of working group on pain management and opioid therapy within the Department of Veterans Affairs-Department of Defense Joint Executive Committee.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="HD276606BC0E6440DB693B3535C717164" level="section">Sec. 104. Establishment of pain management boards of Department of Veterans Affairs.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id7BE67A9EBF7C4D93BDE53C8A8840344B" level="section">Sec. 105. Study on feasibility and advisability of carrying out pharmacy lock-in program by Department of Veterans Affairs.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="idC11763BC708F49BB8002FA2E311DD571" level="section">Sec. 106. Reports and investigation on use of opioids in treatment by Department of Veterans Affairs.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id2F491C54F8AE4036AFEFD0BEF92B0876" level="title">TITLE II—Patient Advocacy</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id673540CB06CF4AA2BD0ED9A2C35A4E20" level="section">Sec. 201. Establishment of Office of Patient Advocacy of the Department of Veterans Affairs.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="idEE90788F7C1C42BEBEBC75D65F4552E8" level="section">Sec. 202. Community meetings on improving care from Department of Veterans Affairs.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="idab28c8833363475599eb6bc7164eac54" level="section">Sec. 203. Improvement of awareness of patient advocacy program and patient bill of rights of Department of Veterans Affairs.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id02cc7a266bee4d11934210804bfeec39" level="section">Sec. 204. Comptroller General Report on Patient Advocacy Program of Department of Veterans Affairs.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="idCFF1439B209F4EDDBCED44A05A5CA49D" level="section">Sec. 205. Report on transition by veterans between different health care settings.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id36462EDDF55B41AD88B31BD9E65924C9" level="title">TITLE III—Complementary and Integrative Health</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id8B8914EC2E0644078C184EE17605383E" level="section">Sec. 301. Expansion of research and education on and delivery of complementary and integrative health to veterans.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id67312e0292d346d2a87aa91ddc4aec4e" level="section">Sec. 302. Program on integration of complementary and integrative health within Department of Veterans Affairs medical centers.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id83DCAA4E21DA4886AC1C6DFB378E71FA" level="section">Sec. 303. Program on use of wellness programs as complementary approach to pain management and related issues for veterans and family members of veterans.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id38C91336CE4741918663FDBDC30565F7" level="title">TITLE IV—Other Veterans Health Care Matters</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id12133B22D3CE415482B726F28137B3DD" level="section">Sec. 401. Additional requirements for hiring of health care providers by Department of Veterans Affairs.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id4A2F6B7516364A6A87B78F310FE5AE44" level="section">Sec. 402. Provision of information on health care providers of Department of Veterans Affairs to State medical boards.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id399893690B4541C18E17EDFA16A6DCA5" level="section">Sec. 403. Report on compliance by Department of Veterans Affairs with reviews of health care providers leaving the Department or transferring to other facilities.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id067B5B2E53DC49E0A6F5900C7348DFF0" level="title">TITLE V—Other Veterans Matters</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="idE67F3326AC6C440EB01E3402D8C60FF4" level="section">Sec. 501. Department of Veterans Affairs program of internal audits.</toc-entry> </toc> </subsection></section><title id="id92B8E473B086498EACC5F946239C5AFA" style="OLC"><enum>I</enum><header>Opioid Therapy and Pain Management</header> <section id="idDAAD69EB530D45D6A06CC73D02917A07"><enum>101.</enum><header>Guidelines on management of opioid therapy by Department of Veterans Affairs and Department of Defense and implementation of such guidelines by Department of Veterans Affairs</header> <subsection id="idDA959D515F514BDD90A864CA08C66865"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs and the Secretary of Defense shall jointly update the VA/DOD Clinical Practice Guideline for Management of Opioid Therapy for Chronic Pain to include the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="id96d8ee6cff4c4dbebf5f947af79e00d3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Guidelines for safely prescribing opioids for the treatment of chronic, non-cancer pain in outpatient settings as developed and released by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id4c2c78cade4d4aa8a26cf8799e5a253e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Enhanced guidance with respect to absolute contraindications for opioid therapy, including guidance with respect to the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="idc6f58e7d34624f21bda15c80afafb1b5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The coadministration of drugs that are capable of inducing a life-limiting drug-drug interaction, including benzodiazepines.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id021ad2a4755a4e29a9f2530a3ba11b2c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The treatment of patients with current acute psychiatric instability or substance use disorder or patients at risk of suicide.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idaaf76d52daab4c5181836c3ac90758a2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The use of opioid therapy to treat patients without any pain, including to treat mental health disorders other than opioid use disorder.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide2b913d77349446dbcc116937ece4579"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Enhanced guidance with respect to the treatment of patients with behaviors or comorbidities, such as post-traumatic stress disorder, psychiatric disorders, or a history of substance abuse or addiction, that require consultation or comanagement of opioid therapy with one or more specialists in pain management, mental health, or addictions.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id971ef38c1c3c4aaabb51f3e812b889d1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Enhanced guidance with respect to the conduct by health care providers of an effectiveness assessment for patients receiving opioid therapy, including patients on long-term opioid therapy, to determine—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id4960253EF60A403E8B38128F7C9A3F0D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>whether opioid therapy is meeting the expected goals of the patient and health care provider of relieving pain, improving function, and providing patient satisfaction; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1A80F36825FA46BEA2F7723E19227753"><enum>(B)</enum><text>whether opioid therapy should be continued.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5e0133ddc0fc4d40ab16860760c7077b"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Requirements that each health care provider of the Department of Veterans Affairs and the Department of Defense, before initiating opioid therapy to treat a patient, use the Opioid Therapy Risk Report tool of the Department of Veterans Affairs, including information from the prescription drug monitoring program of each State that includes the most recent date information relating to the patient was accessed through such program, as required to be included in such tool under section 102(d)(2), to assess the risk for adverse outcomes of opioid therapy for the patient, including the concurrent use of controlled substances such as benzodiazepines, as part of the comprehensive assessment conducted by the health care provider.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id7F5B4210D66248EF88540CD08339F668"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Guidelines to govern the methodologies used by health care providers of the Department of Veterans Affairs and the Department of Defense to taper opioid therapy when adjusting or discontinuing the use of opioid therapy.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id296d36204d244a3f95a7e6ba1d98b556"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Guidelines with respect to appropriate case management for patients receiving opioid therapy who transition between inpatient and outpatient health care settings, which may include the use of care transition plans.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ide7893a2c6c154aee93d90af0998cb182"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Enhanced recommendations with respect to the use of routine and random urine drug tests for all patients before and during opioid therapy to help prevent substance abuse, dependence, and diversion, including requirements—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idDDF22F755C19476FB42111CB7FAD9BF8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that such tests occur not less frequently than once each year; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE407501029B8479D8F757A8A61D06349"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that health care providers appropriately interpret and respond to the results from such tests to tailor pain therapy, safeguards, and risk management strategies to each patient.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idf613e212e4414240a473c76ca2248cd6"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Guidance that health care providers discuss with patients, before initiating opioid therapy, options for pain management therapies without the use of opioids and options to augment opioid therapy with other clinical and complementary and integrative health services to minimize opioid dependence.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idED7B9076B27A415B9D360F53A8946B5C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation before update</header><text>Before updating the guideline under subsection (a), the Secretary of Veterans Affairs and the Secretary of Defense shall jointly consult with the working group on pain management and opioid therapy established in section 103.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id0c27d8e675e2473b84d12cf8cf2a2a62"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Comptroller General report on implementation by Department of Veterans Affairs</header><text>Not later than one year after the Secretary of Veterans Affairs updates the guideline under subsection (a), and not less frequently than annually thereafter, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on—</text>
 <paragraph id="id291F265FA2104815931353C93891ADF9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the implementation by each medical facility of the Department of Veterans Affairs of such guideline; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id92B8ED673A0745EA9D9EF05175908EE2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the compliance by each such medical facility with such guideline.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ida5a19ffcabb84d96a58912dd155d8268"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Controlled substance defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>controlled substance</term> has the meaning given that term in section 102 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/802">21 U.S.C. 802</external-xref>).</text>
				</subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id57FB62B097584B20A2B67B3D024AB2BF"><enum>102.</enum><header>Improvement of opioid safety measures by
			 Department of
			 Veterans Affairs</header>
 <subsection id="idb8ef864bc927457bb8d27ce9b0824b93"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Expansion of Opioid Safety Initiative</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall expand the Opioid Safety Initiative of the Department of Veterans Affairs to include all medical facilities of the Department.</text>
				</subsection><subsection id="id6f9b7baf87134829b2922a545242ea71"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Pain management education and training</header>
 <paragraph id="id380849CFD1A54FC5838CFB4EF0948A21"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In carrying out the Opioid Safety Initiative of the Department, the Secretary shall require all employees of the Department responsible for prescribing opioids to receive education and training described in paragraph (2) in order to appropriately implement and comply with the VA/DOD Clinical Practice Guideline for Management of Opioid Therapy for Chronic Pain, including any updates to such guideline.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id602bc96a9cae4660831ccef5376b5c17"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Education and training</header><text>Education and training described in this paragraph is education and training on pain management and safe opioid prescribing practices for purposes of safely and effectively managing patients with chronic pain and includes education and training on the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="id17627e1fecc54ddfb53305b1ed690cd8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The safe and effective use of opioid therapy to treat chronic pain that is non-cancer related.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9ECD8D3478F640FC97125FA45A3DD369"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The use of evidence-based pain management therapies, including cognitive-behavioral therapy, non-opioid alternatives, and non-drug approaches to managing pain and related health conditions including complementary and integrative health services.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id844219745c3249fc8f510d08ee73a1d8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Screening and identification of patients with substance use disorder, including drug-seeking behavior, before prescribing opioids, assessment of the risk potential for patients developing an addiction, and referral of patients to appropriate addiction treatment professionals if addiction is identified or strongly suspected.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id918dd0fad1544808a07ecb7216792580"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The safe and effective use of urine drug tests.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3f1b9fcaa3be4bb9a6fb56ee79d498b9"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Prescription of the lowest effective dose of opioids based on patient need, use of opioids only for a limited period of time, and augmentation of opioid therapy with other pain management therapies and modalities.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id96b08db476c74d9b986b88b37a91c928"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The use of safe and effective tapering programs for patients taking opioids and other controlled substances, such as benzodiazepines, concurrently and patients taking high-risk opioids.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf857b716996048cf8c78ec5cece8c33a"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Communication with patients on the potential harm associated with the use of opioids and other controlled substances, including the need to safely store and dispose of supplies relating to the use of opioids and other controlled substances.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4c4ef77350a149f08a8573cc3ac0d255"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Such other education and training as the Secretary considers appropriate to ensure that veterans receive safe, high-quality pain management care from the Department.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idd6f6250981a64dba9129d25bfd694865"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Use of existing program</header><text>In providing education and training described in paragraph (2), the Secretary shall use the Interdisciplinary Chronic Pain Management Training Team Program of the Department.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id58662acd32164d63a3a7f59c107b8549"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Pain management teams</header>
 <paragraph id="id795FA39F0B56403D87F54CEEAFD04CAA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In carrying out the Opioid Safety Initiative of the Department, each medical facility of the Department shall identify and designate a pain management team of health care professionals responsible for coordinating and overseeing therapy at such facility for patients experiencing acute and chronic pain that is non-cancer related.</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="id6D486620862243D39B2879F583D7C476"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Establishment of protocols</header>
 <subparagraph id="id042578990A664846BF050BF382E9AECF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The director of each Veterans Integrated Service Network shall establish protocols for the designation of pain management teams at each medical facility within that Veterans Integrated Service Network.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id379B7C56E4DB4A16A73FC9B80E227E1B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Consultation on prescription of opioids</header><text>Each protocol established for a medical facility under subparagraph (A) shall ensure that any health care provider without expertise in prescribing analgesics or who has not completed the education and training under subsection (b), such as a mental health care provider, does not prescribe opioids to a patient unless that health care provider—</text>
 <clause id="id1BAAE2413197479E99301546CC47F248"><enum>(i)</enum><text>consults with a health care provider with pain management expertise or who is on the pain management team of the medical facility; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id5D915E9DF3184533B6932FF2D9B52D75"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>refers the patient to that pain management team for any subsequent prescriptions and related therapy.</text>
							</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id54cc2bf801744a11a2b29fed5dd825c0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report</header>
 <subparagraph id="id9EC0AB3C6755495EAD3D6D2355CDC661"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the head of each medical facility of the Department shall submit to the director of the Veterans Integrated Service Network in which the medical facility is located a report identifying the health care professionals that have been designated as members of the pain management team at the medical facility.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idAB47033C2532423E890C49272F2DD612"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>Each report submitted under subparagraph (A) with respect to a medical facility of the Department shall include—</text>
 <clause id="id28532A037F1A4ADCA365B403294ECFAB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a certification as to whether all members of the pain management team at the medical facility have completed the education and training required under subsection (b); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idBAD7F01AC813422289931E115744AFC1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a plan for the management and referral of patients to such pain management team if health care providers without expertise in prescribing analgesics prescribe opioid medications to treat acute and chronic pain that is non-cancer related.</text>
							</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0ee8afa9eab64d99b1250011045e916c"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Tracking and monitoring of opioid use</header>
 <paragraph id="id5F8EBD882C714157A0D6E00BBEA147AF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Tracking of data on opioid use</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, in carrying out the Opioid Safety Initiative and the Opioid Therapy Risk Report tool of the Department, the Secretary shall, through the Computerized Patient Record System of the Department, allow for real-time tracking of and access to data on—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id72BCB6C9DAB74FE1B8E33AA8AC6FD720"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the key clinical indicators with respect to the totality of opioid use by veterans;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id84ff31f148a84770abc849c98ff01e86"><enum>(B)</enum><text>concurrent prescribing by health care providers of the Department of opioids in different health care settings, include data on concurrent prescribing of opioids to treat mental health disorders other than opioid use disorder; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf5aa6a650d444105a4f92d083c1ab9cd"><enum>(C)</enum><text>mail-order prescriptions of opioids prescribed to veterans under the laws administered by the Secretary.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idD5991C2C514649059578EF2B5C8E75BE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prescription drug monitoring programs of States</header><text>In carrying out the Opioid Safety Initiative and the Opioid Therapy Risk Report tool of the Department, the Secretary shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idADA67B56B91E4D9884BAC6AEB3AA464A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ensure access by health care providers of the Department to information on controlled substances, including opioids and benzodiazepines, prescribed to veterans who receive care outside the Department through the prescription drug monitoring program of each State, including by seeking to enter into memoranda of understanding with States to allow such access;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id476FF72F575F40DA87A482A5FB65A517"><enum>(B)</enum><text>include such information in the Opioid Therapy Risk Report; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8bbe32b81b02417581469efeef286efb"><enum>(C)</enum><text>require health care providers of the Department to submit to the prescription drug monitoring program of each State information on prescriptions of controlled substances received by veterans in that State under the laws administered by the Secretary.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id3d382db98f66414a8a3dd8438e61faf2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report on implementation</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the progress of the Department in implementing the improvements to the Opioid Therapy Risk Report tool of the Department required under paragraphs (1) and (2).</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id100f3a971c1e4db2b8b6b5b5fc4fe79a"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Availability of opioid receptor antagonists</header>
					<paragraph id="id9FF02325827B4B72A56E09C7EF7FA2AF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Increased availability and use</header>
 <subparagraph id="id2AC4B769A3A9407392C91E92487D5672"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall increase the availability of opioid receptor antagonists approved by the Food and Drug Administration, such as naloxone, to veterans and increase the availability of opioid receptor antagonists for use by health care providers of the Department in treating veterans.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4B880A200F7A42518E2B409EF97FF658"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Availability, training, and distribution</header><text>In carrying out subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall, not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act—</text>
 <clause id="id6add2b7453144caa998a29cfe1b06f54"><enum>(i)</enum><text>equip each medical facility of the Department with opioid receptor antagonists approved by the Food and Drug Administration;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id385936C310894EEB9EFA4E6219E8BB54"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>enhance training for health care providers of the Department on distributing such opioid receptor antagonists; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idec12ae7fdc9d48bc810e0bc6b85eef60"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>expand the Overdose Education and Naloxone Distribution program of the Department to ensure that all veterans in receipt of health care under the laws administered by the Secretary who are at risk of opioid overdose have access to such opioid receptor antagonists and training on the proper administration of such opioid receptor antagonists.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id73E8A023ECC140AF8FEDE8CBBB4AC488"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Veterans who are at risk</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (B), veterans who are at risk of opioid overdose include—</text> <clause id="id156445E2AE254056BEAB2D24193AC3E1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>veterans receiving long-term opioid therapy;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idF34598A01436486D8901D713EEABDFCE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>veterans receiving opioid therapy who have a history of substance use disorder or prior instances of overdose; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id697A93398E72460FB8203C23D75539F1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>veterans who are at risk as determined by a health care provider who is treating the veteran.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id16d07e8f370842039a86ac176451bead"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on compliance with paragraph (1) that includes an assessment of the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="idB8DBBBE5502A40BFBD251134751BFCCB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Whether all medical facilities of the Department are equipped with opioid receptor antagonists approved by the Food and Drug Administration.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4B015742BB8B4972B23BC5B898EA81E1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The progress of the Department in ensuring that any such facilities that are not equipped with such opioid receptor antagonists obtain such opioid receptor antagonists.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id89C166BC23C1456FACF0961104AD1A1D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Whether all veterans at risk of opioid overdose have access to such opioid receptor antagonists and training on the proper administration of such opioid receptor antagonists.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF2B56A2F43854851A0DB7AECAF8DBD30"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The progress of the Department in ensuring that all veterans at risk of opioid overdose have access to such opioid receptor antagonists and training on the proper administration of such opioid receptor antagonists.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id9BCE86251C1F45B982878032F18C5465"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Inclusion of certain information and capabilities in Opioid
			 Therapy Risk Report tool</header>
 <paragraph id="id8719FAEF426E4892A1A6D06C489CEC0A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Information</header><text>The Secretary shall include in the Opioid Therapy Risk Report tool of the Department—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idF934C3B818204996A08415A6039E3731"><enum>(A)</enum><text>information on the most recent time the tool was accessed by a health care provider of the Department with respect to each veteran; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF87428F46A63490F8DA733C9804F26AF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>information on the results of the most recent urine drug test for each veteran.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idC33CE593C2E642AD883329D3087B13F6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Capabilities</header><text>The Secretary shall include in the Opioid Therapy Risk Report tool the ability of health care providers of the Department to determine whether a health care provider of the Department prescribed opioids to a veteran without checking the information in the tool with respect to the veteran.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5982C9F8DBA84297A1F2A1C2881B7D8F"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Notification of risk in computerized health record</header><text>The Secretary shall modify the Computerized Patient Record System of the Department to ensure that any health care provider that accesses the record of a veteran, regardless of the reason the veteran seeks care from the health care provider, will be immediately notified whether the veteran—</text>
 <paragraph id="idAEF9E84E94A14BD2A6F990C199447E3D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is receiving opioid therapy and has a history of substance use disorder or prior instances of overdose;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id276C53EE343A4670AE6F6138AD4101A8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>has a history of opioid abuse; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id7A0A9D8F4BB34B7A8DAFC378CD3AA8AB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>is at risk of becoming an opioid abuser as determined by a health care provider who is treating the veteran.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id79BEC329C9DC480F91605E159351EA59"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Controlled substance defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>controlled substance</term> has the meaning given that term in section 102 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/802">21 U.S.C. 802</external-xref>).</text> </subsection></section><section id="id02e5e49b121f49f4aec78483b2f63f60"><enum>103.</enum><header>Establishment of working group on pain management and opioid therapy within the Department of Veterans Affairs-Department of Defense Joint Executive Committee</header> <subsection id="id0E7A22BEC4874C4E86D1BF0DA28567E4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Working group on pain management and opioid therapy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established within the Health Executive Committee of the Department of Veterans Affairs-Department of Defense Joint Executive Committee established under section 320 of title 38, United States Code, a working group on pain management and opioid therapy for individuals receiving health care from either the Department of Veterans Affairs or the Department of Defense that shall cover, at a minimum, the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="id537B49EE8E1B4A37B50E6EFF0575191D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The opioid prescribing practices of health care providers of each Department.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id547EF5B4339A475F9F1E614BC31E85DA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The ability of each Department to manage acute and chronic pain among individuals receiving health care from that Department, including training health care providers with respect to pain management.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id86359ECAD4554DF98291BF373866933D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The use by each Department of complementary and integrative health in treating such individuals.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id1651D879EBDB47F0B1E4A9D9E03597A2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The concurrent use by health care providers of each Department of opioids and prescription drugs to treat mental health disorders, including benzodiazepines.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idEEC9AC2ED9584A0BA353DAA55D28BDB6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The practice by health care providers of each Department of prescribing opioids to treat mental health disorders.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id3ecfd63c78404994bffc74cf8f9b47ae"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The coordination in coverage of and consistent access to medications prescribed for patients transitioning from receiving health care from the Department of Defense to receiving health care from the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idf717da70862d4943bf51a1893b592c4c"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The ability of each Department to identify and treat substance use disorders among individuals receiving health care from that Department.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id7892a3b2365a49f5b3a3c42beb81b4a2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Coordination and consultation</header><text>The working group established under subsection (a) shall—</text> <paragraph id="id9D69D86FCA4A4317B06C25B90F37DD54"><enum>(1)</enum><text>coordinate the activities of the working group with other relevant working groups established under section 320 of title 38, United States Code, including the working groups on evidence based practice, patient safety, pharmacy, psychological health, and pain management;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idC1ABEB465D2B460C9056AAD4EBCF5186"><enum>(2)</enum><text>consult with other relevant Federal agencies, including the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, with respect to the activities of the working group; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id42898DFC72AA49FBBDE4C48F15701488"><enum>(3)</enum><text>consult with the Department of Veterans Affairs and the Department of Defense with respect to, review, and comment on the VA/DOD Clinical Practice Guideline for Management of Opioid Therapy for Chronic Pain, or any successor guideline, before any update to the guideline is released.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id28DAD2A32658461A8D9EF1BA788E4899"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs and the Secretary of Defense shall jointly ensure that the working group established under subsection (a) is able to meaningfully consult with respect to the updated guideline required under subsection (a) of section 101, as required by subsection (b) of such section, not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="HD276606BC0E6440DB693B3535C717164"><enum>104.</enum><header>Establishment of pain management boards of Department of Veterans Affairs</header>
 <subsection id="H63472896DB4C4D988AC636B680753A1B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/73">chapter 73</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA906B4299DE047BF888F26486C182E59" style="USC">
						<section id="H8AB48CCD92124256934C67533168C9D3"><enum>7309A.</enum><header>Pain management boards</header>
 <subsection id="HDB62594A237A4FA69855A2ADB3054318"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish in each Veterans Integrated Service Network a Pain Management Board (in this section referred to as a <quote>Board</quote>).</text>
							</subsection><subsection id="H59200F4478F046A2A4A397B917E9F9EC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header>
								<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HD865605BE2D94C47B2415235A1AA905E"><enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>Each Board shall—</text> <subparagraph id="id69CC5C04979A4D5299A600E7CAAA4FED" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>consult with health care professionals and other employees of the Department located in the Veterans Integrated Service Network covered by the Board, patients who are being treated at medical facilities of the Department located in such Veterans Integrated Service Network, and family members of such patients with respect to the pain management resources and best practices of the Department;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC3CD24D632C5478B8A8F17F98D66B5F8" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>oversee compliance by the health care professionals and other employees of the Department with the best practices of the Department, including by issuing such recommendations to improve compliance with such best practices as the Board considers appropriate;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id413FECAD63784B318E937317A08F5FAF" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provide oversight of the pain management practices of the pain management committees of each medical facility of the Department and the health care professionals and other employees of the Department that are located in the Veterans Integrated Service Network covered by the Board;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8582B3331F604AFAB728A50A39AF9967" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>carry out educational forums, as the Board considers appropriate, for individuals specified in subparagraph (A) on pain management and treatment that may include the sharing of updated research and best practices from medical experts, other health care systems, and such other Federal agencies as the Board considers necessary to carry out this subparagraph; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id37E8C0A81AB9441A8774F90D3787CFD4" indent="up1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>carry out public hearings, symposiums, or other events, as the Board considers appropriate, during which health care professionals discuss and share best practices on pain management and complementary and integrative health.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idB93C894D77BE4225BC34D846C5B3F025" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id582AA41636964CE68949F14F7C402AE3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Each Board may provide treatment recommendations for patients with complex clinical pain who are being treated at a medical facility of the Department located in the Veterans Integrated Service Network covered by the Board, and assist in facilitating communication between such patients and their health care providers, regardless of whether such treatment is on an in-patient or out-patient basis, and for whom a request for such recommendations, subject to subparagraph (C), has been made by an individual described in subparagraph (B).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFED6087594D74FAEA8D592602288DDE0" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An individual described in this subparagraph is one of the following individuals:</text> <clause id="HC21F87FF1D1C419DB3EA4900E0E315BA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The patient.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4728F219D67A4EEBBE5309F7C66A2320"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The spouse of the patient.</text> </clause><clause id="H485E95769D6D40CD81905119ECF785FC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>A family member of the patient or another individual if such family member or individual has been designated by the patient to make health care decisions for the patient or to receive health care information with respect to the patient.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H93EA1A37068B4E35993CAB2AD8FD152D"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>A physician of the patient.</text> </clause><clause id="H216670EE3025483DB3E8B461AD24E170"><enum>(v)</enum><text>An employee of the medical facility of the Department described in subparagraph (A).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idFD6C3B2ADB154F7DAEDA629ED6002A01" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An individual described in subparagraph (B) may not request treatment recommendations under subparagraph (A) unless the individual—</text>
 <clause id="id61202BFECE284F658DD64E6C8D4CB9FD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has requested treatment recommendations from the pain management committee of the medical facility of the Department at which the patient is receiving treatment; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idB198CE9BD0934402B34E53D8F91925FC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has received treatment recommendations from such committee and is not satisfied with those treatment recommendations.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9F46DB714B39413686015FA1637C5306" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Based on treatment recommendations developed under paragraph (2)(A), consultations conducted under paragraph (1)(A), and educational forums and public events carried out under subparagraphs (C) and (D) of paragraph (1), each Board shall provide to health care professionals of the Department located in the Veterans Integrated Service Network covered by the Board recommendations on the best practices regarding pain management in cases of complex clinical pain.</text>
								</paragraph><paragraph id="H7CC6B8E1306E40238A0413D19B67EDEC" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H178EEFBB02A247D0B9D1D2A7D08594A4"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each Board shall annually submit to the Secretary and the Under Secretary for Health a report (with all personally identifiable information of patients redacted) on pain management practices carried out in the Veterans Integrated Service Network covered by the Board. Each such report shall include, for the year covered by the report, the following:</text>
 <clause id="H5C083B8C6C244B1087D3054483CEA69B" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The treatment recommendations provided under paragraph (2)(A), including—</text> <subclause display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAC837FBF937F42F194592E3DD0DC2BAB"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a summary of such recommendations; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8DDD054297AD4065A4419B8EF53C7D16"><enum>(II)</enum><text>an explanation of the merits of each such recommendation.</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H67294906F1FA441D89EEBE210B66BBBB" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The recommendations for best practices provided under paragraph (3), including—</text>
 <subclause display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1D432ADFAC2847D7973D48A7FFBAFAD0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a summary of such recommendations; and</text> </subclause><subclause display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCCEFC1AE4C554920AB69DB83E12CE11E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>an explanation of the merits of each such recommendation.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3BF2A5AD6B4C49FABD739F2654DE5170" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Such other information as the Board considers appropriate.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H921F5CE4AEE64987B7E7A2E90DB51B24" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Not later than January 31 of each year, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a report that contains comprehensive information from each report submitted to the Secretary under subparagraph (A) during the year preceding the submittal of the report by the Secretary, disaggregated by Board.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HCACC78D3A7DD47B59ED1686F7713A410" indent="up1"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.) shall not apply to any Board.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H345022F0FBA74FD0BBA991C2A3D6A0AA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Membership</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HC6C6C0FB7F4B4AA883BFDB5AD39356F6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Each Board shall include the following individuals appointed by the Secretary:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H1B85F67B1261419EAFFD9AEC02281A81" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A board certified pain medicine specialist.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3C5E7A1008624A15B46059175392DB87" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A trained and qualified member of the primary care team of a medical facility of the Department with experience in pain care, such as a nurse practitioner.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2C9975589F38497380AC1969603C8361" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A pain psychologist.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9D3B7AB853C447F2BC02D3FBC4C4640B" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A pain social worker.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4DA3DDA91B904969920DD5982A2CE8B9" indent="up1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>A clinical pharmacist.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF3EA116BE3E64186A9D9792ADF6EB20A" indent="up1"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A pain point of contact for a Veterans Integrated Service Network.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC56AAEC2AE1142E5BABB30CE2CB0EF92" indent="up1"><enum>(G)</enum><text>A physician with addiction and psychopharmacology expertise and experience.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H715C1196F1284063B9AE4719BBF1F484" indent="up1"><enum>(H)</enum><text>An allied health care professional.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7F4C2B9EA743460A8DB114947D7D51B7" indent="up1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>A clinician with expertise in complementary and integrative health.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB54861C3905742CC82BE99A34A759E52" indent="up1"><enum>(J)</enum><text>A clinical behavioral therapist.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id999B424D8B824FB58212CDA872B5E448" indent="up1"><enum>(K)</enum><text>A patient advocate.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idEA70B782BCD84555ABD77591A49594B1" indent="up1"><enum>(L)</enum><text>A representative of the labor interests of employees of the Department who are responsible for prescribing drugs.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC4CC6B79AF3F4DA99DD083A23FDDCE93" indent="up1"><enum>(M)</enum><text>A current or former clinical patient.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEA027905DA7D474A8B0F24E85F3544A3" indent="up1"><enum>(N)</enum><text>A family member of a current or former clinical patient.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H35A09619EFAF434B91ED0D6258F5919F" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Of the members appointed under paragraph (1), not less than three shall be representative of the demographic of patients served by the Veterans Integrated Service Network covered by the Board, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idF3A527E913BA434EA0FAB776671B26CA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not less than two current or former patients treated at a medical facility of the Department for complex clinical pain; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC5E11ED66CF3412CADF4465362615E16"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not less than one family member of such a current or former patient.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id8882FEDEF71749F3A737715877DC0EE6" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Secretary shall determine the terms of service of the members of each Board.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2AA0578C216E48DB83F588A525169063" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id40A0D105879E40C390BB65CC3613E2E9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Members of each Board shall serve without pay and, except as provided in subparagraph (B), members who are full-time officers or employees of the United States may not receive additional pay, allowances, or benefits by reason of their service on the Board.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3E509FABDCB745559F89E70AF37374BB" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Members may receive travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, for travel in connection with their duties as members of the Board.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE5714FD156F445E093B83C20E5AC6E38" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any member who has clinical duties as an officer or employee of the United States shall be relieved of such duties during periods in which such relief is necessary for the member to carry out the duties of the Board.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0FFDFE78214D411FBC44CCD194CA010B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Availability of information</header><text>In carrying out the duties of a Board under subsection (b), specific information identifying a patient and other confidential information relating to a patient may not be made available to any member appointed under subsection (c)(1) solely based on qualifications under subparagraph (M) or (N) of such subsection.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id626DC0109D86410FB3119A23A6638623"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Employment protections</header><text>No adverse personnel action may be made against an employee of the Department in connection with a communication by the employee with a member of a Board relating to the duties of the Board under subsection (b) and any such communication shall be covered by the employment and whistleblower protections otherwise applicable to communications by employees of the Department.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idCBD29F7D593649E4B0E7DB3D51F21CDF"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Resources of Department</header><text>The Secretary shall make available to each Board the resources and personnel of the Department necessary for the Board to carry out the duties of the Board under subsection (b), including resources and personnel of the General Counsel of the Department.</text>
							</subsection><subsection id="H26B7BB2400024041BC0473279B99C366"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Powers</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H96D62757679F48349444C3D4FDA85435"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each Board may, for the purpose of carrying out this section, hold hearings, sit and act at times and places, take testimony, and receive evidence as the Board determines appropriate.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA7D338C2E992426D86970664925E01AD" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Each Board may conduct site visits of medical facilities of the Department to collect information that the Board considers necessary to carry out this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5FD737DE26D547D7AD0504EBA666F618" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Secretary shall provide to each Board such administrative support services as the Secretary considers necessary for the Board to carry out this section.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HFA4EE7EFCB9841D98D16EC501E3E96D2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of chapter 73 of such title is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 7309 the following new item:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD1928014A23E474781164C09BB5FE7BB" style="USC">
						<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
							<toc-entry level="section">7309A. Pain management boards.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</subsection></section><section id="id7BE67A9EBF7C4D93BDE53C8A8840344B"><enum>105.</enum><header>Study on feasibility and advisability of carrying out pharmacy lock-in program by Department of
			 Veterans Affairs</header>
 <subsection id="idCF3E7E9F94A04E18BFE552D8BAAAC3EA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall conduct a study on the feasibility and advisability of carrying out a pharmacy lock-in program under which veterans at risk for abuse of prescription drugs are permitted to receive prescription drugs only from certain specified pharmacies of the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id7002B907A39C4DC29F452CBBD2E56356"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on the study conducted under subsection (a).</text>
				</subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idC11763BC708F49BB8002FA2E311DD571"><enum>106.</enum><header>Reports and investigation on use of opioids in treatment by Department of Veterans Affairs</header>
				<subsection id="id9477CA5181344641A8B6D2FC372B78BB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Comptroller General report</header>
 <paragraph id="idE8C23F4774B344AFB5BEE71E24521F7F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on the Opioid Safety Initiative of the Department of Veterans Affairs and the opioid prescribing practices of health care providers of the Department.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idD8AE7915B7A84C04A84E1E51DE053E09"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report submitted under paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text> <subparagraph id="id6840A800D35F46D19E4FFACFA18D7FAD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Recommendations on such improvements to the Opioid Safety Initiative of the Department as the Comptroller General considers appropriate.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE6EBDEC7C256413BB9A1EBEF295481E6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Information with respect to—</text> <clause id="id99C3C6D0B25344DF993DFB64C01BFCD9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>deaths resulting from sentinel events involving veterans prescribed opioids by a health care provider of the Department;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id340181C6C199498F99622A765CF8205F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>overall prescription rates and prescriptions indications of opioids at all medical facilities of the Department to treat non-cancer, non-palliative, and non-hospice care patients, including whether each medical facility or health care provider of the Department is among the top ten percent of medical facilities or health care providers of the Department with respect to such prescription rates;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id10cd80a2785b434aa853734131fbef35"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the prescription rates and prescriptions indications of benzodiazepines and opioids concomitantly by health care providers of the Department, including whether each medical facility or health care provider of the Department is among the top ten percent of medical facilities or health care providers of the Department with respect to such prescription rates;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id30c0872469cb4ee3aac5731b4b2779ba"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the practice by health care providers of the Department of prescribing opioids to treat patients without any pain, including to treat patients with mental health disorders other than opioid use disorder; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="ided7a516ecce44450bebd53141accacb9"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the effectiveness of opioid therapy for patients receiving such therapy, including the effectiveness of long-term opioid therapy.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8c84eca99ab94f8e9a9bac38dc869647"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Recommendations with respect to whether sanctions are needed, such as written warnings or performance improvement plans, for health care providers of the Department that are—</text>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7657B23C7E944BAFA10835EE901C9884"><enum>(i)</enum><text>not practicing at a level meeting or exceeding the minimum level standard of care established by the Department; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id59D371A907954D559CE1EB192F2A4D8F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>not following the enhanced guidance with respect to absolute contraindications for opioid therapy set forth in the VA/DOD Clinical Practice Guideline for Management of Opioid Therapy for Chronic Pain, as updated under section 101.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id14208b60a4f244ec95acf2f9718fda35"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Quarterly progress report on implementation of Comptroller General recommendations</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and not later than 30 days after the end of each quarter thereafter, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to the Committee on Veterans Affairs’ of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans Affairs’ of the House of Representatives a progress report detailing the actions by the Department of Veterans Affairs during the period covered by the report to address any outstanding findings and recommendations by the Comptroller General of the United States with respect to the Veterans Health Administration.</text>
				</subsection><subsection id="id6773a60c198849d29b8f2c42be287d14"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Annual report and investigation on opioid therapy</header>
 <paragraph id="id2D6B32552DD5425694B5B28969881C90"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and not less frequently than annually thereafter, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a report that contains, for the one year period preceding the submittal of the report, the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="id9b02417b648b4b3f82160d11af902a3f"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The number of patients and the percentage of the patient population of the Department of Veterans Affairs who were prescribed benzodiazepines and opioids concurrently by a health care provider of the Department.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id124c24355f9a4d879edf8c98042f507a"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The number of patients and the percentage of the patient population of the Department without any pain who were prescribed opioids by a health care provider of the Department, including those who were prescribed benzodiazepines and opioids concurrently.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0e33afa42d0c451fa373dbb92b554b16"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The number of non-cancer, non-palliative, and non-hospice care patients and the percentage of such patients who were treated with opioids by a health care provider of the Department on an inpatient-basis and who also received prescription opioids by mail from the Department while being treated on an inpatient-basis.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD147AEDF55D84673BF8EE0F8CED9199F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The number of non-cancer, non-palliative, and non-hospice care patients and the percentage of such patients who were prescribed opioids concurrently by a health care provider of the Department and a health care provider that is not a health care provider of the Department.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfc3e446eeea34912b266058ffa6c2d15"><enum>(E)</enum><text>With respect to each medical facility of the Department, information on opioids prescribed by health care providers at the facility to treat non-cancer, non-palliative, and non-hospice care patients, including information on—</text>
 <clause id="id04CA5B815F03497192E2BEFC01F35E75"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the prescription rate at which each health care provider at the facility prescribed benzodiazepines and opioids concurrently to such patients and the aggregate such prescription rate for all health care providers at the facility;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id5c739e39d9c14588bfc16abe78856c5b"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the prescription rate at which each health care provider at the facility prescribed benzodiazepines or opioids to such patients to treat conditions for which opioids or benzodiazepines are not an approved treatment and the aggregate such prescription rate for all health care providers at the facility;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id30f74e8aa5294d3bb120175a182558b4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the prescription rate at which each health care provider at the facility prescribed or dispensed mail-order prescriptions of opioids to such patients while such patients were being treated with opioids on an inpatient-basis and the aggregate such prescription rate for all health care providers at the facility; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idCCAD616524534EF5B9A361C0F05E848B"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the prescription rate at which each health care provider at the facility prescribed opioids to such patients who were also concurrently prescribed opioids by a health care provider that is not a health care provider of the Department and the aggregate such prescription rate for all health care providers at the facility.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC08B9C5EB1DF4D1EB3969622268B96DE"><enum>(F)</enum><text>With respect to each medical facility of the Department, the number of times a pharmacist at the facility overrode a critical drug interaction warning with respect to an interaction between opioids and another medication before dispensing a medication to a veteran.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id38F645A3BA87485D84008C291412D84F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Investigation</header><text>If a report submitted under paragraph (1) indicates that a prescription rate described in subparagraph (E) of such paragraph at a medical facility of the Department is among the top ten percent of medical facilities of the Department with respect to such prescription rate, the Secretary shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id98BB075D4DF945C688BCB8C90D40BE5B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>through the Office of the Medical Inspector of the Veterans Health Administration, conduct a full investigation of the medical facility; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1B5E96FA7ACE4C8DA4D30D9FF925A522"><enum>(B)</enum><text>immediately notify the Committee on Veterans Affairs’ of the Senate, the Committee on Veterans Affairs’ of the House of Representatives, and each Member of the Senate and the House of Representatives who represents the area in which the medical facility is located.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="idEE5035CE7F2847E1A43A0E841A7CC2EC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Prescription rate defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>prescription rate</term> means, with respect to a health care provider or medical facility of the Department, each of the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="id31909b59f0ff423eb8f64c15d7935a02"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The number of patients treated with opioids by the health care provider or at the medical facility, as the case may be, divided by the total patient population of that health care provider or medical facility.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id136F592EA1DC4937AF4198116E509F94"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The average number of morphine equivalents per day prescribed by the health care provider or at the medical facility, as the case may be, to patients being treated with opioids.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id19393991175E457CAD77AD19F9B2AD73"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Of the patients being treated with opioids by the health care provider or at the medical facility, as the case may be, the average number of prescriptions of opioids per patient.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section></title><title id="id2F491C54F8AE4036AFEFD0BEF92B0876" style="OLC"><enum>II</enum><header>Patient Advocacy</header>
			<section id="id673540CB06CF4AA2BD0ED9A2C35A4E20"><enum>201.</enum><header>Establishment of Office of Patient Advocacy of the Department of Veterans Affairs</header>
 <subsection id="id27F55E403B1C4A2EACFBB63DE7DAF66B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/73">chapter 73</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id38239381B75B4CC2AD16CBCA72B32ECA" style="USC">
						<section id="id6E3FA9FC30FD40828B47B4E3817EC446"><enum>7309A.</enum><header>Office of Patient Advocacy</header>
 <subsection id="id39d54c38f93a422684899181f1552eec"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established in the Department within the Office of the Under Secretary for Health an office to be known as the <quote>Office of Patient Advocacy</quote> (in this section referred to as the <quote>Office</quote>).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id44d3b7deaa72463b9ae46a93ac1c0e32"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Head</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id73AEFD19F9DE45ADAA32F26D59260778"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Director of the Office of Patient Advocacy shall be the head of the Office.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id91C26F98269E410FBB9E1A9226E71956" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Director of the Office of Patient Advocacy shall be appointed by the Under Secretary for Health from among individuals qualified to perform the duties of the position and shall report directly to the Under Secretary for Health.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id120d4f8860c64f0daee1bdedd688a32c"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Function</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idF9A17FA61D75472A9526CB014BD735E8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The function of the Office is to carry out the Patient Advocacy Program of the Department.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id35ED39519709427F993C335C9EC0B53E" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In carrying out the Patient Advocacy Program of the Department, the Director shall ensure that patient advocates of the Department—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idE0703304AA5C47F4BC08AC0353B326D8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>advocate on behalf of veterans with respect to health care received and sought by veterans under the laws administered by the Secretary;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4F74F69C6E2D481E84D3979478B66ED4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>carry out the responsibilities specified in subsection (d); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id896DCD1352A844A5A3AF0208190CFBB2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>receive training in patient advocacy.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id05CBB5C05CF243C8A75DFC939EF54860"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Patient advocacy responsibilities</header><text>The responsibilities of each patient advocate at a medical facility of the Department are the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="id449a92416dfd4b3c96ade2d69a0523ee"><enum>(1)</enum><text>To resolve complaints by veterans with respect to health care furnished under the laws administered by the Secretary that cannot be resolved at the point of service or at a higher level easily accessible to the veteran.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id9750b4a6a7584206bf0308c8a71b6a32"><enum>(2)</enum><text>To present at various meetings and to various committees the issues experienced by veterans in receiving such health care at such medical facility.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id52884b8d955545fda8d018882ee16f52"><enum>(3)</enum><text>To express to veterans their rights and responsibilities as patients in receiving such health care.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id03f8d3e730be411e8dfe4160b13676d9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>To manage the Patient Advocate Tracking System of the Department at such medical facility.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idf6fcd51e81364dc488ec2e7d1d84245d"><enum>(5)</enum><text>To compile data at such medical facility of complaints made by veterans with respect to the receipt of such health care at such medical facility and the satisfaction of veterans with such health care at such medical facility to determine whether there are trends in such data.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id352e80b1e5da407db4a5827b9f0a803a"><enum>(6)</enum><text>To ensure that a process is in place for the distribution of the data compiled under paragraph (5) to appropriate leaders, committees, services, and staff of the Department.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ide106b360de9e4bc3a36b6ffe9cc1525d"><enum>(7)</enum><text>To identify, not less frequently than quarterly, opportunities for improvements in the furnishing of such health care to veterans at such medical facility based on complaints by veterans.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idb1aace6275f4451688cb8eead4dc6208"><enum>(8)</enum><text>To ensure that any significant complaint by a veteran with respect to such health care is brought to the attention of appropriate staff of the Department to trigger an assessment of whether there needs to be a further analysis of the problem at the facility-wide level.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id1caf03354b34427295a2224f73c805c3"><enum>(9)</enum><text>To support any patient advocacy programs carried out by the Department.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id4d60742a13e7458883ec47115507acdf"><enum>(10)</enum><text>To ensure that all appeals and final decisions with respect to the receipt of such health care are entered into the Patient Advocate Tracking System of the Department.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ida079d9697afd42419b64a728394c4095"><enum>(11)</enum><text>To understand all laws, directives, and other rules with respect to the rights and responsibilities of veterans in receiving such health care, including the appeals processes available to veterans.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id7b0131dab2c9447f8a624c1568d9e2aa"><enum>(12)</enum><text>To ensure that veterans receiving mental health care, or the surrogate decisionmakers for such veterans, are aware of the rights of veterans to seek representation from systems established under section 103 of the Protection and Advocacy for Mentally Ill Individuals Act of 1986 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/10803">42 U.S.C. 10803</external-xref>) to protect and advocate the rights of individuals with mental illness and to investigate incidents of abuse and neglect of such individuals.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id1aad38498b01499e86c1afcb0c2ea15b"><enum>(13)</enum><text>To fulfill requirements established by the Secretary with respect to the inspection of controlled substances.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id0c73c5e60a184daf9bdd17d4d89d9724"><enum>(14)</enum><text>To document potentially threatening behavior and report such behavior to appropriate authorities.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id3DD5A2AF23C74820A8264EED2D6A56B7"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Training</header><text>In providing training to patient advocates under subsection (c)(2)(C), the Director shall ensure that such training is consistent throughout the Department.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id55B6580965944AA2A15758D4D6EA108D"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>Not later than two years after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Jason Simcakoski Memorial Opioid Safety Act</short-title>, and not less frequently than annually thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on the activities conducted by the Office during the period covered by the report.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id1329F13799EE4F22BDAE28CC39D4B17C"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Controlled substance defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>controlled substance</term> has the meaning given that term in section 102 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/802">21 U.S.C. 802</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="id56A4F50BFEEF48EE8E1FA524A7588F35"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of chapter 73 of such title is amended by adding after the item relating to section 7309 the following new item:</text>
					<quoted-block id="id17d9e79c-20ff-4275-ad5f-8eea9bb0a765" style="OLC"><toc><toc-entry idref="id6E3FA9FC30FD40828B47B4E3817EC446" level="section">7309A. Office of Patient Advocacy.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="id824FF6FC69CE4EA5BA48A9E4856E005F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Date fully operational</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall ensure that the Office of Patient Advocacy established in section 7309A of title 38, United States Code, as added by subsection (a), is fully operational not later than the date that is one year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="idEE90788F7C1C42BEBEBC75D65F4552E8"><enum>202.</enum><header>Community meetings on improving care from Department of Veterans Affairs</header>
				<subsection id="id2208ce366cde4d02968524e8a95fe518"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Community meetings</header>
 <paragraph id="id3B38F8CA82B74A3D806283810134142E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Medical centers</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and not less frequently than once every 90 days thereafter, each medical center of the Department of Veterans Affairs shall host a community meeting open to the public on improving health care from the Department.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id94ac008b8404432bb3c86d4c93d0cd1b"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Community based outpatient clinics</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and not less frequently than annually thereafter, each community based outpatient clinic of the Department shall host a community meeting open to the public on improving health care from the Department.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idF9DBD1A99B514D1A8F68BC502F9614AB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Attendance by Director of Veterans Integrated Service Network or designee</header>
 <paragraph id="idAC70A4CBF3484EDC9CC151280C2CC050"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2), each community meeting hosted by a medical center or community based outpatient clinic under subsection (a) shall be attended by the Director of the Veterans Integrated Service Network in which the medical center or community based outpatient clinic, as the case may be, is located, or an employee designated by the Director who works in the office of the Director.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idF380C6347CA640C4B4131F6287F8E5D4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Attendance by Director</header><text>Each Director of a Veterans Integrated Service Network shall attend not less than one community meeting under subsection (a) hosted by each medical center located in the Veterans Integrated Service Network each year.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id6f19fadd18d04adeb7c2f1ffa57a9515"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>Each medical center or community based outpatient clinic hosting a community meeting shall send timely notice of the community meeting to the Committee on Veterans Affairs’ of the Senate, the Committee on Veterans Affairs’ of the House of Representatives, and each Member of the Senate and the House of Representatives who represents the area in which the medical facility is located.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="idab28c8833363475599eb6bc7164eac54"><enum>203.</enum><header>Improvement of awareness of patient advocacy program and patient bill of rights of Department of
 Veterans Affairs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall, in as many prominent locations as appropriate to be seen by the largest percentage of patients and family members of patients at each medical facility of the Department of Veterans Affairs—</text>
 <paragraph id="id13350126eb82499697a1a3464794d2c9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>display the purposes of the Patient Advocacy Program of the Department and the contact information for the patient advocate at such medical facility; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idfb354ecbab3e40589cbc0cdd5290e5a8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>display the rights and responsibilities of—</text> <subparagraph id="idE5CBC8E265D84DEFB595D9114DB49265"><enum>(A)</enum><text>patients and family members of patients at such medical facility; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB2A5B41CB8F0464E8A1D0E6CDA8DFE71"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to community living centers and other residential facilities of the Department, residents and family members of residents at such medical facility.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="id02cc7a266bee4d11934210804bfeec39"><enum>204.</enum><header>Comptroller General Report on Patient Advocacy Program of Department of Veterans Affairs</header>
 <subsection id="id4b1c73b71be84bd88c88520e1fdae7db"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than three years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on the Patient Advocacy Program of the Department of Veterans Affairs (in this section referred to as the <quote>Program</quote>) as carried out under the Office of Patient Advocacy of the Department established in section 7309A of title 38, United States Code, as added by section 201(a).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idbf626c31d4d64755a7f1da42fbefbfa1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report required by subsection (a)—</text> <paragraph id="id3b343aa0079f44409d7066a33c1c38bb"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall include—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id1db3bf6948394df68e604772eb40fb4d"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such recommendations and proposals for improving or modifying the Program as the Comptroller General considers appropriate; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id62893bfcec8c44328c9cb027a17fb091"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such other information with respect to the Program as the Comptroller General considers appropriate; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idefc0b026a37b49bb8cb14905dd56f797"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may include—</text> <subparagraph id="idc9c104264b75433ea84e25f09a89ef45"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of the Program, including—</text>
 <clause id="id4dc6c85db2404e4ea7eb42b2d9045f85"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the purposes of the Program;</text> </clause><clause id="idf4913d06c4a44a789e7b355b08ee8f01"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the activities carried out under the Program; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idfa7a065d3b844659974d3beacc94cb6f"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the sufficiency of the Program in achieving the purposes of the Program;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb999907b27f84df8ad9cfbb4fcffe1ec"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an assessment of the sufficiency of staffing of employees of the Department responsible for carrying out the Program;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id97019a7dc0394fba81df264d4fcf9098"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an assessment of the sufficiency of the training of such employees; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5ed661df75024df99b6a1caa4c9418e7"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an assessment of—</text>
 <clause id="id3D959C6FDC8548228A04E413E4FCB9D7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>awareness of the Program among veterans and their family members; and</text> </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE46F99BBBB104914A76FC7F9F3DA7ED2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the use of the Program by veterans and their family members.</text>
							</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idCFF1439B209F4EDDBCED44A05A5CA49D"><enum>205.</enum><header>Report on transition by veterans between different health care settings</header>
 <subsection id="id56694174F08D4C0CB9F08ACF09D1EBA8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on the transitions undergone by veterans in receiving health care in different health care settings.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id3BEAF44160C04D3B9FC65678DCD70DE0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall include the following:</text> <paragraph id="id1DBCBD0ABEA04F249991316DFD5A128D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An evaluation of the standards of the Department for facilitating and managing the transitions undergone by veterans in receiving health care in different health care settings.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id42694124E4AE4FE9B85AA42B5B51EE3E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An assessment of the case management services of the Department that are available for veterans who are undergoing a transition in health care settings.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id30820aec35c54f6f9c5b2761e31c07b3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An assessment of the coordination in coverage of and consistent access to medications prescribed for patients transitioning from receiving health care from the Department of Defense to receiving health care from the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id99B61D6B4E7349F3989C65CD4D7A4A0E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Such recommendations to improve transitions in health care settings among veterans as the Secretary considers appropriate, including the coordination of drug formularies between the Department of Defense and the Department of Veterans Affairs and the development of care transition plans for patients with complex medical issues.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section></title><title id="id36462EDDF55B41AD88B31BD9E65924C9"><enum>III</enum><header>Complementary and Integrative Health</header>
			<section id="id8B8914EC2E0644078C184EE17605383E"><enum>301.</enum><header>Expansion of research and education on and delivery of complementary and integrative health to
			 veterans</header>
 <subsection id="id7f883221d470436e819591eea69bb7c8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Development of plan To expand research, education, and delivery</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall develop a plan to expand materially and substantially the scope of the effectiveness of research and education on, and delivery and integration of, complementary and integrative health services into the health care services provided to veterans.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id61EF167543EA4251929E15E3B0448DDC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The plan required by subsection (a) shall provide for the following:</text> <paragraph id="id18d9513619084f2098c25a3170de7e24"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Research on the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="idF2E3CBD178C04EAF94087E5AD4B77C6C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The effectiveness of various complementary and integrative health services, including the effectiveness of such services integrated with clinical therapies.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD702B4DEE0214AEA8D0DAE0C3208D461"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Approaches to integrating complementary and integrative health services into other health care services provided by the Department.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idA110FE9E3F8C412086639F891FAA4CEC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Education and training for health care professionals of the Department on the following:</text> <subparagraph id="idD72694146626400E916DDB58E968787B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Complementary and integrative health services selected by the Secretary for purposes of the plan.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idAE484A17CCCF436F81DEE6FCCD5D3B64"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Appropriate uses of such services.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id21465F6D6C814119914E72F979459AE3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Integration of such services into the delivery of health care to veterans.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5ad07d834d944e62aa1cd9c92f3c29f7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Research, education, and clinical activities on complementary and integrative health at centers of innovation at medical centers of the Department.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id4F7BB205238648D5887B30ACFADC56FB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Identification or development of metrics and outcome measures to evaluate the effectiveness of the provision and integration of complementary and integrative health services into the delivery of health care to veterans.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id2f78b31a4a444dac989b005d75a856e6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Integration and delivery of complementary and integrative health services with other health care services provided by the Department.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id55DC924F521448F8B8A3AFA70E423C8C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consultation</header>
 <paragraph id="id00CAC8CFB0224E5D8421435D436419C2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary shall consult with the following:</text> <subparagraph id="id50f3194b32dc43998fdff845c589581e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Director of the National Center for Complementary and Integrative Health of the National Institutes of Health.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0cda4f0a32a5411ba8aa4fe8a0d427b0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Commissioner of Food and Drugs.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id344ade56b5254079b396e3d0ee1db7ac"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Institutions of higher education, private research institutes, and individual researchers with extensive experience in complementary and integrative health and the integration of complementary and integrative health practices into the delivery of health care.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id96adfec7fae14f518cfc2a40e0c77857"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Nationally recognized providers of complementary and integrative health.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfd9ad395493a4e868876cb76aab74c02"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Such other officials, entities, and individuals with expertise on complementary and integrative health as the Secretary considers appropriate.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idADFEDD5B6A924D9DB00B5055FF113999"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Scope of consultation</header><text>The Secretary shall undertake consultation under paragraph (1) in carrying out subsection (a) with respect to the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="id99c6495d22f94ad3b39df6964530136b"><enum>(A)</enum><text>To develop the plan.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6224319e25a6470b8d5de86a761edfb8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>To identify specific complementary and integrative health practices that, on the basis of research findings or promising clinical interventions, are appropriate to include as services to veterans.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5b2d97b82463498594ddcba9127c740e"><enum>(C)</enum><text>To identify barriers to the effective provision and integration of complementary and integrative health services into the delivery of health care to veterans, and to identify mechanisms for overcoming such barriers.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idc2dfdbf0c4bb4f89b128e2d8653ff1de"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id481F8F1F7361445A88DE5756EAC4D065"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Complementary and integrative health defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>complementary and integrative health</term> has the meaning given that term by the National Institutes of Health.</text> </subsection></section><section id="id67312e0292d346d2a87aa91ddc4aec4e"><enum>302.</enum><header>Program on integration of complementary and integrative health within Department of Veterans Affairs medical centers</header> <subsection id="id9d3a433895d9447d96865a9bd79b45ff"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Program required</header><text>Not later than the completion of the development of the plan under section 301, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="id4F6D5D7CB1E54965A4C7D15DF049DC01"><enum>(1)</enum><text>carry out, through the Office of Patient Centered Care and Cultural Transformation of the Department of Veterans Affairs, a program to assess the feasibility and advisability of integrating the delivery of complementary and integrative health services selected by the Secretary with other health care services provided by the Department for veterans with mental health conditions, chronic pain conditions, other chronic conditions, and such other conditions as the Secretary determines appropriate; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idE00BA3D5D4164E4286BC8CE5F64EA02E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in developing the program—</text> <subparagraph id="id797E18A7B54D4A88A5BD045D3E2AF5A7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>use the plan developed under section 301; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idAE1A0F99DB0A4605A91BE5D59AFC1293"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identify and, to the extent practicable, resolve barriers to the provision of complementary and integrative health services selected by the Secretary and the integration of those services with other health care services provided by the Department.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id2135322a44da4370bd1e274216668eb4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Locations</header>
 <paragraph id="ide67259fbeb3e4c81895d42ecc3b0027d"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall carry out the program at not fewer than 15 medical centers of the Department.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id4B1D25AC247E4D68B481BA882D4D7C4D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Polytrauma centers</header><text>Not less than two of the medical centers designated under paragraph (1) shall be located at polytrauma rehabilitation centers of the Department.</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="id932FB1AE2F284CDAB3F725B4E999C83B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Medical centers with high prescription rate of opioids</header>
 <subparagraph id="id133FACE8ED4C41B6A41802D22577FABD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In selecting medical centers under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall give priority to medical centers of the Department at which there is a prescription rate of opioids that is among the top ten percent of medical centers of the Department with respect to such prescription rate.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id422D32A27B42490091F32489D56F420E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Prescription rate defined</header><text>In this paragraph, the term <term>prescription rate</term> means, with respect to a medical center of the Department, each of the following:</text> <clause id="id1B5276FE2E534D42B097A93F43895554"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The number of patients treated with opioids at the medical center divided by the total patient population of that medical center.</text>
 </clause><clause id="idD403F3D8BF55498C88A66F7110C27AC3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The average number of morphine equivalents per day prescribed at the medical center to patients being treated with opioids.</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idC23F434036C94754B1E5DF2798B0EACF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Of the patients being treated with opioids at the medical center, the average number of prescriptions of opioids per patient.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id78c4eaea46e141f7b3365f62539ffe4e"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Selection of locations</header><text>In carrying out the program, the Secretary shall select locations that include the following areas:</text> <subparagraph id="ide0524c62c76e427587d8b062fab2ad11"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Rural areas.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id47c19eade8494a599120eab96b9338fa"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Areas that are not in close proximity to an active duty military installation.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idae889602caa04877bba5a04f9c9b852a"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Areas representing different geographic locations, such as census tracts established by the Bureau of the Census.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id717D79CE0374495B8046A6445071C951"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Provision of services</header><text>Under the program, the Secretary shall provide covered services to covered veterans by integrating complementary and integrative health services with other services provided by the Department at the medical centers designated under subsection (b)(1).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id113da0a9a6c749bf8197620c8e9bfb26"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Covered veterans</header><text>For purposes of the program, a covered veteran is any veteran who—</text> <paragraph id="idf909d2580e4d41a6b6ecbbee0cf51cca"><enum>(1)</enum><text>has a mental health condition diagnosed by a clinician of the Department;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idCF5853B52DFB43988366373634AFC39C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>experiences chronic pain;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idB49A797D667B4443B1E42C1046308D08"><enum>(3)</enum><text>has a chronic condition being treated by a clinician of the Department; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idEC1762AF98A043EFBC96CD14D5004CF3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>is not described in paragraph (1), (2), or (3) and requests to participate in the program or is referred by a clinician of the Department who is treating the veteran.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id7472ca90faad482bbc4a834b40193ea2"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Covered services</header>
 <paragraph id="idADB60F1503164BAC81FF54F4A1A06524"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of the program, covered services are services consisting of complementary and integrative health services as selected by the Secretary.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id20B0D080AB2E4239BB6AF827A5799D1D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administration of services</header><text>Covered services shall be administered under the program as follows:</text> <subparagraph id="ida4880c37328f4c30801e03e978cb72a2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Covered services shall be administered by professionals or other instructors with appropriate training and expertise in complementary and integrative health services who are employees of the Department or with whom the Department enters into an agreement to provide such services.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0c6f61d6b81d47b9bb72415ced9be908"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Covered services shall be included as part of the Patient Aligned Care Teams initiative of the Office of Patient Care Services, Primary Care Program Office, in coordination with the Office of Patient Centered Care and Cultural Transformation.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE6877ED7D35742A38313B20BF0E3A543"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Covered services shall be made available to—</text> <clause id="idD5E5FB63E0AF4B04BCD21CE5D1800492"><enum>(i)</enum><text>covered veterans who have received conventional treatments from the Department for the conditions for which the covered veteran seeks complementary and integrative health services under the program; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idB4A10EFC8D28431F9FE742332BBBBD12"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>covered veterans who have not received conventional treatments from the Department for such conditions.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id9cd6bbb85fba4bf782b65b492c243e39"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Voluntary participation</header><text>The participation of a veteran in the program shall be at the election of the veteran and in consultation with a clinician of the Department.</text>
				</subsection><subsection id="id6ce073dc377c4f48b4975c420b64b778"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header>
 <paragraph id="id3DC7F0D5F4A144FB823225C916348E94"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Quarterly reports</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the commencement of the program and not less frequently than once every 90 days thereafter for the duration of the program, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on the efforts of the Secretary to carry out the program, including a description of the outreach conducted by the Secretary to veterans and community organizations to inform such organizations about the program.</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="idA0A62951EDDA42BCA94EF4B59F70E02B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Final report</header>
 <subparagraph id="id5F51249BE759462AB1CE2A67DC6D77F7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than three years after the date of the commencement of the program, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on the program.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id29B2427A4554444D97AD31E31ED89043"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report submitted under subparagraph (A) shall include the following:</text> <clause id="id8B79D714CE304066BBDD0BDFC04075EF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The findings and conclusions of the Secretary with respect to the program, including with respect to—</text>
 <subclause id="id26EDED89BE1F4CC7AA818548FDE8E519"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the use and efficacy of the complementary and integrative health services established under the program; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idDBE6AAFD5C0546D5AFCAB36E93F25EED"><enum>(II)</enum><text>an assessment of the benefit of the program to covered veterans in mental health diagnoses, pain management, and treatment of chronic illness.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="idDFBEB334EE4A48CE9A8C009FF035D40C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Barriers identified under subsection (a)(2)(B) that were not resolved.</text> </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idFD49EAA710524D96BD95062F64A90EB1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Such recommendations for the continuation or expansion of the program as the Secretary considers appropriate.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idCD3ACCED9A034E80B421383918DC933A"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Complementary and integrative health defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>complementary and integrative health</term> shall have the meaning given that term in section 301(e).</text> </subsection></section><section id="id83DCAA4E21DA4886AC1C6DFB378E71FA"><enum>303.</enum><header>Program on use of wellness programs as complementary approach to pain management and related issues for veterans and family members of veterans</header> <subsection id="id2c7c6773d00d4011aa252d2584a7b60b"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Program required</header> <paragraph id="id2F769D10819E4502A88856454CFA799A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall carry out a program through the award of grants to public or private nonprofit entities to assess the feasibility and advisability of using wellness programs to complement the provision of pain management and related health care services, such as mental health care services, to veterans and family members of veterans.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id56872680C5E24DA7B1046722525564B9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Matters To be addressed</header><text>The program shall be carried out so as to assess the following:</text> <subparagraph id="id20a8af65dfa440c0b26122150800d357"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Means of improving coordination between Federal, State, local, and community providers of health care in the provision of pain management and related health care services to veterans and family members of veterans.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB9A4B5BEEA0F49BA9B7CCBE3BBDD729B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Means of enhancing outreach, and coordination of outreach, by and among providers of health care referred to in subparagraph (A) on the pain management and related health care services available to veterans and family members of veterans.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id463FDD4E279E4CE7A170428867BF1976"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Means of using wellness programs of providers of health care referred to in subparagraph (A) as complements to the provision by the Department of Veterans Affairs of pain management and related health care services to veterans and family members of veterans.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id81548754095e48b7a9466a96e41b7aaa"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Whether wellness programs described in subparagraph (C) are effective in enhancing the quality of life and well-being of veterans and family members of veterans.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id419C1C571B7A40618EBBEBFE9AC7A8D3"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Whether wellness programs described in subparagraph (C) are effective in increasing the adherence of veterans to the primary pain management and related health care services provided such veterans by the Department.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF64063EDAADF49C4B1F4DC99A90DCD9F"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Whether wellness programs described in subparagraph (C) have an impact on the sense of well-being of veterans who receive primary pain management and related health care services from the Department.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id45A4B53D51EC4F3CB666F8E883B2BCA2"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Whether wellness programs described in subparagraph (C) are effective in encouraging veterans receiving health care from the Department to adopt a more healthy lifestyle.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id7F733A6A66934DF88A363EE8F9A6E29A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>The Secretary shall carry out the program for a period of three years beginning on the date that is one year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id52cd2a63e26b4ff88d98a108803dd5c6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Locations</header><text>The Secretary shall carry out the program at facilities of the Department providing pain management and related health care services, such as mental health care services, to veterans and family members of veterans.</text>
				</subsection><subsection id="idE579FA7ED1224C6D84CEBB049033B9C8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Grant proposals</header>
 <paragraph id="idCB8F5D6B95AD464EA5B25164F0673FC6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A public or private nonprofit entity seeking the award of a grant under this section shall submit an application therefor to the Secretary in such form and in such manner as the Secretary may require.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id80191febc81f43bfb7702a8dc9cddbe4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application contents</header><text>Each application submitted under paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text> <subparagraph id="id86df4daaa9ae49b6aa082cf3e66da2f0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A plan to coordinate activities under the program, to the extent possible, with the Federal, State, and local providers of services for veterans to enhance the following:</text>
 <clause id="id2037ABC339AE4E758DB89E3E8D9CE759"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Awareness by veterans of benefits and health care services provided by the Department.</text> </clause><clause id="id4026099F6D254284AC0087FD91D4215F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Outreach efforts to increase the use by veterans of services provided by the Department.</text>
 </clause><clause id="id1760893EC07E45CBA634FCE29A88612B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Educational efforts to inform veterans of the benefits of a healthy and active lifestyle.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id13be0f9932b947f1be50ee899c0189d6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A statement of understanding from the entity submitting the application that, if selected, such entity will be required to report to the Secretary periodically on standardized data and other performance data necessary to evaluate individual outcomes and to facilitate evaluations among entities participating in the program.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id51B869A5E4B24EFCBCA9E3F388FFFEBA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Such other requirements as the Secretary may prescribe.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id9CDB54EE64B446DFA6CF842A0FD5CC41"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Grant uses</header> <paragraph id="idEAF48F65004F456099B73E7D0B92D94F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A public or private nonprofit entity awarded a grant under this section shall use the award for purposes prescribed by the Secretary.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id6D5FE4449EEA4BD491B021D5C195BDBF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible individuals</header><text>In carrying out the purposes prescribed by the Secretary in paragraph (1), a public or private nonprofit entity awarded a grant under this section shall use the award to furnish services only to veterans and family members of veterans.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id756393FC01A84E128B9EAA48DCE97403"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reports</header>
					<paragraph id="iddb1f4ac48f4e41d28af85e587b323541"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Periodic reports</header>
 <subparagraph id="id6D9C1F831019408A9EB75F10483125EB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the commencement of the program, and not less frequently than every 180 days thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the program.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id07a8a350c21c4f09b203f7ae56b8ec1b"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Report elements</header><text>Each report required by subparagraph (A) shall include the following:</text> <clause id="idb92580dec5864ae78a6798f8427de826"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The findings and conclusions of the Secretary with respect to the program during the 180-day period preceding the report.</text>
 </clause><clause id="id0dfa9b909d254f9ea308ade38797bd3e"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>An assessment of the benefits of the program to veterans and their family members during the 180-day period preceding the report.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idf1bd365e4804477dadb5fe3b94110e99"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Final report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the end of the program, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report detailing the recommendations of the Secretary as to the feasibility and advisability of continuing or expanding the program.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8CDA180B02A04418AAA504D7DC836677"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Wellness defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>wellness</term> has the meaning given that term in regulations prescribed by the Secretary for purposes of this section.</text>
				</subsection></section></title><title id="id38C91336CE4741918663FDBDC30565F7" style="OLC"><enum>IV</enum><header>Other Veterans Health Care Matters</header>
 <section id="id12133B22D3CE415482B726F28137B3DD"><enum>401.</enum><header>Additional requirements for hiring of health care providers by Department of Veterans Affairs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall, as part of the hiring process for each health care provider considered for a position at the Department of Veterans Affairs after the date of the enactment of this Act, request from the medical board of each State in which the health care provider has a medical license—</text>
 <paragraph id="id0FBAED4558644C308F94B1F2AA959770"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information on any violation of the requirements of the medical license of the health care provider during the 20-year period preceding the consideration of the health care provider by the Department; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id171541E3D252452A8CF70350037CF167"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information on whether the health care provider has entered into any settlement agreement for a disciplinary charge relating to the practice of medicine by the health care provider.</text>
				</paragraph></section><section id="id4A2F6B7516364A6A87B78F310FE5AE44"><enum>402.</enum><header>Provision of information on health care providers of Department of Veterans Affairs to State
 medical boards</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 552a of title 5, United States Code, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall, with respect to any health care provider of the Department of Veterans Affairs that has violated a requirement of their medical license, provide to the medical board of each State in which the health care provider is licensed detailed information with respect to such violation.</text>
			</section><section id="id399893690B4541C18E17EDFA16A6DCA5"><enum>403.</enum><header>Report on compliance by Department of Veterans Affairs with reviews of health care providers
 leaving the Department or transferring to other facilities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on the compliance by the Department of Veterans Affairs with the policy of the Department—</text>
 <paragraph id="id0103A17245F94543B7624E7D9AEDC917"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to conduct a review of each health care provider of the Department who transfers to another medical facility of the Department or leaves the Department to determine whether there are any concerns, complaints, or allegations of violations relating to the medical practice of the health care provider; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idECAD4C8743CC412E8FDC4BA82351527E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to take appropriate action with respect to any such concern, complaint, or allegation.</text> </paragraph></section></title><title id="id067B5B2E53DC49E0A6F5900C7348DFF0" style="OLC"><enum>V</enum><header>Other Veterans Matters</header> <section id="idE67F3326AC6C440EB01E3402D8C60FF4"><enum>501.</enum><header>Department of Veterans Affairs program of internal audits</header> <subsection id="idA5B39AF4DFDE422C92DC448B8004F159"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/5">chapter 5</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/527">section 527</external-xref> the following new section:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id971942E29B0E4D37AD8D72B1D8505EFA" style="USC">
						<section id="idC89F3085A46C4BE6805F0084F64E37C5"><enum>527A.</enum><header>Program of internal audits</header>
 <subsection id="id483389A502034AB08BFD3C046E64805E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Program required</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idAE229971FF3D4DFFB1EFEDCC63CC76D2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary shall carry out a program of internal audits and self-analysis to improve the furnishing of benefits and health care to veterans and their families.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idC05DB94FF6714FDFB11A4C7A9A731D79" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Secretary shall carry out the program required by paragraph (1) through an office the Secretary shall establish for purposes of the program within the office of the Secretary that is interdisciplinary and independent of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idC21F2987FF404FFF8599FAF25B2A37E3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the other offices within the office of the Secretary; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD9428B2B9895442783956EFF87EA97E3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the covered administrations (or functions of such administrations), staff organizations, and staff offices identified under subsection (b)(1)(A).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id6751D7F71B654DF28383698DE4AB298D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Program requirements</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id91A2ECD0DDB84D868912CA53D9A97962"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In carrying out the program required by subsection (a), the Secretary shall—</text> <subparagraph id="id3383CD8FC4B046869684C87AF2F2366B" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>conduct periodic risk assessments of the Department to identify those covered administrations (or functions of such administrations), staff organizations, and staff offices of the Department the audit of which would lead towards the greatest improvement in the furnishing of benefits and health care to veterans and their families;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC31D679E667947C4BE5AD51A782EED3D" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>develop plans that are informed by the risk assessments conducted under paragraph (1) to conduct internal audits of the covered administrations (or functions of such administrations), staff organizations, and staff offices identified under subparagraph (A); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1BC0D827AB5A4C34A9F8462578B150BE" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>conduct internal audits in accordance with the plans developed pursuant to subparagraph (B).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idDA9DAECF13554BA898DBD5AD26D49BF3" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Secretary shall carry out under the program required by subsection (a) an audit of not fewer than five covered administrations (or functions of such administrations), staff organizations, or staff offices of the Department each year.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id67F1DD092210460ABCB752CFB9766794" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In identifying covered administrations (or functions of such administrations), staff organizations, and staff offices of the Department under paragraph (1)(A), the Secretary shall accord priority to the covered administrations and functions of such administrations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id7C7A8C092FC241F599DBE611C31FA5FB" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id135BCFE46AA347B1B702485C68FAAADA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>For purposes of this subsection, the covered administrations of the Department are the following:</text> <clause id="idDAA9B0211018430BA967B3395E37DF75" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The National Cemetery Administration.</text>
 </clause><clause id="id847916CD6EB94ABAB11F1249D76AC31E" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The Veterans Benefits Administration.</text> </clause><clause id="idB38ABA4A00E348E1816CB928C6780145" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The Veterans Health Administration.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id70323279C65345F5BB7386FF27FCC7A4" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>For purposes this subsection, the covered staff organizations of the Department are the following:</text> <clause id="idaac77865b080479e80105be9b81d7ed2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The Office of Acquisition, Logistics, and Construction.</text>
 </clause><clause id="idb79fe2abfcf540da9801ede95cc5b887"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The Advisory Committee Management Office.</text> </clause><clause id="ida928b68dce4b49dabe7422aebb6b4d17"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The Board of Veterans' Appeals.</text>
 </clause><clause id="idf91c8316f299422e950c18a734278ae4"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The Center for Faith-Based and Neighborhood Partnerships.</text> </clause><clause id="idb44821f53a8a48bbab43f18151c5544a"><enum>(v)</enum><text>The Center for Minority Veterans.</text>
 </clause><clause id="ide3b6c64f47d44839b0e890eb305ac5d0"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>The Center for Women Veterans.</text> </clause><clause id="id5279203d3d8d4f3790ccc4ec7b194002"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>The Office of General Counsel.</text>
 </clause><clause id="idc39a64f2cdd74234a023a1f780a67865"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>The Office of Regulation Policy and Management.</text> </clause><clause id="id539a6264660747e98649e96abddad079"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>The Office of Employment Discrimination Complaint Adjudication.</text>
 </clause><clause id="id6a37e20860814ce7af08132e65bb0063"><enum>(x)</enum><text>The Office of Interagency Care and Benefits Coordination.</text> </clause><clause id="idfdbc92c3f33141caaefdfcb668a35827"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>The Office of Small and Disadvantaged Business Utilization.</text>
 </clause><clause id="idf2807bef7d3348de9730d8b86f883fb9"><enum>(xii)</enum><text>The Office of Survivors Assistance.</text> </clause><clause id="idcb4605bea33b4139805f4fe0a9c7221c"><enum>(xiii)</enum><text>The Veterans' Service Organizations Liaison.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id877EC4C2E0DA49AEAFAE77EB7AB162B8" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>For purposes of this subsection, the covered staff offices of the Department are the following:</text> <clause id="ida181fc15f9bf4a3795abe3e25535faf2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The office of the Assistant Secretary for Congressional and Legislative Affairs.</text>
 </clause><clause id="id35cf7833e6d8420f83e15d6bcc21233f"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The office of the Assistant Secretary for Human Resources and Administration.</text> </clause><clause id="id58bcb251d36045efaa11f9a299346223"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The office of the Assistant Secretary for Information and Technology.</text>
 </clause><clause id="idaa933f02c70143ba86aa48e15621c3c3"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The Office of Management.</text> </clause><clause id="id194840e574a34afa8d97022df3c65b84"><enum>(v)</enum><text>The office of the Assistant Secretary for Operations, Security, and Preparedness.</text>
 </clause><clause id="id795da8cf0602492aaca0151a1ef2b654"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>The office of the Assistant Secretary for Policy and Planning.</text> </clause><clause id="idca7652a4f91d4872a2e5e50bd0f1dac5"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>The office of the Assistant Secretary for Public and Intergovernmental Affairs.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idB938615A4490425B857DE209EA151783"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reports</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id32425BC655914842BB0CD99668AA3259"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Not later than 90 days after completing an audit under the program required by subsection (a), the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on the audit.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id341475C58E014C4580B069DA360EE76E" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Each report submitted under paragraph (1) with respect to an audit shall include the following:</text> <subparagraph id="id1654BA50884646A0AC970B6D3BD3364F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A summary of the audit.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id488B435A39014816924D27247234F0EF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The findings of the Secretary with respect to the audit.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF6A93C29737F4A35B8058B34CEDA43F3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Such recommendations as the Secretary may have for legislative or administrative action to improve the furnishing of benefits and health care to veterans and their families.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1F7D6C4F5F4B4587ADC1764CE1DDF404" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In this subsection, the term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> includes—</text> <subparagraph id="idBBCD0AF8FC244078923EBACEDB98B921"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, the Committee on Appropriations, and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7BA6CDA6A2CB4B99B729B8206E1A5AA0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, the Committee on Appropriations, and the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="id8805903F11164D73ADF983F6143C62C6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>First risk assessment</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall complete the first risk assessment required by section 527A(b)(1)(A) of such title, as added by subsection (a), by not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id4BC7F93FBE7C4070A7D64703CD324725"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of chapter 5 of such title is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 527 the following new item:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idCD610A005848448E9D95ECA71421904E" style="OLC"><toc><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">527A. Program of internal audits.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></title></legis-body>
</bill>


