<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Placed-on-Calendar-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S2078 PCS: United States Commission on International Religious Freedom Reauthorization Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><calendar>Calendar No. 238</calendar><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2078</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date>September 24, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S310">Mr. Corker</sponsor>, from the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name>, reported the following original bill; which was read twice and placed on the calendar</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To reauthorize the United States Commission on International Religious Freedom, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body>
 <section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>United States Commission on International Religious Freedom Reauthorization Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </section><section id="id6925af03e8214b1ea1a831caa8931b41"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of the Congress that the United States Commission on International Religious Freedom—</text>
 <paragraph id="id6800C199C76C40EEBAC13D815013A37C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">was created by Congress to independently assess and to accurately and unflinchingly describe threats to religious freedom around the world; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id30669d91ea4f4f64946df08f03159238"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in carrying out its prescribed duties, should use its authorized powers to ensure that efforts by the United States to advance religious freedom abroad are timely, appropriate to the circumstances, prudent, and effective.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="id653b955ac474463fa3e6526fe98ac943"><enum>3.</enum><header>Extension of authority</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 209 of the International Religious Freedom Act of 1998 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/6436">22 U.S.C. 6436</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>September 30, 2015</quote> and inserting <quote>September 30, 2019</quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="id63ecdfc9e66f475491303741295c086a"><enum>4.</enum><header>Strategic plan</header>
 <subsection id="id9dc12402c1a742c5a6579d8558f50526"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> <paragraph id="id01ffbc4ba86c4b3992dcd3f7fa4e8cb8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id3a9810bd90a1445a89f17e9d57792812"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate</committee-name>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id03F6F5F29DD046C48CFFFA6BC2D86EEC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives</committee-name>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9CF7F248E4F74B9DB5A469D88E54D23E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSAP00">Committee on Appropriations of the Senate</committee-name>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9E5AF15871EE46D1AA2B5E64B882A3EF"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives</committee-name>.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id8f5b8d39607b4a47b436382f07a1a4fc"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the United States Commission on International Religious Freedom established under section 201 of the International Religious Freedom Act of 1998 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/6431">22 U.S.C. 6431</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id3023ac49e1154813a0b26876a770801b"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Commissioner</header><text>The term <term>Commissioner</term> means a member of the Commission.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id16b84144bf4c4d5ea1eca4740eafbf71"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Vice chair</header><text>The term <term>Vice Chair</term> means the Vice Chair of the Commission who was appointed to such position by an elected official from the political party that is different from the political party of the elected official who appointed the Chair of the Commission.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idf5b9e31643944cafa9feed30c1e8bc98"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Strategic policy and organizational review planning process</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and not less frequently than biennially thereafter, the Chair and Vice Chair of the Commission, in coordination with the Commissioners, the Ambassador-at-Large for International Religious Freedom, Commission staff, and others jointly selected by the Chair and Vice Chair, shall carry out a strategic policy and organizational review planning process that includes—</text>
 <paragraph id="id3148800fa56643d0a076491bded59360"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a review of the duties set forth in section 202 of the International Religious Freedom Act of 1998 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/6432">22 U.S.C. 6432</external-xref>) and the powers set forth in section 203 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/6432a">22 U.S.C. 6432a</external-xref>);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id1F041887B6734C61B9F26B3D98F501B0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the preparation of a written description of prioritized actions that the Commission is required to complete to fulfill the strategic plan required under subsection (d);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="iddba4ef3e27e142b3b892c853beb38a2c"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a review of the scope, content, and timing of the Commission’s annual report and any required changes; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id254ed311deed4ceba50d77af6e9987b7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a review of the personnel policies set forth in section 204 of the International Religious Freedom Act of 1998 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/6432b">22 U.S.C. 6432b</external-xref>) and any required changes to such policies.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id62a9422b4fbc4fff9483ed0e148d32e4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Unanimous agreement</header>
 <paragraph id="id17E830679D3048CCB8FFF744DE29CB62"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To the greatest extent possible, the Chair, Vice Chair, and all of the Commissioners shall ensure that this section is implemented in a manner that results in unanimous agreement among the Commissioners with regard to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id54EBA958BC804263BC51E05DCCED0330"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the strategic policy and organizational review planning process required under subsection (b); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE4DE829C8A434120B99BD20B94D36DD9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the strategic plan required under subsection (d).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id32bcdebf0fc9420f86ad20869baac3c5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Alternative approval process</header><text>If unanimous agreement under paragraph (1) is not possible, items for inclusion in the strategic plan may, at the joint discretion of the Chair and Vice Chair, be approved by an affirmative vote of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id2A667C84324C4E0B83E1F01F3CE4BE11"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a majority of Commissioners appointed by an elected official from the political party of the President; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id63DF98A4BF154792A814CFC9E6EA5F28"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a majority of Commissioners appointed by an elected official from the political party that is not the party of the President.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id88e741f54fa544b3bf5ed33bdad44a1b"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Submission of strategic plan</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of the Act, and not less frequently than biennially thereafter, the Chair and Vice Chair of the Commission shall jointly submit, to the appropriate congressional committees, a written strategic plan that includes—</text>
 <paragraph id="id9b009b5fed124f49a0fdf9b1f9f80b29"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a description of prioritized actions for the Commission for a period of time to be specified by the Commissioners;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id18e6fd6372b744f6baae3843a87f0877"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of any changes the Commission considers necessary with regard to the scope, content, and timing of the Commission’s annual report;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idac4219db955b4ec8bdac9a9b35fc1532"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a description of any changes the Commission considers necessary with regard to personnel matters; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idaed4ad9206924a92b3ddf493149d811c"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the Commission’s funding requirements for the period covered by the strategic plan.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5a9bbe669e0049819d8b2e2b2ee9b8aa"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Pending issues</header><text>The strategic plan required under subsection (d) may identify any issues or proposals that have not yet been resolved by the Commission.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="ide5dfd7d284bd4698b58e59879eb3c818"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Implementation of personnel provisions and annual report</header><text>Notwithstanding section 204(a) and 205(a) of the International Religious Freedom Act of 1998 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/6432b">22 U.S.C. 6432b(a)</external-xref> and 6533(a)), the Commission is authorized to implement provisions related to personnel and the Commission’s annual report that are included in the strategic plan submitted pursuant to this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id74bd62b27ac0493fb85e9f782ddebbad"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Congressional oversight</header><text>Upon request, the Commission shall—</text> <paragraph id="id73FF60F83F79490C88D6A750DF4D9BAA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>make available for inspection any information and documents requested by the appropriate congressional committees; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idCD08D86023534F81B6F18974EBAF70B1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>respond to any requests to provide testimony before the appropriate congressional committees.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id0d7749caddd543f5ae517af10eea7559"><enum>5.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 207 of the International Religious Freedom Act of 1998 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/6435">22 U.S.C. 6435</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5D09422B81D642758583AE3D09F5F24C" style="OLC">
				<section id="id4E19EF718B4F4F8E8D642061EDF072D3"><enum>207.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
 <subsection id="id05df0f26e33d4111a39a807fa53bab4b"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Commission $3,500,000 for each of the fiscal years 2016 to 2019 to carry out the provisions of this Act and section 4 of the <short-title>United States Commission on International Religious Freedom Reauthorization Act of 2015</short-title>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id21289945708f4dc99e22352bb7f1515e"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Availability of funds</header><text>Amounts authorized to be appropriated under subsection (a) shall remain available until the earlier of—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idFAC62C662AA04815A7715FA13B1594BB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the date on which they have been expended; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3C3FB8A60845419D92FFABCFA202E58C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the date on which the Commission is terminated under section 209.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5F032864F3C44EA89A06E0F55521389A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>In each fiscal year, the Commission shall only be authorized to expend amounts that have been appropriated pursuant to subsection (a) if the Commission—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id813BC8FE29C84BEF8E981ADE622C4596"><enum>(1)</enum><text>complies with the requirements set forth in section 4 of the <short-title>United States Commission on International Religious Freedom Reauthorization Act of 2015</short-title>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id377524E83B5743DDBF878D104BCB6278"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submits the annual financial report required under section 208(e) to the appropriate congressional committees.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body><endorsement><action-date>September 24, 2015</action-date><action-desc>Read twice and placed on the calendar</action-desc></endorsement></bill>


