<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1643 RS: Ensuring the Safety and Security of Iranian Dissidents in Iraq Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-06-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><calendar>Calendar No. 133</calendar><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1643</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150623">June 23, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S342">Mr. Blunt</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><action stage="Reported-in-Senate"><action-date>June 25, 2015</action-date><action-desc>Reported by <sponsor name-id="S310">Mr. Corker</sponsor>, with an amendment</action-desc><action-instruction>Omit the part struck through and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require a report on actions to secure the safety and security of dissidents housed at Camp
			 Liberty, Iraq.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body>
 <section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Ensuring the Safety and Security of Iranian Dissidents in Iraq Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </section><section id="id4CAD12AE8A4B4EBEA48899C773E5EF62"><enum>2.</enum><header>Report on actions to secure the safety and security of dissidents housed at Camp Liberty, Iraq</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"><deleted-phrase reported-display-style="strikethrough">Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall certify, in writing, to the committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives whether or not the Central Government of Iraq is taking appropriate and sufficient actions to ensure the safety and security of dissidents housed at Camp Liberty, Iraq.</deleted-phrase></text>
 <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8F34807A98CE4D638A763782B943027A"><enum></enum><text><added-phrase reported-display-style="italic">Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall submit to the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives a written report setting forth an assessment of whether the Central Government of Iraq is taking appropriate and sufficient actions to ensure the safety and security of dissidents housed at Camp Liberty, Iraq. </added-phrase></text></subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement><action-date>June 25, 2015</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment</action-desc></endorsement></bill>


