<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S2187 IS: FDA Regulatory Efficiency Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-10-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 2187</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151021">October 21, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S356">Mr. Donnelly</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S377">Mr. Gardner</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To establish a third-party quality system assessment program.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>FDA Regulatory Efficiency Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="HE368FE389F9A486CA08454C91DC33D85"><enum>2.</enum><header>Third-party quality system assessment</header>
 <subsection id="HA66205A8430C488BA8E01ECA1BD8E372"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of third-Party quality system assessment program</header><text>Chapter V of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act is amended by inserting after section 524A (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/360n-1">21 U.S.C. 360n–1</external-xref>) the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H72960DCE0E22461498BD4A5DA05739D7" style="OLC">
					<section id="H38D47817189E40A6A01F078CAF6912FF"><enum>524B.</enum><header>Third-party quality system assessment</header>
						<subsection id="HC2EF029F6457448A923FC157E6DF08D8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Accreditation and assessment</header>
 <paragraph id="H7963A7F916B34510A1A6AD94EEE3BE4C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general; certification of device quality system</header><text>The Secretary shall, in accordance with this section, establish a third-party quality system assessment program—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HC185138487CE44F283F638DAEB8F9D2F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to accredit persons to assess whether a requestor’s quality system, including its design controls, can reasonably assure the safety and effectiveness of in-scope devices subject to device-related changes;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF3EB63FC83274EF19991EA15DB7510E4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>under which accredited persons shall (as applicable) certify that a requestor’s quality system meets the criteria included in the guidance issued under paragraph (5) with respect to the in-scope devices at issue; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC57839D8CC1A48468DBF54140CC0EB13"><enum>(C)</enum><text>under which the Secretary shall rely on such certifications for purposes of determining the safety and effectiveness (or as applicable, substantial equivalence) of in-scope devices subject to the device-related changes involved, in lieu of compliance with the following submission requirements:</text>
 <clause id="HE607093364F9486D85CCCAB43826DF08"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A premarket notification.</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="H18974ED0D8E54CC3932AA737B7E54C02"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A 30-day notice.</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HCCA37B5B97BE43CE89FEAFD442D5A238"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>A Special PMA supplement.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H333928D3D030458998A3F1C1DB84661E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H3D5B55FFF14B4E43AE17F1B92E2C714E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the term <quote>device-related changes</quote> means changes made by a requestor with respect to in-scope devices, which are—</text> <clause id="H4AAC5DA121C84803A40FB929BC4C1836"><enum>(i)</enum><text>changes to a device found to be substantially equivalent under subsections (f)(1) and (i) of section 513 to a predicate device, that—</text>
 <subclause id="H33E54551F58248C49B32E2C8EAE43374"><enum>(I)</enum><text>would otherwise be subject to a premarket notification; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="HDA55A4FC76574850AE423AC96CFB4946"><enum>(II)</enum><text>do not alter—</text>
 <item id="H5AB62D0AC85248B08166CAA6A3DEC5D6"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the intended use of the changed device; or</text> </item><item id="HA5339207F9904592A99BC540DFA7CA89"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the fundamental scientific technology of such device;</text>
 </item></subclause></clause><clause id="H7ACAF1609FF4469EBF8E9D5095F7D4CD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>manufacturing changes subject to a 30-day notice;</text> </clause><clause id="HE0C6C8E6039640BC9149771B9A150ABB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>changes that qualify for a Special PMA Supplement; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H2A2C07FA24E34729B94A1B4B9987D136"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>such other changes relating to the devices or the device manufacturing process as the Secretary determines appropriate;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1A23F2B9349D46C9A3A79DCD77A098F7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the term <quote>in-scope device</quote> means a device within the scope of devices agreed to by the requestor and the accredited person for purposes of a request for certification under this section;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD098D6DC8E614CB6887FA6E01E2736CF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the term <quote>premarket notification</quote> means a premarket notification under section 510(k);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6D1F54DE43BF4115BF551DEEC46F8ED5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the term <quote>quality system</quote> means the methods used in, and the facilities and controls used for, the design, manufacture, packaging, labeling, storage, installation, and servicing of devices, as described in section 520(f);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H56CC7607621044029CB724BCF635C453"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the term <quote>requestor</quote> means a device manufacturer that is seeking certification under this section of a quality system used by such manufacturer;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H72A9610C97BC41A6811AC30FC33015C0"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the term <quote>Special PMA</quote> means a PMA supplement under section 814.39(d) of title 21, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulations); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H1D9AC313729042D8A5E861A63B68D926"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the term <quote>30-day notice</quote> means a notice described in section 515(d)(6).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF86407BBCB794E3993ACE548130E9D04"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Accreditation process; accreditation renewal</header><text>Except as inconsistent with this section, the process and qualifications for accreditation of persons and renewal of such accreditation under section 704(g) shall apply with respect to accreditation of persons and renewal of such accreditation under this section.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="H8F1816A801A143ADAB56B260885F07A2"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Use of accredited parties to conduct assessments</header>
								<subparagraph id="H85D6B592F7744C939C3BE49F47CB2C22"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Initiation of assessment services</header>
 <clause id="H0B01996E70DB4C0A94B4C7701B0E865E"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Date assessments authorized</header><text>Beginning after the date on which the final guidance is issued under paragraph (5), an accredited person may conduct an assessment under this section.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3A7F0EC3CA2A429387E80DCFB69DA92C"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Initiation of assessments</header><text>Use of one or more accredited persons to assess a requestor’s quality system under this section with respect to in-scope devices shall be at the initiation of the person who registers and lists the devices at issue under section 510.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H22DFD91E529B413F972D07B6C58DFBA8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Compensation</header><text>Compensation for such accredited persons shall—</text> <clause id="H9EA2D4526362410482A8FC20B3A78B25"><enum>(i)</enum><text>be determined by agreement between the accredited person and the person who engages the services of the accredited person; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H0D596A0EEC9D4E06A0BCD1CE93D3EB22"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>be paid by the person who engages such services.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBFBBAF0D9A8B416590EE48037222FD44"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Accredited person selection</header><text>Each person who chooses to use an accredited person to assess a requestor’s quality system, as described in this section, shall select the accredited person from a list of such persons published by the Secretary in accordance with section 704(g)(4).</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2B973D6B06664935B845CFFD09DFD7FC"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Guidance; criteria for certification</header>
 <subparagraph id="H1D01B09FD0AF44CDAA855AF8F94587D9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The criteria for certification of a quality system under this section shall be as specified by the Secretary in guidance issued under this paragraph.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0D869B11A6024548BA2E36C8E4B1D47B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contents; criteria</header><text>The guidance under this paragraph shall include specification of—</text> <clause id="H1782F14884D748D687A37D7D5B3F0BC1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>evaluative criteria to be used by an accredited person to assess and, as applicable, certify a requestor’s quality system under this section with respect to in-scope devices; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H0C4F01C6428D44B990EAAE2D0C40CBD1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>criteria for accredited persons to apply for a waiver of, and exemptions from, the criteria under clause (i).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H49803853A9D04BF1A94DE58DE899FE02"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Timeframe for issuing guidance</header><text>The Secretary shall issue under this paragraph—</text> <clause id="H460BBB6B46524590BA40EA714D93EB3B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>draft guidance not later than 12 months after the enactment of the <short-title>FDA Regulatory Efficiency Act</short-title>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD186440905D04078A55F8020F3DD2A75"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>final guidance not later than 12 months after issuance of the draft guidance under clause (i).</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H534DC154F1B840AB943EA0CBA5BE9223"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of third-Party assessment</header> <paragraph id="H633D5A5D85194336855C34090BF80D6C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Assessment summary; certification</header> <subparagraph id="H63CED4E6E3624A1592EC77A4B7B6C721"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Submission of assessment to secretary</header><text>An accredited person who assesses a requestor’s quality system under subsection (a) shall submit to the Secretary a summary of the assessment—</text>
 <clause id="H4F99D5CA828A4A33AE2693CEE634FCFD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>within 30 days of the assessment; and</text> </clause><clause id="HF3ADD48678764A6AA891B1D35080B14F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>which shall include (as applicable)—</text>
 <subclause id="H48F9D0F86D4F49209B8354EFED88BDAF"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the accredited person’s certification that the requestor has satisfied the criteria specified in the guidance issued under subsection (a)(5) for quality system certification with respect to the in-scope devices at issue; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HDD6D67DA712647758895CBE01350DF56"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any waivers or exemptions from such criteria applied by the accredited person.</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB04A036BCA6849CDAA37F9623FCD5040"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Treatment of assessments</header><text>Subject to action by the Secretary under subparagraph (C), with respect to assessments which include a certification under this section—</text>
 <clause id="H849D59E201E340CC9F30EDF393035C90"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Secretary’s review of the assessment summary shall be deemed complete on the day that is 30 days after the date on which the Secretary receives the summary under subparagraph (A); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H589B564C63F44E399BF47BB739913EC2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the assessment summary and certification of the quality system of a requestor shall be deemed accepted by the Secretary on such 30th day.</text>
									</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA776D07EF9B64FF998D4FE6908893776"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Actions by secretary</header>
 <clause id="H503D184A52D540DE852B750C311B1250"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Within 30 days of receiving an assessment summary and certification under subparagraph (A), the Secretary may, by written notice to the accredited person submitting such assessment certification, deem any such certification to be provisional beyond such 30-day period, suspended pending further review by the Secretary, or otherwise qualified or cancelled, based on the Secretary’s determination that (as applicable)—</text>
 <subclause id="H1CB883E599FE4A50B3CEF6CDBEBDD414"><enum>(I)</enum><text>additional information is needed to support such certification;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H6B80558B7B144AEF8A3806A4A4EF6CD2"><enum>(II)</enum><text>such assessment or certification is unwarranted; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HC8D5334DA63C4389B606963CFA5E841B"><enum>(III)</enum><text>such action with regard to the certification is otherwise justified according to such factors and criteria as the Secretary finds appropriate.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H3D861746BCAD424C85E16ABCC7D92794"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Acceptance of certification</header><text>If following action by the Secretary under clause (i) with respect to a certification, the Secretary determines that such certification is acceptable, the Secretary shall issue written notice to the applicable accredited person indicating such acceptance.</text>
									</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H57B62DB5B95840A7AF4D20DFFDC4FC11"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notifications to Secretary by certified requestors or accredited persons for program evaluation
			 purposes</header>
 <subparagraph id="HCF16D12EE6BF412BAD014391ABE53614"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Annual summary report for device-related changes otherwise subject to premarket notification</header><text>A requestor whose quality system is certified under this section that effectuates device-related changes with respect to in-scope devices, without prior submission of a premarket notification, shall ensure that an annual summary report is submitted to the Secretary by the accredited person which—</text>
 <clause id="H5ABD3C3372D2495689D8898E1DA28A72"><enum>(i)</enum><text>describes the changes made to the in-scope device; and</text> </clause><clause id="HEF50F75792EC4C79A82A784545011E3A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>indicates the effective dates of such changes.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7857C0B0CD9C4370A9799316A883A374"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Periodic notification for manufacturing changes otherwise subject to 30-day notice</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A requestor whose quality system is certified under this section that effectuates device-related changes with respect to in-scope devices, without prior submission of a 30-day notice, shall provide notification to the Secretary of such changes in the requestor’s next periodic report under section 814.84(b) of title 21, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation). Such notification shall—</text>
 <clause id="H5AFA3DCF82BB45E68D0FDD8DF669C9A6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>describe the changes made; and</text> </clause><clause id="HD6AB5CCB2928415D8A69A893F02F1441"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>indicate the effective dates of such changes.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF095B5BA5B444D99A6125E3E1F5A6C48"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Periodic notification for device-related changes otherwise subject to special pma supplement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A requestor whose quality system is certified under this section that effectuates device-related changes with respect to in-scope devices, without prior submission of a Special PMA Supplement, shall provide notification to the Secretary of such changes in the requestor’s next periodic report under section 814.84(b) of title 21, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation). Such notification shall—</text>
 <clause id="H7E27DD32EB5A49C58AF4C13F10AD34CD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>describe the changes made, including a full explanation of the basis for the changes; and</text> </clause><clause id="HC2BAB7D1938C4DE98A7D9F1CD09696D3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>indicate the effective dates of such changes.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEBFA0993B6744D1B86B7F0AEEE17B5CC"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Use of notifications for program evaluation purposes</header><text>Information submitted to the Secretary under subparagraphs (A) through (C) shall be used by the Secretary for purposes of the program evaluation under subsection (d).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9BAFAE62AE6A44ADAA1363EE33A3E978"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duration and effect of certification</header><text>A certification under this section—</text> <paragraph id="H386DC9355E474EBFB4D8B02F9DBA8FB1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall remain in effect for a period of 2 years from the date such certification is accepted by the Secretary, subject to paragraph (6);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0B035615011647D99666C25A4CE29B0B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may be renewed through the process described in subsection (a)(3);</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7B57CE544FB24F4A898F57DAF71760A4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>shall continue to apply with respect to device-related changes made during such 2-year period, provided the certification remains in effect, irrespective of whether such certification is renewed after such 2-year period;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEADFF2D94ACC48C093B3FD150CCBCE19"><enum>(4)</enum><text>shall have no effect on the need to comply with applicable submission requirements specified in subsection (a)(1)(C) with respect to any change pertaining to in-scope devices which is not a device-related change under subsection (a)(2);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H997F6CCAD71F4C2BB06CA58885792C87"><enum>(5)</enum><text>shall have no effect on the authority of the Secretary to conduct an inspection or otherwise determine whether the requestor has complied with the applicable requirements of this Act; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9E7CEB42267C4F2E8930F3AB8ACD149C"><enum>(6)</enum><text>may be revoked by the Secretary upon a determination that the requestor’s quality system no longer meets the criteria specified in the guidance issued under subsection (a)(5) with respect to the in-scope devices at issue.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE95C5EF9569349A5AA1BBEA293E9262F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Notice of revocation</header><text>The Secretary shall provide written notification to the requestor of a revocation pursuant to subsection (c)(6) not later than 10 business days after the determination described in such subsection. Upon receipt of the written notification, the requestor shall satisfy the applicable submission requirements specified in subsection (a)(1)(C) for any device-related changes effectuated after the date of such determination. After such revocation, such requestor is eligible to seek re-certification under this section of its quality system.</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="H3B77130EBA4149B387054239C27F217B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Program evaluation; sunset</header>
							<paragraph id="HD0662DB5A09C425DB4D5DA681613BC9E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Program evaluation and report</header>
 <subparagraph id="H3E121590FB354655B71F5A3D589D2E24"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text>The Secretary shall complete an evaluation of the third-party quality system assessment program under this section no later than January 31, 2021, based on—</text>
 <clause id="H7CE9227FCB024CA9A31B22B913BC0210"><enum>(i)</enum><text>analysis of information from a representative group of device manufacturers obtained from notifications provided by certified requestors or accredited persons under subsection (b)(2); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H63C8AFC18DC045EEA21F82753CEFBAC4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>such other available information and data as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA8AE5AAED6C741CCAFCBB99B2AD06CCA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Report</header><text>No later than 1 year after completing the evaluation under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall issue a report of the evaluation’s findings on the website of the Food and Drug Administration, which shall include the Secretary’s recommendations with respect to continuation and as applicable expansion of the program under this section to encompass—</text>
 <clause id="H3975AF079BD1464085A22C8972C84195"><enum>(i)</enum><text>device submissions beyond those identified in subsection (a)(1)(C); and</text> </clause><clause id="HECB60229257446BCA8FBC5EE19F07436"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>device changes beyond those described in subsection (a)(2)(A).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2868B75CA3EE43979B3C9838743B0A5B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>This section shall cease to be effective October 1, 2022.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H80CA22712C5F4433A2B9F91BC5893660"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit the authority of the Secretary to request and review the complete assessment of a certified requestor under this section on a for-cause basis.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="HCD5AC7216E3548B28B3A1F7D5EE24F29"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H2B7A8D11BF774147BD3E1950AD152774"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Requirements for premarket approval supplements</header><text>Section 515(d)(6)(A)(i) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/360e">21 U.S.C. 360e(d)(5)(A)(i)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>subject to section 524B,</quote> after <quote>that affects safety or effectiveness,</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H5919806B01074267BEEB7351DFD65346"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements for 30-day notice</header><text>Section 515(d)(6)(A)(ii) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/360e">21 U.S.C. 360e(d)(5)(A)(ii)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>subject to section 524B,</quote> after <quote>the date on which the Secretary receives the notice,</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB23544DF470940CFBB05774F4FC291D4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Requirements for premarket notification; technical correction to reference to section <enum-in-header>510(k)</enum-in-header></header><text>Section 510(l) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/360">21 U.S.C. 360(l)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>of this subsection under subsection (m)</quote> and inserting <quote>of subsection (k) under subsection (m) or section 524B</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB6B13DFE9F5F4BBC8001D0B9458FE251"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Misbranded devices</header><text>Section 502(t) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/352">21 U.S.C. 352(t)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>or 524B</quote> after <quote>section 519</quote>.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


