<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S2219 IS: Outdoor Recreation Jobs and Economic Impact Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-10-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 2219</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151029">October 29, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S377">Mr. Gardner</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To require the Secretary of Commerce to conduct an assessment and analysis of the outdoor
			 recreation economy of the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Outdoor Recreation Jobs and Economic Impact Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="id68FF052BCFC44F34B22C683F4BA10920"><enum>2.</enum><header>Assessment and analysis of outdoor recreation economy of the United States</header>
 <subsection id="id4C04614E3CCD4C48831FFD0372684E59"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Assessment and analysis</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Commerce, acting through the Director of the Bureau of Economic Analysis, shall conduct an assessment and analysis of the outdoor recreation economy of the United States and the effects attributable to such economy on the overall economy of the United States.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idB711FF36191C48AFA51B4A063220B63A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In conducting the assessment required by subsection (a), the Secretary may consider employment, sales, and contributions to travel and tourism, and such other contributing components of the outdoor recreation economy of the United States as the Secretary considers appropriate.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id1640ACB59DC5488284A264DDF807B157"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In carrying out the assessment required by subsection (a), the Secretary shall consult with the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="idFFE8167EFB36473DBA3C89910C5F94E6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The heads of such agencies and offices of the Federal Government as the Secretary considers appropriate, including the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of the Interior, the Director of the Bureau of the Census, and the Commissioner of the Bureau of Labor Statistics.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idF2F82FDA7E444D7188DE32343424A89D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Representatives of businesses, including small business concerns, that engage in commerce in the outdoor recreation economy of the United States.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id6DC5008B32F94C16B0ABB018CB7BB2B1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header>
 <paragraph id="idFEFEAFB234644705A2A71969E5B2DE8E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than December 31, 2016, the Secretary of Commerce shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on the findings of the Secretary with respect to the assessment conducted under subsection (a).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id0B2C9B61775B4917AA6A5D7DE4D57C54"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of Congress</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> includes the following:</text> <subparagraph id="idE6DFD2B92B5348539DCA45BD01CDCF5C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation, the Committee on Environment and Public Works, the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources, and the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship of the Senate.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA3CE97425EEB47499B917CB18C3738FC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Committee on Energy and Commerce and the Committee on Small Business of the House of Representatives.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1B4A986F16214BDFBD52CB811868083C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Small business concern defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>small business concern</term> has the meaning given such term under section 3 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/632">15 U.S.C. 632</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section></legis-body> </bill> 

