<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S867 IS: STEM Education for the Global Economy Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 867</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150325">March 25, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S332">Mr. Franken</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To improve student academic achievement in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics
			 subjects.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body>
 <section id="id1A71A26B51804BD291C36B387A3975C7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This part may be cited as the <quote><short-title>STEM Education for the Global Economy Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </section><section id="id052B629938F0465C9250F130A57C15E0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Improving science, technology, engineering, and mathematics instruction and student achievement</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title IV of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7101">20 U.S.C. 7101 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id082595ba-bd73-4462-991d-507aa3767b55" style="OLC">
				<part id="idd31ac863-ba5e-461c-8be3-0714cf62e885"><enum>D<?LEXA-Enum B?></enum><header>Improving
				science, technology, engineering, and mathematics instruction and
			 student
				achievement</header>
					<subpart id="id8cf4b284-32c1-4944-923f-6708d1cdfcad"><enum>1<?LEXA-Enum 1?></enum><header>Improving STEM
				instruction and student achievement</header>
 <section id="id62217504-f456-43b5-b9e9-78da34044dc0"><enum>4401.</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purpose of this subpart is to improve student academic achievement in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics, including computer science, by—</text>
 <paragraph id="id3c30b6a8-c845-4092-bc52-41e0bdd64b70"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improving instruction in such subjects through grade 12;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idb334b9dd-217f-4217-9294-b8348fb72bd6"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improving student engagement in, and increasing student access to, such subjects;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id0d32db6e-9773-45ce-96ca-5ab6f1abe0b0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>improving the quality and effectiveness of classroom instruction by recruiting, training, and supporting highly rated teachers and providing robust tools and supports for students and teachers in such subjects; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idcb5f07c6-6135-49fc-a455-552dadb8855b"><enum>(4)</enum><text>closing student achievement gaps, and preparing more students to be college and career ready in such subjects.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="id287d9b67-670d-4bdd-bc04-d7448a29f5b7"><enum>4402.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this subpart:</text> <paragraph id="id4d95664d-d2b5-4f9b-82e2-2ac4c2158ae5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <quote>eligible entity</quote> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id886b1ae1-1e83-46f2-802b-189a2842b884"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a State educational agency; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id888daf19-1b82-4475-8e4a-16428ae5021c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a State educational agency in partnership with 1 or more State educational agencies.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id16ae4c9c-ebf0-43a0-93ae-7a673f1094e7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible
 subgrantee</header><text>The term <quote>eligible subgrantee</quote> means—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="id82153c51-3aec-459f-b404-58e31ee13e63"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a high-need local educational agency;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfe3c100e-b76a-483e-a576-ffb77d925220"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an educational service agency serving more than 1 high-need local educational agency;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idaf281bf4-4ff9-47fa-858b-1f61408e8f0a"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a consortium of high-need local educational agencies; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb9d971c0-1f64-4f3e-b390-fa441405ded1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an entity described in subparagraph (A) or (C) of paragraph (3) that has signed a memorandum of agreement with an entity described in subparagraph (A), (B), or (C) of this paragraph to implement the requirements of this subpart in partnership with such entity.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id18ebd9de-c3f7-48fa-931f-2d88aa8168e1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Outside
 Partner</header><text>The term <quote>outside partner</quote> means an entity that has expertise and a demonstrated record of success in improving student learning and engagement in the identified subjects described in section 4404(b)(2), including any of the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="id4f05a54d-a4df-4b5b-8e92-e4cd73866e61"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A nonprofit or community-based organization, which may include a cultural organization, such as a museum or learning center.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7f433e28-4fde-4e98-9528-6c4ed4d2040c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A business.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id724eb289-0b9d-4e8c-b77f-a63849030661"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An institution of higher education.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id83adbb51-4f4d-4e8a-91ef-5bb646b720f2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>An educational service agency.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id4b14f4c9-bf94-4e92-9627-890f1fe9364b"><enum>(4)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <quote>State</quote> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id67cb0769-d51b-482f-8b3c-9b92bc5bac23"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any of the 50 States;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id61a2e4d3-7ede-442d-a6cd-8aca10067e72"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the District of Columbia;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8d3362c6-548a-4e51-8d85-14408a359f37"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Bureau of Indian Education; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5b86a17a-4557-40a3-861c-a2df43149eaa"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="idc77a1f91-2677-422a-87e7-00fbf46f6f7c"><enum>4403.</enum><header>Grants;
				allotments</header>
							<subsection id="ida06dad20-50e0-4e56-b5e5-068e620c590e"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reservations</header>
								<paragraph id="id7afb2cd5-5658-4e9b-88a9-02aff8e03eb3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In
 General</header><text>From the amounts appropriated for this part for a fiscal year, the Secretary shall reserve—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id94ed4eaa-51db-43c6-8f8b-7564cf4f05b0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not more than 2 percent to provide technical assistance to States under this subpart;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9589cf17-926c-4005-b4e1-9058608db3cb"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not more than 5 percent for State capacity-building grants under this subpart, if the Secretary is awarding such grants in accordance with paragraph (2); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida42edc34-b1ba-4607-83b5-e8b591f5da96"><enum>(C)</enum><text>10 percent for the STEM Master Teacher Corps program under subpart 2.</text>
									</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1ea3cba5-ee7d-447c-8ad0-f620e735227c"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Capacity-building
				grants</header>
									<subparagraph id="id9cd72ff7-1d21-4abf-aa9b-1a0c6de659d6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In
 General</header><text>In any year for which funding is distributed competitively, as described in subsection (c)(1), the Secretary may award 1 capacity-building grant to each State that does not receive a grant under subsection (c), on a competitive basis, to enable such State to become more competitive in future years.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id29a52f00-b16d-41f3-9062-a5eebedb8cac"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>Grants awarded under subparagraph (A) shall be for a period of 1 year.</text>
									</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id6652e93b-f440-4404-80b5-c7eb94416541"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Formula Grants</header>
								<paragraph id="id9d10c2e0-2dd8-4e5e-9dd3-aa1020bdb6ca"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In
 General</header><text>For each fiscal year for which the amount appropriated to carry out this part, and not reserved under subsection (a)(1), is equal to or more than $300,000,000, the Secretary shall award grants to States, based on the formula described in paragraph (2).</text>
								</paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idd8e320fe-9ab4-4fa4-b1de-833104ab2cc4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Distribution of
 Funds</header><text>The Secretary shall allot to each State—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="id8bb83623-ea43-4cbf-bb50-f1c2103784f8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an amount that bears the same relationship to 35 percent of the excess amount described in paragraph (1) as the number of individuals ages 5 through 17 in the State, as determined by the Secretary on the basis of the most recent satisfactory data, bears to the number of those individuals in all such States, as so determined; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id86497e45-4c66-4651-9414-63e0fc6985be"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an amount that bears the same relationship to 65 percent of the excess amount as the number of individuals ages 5 through 17 from families with incomes below the poverty line in the State, as determined by the Secretary on the basis of the most recent satisfactory data, bears to the number of those individuals in all such States, as so determined.</text>
									</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idf6d34ad5-7187-42c9-b839-7a50ab9438ec"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Funding
 Minimum</header><text>No State receiving an allotment under this subsection may receive less than one-half of 1 percent of the total amount allotted under paragraph (1) for a fiscal year.</text>
								</paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id23abc1b8-158b-405a-8114-5777ee0bc1dd"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Puerto
 Rico</header><text>The amount allotted under paragraph (2) to the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico for a fiscal year may not exceed one-half of 1 percent of the total amount allotted under paragraph (1) for such fiscal year.</text>
								</paragraph><paragraph id="id8b013034-4c0e-437b-aa70-d4c465e50a09"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Reallotment of unused
 funds</header><text>If a State does not successfully apply, the Secretary shall reallot the amount of the State's allotment to the remaining States in accordance with this subsection.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0172a86b-78bc-42dc-9000-82e1b40b888d"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Competitive
				Grants</header>
								<paragraph id="id066f94c9-3bdf-4843-a483-dce4f063550c"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In
 General</header><text>For each fiscal year for which the amount appropriated to carry out this part, and not reserved under subsection (a)(1), is less than $300,000,000, the Secretary shall award grants, on a competitive basis, to eligible entities to enable such eligible entities to carry out the activities described in this subpart.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id3a04525c-ecfc-422c-872d-1aa92596c694"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>Grants awarded under this subsection shall be for a period of not more than 3 years.</text>
								</paragraph><paragraph id="id7d00a7de-ad0e-4870-8a67-bca1611267a3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Renewal</header>
									<subparagraph id="id85102dcb-c04c-4c02-86d8-8db396e2fab2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In
 General</header><text>If an eligible entity demonstrates progress, as measured by the metrics described in section 4406(a), the Secretary may renew a grant for an additional 2-year period.</text>
									</subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbb2f53a8-98ed-4694-a310-686f310d997b"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Reduced
 Funding</header><text>Grant funds awarded under subparagraph (A) shall be awarded at a reduced amount.</text>
									</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ida2c0f179-a4cd-4f13-aea9-cf0d6ddfe66b"><enum>4404.</enum><header>Applications</header>
							<subsection id="idfe1cbd1a-5e16-499d-94a8-8f1584a0bc1c"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In
 General</header><text>Each eligible entity or State desiring a grant under this subpart, whether through a competitive grant under section 4403(c) or through an allotment under section 4403(b), shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and accompanied by such information as the Secretary may require.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id28fdf86d-8082-45b7-87f3-284ac19404db"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>At a minimum, an application submitted under subsection (a) shall include the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="id3c6411ed-8fe7-4c05-aced-5d50b5a03a54"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A description of the needs, including assets, identified by the State or eligible entity, based on a State analysis, which—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id85258c58-3c01-4f26-96f4-c0376ed6e587"><enum>(A)</enum><text>may include results from a relevant pre-existing analysis of science, technology, engineering, and mathematics education quality and outcomes in the State or States served by the eligible entity;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id49b395b3-8729-4a1c-aef7-5943e6abb0b5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall include data for elementary school and secondary school grades, as applicable, to the extent that such data are available, on—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="id7f02f823-208d-4f3b-8145-5a5603dba9b2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>student achievement in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="id3526e81a-41a8-4143-ac0e-3872c2f31cbf"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>science, technology, engineering, and mathematics teacher evaluations;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idbc292326-235b-4113-8be5-c05ed73f2314"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>student access to mathematics and science courses needed to enroll in credit-bearing coursework at institutions of higher education in the State or States served by the eligible entity;</text>
 </clause><clause id="ida89590a3-48f4-4ea1-88a0-61b47d8f2cf6"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>access to science, technology, engineering, and mathematics courses for students through grade 12 who—</text>
 <subclause id="id61873dec-0830-456e-a762-25c9268e27ad"><enum>(I)</enum><text>are eligible to receive a free or reduced priced lunch under the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1751">42 U.S.C. 1751 et seq.</external-xref>); or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idf04b5fd5-249a-407b-b723-8b16fbf676e3"><enum>(II)</enum><text>come from families with an income that is below the poverty line;</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="idd017543b-fc0b-43d1-8253-ecfe259811c9"><enum>(v)</enum><text>student achievement gaps in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics subjects;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idde309403-6b9f-41b0-a096-c0b6b337924d"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the percentage of students who successfully—</text>
 <subclause id="iddb89020e-45de-475a-a95d-e16a84750067"><enum>(I)</enum><text>complete Advanced Placement or International Baccalaureate courses in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics subjects; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idc3505ddd-c31a-4234-ade0-3599dddfab46"><enum>(II)</enum><text>complete rigorous, credit-bearing postsecondary education courses in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics subjects;</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="id69b99580-676f-4e08-9685-8530e8d89f41"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>available instructional systems and supports, such as curricula, instructional materials, professional development, teacher evaluation systems, and assessments;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id30554780-2923-4955-98e2-51ef8b62835b"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>science, technology, engineering, and mathematics teacher qualifications; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id958355a4-0115-4393-89c6-0c0a5b03ef7b"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>teacher shortages and teacher distribution among local educational agencies and schools in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics subjects;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0a3e76d5-80f6-4f90-9e23-fd8be057be50"><enum>(C)</enum><text>shall include labor market information regarding the industry and business workforce needs within the area served by the eligible entity;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc8ac1b54-b079-46aa-854f-9015e326c0cb"><enum>(D)</enum><text>shall include an analysis of the quality of pre-service preparation at all public institutions of higher education (including alternative pathways to teacher licensure or certification) for individuals preparing to teach science, technology, engineering, and mathematics subjects in a preschool, elementary school, or secondary school in the State; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idacf8321e-7618-4453-86c2-76d3c97f69c5"><enum>(E)</enum><text>shall include an analysis of the implementation of any multi-tier systems of support that have been employed in the State or States served by the eligible entity to address the learning needs of students in any science, technology, engineering, and mathematics subjects.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id8b777946-fdb6-4bfb-8fd4-4bbaceeea2a7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An identification of the specific science, technology, engineering, and mathematics subjects that the State or eligible entity will address through the activities described in section 4405, consistent with the needs identified under paragraph (1) (referred to in this subpart as identified subjects).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idc714ad20-75c5-48c1-937d-097e65bc40a7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A description, in a manner that addresses any needs identified under paragraph (1), of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id6dbda98d-86f5-4df4-93e2-12fb946210dd"><enum>(A)</enum><text>how grant funds will be used by the State or eligible entity to improve instruction in identified subjects using evidence-based programs of instruction that are aligned with the college and career ready standards and academic assessments;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide1be7c0e-3e02-49cc-b576-3bdf3960719b"><enum>(B)</enum><text>how grant funds will be used to support subgrantees and other high-need local educational agencies in the employment of multi-tiered systems of support to provide early intervening services, as described in section 613(a)(4)(A)(ii) of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act, and to increase student achievement in identified subjects;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id21676cbc-3bad-4e32-836a-6022e5844a07"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the process that the State or eligible entity will use for awarding subgrants, including how relevant stakeholders will be involved;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf1a9e702-18c4-4278-bd6d-241b53d3e963"><enum>(D)</enum><text>how the State’s or eligible entity’s activities and subgrants will be coordinated with other Federal, State, and local programs and activities, including career and technical education programs authorized under the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/2301">20 U.S.C. 2301 et seq.</external-xref>);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2fbfb704-7282-4ef2-9738-580b6dd8d682"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the technical assistance that the State or eligible entity will provide to subgrantees to support the activities undertaken by the subgrantees;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="ide65c8982-e6f4-4634-8ed7-9b231537b142"><enum>(F)</enum><text>how the State or eligible entity will evaluate the activities funded, both at the State and subgrantee level, with funds provided under this subpart, and in a manner consistent with any evaluation activities carried out by the Institute of Education Sciences under section 4407, or the National Science Foundation;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddf4614d7-90dd-4b4b-a447-ae661d615b08"><enum>(G)</enum><text>how the State or eligible entity will allocate funds in a manner that will provide services to both elementary schools and secondary schools;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7aecd7f7-0011-4cc0-b0df-aac138272747"><enum>(H)</enum><text>how the State or eligible entity will provide targeted support to improve instruction in high-need local educational agencies and high-need schools;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9a5b4961-ade0-446f-bf5d-11b2bb26db68"><enum>(I)</enum><text>how the State or eligible entity’s proposed project will ensure an increase in access for students who are members of groups underrepresented in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics subject fields to high-quality courses in 1 or more of the identified subjects; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4c84f9b4-d83e-4f3d-a6b1-147a49f7e68f"><enum>(J)</enum><text>how the State or eligible entity will continue to involve stakeholders in education reform efforts related to science, technology, engineering, and mathematics instruction.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ida43761a9-3f11-4ff0-b186-263e2d5c7665"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Assurances that the State or eligible entity will monitor implementation of approved subgrantee plans.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id554e07ab-67f2-40d2-84b8-73d3fe6a52f5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Additional
 Funding</header><text>A State or eligible entity that submits a request to use the additional State activities reservation described in section 4405(d)(2), shall provide, in a manner that addresses the needs identified under subsection (b)(1), a description of the activities that the eligible entity will carry out with such funds, consistent with section 4405.</text>
							</subsection></section><section id="id0781975f-ab05-45fb-a6f1-cb190e7d90a6"><enum>4405.</enum><header>Authorized
				activities</header>
							<subsection id="id4757e924-fc02-4dbe-b697-55caeb5e1973"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Required
 activities</header><text>Each State or eligible entity that receives a grant under this subpart shall use the grant funds to carry out each of the following activities:</text>
 <paragraph id="idf05bac7b-716f-4544-8af2-c09beb9c0079"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Increasing access for students through grade 12 who are members of groups underrepresented in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics subject fields to high-quality courses in the identified subjects.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idfd11db15-04e3-4313-8c1f-a6461b083333"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Implementing evidence-based programs of instruction based on high-quality standards and assessments in the identified subjects.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id9177d8d1-6ff8-455a-8aab-629a53b728f1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Providing professional development and other comprehensive systems of support for teachers and school leaders to promote high-quality instruction and instructional leadership in the identified subjects.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id3e2dffb5-01f1-47fe-ae0e-80e8ecab89f5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Providing technical assistance to subgrantees and other high-need schools and local educational agencies in order to improve student achievement and narrow achievement gaps in identified subjects, including through—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id72b2b8e2-59f0-49e0-a85c-01a3884b2cc8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the development and implementation of multi-tier systems of support; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5e54ba65-ecb5-41f4-b2f8-67a96d908cea"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the development of curriculum or instructional materials consistent with the principals of universal design for learning.</text>
									</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id7569b3a7-92b6-4701-bb65-1a6df421df01"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Permissible
 activities</header><text>Each State or eligible entity that receives a grant under this subpart may use the grant funds to carry out 1 or more of the following activities:</text>
 <paragraph id="id33062cb4-c11c-4bd6-a9a0-f57cce038fa0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Recruiting qualified teachers and instructional leaders who are trained in identified subjects, including teachers who have transitioned into the teaching profession from a career in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics fields.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idF8905D3C055242CE9E0537D13D8260FC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Recruiting and training teachers to teach dual credit and dual enrollment postsecondary-level courses to high school students in identified subjects.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id80c93465-69b0-4de1-9c4d-8d362214e2be"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Providing induction and mentoring services to new teachers in identified subjects.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idf312d223-c9a6-4fe4-a161-76a322435012"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Developing instructional supports, such as curricula and assessments, which shall be evidence-based and aligned with State college and career ready academic content standards, and may include Internet-based curricula and Internet-based instructional supports.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idf16058a6-c100-4bbe-96e7-28e5277e47b7"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Implementing an interdisciplinary approach, by integrating instruction in 1 or more science, technology, engineering, and mathematics subjects with reading, English language arts, or instruction in other core academic subjects and noncore academic subjects.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5bbf9f33-bad8-485c-a0e6-cba8b18dca58"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Subgrants</header>
								<paragraph id="id8dd57928-fc09-4212-9d4a-5b823095a7ca"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In
 General</header><text>Each State or eligible entity that receives a grant under this section shall award subgrants, on a competitive basis, to eligible subgrantees.</text>
								</paragraph><paragraph id="id348e9568-6a4d-40ab-ac26-ce075363a1f9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Minimum
 Subgrant</header><text>A State or eligible entity shall award subgrants under this subsection that are of sufficient size and scope to support high-quality, evidence-based, effective programs that are consistent with the purpose of this subpart.</text>
								</paragraph><paragraph id="idd0cfca33-42df-4014-86e2-356bedd7604f"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Subgrantee
				Application</header>
									<subparagraph id="id110730a7-62fc-4b51-ba59-677c76436268"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In
 General</header><text>Each eligible subgrantee desiring a subgrant under this subsection shall submit an application to the State or eligible entity at such time, in such manner, and accompanied by such information as the State or eligible entity may require.</text>
									</subparagraph><subparagraph id="id420f0684-d256-479e-ab84-b3b720081246"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contents of Subgrantee
 Application</header><text>At a minimum, the application described in subparagraph (A) shall include the following:</text>
 <clause id="id3f9fb3d6-f370-4f61-b68e-d76aba94c9f5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A description of the activities that the eligible subgrantee will carry out, and how such activities will improve teaching and student academic achievement in the identified subjects, in a manner consistent with scientifically valid research.</text>
 </clause><clause id="id88ce2e53-a7aa-4560-8d50-7545165a0bd9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A description of how the eligible subgrantee will use funds provided under this subsection to serve students and teachers in high-need schools.</text>
 </clause><clause id="idd1d8ad19-8e8c-4151-9bff-f93338c0016d"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>A description of how funds provided under this subsection will be coordinated with other Federal, State, and local programs and activities, including career and technical education programs authorized under the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/2301">20 U.S.C. 2301 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
 </clause><clause id="id57c712c7-8a07-4076-9cd9-34f165a6c062"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>If the eligible subgrantee is working with outside partners, a description of how such outside partners will be involved in improving instruction and increasing access to high-quality learning experiences in the identified subjects.</text>
										</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ida6f97a7c-c0dc-4204-a5fb-b7d0a4daab87"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Subgrantee Use of
				Funds</header>
									<subparagraph id="id8b24edc3-17b0-4e39-ae26-c05a81b4c4e7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Required Use of
 Funds</header><text>Each subgrantee under this subsection shall use the subgrant funds to carry out activities for students through grade 12, consistent with the activities described in the subgrantee's application, which shall include—</text>
 <clause id="ide35b3410-ac36-4bc0-907d-d98c2ec2b846"><enum>(i)</enum><text>high-quality teacher and instructional leader recruitment, support, and evaluation in the identified subjects;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id604f22af-aee8-43be-8843-9fcfa2523e96"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>professional development, which may include development and support for instructional coaches, to enable teachers and instructional leaders to increase student achievement in identified subjects, through—</text>
 <subclause id="id689734ce-4614-4017-b41a-2de862ce0511"><enum>(I)</enum><text>implementation of classroom assessments; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id1938b60b-37a6-412d-ab94-02075af0e61a"><enum>(II)</enum><text>differentiation of instruction in identified subjects for all students, including for students who are children with disabilities and students who are English learners;</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="id7647a67c-bd3d-459d-beb9-de224f3a2a80"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>activities to—</text> <subclause id="id2e6c3725-c5c2-4ea7-a296-8e54644f5053"><enum>(I)</enum><text>improve the content knowledge of teachers; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idbd3d6f02-b27c-4de0-a95e-0151b0d40e01"><enum>(II)</enum><text>facilitate professional collaboration, which may include providing time for such collaborations;</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="id23f172e4-3144-4c5d-95d0-e53607826842"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the development, adoption, and improvement of high-quality curricula and instructional supports that—</text>
 <subclause id="idb54864fa-c0b2-4666-80f1-eb44f0e58124"><enum>(I)</enum><text>are aligned with State college and career ready academic content standards; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id14468db7-6e03-42ea-bbb4-8c5b9e4d6551"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the eligible subgrantee will use to improve student academic achievement in identified subjects;</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="idcca12ee6-a9f4-4b3e-98e5-5baf4b0948bf"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the development or improvement, and implementation, of multi-tier systems of support to provide early intervening services and to increase student achievement in 1 or more of the identified subjects; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id06f74fa7-377c-4b01-ade0-9b980d3d4ea7"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>integrating instruction in the identified subjects with instruction in reading, English language arts, or other core and noncore academic subjects.</text>
										</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8e5956fe-f93c-4bfd-9d02-9880ca2e15bf"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Allowable Use of
 Funds</header><text>In addition to the required activities described in subparagraph (A), each eligible subgrantee that receives a subgrant under this subsection, may also use the subgrant funds to—</text>
 <clause id="id73d55637-65ad-4120-9669-cbd43e71c221"><enum>(i)</enum><text>support the participation of underserved populations in nonprofit competitions related to science, technology, engineering, and mathematics subjects (such as robotics, science research, invention, mathematics, computer science, and technology competitions);</text>
 </clause><clause id="idab92b212-5e76-4a69-b82d-a698eaac9904"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>broaden secondary school students' access to, and interest in, careers that require academic preparation in 1 or more identified subjects; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id18398F476E5C485CBFC0EAEC4E26EC0B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>broaden secondary school students' access to early college high schools, dual enrollment, or concurrent enrollment courses in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics subjects, including providing professional development to teachers and leaders related to this work.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1cda6469-6f6b-493b-a5d4-306db2b6aeca"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Each subgrantee that receives a subgrant under this subsection shall not expend more than 15 percent of the subgrant funds on the activities described in subparagraph (B).</text>
									</subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8f78674a-a2dc-4935-b51d-509fb27d96fe"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Matching
 funds</header><text>A State or eligible entity shall require an eligible subgrantee receiving a subgrant under this subsection to demonstrate that such subgrantee has obtained a commitment from 1 or more outside partners to match, using non-Federal funds or in-kind contributions, not less than 15 percent of the amount of subgrant funds. In the case of significant financial hardship, an eligible subgrantee may apply to the State or eligible entity for, and the State or eligible entity may grant, a waiver of a portion of the minimum matching funds requirement.</text>
									</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0ab02993-373a-49ca-a3b0-aaba5491e96f"><enum>(d)</enum><header>State
				Activities</header>
								<paragraph id="id8ca51f09-fa8e-4402-90fe-e6eba362ca26"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In
 General</header><text>Each State or eligible entity that receives a grant under this subpart may use not more than 5 percent of grant funds for—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idb27c5695-8ed6-4279-9fc8-2dceb47efeda"><enum>(A)</enum><text>administrative costs;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id24750401-f1a8-41f8-867f-23db274507ea"><enum>(B)</enum><text>monitoring the implementation of subgrants;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7e3fdde0-3335-4022-a8ed-91cb9888d081"><enum>(C)</enum><text>providing technical assistance to subgrantees; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id775549b4-d13a-4cb8-bfc9-138ec9daea32"><enum>(D)</enum><text>evaluating subgrants in coordination with the evaluation described in section 4407.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id68f309fd-a547-4aa8-94e6-44a1559be1bf"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reservation</header><text>Each State or eligible entity that receives a grant under this subpart may submit a request to the Secretary to reserve not more than 15 percent of grant funds, inclusive of the amount described in paragraph (1), for additional State activities, consistent with subsections (a) and (b).</text>
								</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idfc976593-b29e-4993-b47f-c7b9a23535ba"><enum>4406.</enum><header>Performance metrics;
				report</header>
							<subsection id="id7cedec14-708c-4730-a24a-324ce6dd4908"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of
 Performance Metrics</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Director of the Institute of Education Sciences, shall establish performance metrics to evaluate the effectiveness of the activities carried out under this subpart.</text>
							</subsection><subsection id="id7cde297e-2518-4f6a-9b9c-ba61efc920f5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Annual
 Report</header><text>Each State or eligible entity that receives a grant under this subpart shall prepare and submit an annual report to the Secretary, which shall include information relevant to the performance metrics described in subsection (a).</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="id50e3c549-2f17-4e3d-8061-56b445dae7c8"><enum>4407.</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">From the amount reserved in accordance with section 9601, the Secretary shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="iddc718ccf-681c-468d-86c7-86e0c0289eb6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>acting through the Director of the Institute of Education Sciences, and in consultation with the Director of the National Science Foundation—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id64a7b33d-7a09-481f-8a2a-5d8af24dd102"><enum>(A)</enum><text>evaluate the implementation and impact of the activities supported under this subpart, including progress measured by the metrics established under section 4406(a); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5c5a174c-d746-4d0a-a673-03c07f41e0eb"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identify best practices to improve instruction in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics subjects; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide00c9436-3efd-4c9b-84d8-6f5acae7e910"><enum>(2)</enum><text>disseminate, in consultation with the National Science Foundation, research on best practices to improve instruction in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics subjects.</text>
							</paragraph></section><section id="id0cdd4818-bd5e-4377-9eb3-9f86225d946b"><enum>4408.</enum><header>Supplement not
 supplant</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Funds received under this subpart shall be used to supplement, and not supplant, funds that would otherwise be used for activities authorized under this subpart.</text>
						</section><section id="ide9247746-690f-462c-ab0d-e7c4a380347d"><enum>4409.</enum><header>Maintenance of
 effort</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">A State that receives funds under this subpart for a fiscal year shall maintain the fiscal effort provided by the State for the subjects supported by the funds under this part at a level equal to or greater than the level of such fiscal effort for the preceding fiscal year.</text>
						</section></subpart><subpart id="idbcbdf6e3-c0a4-4a6d-ac80-7ccaad9eb24a"><enum>2<?LEXA-Enum 2?></enum><header>STEM Master
				Teacher Corps Program</header>
 <section id="id7227b078-20e7-4319-8ca9-8d1f77c5b2a1"><enum>4421.</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purpose of this subpart is to establish a STEM Master Teacher Corps program that—</text>
 <paragraph id="id05dea6e4-7abe-4aca-8405-10df0513792b"><enum>(1)</enum><text>elevates the status of the STEM teaching profession by recognizing and rewarding outstanding STEM teachers;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id3ccc176e-e634-49dd-a97e-22300e82c5a5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>attracts and retains effective STEM teachers, particularly in high-need schools, by offering them additional compensation, instructional resources, and instructional leadership roles; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9326ef2f-80ad-4b08-85a3-886c95e13f65"><enum>(3)</enum><text>creates a network of outstanding STEM teacher-leaders who will—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbaa07d6f-ab75-4a49-ace7-b36daa3f5f28"><enum>(A)</enum><text>share best practices and resources;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8b01789f-c28c-476a-b610-a1361bfbe8b4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>take on leadership responsibilities in their schools, districts, States (if part of the participating area), or consortia with the authority to provide professional support to their STEM colleagues not participating in the STEM Master Teacher Corps;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd71ab19c-f955-4ab1-b0a4-7d6c8c86d600"><enum>(C)</enum><text>aid in the development and retention of beginning teachers by serving as their role models and providing them with instructional support; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcc539b4b-c20b-49d8-8069-44d7e9ef8fb9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>inform the development of STEM education policy.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="id5d68fe88-ea58-44f7-ba3e-1bd49a9910cd"><enum>4422.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this subpart:</text> <paragraph id="idf9f77eda-65cd-4ddf-b7b0-8d2530b1ef9b"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means a consortium of high-need local educational agencies or 1 or more State educational agencies, acting in partnership with 1 or more—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id5330b71e-9689-4ce3-b8d0-4d54f6344c26"><enum>(A)</enum><text>institutions of higher education; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id89f8217e-6c99-4305-84e0-947857253700"><enum>(B)</enum><text>nonprofit organizations with a demonstrated record of success in preparing or improving the effectiveness of STEM teachers.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id4e744613-d30e-4cbe-8b72-0083f99b275f"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Participating
 area</header><text>The term <term>participating area</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="idb7a8ba5d-111d-446c-8680-150a6b922057"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of an eligible entity that includes a State educational agency or consortium of State educational agencies, the State or States; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf70e0090-9858-438d-bece-c1cbebe30e7e"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of an eligible entity that includes a consortium of local educational agencies, the area served by such agencies.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id338fe98d-2aa3-482f-b205-cb7ab2eef12f"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rural
 school</header><text>The term <term>rural school</term> means a public school—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idb9a68fb0-0083-4376-92a8-1e90e66d400c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>designated with a school locale code of Distant Town, Remote Town, Fringe Rural, Distant Rural, or Remote Rural; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida796b102-9e3f-478d-b542-7c61e54cf533"><enum>(B)</enum><text>served by a local educational agency in which not less than two-thirds of the students served by the agency attend a school designated with 1 of the school locale codes listed in subparagraph (A).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idf9230b27-7a74-45de-9dd8-b2cb28ddbf1b"><enum>(4)</enum><header>STEM</header><text>The term <term>STEM</term> means science, technology, engineering, and mathematics, including computer science.</text>
							</paragraph></section><section id="idcc9219cc-7b7c-44c0-b626-16f5a01a42be"><enum>4423.</enum><header>STEM Master Teacher
				Corps Program</header>
							<subsection id="idab49b6c3-be3e-44d1-b981-8b19f7cd4256"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header>
								<paragraph id="ideec117be-8365-420f-a352-21b930a1a31a"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Grants
 authorized</header><text>From the amount reserved under section 4403(a)(1)(C), the Secretary, in consultation with the Director of the National Science Foundation and the heads of other appropriate Federal agencies, as determined by the Secretary, shall establish a STEM Master Teacher Corps program by awarding, on a competitive basis, 1 or more grants of not less than $15,000,000 each to eligible entities to enable the eligible entities to establish the program, in accordance with section 4425.</text>
								</paragraph><paragraph id="id4e55ea84-55e2-44ef-86e8-23054a611339"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Planning
 grants</header><text>The Secretary may award planning grants to eligible entities to enable the entities to make plans to establish the program, in accordance with section 4425.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5c3b18d1-d89c-46fb-b99f-cb42417ea9c6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duration of
				grant</header>
								<paragraph id="id956b27c1-cfca-407f-ac26-4a8b635176cd"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>A grant awarded under this subpart shall be for a period of not more than 5 years.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id3e8dd005-d536-40ee-8194-31ea82b63e82"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Review</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id343cf725-5e79-4534-ba97-b53e64ce8452"><enum>(A)</enum><text>review, 3 years after an eligible entity is awarded a grant under this subpart, the performance of the entity during the 3-year period; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id98dfe040-d9d3-40fc-91a5-69031fa7f95b"><enum>(B)</enum><text>fund the remaining grant period for such entity if the Secretary determines, based on such review, that the entity is achieving satisfactory results.</text>
									</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idadf47b62-74ce-4682-88b6-a8a97475d3db"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Matching
				requirement</header>
								<paragraph id="id83dcd412-76c4-4d8e-b68d-516744186406"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), an eligible entity that receives a grant under this subpart shall provide, from non-Federal sources, an amount equal to not less than 50 percent of the amount of the grant, which may be provided in cash or in-kind, to carry out the activities supported by the grant.</text>
								</paragraph><paragraph id="id7980b6f4-0674-4d6c-a87a-592583438d06"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header>
									<subparagraph id="id12a55550-aa2a-46fb-bf27-1db54fc23c14"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>The Secretary may waive the 50-percent matching requirement under paragraph (1) for an eligible entity that the Secretary determines is unable to meet such requirement. The Secretary shall set a matching requirement for such eligible entities according to the sliding scale described in subparagraph (B).</text>
									</subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id08573311-baea-462c-9429-6687fb6863df"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Sliding
 scale</header><text>The amount of a match under subparagraph (A) shall be established based on a sliding fee scale that takes into account—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="idef337f12-7629-4713-9b41-84751d50213f"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the relative poverty of the population to be targeted by the eligible entity; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="id8ab72489-aec4-4c54-a8de-2869be8d3899"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the ability of the eligible entity to obtain such matching funds.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id6ee88c95-f43b-494e-9925-a280c22c9511"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Consideration</header><text>The Secretary shall not consider an eligible entity's ability to match funds when determining which eligible entities will receive grant awards under this subpart.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id367807de-5915-4d27-a068-fe8aeebcec38"><enum>4424.</enum><header>Application</header>
							<subsection id="id085d6f19-9ad4-49bf-bacb-8fafbc8067c1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>An eligible entity desiring a grant under this subpart shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id7c2c32f5-873d-494b-9f23-2f622c7be940"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>An application submitted under this section shall include—</text>
 <paragraph id="idf5f69fa1-7064-4100-b11f-40a74cd08378"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a description of the STEM Master Teacher Corps program that the eligible entity intends to carry out, including the number of Corps members the entity intends to select, the intended distribution of subjects and grade levels taught, the geographic and economic characteristics of the local educational agencies that are part of the participating area, such as the rural-urban continuum codes and proportion of high-need schools served, and the type of activities proposed for recruitment of Corps members;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id11bc0f44-11a5-4c0a-bf52-5f1642d2b631"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of the roles and responsibilities that each participating local educational agency, State, institution of higher education, or nonprofit organization, as applicable, will have;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ida65cec41-2ef2-48da-be8e-7be54e74fb95"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a demonstration that the entity has sufficient capacity to carry out the activities described in section 4425;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id451cb267-5cf7-4125-83e3-21fce93a6678"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a description of the member selection process and criteria that the applicant will use to select members of the STEM Master Teacher Corps, in accordance with section 4425(b);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id3c3b54f9-dbb7-4106-b165-e99cc13ca68a"><enum>(5)</enum><text>a description of how the eligible entity intends to facilitate networking and sharing of best practices and educational resources relating to STEM education among Corps members, particularly at rural schools, if applicable, and make a selection of these best practices and resources more widely available to other teachers and the STEM educational community, including through electronic means;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id81ef2666-cb9d-4051-9a10-42d7a6bf89e2"><enum>(6)</enum><text>a demonstration that the entity has a clear plan for—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idff32f18e-46f3-4d31-a254-41030c3fb32a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>offering research-based professional development to Corps members, including training on instructional leadership, mentoring, engaging and effectively teaching historically underachieving or underrepresented groups in STEM fields, such as girls, minorities, low-income students, English learners, and students who are children with disabilities, and effective STEM teaching methods, such as incorporating hands-on STEM projects into their lesson plans; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbfa25aca-7760-42ae-9b0d-9c1cd1d27720"><enum>(B)</enum><text>tracking the effectiveness of such professional development;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idd25e2ce0-2d89-4101-8435-62e0dc38de9f"><enum>(7)</enum><text>a demonstration that the entity has a clear plan for evaluating the impact of the professional support provided by STEM Master Teacher Corps members to other teachers in their school, district, and participating area;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idc1f2158b-6e22-4074-84de-0cd27c09e916"><enum>(8)</enum><text>a description of how the local educational agencies and schools served by the eligible entity intend to align STEM Master Teacher Corps members’ duties with school systems and activities already in place, if applicable, such as professional development and mentoring;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id68087601-68ed-42f9-8195-0175e6162151"><enum>(9)</enum><text>an explanation of how STEM Master Teacher Corps members will be afforded the time, authority, and resources to fulfill requirements under the program, and how other teachers will be afforded the time to receive professional support from Corps members;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id43c09c04-d68a-45ba-a695-48f30dcac0fb"><enum>(10)</enum><text>a demonstration that the entity has a clear plan for oversight to ensure that STEM Master Teacher Corps members carry out the responsibilities described in section 4425(c) to the fullest extent practicable, and a description of the actions to be taken if a member does not carry out such responsibilities; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id192bf4b4-dd6b-4a9c-a6ab-7374bcd430c5"><enum>(11)</enum><text>a description of how the grant funds will be financially managed.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idbffc211e-269b-4256-b082-6fae7ff4c50c"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Criteria for awarding
				grants</header>
								<paragraph id="iddcce5eb6-5994-475c-8e3c-70b85beebf4a"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>The Secretary shall award grants under this subpart on the basis of merit considering, at a minimum, the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="idb211e6b3-d61c-4bee-8dbc-8efd662ab158"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The extent to which the local educational agencies that are part of the eligible entity are committed to integrating the program into existing school structures, policies, operations, and budgets, such as by enabling STEM Master Teacher Corps members to take on leadership roles in their schools, districts, and participating area, in addition to their classroom duties, including assisting in the development and implementation of professional development activities and driving the instructional program of the school.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idea0afce4-2d8e-4413-9798-9d3fe9d5140a"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The quality of the proposed professional development, teacher leadership and mentorship activities, and networking opportunities.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id583c50af-9fe1-4e7b-b07a-9a855cc43552"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Demonstration that the local educational agencies and schools they serve have removed barriers to full participation in the program, including affording Corps members and the teachers they mentor the time to participate in activities required by the program.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd10a77ee-f4a0-4bcc-b358-7c2c81e75529"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The number and quality of the individuals that will be served by the program.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6f69318b-37a5-448e-ba91-bd1c9bbc1661"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The capacity of the eligible entity to effectively carry out the program.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id25936bab-2b03-476a-8c67-afe2882858f7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding grants under this subpart, the Secretary shall give priority to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id05cf1bf7-4f2c-4e2b-b3cc-924943637c8f"><enum>(A)</enum><text>eligible entities that intend to include large numbers of teachers in the STEM Master Teacher Corps; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6c83a168-f94d-45a6-a96f-bb95b466f626"><enum>(B)</enum><text>eligible entities that intend to include rural schools, particularly high-need rural schools, in the participating area to be served.</text>
									</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ida2413a2a-be4d-4892-bb7b-4961b5f1493f"><enum>4425.</enum><header>Required use of
				funds</header>
							<subsection id="idcf802238-30c6-4377-a445-3206e77824ee"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>An eligible entity receiving a grant under this subpart shall use grant funds to—</text>
 <paragraph id="id8355f00b-c7c0-4438-97f9-807b55999bd1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>administer the selection of teachers for membership in the STEM Master Teacher Corps, in accordance with the requirements of subsection (b);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id3911c719-43e7-475b-b2d8-d6f741e01f50"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide compensation to each public school teacher who is selected and serves as a member of the STEM Master Teacher Corps, in recognition of the teacher's teaching accomplishments, leadership, and increased responsibilities, which amount shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idb5631845-8501-47bf-9f5c-25dc32ca8e45"><enum>(A)</enum><text>supplement, and not supplant, the teacher's base salary; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddf25bf57-2286-462e-b2c1-bf0b7f6e7f82"><enum>(B)</enum><text>be equal to—</text> <clause id="ide3864776-0bba-4260-884d-651cb21ecbdc"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the case of a teacher who teaches at a high-need public school, including a high-need charter school, $15,000 per year for each year the teacher serves as a member of the Corps; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id9c340622-622f-4416-ba4d-de0626302302"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case of a teacher who teaches at a public school, including a charter school, that is not a high-need school, $5,000 per year for each year the teacher serves as a member of the Corps;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id852b029a-1518-485b-998d-f030a3568fc6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provide research-based professional development activities for members of the STEM Master Teacher Corps, as described in section 4424(b)(6), and track the effectiveness of such professional development in order to determine whether to alter professional development activities;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id9f9a1bd3-7b29-4794-a5ac-d77f0879c038"><enum>(4)</enum><text>provide discretionary resources for STEM Master Teacher Corps members at high-need public schools to use in their classrooms and schools, including for after school activities to enrich STEM education and for equipment and technology to facilitate long distance networking, mentoring, and sharing of best practices;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ide4ee6ff1-57fe-42d7-96eb-bd50d580862c"><enum>(5)</enum><text>assist in coordinating instructional leadership roles for STEM Master Teacher Corps members and mentoring relationships between STEM Master Teacher Corps members and other teachers in the same school, school district, and participating area in which the Corps members serve as instructional leaders;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id28e257ef-2738-4541-aa96-da599b37b3a3"><enum>(6)</enum><text>facilitate efforts by STEM Master Teacher Corps members to inform STEM education policy at the national, State, and local levels;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id96264602-c090-4c84-b1ca-cbabb06d3900"><enum>(7)</enum><text>help defray costs associated with affording STEM Master Teacher Corps members the time to fulfill their duties as Corps members; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id048112d9-9661-4fd7-b4ab-5ab12e170b76"><enum>(8)</enum><text>support other activities that advance the purpose of this subpart.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ide8cc31ee-6619-4926-bde2-2ac40b95b1c5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Selecting Members of
				the STEM Master Teacher Corps</header>
								<paragraph id="id836b5da0-f057-4471-8d93-a41a9ca97c32"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Selection criteria for
 corps members</header><text>The eligible entity shall select, as members of the STEM Master Teacher Corps, exemplary STEM teachers at the elementary school and secondary school levels who teach in the participating area, which may also include special education teachers and teachers of English learners who teach a STEM subject. In selecting the members, the eligible entity shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idc810bf2f-937e-4f07-b20c-f03bffe1ec89"><enum>(A)</enum><text>make decisions based on the teacher's—</text>
 <clause id="idba1b6992-64e4-49d0-aee3-b4530f2ee273"><enum>(i)</enum><text>ability to improve student academic achievement in the STEM fields, as demonstrated by, if applicable, student academic growth in such fields;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id8f8531b6-60fa-4329-92bf-57f3a1677185"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ability to enhance student engagement in such fields; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id10eb12f3-d07b-4d19-a4c3-2df54e4dd56b"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>record of leadership in the teacher’s school and involvement in professional and outreach activities; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddf462a92-0a36-46f9-bb1b-ddeb5bc00744"><enum>(B)</enum><text>evaluate the teacher’s ability and record based on multiple measures, such as—</text>
 <clause id="idb4a5634e-0fc1-460b-97dc-64b7bf8e9d70"><enum>(i)</enum><text>teacher evaluations of pedagogical skills;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id477901e8-c5c2-4004-a424-6ecdc11c6ee5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an assessment of content knowledge;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id406cc576-24ed-4b97-bac0-f81cf86ca190"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the performance and improvement of the teacher’s students on tests;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id20a3ccd6-ed81-4110-906c-b701981cd7ff"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>demonstration of practical professional experience in the teacher’s discipline, such as having worked in industry or research;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id3c343371-87de-4fef-922e-43800a5bdebb"><enum>(v)</enum><text>involvement in STEM discipline professional societies;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idc448a8c1-01a8-4165-928a-5363cde83d8e"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>STEM outreach and community involvement; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id219a45cc-4a87-4b05-9e39-5e00167ba470"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>certification by the National Board for Professional Teaching Standards, or other equivalently rigorous, performance-based, peer-reviewed certification, as a high-performing teacher.</text>
										</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id4253448e-0796-4b21-9896-cf59162e945c"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Overall corps
 membership requirements</header><text>An eligible entity receiving a grant under this subpart shall ensure that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id96d83c95-4252-4dd1-98d5-4a349a926208"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not more than 5 percent of the STEM teachers who teach in the participating area are members of the Corps;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id640be329-67cc-4b45-9ef6-f1bb36aff2e5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not less than 75 percent of the STEM Master Teacher Corps members are teachers at high-need schools;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id122ccda3-3ed7-4a53-a9f5-5876ec018034"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the proportion of STEM Master Teacher Corps members in the participating area who teach at rural high-need schools is not less than the proportion of all teachers who teach at rural high-need schools in the participating area;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9b67ecdd-7027-4dbc-bbc9-38eb6abd4999"><enum>(D)</enum><text>there are multiple cohorts of STEM Master Teacher Corps members; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5c0fdc0c-1d28-422a-a63c-910335b0400e"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the STEM Master Teacher Corps includes teachers from each of the disciplines of science, technology, engineering, and mathematics, if teachers from each of these disciplines meeting the standards of Corps membership are available in the participating area and may include teachers of career and technical education.</text>
									</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0da34a7c-b306-4f11-85ec-3260d22b3b3c"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Participation of
 private school teachers</header><text>An eligible entity may select STEM teachers who teach at private schools in the participating area to be members of the STEM Master Teacher Corps, except that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idd61d0b1b-941e-4c22-aa9f-8a569856a03a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not more than 5 percent of teachers selected as STEM Master Teacher Corps members shall be teachers at private schools; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id96ca898d-4205-4f36-8882-86c36303636d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>private school teachers shall not be eligible for compensation described in subsection (a)(2), discretionary resource funds described in subsection (a)(4), or for defrayment funds described in subsection (a)(7).</text>
									</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1bebfd26-3607-44cb-b03c-a7b7b64a702d"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Corps member
 requirements</header><text>Each teacher selected to be a member of the STEM Master Teacher Corps who wishes to join the Corps shall enter into an agreement with the eligible entity, under which the teacher shall, as a condition of receiving the compensation described in subsection (a)(2) and the discretionary resources described in subsection (a)(4), agree to carry out the responsibilities of a master teacher as required by the eligible entity, including—</text>
 <paragraph id="id85717e8e-fddc-4997-a4f4-aa1cf40fa412"><enum>(1)</enum><text>participating in professional development activities offered by the program;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idce598ffd-10d8-4993-9253-21ffee527196"><enum>(2)</enum><text>networking and sharing best practices and educational resources with other members of the STEM Master Teacher Corps; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id012fddee-1ffe-411b-9f05-ef192540d75b"><enum>(3)</enum><text>contributing to the professional development of the teacher's colleagues, which may include providing school-based professional support to other STEM teachers through regular weekly professional development sessions and individual coaching, where possible, leading professional learning communities, and taking on other instructional leadership roles in the teacher's school, district, State, if part of the participating area, or consortium.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id9b95adbf-be5e-45a7-9a2b-e6a695946109"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Collection for
				Noncompliance</header>
								<paragraph commented="no" id="id8808bfec-0b72-4f12-b006-84802a867daa"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Monitoring
 compliance</header><text>Each eligible entity that receives a grant under this subpart shall monitor whether each teacher the entity selects to be a member of the STEM Master Teacher Corps is in compliance with the Corps member requirements described in subsection (c).</text>
								</paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idde7a82e6-55e5-4c59-9eff-5474dd466566"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Collection of
				repayment</header>
									<subparagraph commented="no" id="id3043c90e-e3c6-4987-81bd-ab21af2c0901"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>A teacher selected to be a member of the STEM Master Teacher Corps shall repay the additional compensation provided for a school year described in subsection (a)(2) to the eligible entity if—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="idef357e57-74f5-42e8-b631-1d8d0aef99f7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the entity finds the teacher not in compliance with the Corps member requirements described in subsection (c) and the entity determines the teacher should no longer be a member of the Corps for such year; or</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="id3653d47a-3bb1-44f9-b0e0-e269cc1f81c5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the teacher withdraws during such year from membership in the Corps without an accepted excuse, as determined by the eligible entity.</text>
										</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id03492a47-81e7-49a4-8e74-655ed7b68dca"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Compensation returned
				to the Treasury</header>
										<clause commented="no" id="id29be929a-fb60-4487-9cf6-39dce0f84fe5"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>Except as provided in clause (ii), an eligible entity that receives repaid compensation under subparagraph (A) shall return such compensation to the United States Treasury.</text>
										</clause><clause commented="no" id="idfab4152f-5df8-4b66-90de-528449c3ac40"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Administrative
 costs</header><text>An eligible entity that receives repaid compensation under subparagraph (A) may retain a percentage, determined by the Secretary, of such repayment to defray administrative costs associated with the collection.</text>
										</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idd668e158-01d5-4caa-9f0f-0b88fdf31b1a"><enum>4426.</enum><header>Performance metrics;
				report</header>
							<subsection id="id19df9093-acf7-493d-ad1d-b3aa1564d031"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of
 performance metrics</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Director of the Institute of Education Sciences, shall establish performance metrics to evaluate the effectiveness of the activities carried out under this subpart.</text>
							</subsection><subsection id="idc94d67fc-0695-476b-816f-e5cd0d208640"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Annual
 report</header><text>Each eligible entity that receives a grant under this subpart shall prepare and submit an annual report to the Secretary, which shall include information relevant to the performance metrics described in subsection (a).</text>
							</subsection></section><section id="id8809d3e1-c73b-43a0-a5a4-66f98658c729"><enum>4427.</enum><header>Supplement not
 supplant</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Funds received under this subpart shall be used to supplement, and not supplant, funds that would otherwise be used for activities authorized under this subpart.</text>
 </section><section id="ideb456acd-69da-40a6-9240-2e428d8af763"><enum>4428.</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">From the amount reserved in accordance with section 9601, the Secretary shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="idb364f99e-6f56-41ef-b4e7-4621dcb6c383"><enum>(1)</enum><text>acting through the Director of the Institute of Education Sciences, and in consultation with the Director of the National Science Foundation—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idad10a841-6802-4f0f-972e-8c23d0b3abea"><enum>(A)</enum><text>evaluate the implementation and impact of the activities supported under this subpart, with regard to the program's success in achieving the purpose described in section 4421;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf1aa8d38-bc93-4c96-a58c-c036e5265bb5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identify optimal strategies for the design, implementation, and continuing development of the STEM Master Teacher Corps program; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1e6d01ad-3e63-4708-99de-814b0a20e814"><enum>(C)</enum><text>identify best practices for developing, supporting, and retaining STEM teachers based on lessons learned from the STEM Master Teacher Corps program; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idf66c91a2-f57d-41b7-b19a-86bee00e843c"><enum>(2)</enum><text>disseminate findings from the evaluation conducted under paragraph (1) to the STEM education field and make the findings publicly available.</text></paragraph></section></subpart></part><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


