<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S2025 IS: National Oceans and Coastal Security Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-09-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2025</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150910">September 10, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To promote the protection and conservation of
			 United States ocean, coastal, and Great Lakes ecosystems, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="ID0D7B91211D574AF3A18ED7495E2B36A0" style="OLC">
 <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="IDD7991980ECA84B919535B307C42C6B5C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>National Oceans and Coastal Security Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID3ee74391dcaa4464b9dfa3fe78dff993" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idA67C2F4DB7CB49CD97A67E83236E9225"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Coastal shoreline county</header><text>The term <term>coastal shoreline county</term> has the meaning given the term by the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency for purposes of administering the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4001">42 U.S.C. 4001 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID604da1191e9040d49f8f87fea97c712e"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Coastal State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>coastal State</term> has the meaning given the term <quote>coastal state</quote> in section 304 of the Coastal Zone Management Act of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1453">16 U.S.C. 1453</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id1132e16fb79f4a0ca03a7707af5406d3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Corpus</header><text>The term <term>corpus</term>, with respect to the Fund, means an amount equal to the Federal payments to the Fund, amounts contributed to the Fund from non-Federal sources, and appreciation from capital gains and reinvestment of income.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddf178d97435a42d1b5dd829df523078f"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Foundation</header><text>The term <term>Foundation</term> means the National Fish and Wildlife Foundation established by section 2(a) of the National Fish and Wildlife Foundation Establishment Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/3701">16 U.S.C. 3701(a)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id18178B6FB45B48D7A7847FE713F39BEB"><enum>(5)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Fund</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Fund</term> means the National Oceans and Coastal Security Fund established under section 4(a).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="IDE4D137237A7F45A8B64BA101A0B47F35"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Income</header><text>The term <term>income</term>, with respect to the Fund, means an amount equal to the dividends and interest accruing from investments of the corpus of the Fund.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="IDf51f2f4aa3564f03832af2a11a7a9b86"><enum>(7)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Indian tribe</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Indian tribe</term> has the meaning given that term in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/450b">25 U.S.C. 450b</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="IDcf38e7f8106045459ff0570b21ada7ef"><enum>(8)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as otherwise specifically provided, the term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Commerce.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID77462a46f94e469c8da305113fef192a"><enum>(9)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Tidal shoreline</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>tidal shoreline</term> has the meaning given that term pursuant to section 923.110(c)(2)(i) of title 15, Code of Federal Regulations, or a similar successor regulation.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID729029D60A874D2DBFC0B4CB56660CB6" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Purposes and agreements</header>
 <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idEAA00C0242C942FD9D90FEC036AF86C2"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Purposes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The purposes of this Act are to protect, conserve, and restore the oceans, coasts, and Great Lakes of the United States, ensuring present and future generations will benefit from the full range of ecological, economic, social, and recreational opportunities and services these resources are capable of providing.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id2E083FA8C322474795098469F40DCCF0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Agreements</header><text>The Secretary and the Foundation may enter into such agreements as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="id5cd9e2bd5e7b4d5c9b5141e2b2673a3a"><enum>4.</enum><header>National Oceans and Coastal Security Fund</header>
 <subsection id="idc9d67ad2d83841b6be64d7b94e072cfc"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary and the Foundation are authorized to establish the National Oceans and Coastal Security Fund as a tax exempt fund to further the purposes of this Act.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="id7f527994e1004d0b90be608167ba2dfd"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Deposits</header>
 <paragraph id="id36729BCC3B354CB8BD0854502FDBD876"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There shall be deposited into the Fund, which shall constitute the Fund’s assets amounts as follows:</text>
 <subparagraph id="idaaa070cb95b345e5b1ca7deffc98a91a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Amounts appropriated or otherwise made available to carry out this Act.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7af47e86f8ed404887aa4eb1887885ba"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Amounts earned through investment under subsection (c).</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id71cdbe1f61d847b88a8457a27e9ed2ac"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prohibitions on donations from foreign governments</header>
 <text>No amounts donated by a foreign government, as defined in section 7342 of title 5, United States Code, may be deposited into the Fund.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idee4e12aae7184877bfa4247098f22a19"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Investments</header><text>The Foundation shall invest the Fund corpus and income for the benefit of the Fund.</text> </subsection><subsection id="id96a302c587204a4d960e9890b1bfb389"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>Any amounts received by the Foundation pursuant to this Act shall be subject to the provisions of the National Fish and Wildlife Foundation Establishment Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/3701">16 U.S.C. 3701 et seq.</external-xref>), except the provisions of—</text>
 <paragraph id="idda539276fa294accbe9ddc68cdbdcae6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>section 4(e)(1)(B) of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/3703">16 U.S.C. 3703(e)(1)(B)</external-xref>); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idd1bd354dee92487285a9c591cb6a7163"><enum>(2)</enum><text>section 10(a) of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/3709">16 U.S.C. 3709(a)</external-xref>).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1826ef3ebfd54740919358cf67532774"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Withdrawals and expenditures</header>
 <paragraph id="id06386c7137b64037828e59f9db0e02f6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Allocation of funds</header><text>Each fiscal year, the Foundation shall, in consultation with the Secretary, allocate an amount equal to not less than 3 percent and not more than 7 percent of the corpus of the Fund and the income generated from the Fund from the current fiscal year.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idb5d686e5b29f4be9ab4aa4deb87bdac0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Expenditure</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (3), of the amounts allocated under paragraph (1) for each fiscal year—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id54a504d16a26432d9519c9ddd82296de"><enum>(A)</enum><text>at least 59 percent shall be used by the Foundation to award grants to coastal States under section 6(b);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8fecc5b68a4e475c904dc7492a8eba7b"><enum>(B)</enum><text>at least 39 percent shall be allocated by the Foundation to award grants under section 6(c); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id927091e0ac934164bb520714e168d444"><enum>(C)</enum><text>no more than 2 percent may be used by the Secretary and the Foundation for administrative expenses to carry out this Act, which amount shall be divided between the Secretary and the Foundation pursuant to an agreement reached and documented by both the Secretary and the Foundation.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id438dfdacd49549edb3832aab9cdc80a5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Program adjustments</header>
 <subparagraph id="id50437069feed437490a598d4f851f9fe"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In any fiscal year in which the amount described in subparagraph (B) is less than $100,000,000, the Foundation, in consultation with the Secretary, may elect not to use any of the amounts allocated under paragraph (1) for that fiscal year to award grants under subsection (b) or (c) of section 6.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6924b36c1474444bb4c1dcfe8cfb928f"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Determination amount</header><text>The amount described in this subparagraph for a fiscal year is the amount that is equal to the sum of—</text>
 <clause id="id3f908b9cdf714007ac4a3acf26345194"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the amount that is 5 percent of the corpus of the Fund; and</text> </clause><clause id="ida1f4b58aa2c944c4b56ab33343deb013"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the aggregate amount of income the Foundation expects to be generated from the Fund in that fiscal year.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id6e1b92f479634e6aa30160eab32cce31"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Recovery of payments</header><text>After notice and an opportunity for a hearing, the Secretary is authorized to recover any Federal payments under this section if the Foundation—</text>
 <paragraph id="id153bd84514234773a0edb186bc5fc173"><enum>(1)</enum><text>makes a withdrawal or expenditure of the corpus of the Fund or the income of the Fund that is not consistent with the requirements of section 5; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id315de5e7ebbb47cfa20c512659602854"><enum>(2)</enum><text>fails to comply with a procedure, measure, method, or standard established under section 6(a)(1).</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id5e1d0f73be3346cd90a7a49aecc389bb"><enum>5.</enum><header>Eligible uses</header> <subsection id="idc053b28a5988484490a5c1cf2684a6e0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Amounts in the Fund may be allocated by the Foundation to support programs and activities intended to protect, conserve, and restore ocean and coastal resources and coastal infrastructure, including baseline scientific research, ocean observing, and other programs and activities carried out in coordination with Federal and State departments or agencies, including the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="id583d7c8bbfde4f838f3d713a6725bfdb"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Ocean, coastal, and Great Lakes restoration and protection, including efforts to address potential impacts of sea level change, changes in ocean chemistry, and changes in ocean temperature.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ida22ca7f3f7f64ec8be74961f01e5029f"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Restoration, protection, or maintenance of living ocean, coastal, and Great Lakes resources and their habitats.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id4c8035e1a40d4cc1afc3ac9fcd4cd31d"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Planning for and managing coastal development to enhance ecosystem integrity or minimize impacts from sea level change and coastal erosion.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idbb7620b0e076442a8198ed595f64f05e"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Analyses of current and anticipated impacts of ocean acidification and potential responses.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id27c0441c670841db9bcac1e1feb66ef8"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Projects to address management issues which are regional or interstate in scope.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idc780c1febdf84121b0ee20af05a56d19"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Efforts that contribute to the understanding of ecological, economic, and societal threats faced by changes to the oceans, coasts, and Great Lakes.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id6bb924a797464562b6f739f9844ab833"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Efforts to better understand the processes that govern the fate and transport of petroleum hydrocarbons released into the marine environment from natural and anthropogenic sources, including spills and spill response and preparedness technologies.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id8f75a4b3780f4959ab5f6d0c1dfd5704"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Efforts to preserve, protect, and expand coastal access for persons engaged in water-dependent commercial activities including commercial fishing, recreational fishing businesses, aquaculture, boatbuilding, or other water-dependent coastal-related businesses.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id3f51425ea5244f9f96ba350fe91076cb"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Efforts to assist coastal States in strengthening, stabilizing, hardening, elevating, relocating, or otherwise enhancing the resiliency of bridges, roads, pedestrian walkways, and bicycle transportation facilities, and associated infrastructure, that are already subject to or face increased future risks of coastal flooding, coastal erosion, or sea level change.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id716a1701f6d64504b56af93fbb8dc05c"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Acquiring property or interests in property if—</text> <subparagraph id="id179c6d096d864dfc9a0158f3819c9f1f"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the area is located within a coastal shoreline county or adjacent county;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id300dbf68463746de8ffd0a239f14ba4d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the funds made available under this subtitle are used to acquire land or interest in land by purchase, exchange, or donation from a willing seller;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfc8e3fa64cef49ca897fc6c2684d12f2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Governor of the State in which the property or interests in property are acquired approves of the acquisition; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="ida8058b9e5e2842c4a50f247deaaa3126"><enum>(D)</enum><text>such property or interest is acquired in a manner that will ensure such property or interest will be administered to support the purposes of this Act.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id83743c61b795463da08b636f73bf361c"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Protection and relocation of critical coastal public infrastructure affected by erosion or sea level change.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idb5052e79e187411b8387e48d0bd6d7eb"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Matching requirement</header><text>An amount from the Fund may not be allocated to fund a project or activity described in paragraph (10) or (11) of subsection (a) unless non-Federal contributions in an amount equal to 30 percent or more of the cost of such project or activity is made available to carry out such project or activity.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idcba04602dd11449e9cf88aa7cd0a5f42"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Prohibition on use of funds for litigation</header><text>No funds made available under this Act may be used to fund litigation over any matter.</text> </subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id51508F7ECDB74EB8AC3F27844031201A" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>6.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Grants</header> <subsection id="ida399018a8ce041e69df63a8eeb622f51"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Administration of grants</header> <paragraph id="idaf4ddc59b4694d1f9bf7d171f3056f0c"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after funds are deposited into the Fund and made available to the Foundation for administrative purposes, the Foundation shall establish the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="id4408ace62a8a4ae4b1e8e28ede58484a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Application and review procedures for the awarding of grants under this section, including requirements ensuring that any amounts awarded under such subsections may only be used for an eligible use described under section 5.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id75e8c737e8c741ac9810fae76c88374c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Selection procedures and criteria for the awarding of grants under this section that—</text> <clause id="id2845d5177bb9491e9ca4578c35bcd9db"><enum>(i)</enum><text>require consultation with the Secretary and the Secretary of the Interior; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idf97f70414cc44346bf561f08bd0d6f8b"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>prioritize projects where non-Federal partners have committed to share the cost of the project.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc0175319eccd4d1e8622dc97c4521597"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Eligibility criteria for awarding grants—</text>
 <clause id="id065ddbeb8a3b4bd5bc967377822aacf8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>under subsection (b) to coastal States; and</text> </clause><clause id="id465a8e77ab264b1eb7da7055eea947cf"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>under subsection (c) to entities including States, Indian tribes, regional bodies, associations, non-governmental organizations, and academic institutions.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc60ba7923c4440e2b587988816686a05"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Performance accountability and monitoring measures for programs and activities funded by a grant awarded under subsection (b) or (c).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide047b7a1297b46c6a217d0bc834b6cea"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Procedures and methods to ensure accurate accounting and appropriate administration of grants awarded under this section, including standards of recordkeeping.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf8692bf92fd149329a7502ee1fb2e173"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Procedures to carry out audits of the Fund as necessary, but not less frequently than once every 5 years.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idaaa870c09c964b9ab727b81571799023"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Procedures to carry out audits of the recipients of grants under this section.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9f9c8236ee924d16b7b67ace880f4858"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Procedures to make publicly available on the Internet a list of all projects funded by the Fund, that includes at a minimum the grant recipient, grant amount, project description, and project status.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0d0b4d7663e245289928450de5e90042"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Approval</header>
 <text>The Foundation shall submit to the Secretary for approval each procedure, measure, method, and standard established under paragraph (1).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idf0b11b104f8946e28ac2ac8203c3502e"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grants to coastal States</header>
 <paragraph id="idc589eb06d0ca4aebae92728187e9633c"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (3), the Foundation shall award grants of amounts allocated under section 4(e)(2)(A) to eligible coastal States that have a coastal management program approved under the Coastal Zone Management Act of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1451">16 U.S.C. 1451 et seq.</external-xref>), based on the following formula:</text>
 <subparagraph id="id6960c16e1ac24e8d8bae8cad9ffe6f7d"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Fifty percent of the funds are allocated equally among such coastal States.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id38ca54bdc0cd4b6f8c1a418f5cdb37c9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Twenty-five percent of the funds are allocated on the basis of the ratio of tidal shoreline miles in a coastal State to the tidal shoreline miles of all coastal States.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7487a72ddef848bea258688fd33c00d4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Twenty-five percent of the funds are allocated on the basis of the ratio of population density of the coastal shoreline counties of a coastal State to the population density of all coastal shoreline counties.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id96fffab3c75b4e31b866bfd595ce56b1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible coastal State defined</header><text>In this subsection, the term <quote>eligible coastal State</quote> means—</text> <subparagraph id="id00347d4461af4c78b30cbeda89e418bd"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a coastal State that has a coastal management program approved under the Coastal Zone Management Act of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1451">16 U.S.C. 1451 et seq.</external-xref>); or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8aa9f487d21f43e99cdd23e4b55cb6ea"><enum>(B)</enum><text>during the period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act and ending on December 31, 2018, a coastal State that had, during the period beginning January 1, 2008, and ending on the date of the enactment of this Act, a coastal management program approved under the Coastal Zone Management Act of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1451">16 U.S.C. 1451 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id8bdbb4aa78f846db9d89ac0384256262"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Maximum allocation to States</header><text>Notwithstanding paragraph (1), not more than 10 percent of the total funds distributed under this subsection may be allocated to any single State. Any amount exceeding this limit shall be redistributed among the remaining eligible coastal States according to the formula established under paragraph (1).</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="id573f356461264d869ecf2b4de68b578f"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Maximum allocation to certain geographic areas</header>
 <subparagraph id="id22bb519ff3f44d8ebdd324f32aac463f"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding paragraph (1), each geographic area described in subparagraph (B) may not receive more than 1 percent of the total funds distributed under this subsection. Any amount exceeding this limit shall be redistributed among the remaining eligible coastal States according to the formula established under paragraph (1).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id68a3c9c066e84d148a2c4a4ea12ebdac"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Geographic areas described</header><text>The geographic areas described in this subparagraph are the following:</text> <clause id="id3d1422a4d7ee4f94862a8a9cc2ef0663"><enum>(i)</enum><text>American Samoa.</text>
 </clause><clause id="id7fb5376dd45d44d8b4b5a39eb0ffc510"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.</text> </clause><clause id="ide1e23ca01bfa4a1799427fca34fbf18f"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Guam.</text>
 </clause><clause id="id97e4825440db4a3690948306ed244dea"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Puerto Rico.</text> </clause><clause id="id5774baf32b484900b811cd16fea4e327"><enum>(v)</enum><text>The Virgin Islands.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idce2e242128494cea86443a69898cba8f"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Requirement to submit plans</header>
 <subparagraph id="idcd32e708d95a464b9e510442a9bd8b20"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under this subsection, a coastal State shall submit to the Secretary, and the Secretary shall review for approval, a 5-year plan, which shall include the following:</text>
 <clause id="idb4495c04a5c24fc8b64fcaba53978a4e"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Criteria to determine eligibility for entities which may receive grants under this subsection.</text> </clause><clause id="id8d09f63c63f94d16acd86c2d488897bc"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A description of the competitive process the coastal State will use in allocating funds received from the Fund, except in the case of allocating funds under paragraph (7), which shall include—</text>
 <subclause id="id00cab75525be43e7867e5740fd19c135"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a description of the relative roles in the State competitive process of the State coastal zone management program approved under the Coastal Zone Management Act of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1451">16 U.S.C. 1451 et seq.</external-xref>) and any State Sea Grant Program; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idf50f7486e8ca49d0aafc432bef44da8d"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a demonstration that such competitive process is consistent with the application and review procedures established by the Foundation under subsection (a)(1).</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause commented="no" id="id4d54e8252c7c4373bba789205d912698"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>A process to certify that the project or program and the awarding of a contract for the expenditure of amounts received under this paragraph are consistent with the standard procurement rules and regulations governing a comparable project or program in that State, including all applicable competitive bidding and audit requirements.</text>
 </clause><clause id="id0ebb1c962d1c44d3a7c995dfc4ae5f05"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Procedures to make publicly available on the Internet a list.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6e0c41fb05d046b28a153215719b2173"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Updates</header><text>As a condition of receiving a grant under this subsection, a coastal State shall submit to the Secretary, not less frequently than once every 5 years, an update to the plan submitted by the coastal State under subparagraph (A) for the 5-year period immediately following the most recent submittal under this paragraph.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idffd5b6ab2c6b482ebac94c211d200992"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Opportunity for public comment</header><text>In determining whether to approve a plan or an update to a plan described in subparagraph (A) or (B) of paragraph (5), the Secretary shall provide the opportunity for, and take into consideration, public input and comment on the plan.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idc9b325000c9045aabf4050e569861b41"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Indian tribes</header><text>As a condition on receipt of a grant under this subsection, a State that receives a grant under this subsection shall ensure that Indian tribes in the State are eligible to participate in the competitive process described in the State’s plan under paragraph (5)(A)(ii).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idb668e83490cb444fb629f82ae062b8c2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>National grants for oceans, coasts, and Great Lakes</header>
 <paragraph id="id6e09a6d7bb90475b8ef79d185f25c750"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Foundation may use amounts allocated under section 4(e)(2)(B) to award grants according to the procedures established in subsection (a) to support activities consistent with section 5.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="id93f161f0f62d48f1b04c1cd858ab1f0b"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Advisory panel</header>
 <subparagraph id="id5e56e4bbf1c54163ad4d8915498b77c5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Foundation shall establish an advisory panel to conduct reviews of applications for grants under paragraph (1) and the Foundation shall consider the recommendations of the advisory panel with respect to such applications.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8d2f03ed3fec42218a1e7955cb0b8bcb"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>The advisory panel established under subparagraph (A) shall include persons representing—</text> <clause id="id0ae16802f0a7409181e9c6559f76522f"><enum>(i)</enum><text>dependent industries;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id6189d44ef85a4627b7e56e342ee8fd31"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>geographic regions;</text> </clause><clause id="id5c5ff9cc3840489b811f367cfbb4d59a"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>nonprofit organizations; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id56a150537e3d4007a3e8fc616ead069d"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>academic institutions.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID2b4fc266e95244c398a0b26c0a6c71cf" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>7.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Annual report</header> <subsection id="id2ebbe3c48af7407b9fd3f876ee14c308"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement for annual report</header><text>Subject to subsection (c), beginning with fiscal year 2017, not later than 60 days after the end of each fiscal year, the Foundation shall submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives a report on the operation of the Fund during that fiscal year.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id07e2930d3f034695a7eb5400a2ea17d0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Content</header><text>Each annual report submitted under subsection (a) for a fiscal year shall include—</text> <paragraph id="ida6054bd58a204b8cac4eed3bfadac606"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a full and complete statement of the receipts, including the source of all receipts, expenditures, and investments of the Fund;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ide22ef3a468114189b44de54101bc9f90"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a statement of the amounts deposited in the Fund and the balance remaining in the Fund at the end of the fiscal year; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id3f4306ea544c4054adc2a3a136e79222"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a description of the expenditures made from the Fund for the fiscal year, including the purpose of the expenditures.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idA2E96CC3912349D6A9A0B3FAF422542B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exception for certain years</header><text>For any fiscal year in which the amount described in section 4(e)(3)(B) is less than $100,000,000, the Foundation, in consultation with the Secretary, may elect not to submit an annual report under this section for such fiscal year.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="id35C26860635D4907A041E55F5F98BB90"><enum>8.</enum><header>Funding</header>
			<subsection id="id3e57d6b33f6b4fd785855df72c996532"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Outer
 continental shelf lease revenue</header><text>Section 8 of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1337">43 U.S.C. 1337</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2BB5A5C47FBA40EEAFAB4BF5C050DF05" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="idd4fe87bda7d14cb5aee22fb1cc16c817"><enum>(q)</enum><header>Deposits in the
				National Oceans and Coastal Security Fund</header>
						<paragraph id="idb9513034393f447c957259944b7c98d0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>Beginning with the first fiscal year beginning after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>National Oceans and Coastal Security Act</short-title>, the Secretary shall deposit 12.5 percent of the revenue paid to the United States under this section in the National Oceans and Coastal Security Fund established pursuant to section 4 of that Act.</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="idded6164cf12e4abcbc27bf93797d7a0a"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Fines collected
				for violations of Federal law</header>
							<subparagraph id="idb1e3e25cbf5f4736b880fc6c616da7a1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>Beginning with the first fiscal year beginning after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>National Oceans and Coastal Security Act</short-title>, the President shall ensure that 10 percent of the civil penalties paid to the United States for a violation of a law set out under subparagraph (B) or for a violation of any requirement or prohibition of any rule, order, or permit promulgated, issued, or approved under such a law that occurs on the outer Continental Shelf are deposited in the National Oceans and Coastal Security Fund.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idaf878686fee243dd80aee881210e7840"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Laws</header><text>The laws set out under this subparagraph are the following:</text>
 <clause id="id3c23172aba8d4d9e9bfda4267aa6014b"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1251">33 U.S.C. 1251 et seq.</external-xref>) other than penalties provided for under section 311 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1321">33 U.S.C. 1321</external-xref>).</text>
 </clause><clause id="idb130482707914dcbbaec7512ed24cd59"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9601">42 U.S.C. 9601 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
 </clause><clause id="id2a87c44a322d4ac1b6a5219c7cc0c798"><enum>(iii)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/601">Chapter 601</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code.</text>
 </clause><clause id="idfb6d4455916641f9a661f681868564ab"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The Act of March 3, 1899 (30 Stat. 1151, chapter 425; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/401">33 U.S.C. 401 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


