<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1985 IS: Southern Utah Open OHV Areas Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-08-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1985</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150805">August 5, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S118">Mr. Hatch</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To provide for the conveyance of certain land to Washington County, Utah, to authorize the exchange
			 of Federal land and non-Federal land in the State of Utah, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body>
 <section id="idE9907FE0B9E847A6A27AC7A5C7DAE09C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Southern Utah Open OHV Areas Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="idC4EDA2AD817A4E3DBD036BD8DA41EDD6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
 <paragraph id="id6F7A4B45B9EE44CB95174B4FB7B5093E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>County</header><text>The term <term>County</term> means Washington County, Utah.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idCF8FC79273FC46699B2D4BF2BDDEE32A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federal land</header><text>The term <term>Federal land</term> means land owned and managed by the Bureau of Land Management in the County that is identified on the map as <quote>Federal Lands Proposed to Transfer to SITLA</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id0E11C4AE7C614ECFBCFBB5E6E331D805"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Map</header><text>The term <term>map</term> means the map prepared by the State of Utah School and Institutional Trust Lands Administration entitled <quote>Sand Mountain Exchange Washington County, Utah</quote> and dated July 29, 2015.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id4EEEF11F3A7A4F7DB9B0EFA3EF18F24A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Non-Federal land</header><text>The term <term>non-Federal land</term> means the State land identified on the map as <quote>SITLA Lands Proposed to Transfer to Federal</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id7fcb9dbfdd6f470985524f3bcf3da558"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Public water agency</header><text>The term <term>public water agency</term> means the Washington County Water Conservancy District.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idE53D91AFB55048DABC8B22CC9AA8144D"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4012005DEE0A4BCD9F84797C15C7E578"><enum>(7)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means the State of Utah.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="id408be2111f374fc193e5748effbd1c47"><enum>3.</enum><header>Exchange of Federal land and non-Federal land</header>
 <subsection id="id06270aab036e42d8a84c2d6b75163a27"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text>If the State offers to convey to the United States title to the non-Federal land, the Secretary shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="id5b4d5f8429dd4be4aec7d2f0cd2045c9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>accept the offer; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="ida2e85a01cfe942e182c8fdb58d4d3287"><enum>(2)</enum><text>on receipt of all right, title, and interest in and to the non-Federal land, convey to the State all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to the Federal land.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id05517ae81521424fbce8e1b756a6f333"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Valid Existing Rights</header><text>The exchange authorized under subsection (a) shall be subject to valid existing rights.</text> </subsection><subsection id="idf82ebf2ae0da47c28ab06bec319ce967"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Title approval</header><text>Title to the Federal land and non-Federal land to be exchanged under this section shall be in a format acceptable to the Secretary and the State.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="id2ef61dad5a724b56b36108ee27907bbc"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Appraisals</header>
 <paragraph id="idc066c654aa054d8d95ea509333661b4f"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The value of the Federal land and the non-Federal land to be exchanged under this section shall be determined by appraisals conducted by 1 or more independent appraisers retained by the State, with the consent of the Secretary.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id2fa1354303ca421099241a7137f6f623"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applicable law</header><text>The appraisals under paragraph (1) shall be conducted in accordance with nationally recognized appraisal standards, including, as appropriate, the Uniform Appraisal Standards for Federal Land Acquisitions.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idd6cd7a4b6b7d4fb7961a0243fff444dd"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Approval</header><text>The appraisals conducted under paragraph (1) shall be submitted to the Secretary and the State for approval.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id11a57ec110fe43c89908a77ac19f666b"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Reimbursement of State costs</header><text>The Secretary shall reimburse the State in an amount equal to 50 percent of the costs incurred by the State in retaining independent appraisers under paragraph (1).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5661E6A7EBE54047A5BE417FC18D553E"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Equal value exchange</header>
 <paragraph id="id77a1e0437cbc4e6e99a9945f28625a7d"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The value of the Federal land and non-Federal land to be exchanged under this section—</text> <subparagraph id="ide8bf9910b2954eb89eb5ee7129cfa56a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall be equal; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4da1cd9be68e46b4831d98d696f900e2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall be made equal in accordance with paragraph (2).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id4A59D5DC75CD4B3593645709BFBEEC71"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Equalization</header> <subparagraph id="id5D20A6B00B0E44D78FD8AD50571436DD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Surplus of Federal land</header><text>If the value of the Federal land exceeds the value of the non-Federal land, the value of the Federal land and non-Federal land shall be equalized, as determined to be appropriate and acceptable by the Secretary and the State—</text>
 <clause id="id29AAF332D00445D880348489AAC819F8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by reducing the acreage of the Federal land to be conveyed;</text> </clause><clause id="idE9A297304AC44475B277AEC7A5F6A5BD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by adding additional State land to the non-Federal land to be conveyed; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="idadc4bd90def743c9ad4d4521f4aa0890"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by the State making a cash payment to the United States.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4DE9ECE0A35B46C4B5782B7A2E7BA032"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Surplus of non-Federal land</header><text>If the value of the non-Federal land exceeds the value of the Federal land, the value of the Federal land and non-Federal land shall be equalized, as determined to be appropriate and acceptable by the Secretary and the State—</text>
 <clause id="idda5963307ba2400896f63e8b849a47c0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by reducing the acreage of the non-Federal land to be conveyed; or</text> </clause><clause id="id13811c7c3bd0411ab3f0077fc508eb90"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by the United States making a cash payment to the State.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idB2A56D1E7D764D3691FB5DF4784AA277"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Use of non-Federal land</header><text>On the conveyance of the non-Federal land to the Secretary under this section, the non-Federal land shall be used only—</text>
 <paragraph id="id9A91D654BB4A45608F325A8A7772EB3B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>as an open riding area for the use of off-highway vehicles; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idB13E0C3CB62E4548986801F02A766113"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for any other recreational use that does not significantly impact the open use of off-highway vehicles.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idfbab89af227c47f39e7b47acb76e826e"><enum>4.</enum><header>Conveyance of land to Washington County, Utah</header>
 <subsection id="id5f7d4e6ccac74efa8a7628003699f323"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As soon as practicable after notification by the County and subject to valid existing rights, the Secretary shall convey to the County, without consideration, all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to the land described in subsection (b).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id2aa3541d083a4c3db5072f11e46ff905"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Description of land</header><text>The land referred to in subsection (a) consists of the land managed by the Bureau of Land Management that is generally depicted on the map as <quote>Open OHV Areas</quote>.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="id11f40f81c8fc4c848283ee2ba70c4759"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Map and legal description</header>
 <paragraph id="idcc80f34651bf4459b1883e985bc44bfc"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As soon as practicable after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall finalize the legal description of the land to be conveyed to the County under this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idbc4790b33b0d4781b573f0fa73706bed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Minor errors</header><text>The Secretary may correct any minor error in—</text> <subparagraph id="id344e25ba858f41aca160ed3b849dd822"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the map; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5ba88c94241f4eb8873d883c7a76bf9a"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the legal description.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idc8fa1018b44341f8a4e51b93dbb64c0f"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>The map and legal description shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the Bureau of Land Management.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0fdecaabd8494cebaa764332dd732f61"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Use of conveyed land</header><text>The land conveyed under this section shall be used—</text> <paragraph id="idcb293cd4c92441368112e6a6ee246ad8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>primarily as an open riding area for the use of off-highway vehicles; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ida748775ef52249c98c5f5236e3969d10"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for the construction, maintenance, replacement, or operation of—</text> <subparagraph id="id9972B9D3B8164CED8A866D3B8AF83975"><enum>(A)</enum><text>water storage or conveyance facilities;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB60DAEA9BFDC44A680E001C7467F094C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>subsurface water recharge facilities; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD6D38A3AD22D486198807BD6BD2A2FD0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>solar or hydroelectric generation or transmission facilities.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ide3c54b521f7d4313915642a2c7cead66"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Administrative costs</header><text>The Secretary shall require the County to pay all survey costs and other administrative costs necessary for the preparation and completion of any patents for, and transfers of title to, the land described in subsection (b).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id05404426292b4a16899ea36384465e7d"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Conditions</header><text>As a condition of the conveyance under subsection (a), the County shall agree—</text> <paragraph id="idf211c820bb0e4327b9a5f1a0e846cb3f"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to pay any administrative costs associated with the conveyance including the costs of any environmental, wildlife, cultural, or historical resources studies;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id16899ffe68064ad7bba7d443ed65288f"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to release and indemnify the United States from any claims or liabilities that may arise from uses carried out on the land described in subsection (b) on or before the date of enactment of this Act by the United States or any person; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id9918dcc2c6404922b06980b9231a0149"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to accept such reasonable terms and conditions as the Secretary determines necessary.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idf5f4ff12989f4c2ab4790e22ebcf187e"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Water conveyance, recharge, and renewable energy corridor</header> <paragraph id="id5876E197591A4815891F3C352B312ECB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, in accordance with applicable laws (including the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>) and title V of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1761">43 U.S.C. 1761 et seq.</external-xref>)), shall, prior to making the conveyance described in subsection (a), issue to the public water agency or the State—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idD20CFF8DC61B47B8AFF6737C8EDEB441"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a 250-foot right-of-way for the construction, maintenance, repair, and replacement of a buried water conveyance pipeline and the associated construction, operation, and maintenance of subsurface water recharge facilities, as depicted on the map as <quote>Pipe Line 1</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0861EB678F48471597958AE06E798DEF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a 150-foot right-of-way for the construction and maintenance of solar and hydroelectric generation and transmission facilities, as depicted on the map as <quote>Transmission Line</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id35553100053F445EBDB7FD38260F33D9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>The water conveyance and renewable energy facilities shall employ best management practices to limit, to the extent practicable, the impacts of the water conveyance facilities on off-highway vehicle activities.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id55d3cbe11c6d41eba42863a7c0189bd7"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Water storage facilities</header><text>The Secretary, in accordance with applicable laws (including the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>) and title V of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act 5 of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1761">43 U.S.C. 1761 et seq.</external-xref>)), shall convey to the public water agency or the State 214.8 acres of the land described in subsection (b) for the construction, operation, maintenance, and repair of a water storage facility and associated facilities as depicted on the map as <quote>Hurricane Cliffs Afterbay</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id337271809a8448c6afe3c31eb5b6ca67"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Sand hollow regional pipeline corridor</header><text>The Secretary, in accordance with applicable laws (including the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>) and title V of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1761">43 U.S.C. 1761 et seq.</external-xref>)), shall, prior to making the conveyance described in subsection (a), issue to the public water agency a 200-foot right-of-way for the construction, maintenance, repair, and replacement of a buried water conveyance pipeline, as depicted on the map as <quote>Pipe Line 2</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE1EC9935BE0B4CD9924324B2DF48F749"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Reversion</header><text>If the land conveyed under this section ceases to be used for a public purpose in accordance with subsection (d), the land shall, at the discretion of the Secretary, revert to the United States.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


