<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S2072 IS: To require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to establish a program under which the Administrator shall defer the designation of an area as a nonattainment area for purposes of the 8-hour ozone national ambient air quality standard if the area achieves and maintains certain standards under a voluntary early action compact plan.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-09-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 2072</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150924">September 24, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S118">Mr. Hatch</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S312">Mrs. McCaskill</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEV00">Committee on Environment and Public Works</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to establish a program under
			 which the Administrator shall defer the designation of an area as a
			 nonattainment area for purposes of the 8-hour ozone national ambient air
			 quality standard if the area achieves and maintains certain standards
			 under a voluntary early action compact plan.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
 <section id="id67FDFAADBA1546428FEA6CA538F36BBC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="idAD34BDCD5B9447A5A3024EB2C2AB8C07"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idB3B62C9924D5421586006CC4A54634F9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Early Action Compact Program</header><text>The term <term>Early Action Compact Program</term> means the program established under section 2(a).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idDFCF9F7B3DDB44A282307E44DA89996C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Episode</header><text>The term <term>episode</term> has the meaning given the term in the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7401">42 U.S.C. 7401 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idA00F0908A87D46AD816F1C955EE9E29E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Ozone standard</header><text>The term <quote>ozone standard</quote> means the 8-hour ozone standard national ambient air quality standard under the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7401">42 U.S.C. 7401 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idD0CE78DAC3F44C858549C7C7D9B13CBA"><enum>(5)</enum><header>State implementation plan</header><text>The term <term>State implementation plan</term> means a State or tribal implementation plan, as those terms are used in the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7401">42 U.S.C. 7401 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="idD36BDFC0376D470CB1ADEA7D440F424A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Early Action Compact Program</header>
 <subsection id="id6B29B895CC584CAAAF474EB94E79BBB1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall establish a program, to be known as the <quote>Early Action Compact Program</quote>, under which State, local, and tribal governments may develop early action compact plans designed to achieve and maintain the ozone standard.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="idD5FB5512DD274858AAA0926B51E64DBB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Notification</header>
 <paragraph id="idAF0EB31708E74814A41EDDA1416A9DFA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To be eligible to participate in the Early Action Compact Program, a State, local, or tribal government shall submit to the Administrator—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idBA091DE377224692BB28C21A55493E77"><enum>(A)</enum><text>on the date on which the applicable State submits to the Administrator the nonattainment recommendations of the State, a notice of the intent of the State, local, or tribal government to participate in the Early Action Compact Program; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id70251B93339E4BCBB07DF8E2944D85A0"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 1 year after the date on which the State, local, or tribal government submits the notice under subparagraph (A), an early action compact plan in accordance with section 3.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idCE3CF18B7A0A44E0A42B76D0E66B0A42"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation on nonattainment status</header><text>In the case of an area under the jurisdiction of a State, local, or tribal government that provides a notice under paragraph (1)(A), the Administrator may not designate the area as a nonattainment area under section 107 of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7407">42 U.S.C. 7407</external-xref>) until after the Administrator has issued a decision on an early action compact plan of the area under section 4.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idCD97D581E5564DACA284A5660F51EDC9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Minimum requirements</header><text>The Early Action Compact Program shall include, at a minimum, provisions to ensure—</text> <paragraph id="idD9DC379A60384D0AB3447D5CFC240458"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the use of best available science;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idC84B251D144F4B339D288D6FC3803E87"><enum>(2)</enum><text>participation by State, local, and tribal governments through locally crafted solutions;</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id9981349F540D47FA938B1C7F96D640DB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the voluntary development and implementation by the State, local, and tribal governments of early action compact plans;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id271AA9E902784860B3FBA2A02F04C802"><enum>(4)</enum><text>that if a State implementation plan is required due to designation of an area as a nonattainment area following the implementation of an early action compact plan in accordance with this section, the Administrator shall provide credit to applicable State, local, or tribal governments and industry participants for actions and investments carried out pursuant to the Early Action Compact Program toward ozone attainment; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id022C048CF0264AB1A3A1C7FEBAE1EC7A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>that, in the case of the failure of an area to achieve ozone attainment, the Administrator shall defer designation of the area as a nonattainment area for ground-level ozone under section 107 of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7407">42 U.S.C. 7407</external-xref>) if that area—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="idFAD98B0C4BF24FD5A0C3EC08195CFD30"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is participating in the Early Action Compact Program; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id405D19453D034F9AB2E3C7892040A3B6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is an area in which an early action compact plan is being implemented to improve the air quality of the area.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ide5d4a645f5d94ba18424f062e0046d07"><enum>3.</enum><header>Early action compact plan requirements</header>
 <subsection id="id41256E68EA82499EA885D7DFE97915E3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to section 6, an early action compact plan entered into under the Early Action Compact Program shall include—</text>
 <paragraph id="idF7C2C22906144EC89A22F94A1E50A83C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>general provisions to ensure—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="iddf1cae9a2c4843c2a3b24f3579d9544e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>public involvement in the development of the plan, including—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="id7f8a58dc62b44e2fbc43b50c628b05e2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>public comment on a proposed early action compact plan in accordance with the standard State implementation plan revision process as implemented by the applicable State; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="idffe9901cea514a73b4c66aa4a349fbae"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the provision to the public of information, updates, awareness, and other opportunities for public involvement;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb27e74ba950640fe87685c3a01f8afb1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that, in the case of the failure of an area to achieve ozone attainment, an area is credited under the standard State implementation plan process for all emission reductions that result from measures implemented under the early action compact plan for that area; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbe344a22f9544d62a3d6a7be0c54db09"><enum>(C)</enum><text>that amendments to the early action compact plan accommodate adaptive approaches that reflect developing science, monitoring, and control mechanisms;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5e608e263eca4375ba2e0fd6fd4b06e2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>measurable milestones, including—</text> <subparagraph id="idbabc3b9e55f84579819686bc9ee2376c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>completion of emissions inventories and modeling using best available science and Environmental Protection Agency modeling guidance and tools;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3f1f8a3da2284d64b4ffe0c56172afeb"><enum>(B)</enum><text>adoption of control strategies that demonstrate attainment;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idece3422876eb4c20bbb82c24149a0923"><enum>(C)</enum><text>if necessary, completion and adoption of early action State implementation plan revisions;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id443beb408c924177ad4fa5496eac6707"><enum>(D)</enum><text>subject to subsection (b) and section 6(b)(2)(B), attainment with the ozone standard (including any applicable revised ozone standards that are finalized after the date on which the early action compact plan is approved by the Administrator) by not later than 10 years after the date on which the Administrator approves the early action compact plan; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbaf53b2679774db6a858ecb03e33c1ff"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a post-attainment plan;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1636512e147d4a228d9a2f5609245f7f"><enum>(3)</enum><text>emissions inventories that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idB3D21CD756934C3CAD1471CDFD455BD9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>use the most current tools available and will be completed for at least 1 recent episode so as to support the early action compact plan; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3E9C7CAE072D4E37A226FAD3241B2B08"><enum>(B)</enum><text>include—</text> <clause id="idcbf06a7f415f408596b79f7edfb3ded7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>at least 1 recent episode reflective of a typical ozone season exceedance that meets the episode selection guidance of the Administrator to ensure that representative meteorological regimes are considered;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id66f88a14d433404fac4cecb37a909be1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>baseline data to accurately measure ozone reductions of control measures implemented through the early action compact plan; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idd220ebe4a12045eb9782690ca136dac9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>continuing episode inventories—</text> <subclause id="id0566DD0DEF404BD9B760EC390A8B4BE5"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to inform appropriate control measures; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idEE7D098A6BB74FC2AC569597E4CB620A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>to improve understanding of emission trends and the contributors to ozone production in the area;</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id051160abbc3647e98b5d450e7e547746"><enum>(4)</enum><text>modeling emissions inventories—</text> <subparagraph id="id7B4D75F56B5C4D03B4B2F4A359E7DBBB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to develop State implementation plan quality modeling episodes that—</text>
 <clause id="id865102F75C9F4F5BBBAE09D0FA9664A1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>perform within the margin of accuracy determined by the Administrator based on best practices; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idB5B66721DEC14BB2A35FAA32031DC653"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>include a base case and future case on or before the date of approval by the Administrator of the early action compact plan; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1FB0C8FF473A45E28968A404B36309D9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that sufficiently account for projected growth in ozone precursor emissions, particularly from stationary, nonroad, and on-road mobile sources;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id847dfc482eb148fe98a230b306ef3739"><enum>(5)</enum><text>continuing development of episodes to represent a variety of situations that contribute to ozone production in a manner that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idAD93858D4ECF4EFE96E61784529AA10B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>supports the early action compact plan;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id22A0A6DF7AE24C7C90AAA2F119ACDC71"><enum>(B)</enum><text>determines control strategies;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id82D6389C6E014D26BEAC038C46E1A1AF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>demonstrates relative effectiveness of control measures; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id249F82AEF77243F9987062E0D40C4634"><enum>(D)</enum><text>demonstrates attainment within the early action compact plan period;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id6b47260f90ed4fca8fa78bd768cdb0cd"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the applicable Federal, State, local, and tribal control strategies that—</text> <subparagraph id="id1A9D7A0AEC2E49FC8664941565A0C16A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>demonstrate attainment not later than the attainment date of the early action compact plan;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9ff75762fb1d40cd984278b4f847841a"><enum>(B)</enum><text>are designed and implemented by the community with full stakeholder participation;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4ca33b9cae6a4747ab03181bd11f2d51"><enum>(C)</enum><text>following the adoption of Federal and State controls to be implemented by the attainment date of the early action compact, identify local control strategies that are—</text>
 <clause id="idC401BF304BF147159E355201D8C7A3B7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>specific;</text> </clause><clause id="id83141DD0B9D34B99B697260A53A3315E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>quantifiable;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idEBEF2BA737DF47FD94F4A8AF8AB15EA2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>permanent; and</text> </clause><clause id="idAF23CA10A41B4861A910D717EF3F5902"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>enforceable; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9db5150c8d1b4bcc9513d52eb67b98f3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>shall be—</text> <clause id="idBB2DE33CD54649D4B9282E20FEBBA1A1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>incorporated by the applicable State or Indian tribe into the State implementation plan; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id1EF1A255915E49338A51DDEC96C65B17"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>submitted to the Administrator for approval; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idb2778de33faf48228892822c07d8ceaa"><enum>(7)</enum><text>maintenance for growth provisions—</text> <subparagraph id="ide6587186ebb445888d87c8d99e016e74"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to address increases in emissions at least 5 years beyond the attainment date of the early action compact plan to ensure the area remains in attainment of ozone standards; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2683ab6dcddc41b8b36bad1c92a183dd"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to require continuing planning processes, including—</text> <clause id="idFA7DE52B067D4AE9AF146F5DDF9A46A5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>modeling updates;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idE86DCBF02A5D45118EC26F67A5DD76F6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>identification of actual new point sources;</text> </clause><clause id="id506081558BF1453DBF3964ED7E1CADBB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>impacts from growth; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id9805384C7A56418E8FF04BBC97ABFAA3"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>future transportation patterns and the impact on ozone levels.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idA4FE74236B8C4D87B227C823B990EE4E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effect of updated ozone standards</header> <paragraph id="idC9395A455D204869B2137EC2F17C60DC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Revised plans</header> <subparagraph id="idB9F2091FB89A42B997EA261179A15647"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In any case in which, during the 10-year effective period of an early action compact plan approved under this Act, the Administrator finalizes a new, updated, or modified ozone standard that is applicable to the early action compact plan, the affected State, local, or tribal government shall submit to the Administrator, by not later than 1 year after the date of finalization of the new, updated, or modified ozone standard, a revised early action compact plan that incorporates adjusted milestones to meet the new, updated, or modified ozone standard, in accordance with paragraph (2).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3BC5C3A2C0E345DA949BBCC15305035D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Failure to submit</header><text>If an affected State, local, or tribal government fails to submit to the Administrator a revised early action compact plan by the applicable deadline under subparagraph (A), the Administrator shall withdraw approval of the early action compact plan.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id8DE16E0931D64D1BBA5BC3D36F6FD570"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deadlines</header>
 <subparagraph id="idB42FB2F8F20246169D638A8E7962EE8C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Modification to ozone standards during initial 5-year period</header><text>If the Administrator finalizes a new, updated, or modified ozone standard that is applicable to an early action compact plan during the 5-year period beginning on the date of approval of the early action compact plan under section 4, the revised early action compact plan under paragraph (1) shall ensure achievement by the affected areas of attainment during the 10-year period beginning on the date of approval of the original early action compact plan.</text>
					</subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5D7F68E547B14A05AD41A089D33F80D4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Modification to ozone standards during final period</header>
 <clause id="id8DED7DBB07EE4B14B41A342EDEE0E258"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Definition of final period</header><text>In this subparagraph, the term <term>final period</term>, with respect to an early action compact plan, means the period—</text> <subclause id="id6B57BDFDC56544E9A8F804A3BA7A96E6"><enum>(I)</enum><text>beginning on the date that is 5 years after the date of approval of the early action compact plan under section 4; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id5498CBF2B0F248A49A6B04ADF3484BF9"><enum>(II)</enum><text>ending on the date that is 10 years after that date of approval.</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="idC6FC37470C3342369EF3D11C0252DE8E"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>Notwithstanding subsection (a)(2)(D), if the Administrator finalizes a new, updated, or modified ozone standard that is applicable to an early action compact plan during the final period of the early action compact plan, the revised early action compact plan under paragraph (1) shall ensure achievement by the affected areas of attainment during the 5-year period beginning on the date of submission of the revised early action compact plan.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id4B99F711560640E88542A4252949F0B7"><enum>4.</enum><header>Decisions on early action compact plans</header>
 <subsection id="idDCC9F6A3B78A4428886D3AF608C589EC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator shall issue a decision on each early action compact plan or revised early action compact plan submitted to the Administrator under this Act by not later than 1 year after the date on which the plan is submitted.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id6E4E2704026042E1BC935ECE9D54B7BE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Types of decisions</header><text>In issuing a decision under this section, the Administrator shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="idA4DE0731D4AF4795BCCFB4A10CA23B24"><enum>(1)</enum><text>approve the early action compact plan;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id300464A2B4494B6A9E06E961846C4AFD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>deny the early action compact plan; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id699EF22D9B0C4715ADEB345B3D32C094"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in accordance with subsection (c), make specific suggestions to modify the early action compact plan.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1AD8BA798CFF4BE4AD76B0EC13BA6E46"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Modifications</header>
 <paragraph id="id32D72772A77348448FE667FEADEA9D62"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date on which a State, local, or tribal government receives suggestions from the Administrator under subsection (b)(3), the State, local, or tribal government may submit to the Administrator, for approval in accordance with subsection (b), a modified early action compact plan that takes the suggestions of the Administrator into consideration.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB672BCEBECEA4621B35AD6A7C8C7893B"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Limitation on nonattainment status</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a State, local, or tribal government that submits to the Administrator a modified early action compact plan under paragraph (1), the Administrator may not designate the area subject to the early action compact plan as a nonattainment area under section 107 of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7407">42 U.S.C. 7407</external-xref>) until after the date on which the Administrator issues a decision on the modified early action compact plan of the area under this section.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id5d71b0f822a84596b4dd760faeb7fc35"><enum>5.</enum><header>Duties of Administrator</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In carrying out the Early Action Compact Program, the Administrator shall—</text> <paragraph id="id1b2e6d5a379a4004a857b0e5b5840401"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognize the commitment of each State, local, or tribal area to voluntarily adopt an early, substantive, enforceable, and scientifically based attainment plan with early implementation of control measures by becoming a party to an early action compact plan developed in accordance with this Act;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id41f4019a4ee843d898a9a6aa1e8c1ab1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide technical assistance to States, Indian tribes, and local areas in the development of early action compact plans;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idc38bd514341544e28d77c4a561222b32"><enum>(3)</enum><text>ensure prompt review and approval of submitted early action compact plans;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idC69CA927844349508743015FA7D03B84"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in a case in which the Administrator denies a submitted early action compact plan, provide an explanation of the reason for denying the submitted early action compact plan;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id1b45c55379bc4f529ae8355d99df52c6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in the case of the failure of an area subject to an early action compact plan to achieve attainment status during the period for which the plan is in effect, defer designation of the area as a nonattainment area until the expiration of that period if the area continues to meet the terms of the plan, including any milestones established by the plan;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id72254bf1130548a99fbc2a1012a771b5"><enum>(6)</enum><text>expeditiously designate an area as an attainment area and impose no additional requirements other than the post-attainment plan if area monitors reflect attainment by not later than the early action compact plan attainment date; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idef27904a7cf84bf3893eff9315136ce6"><enum>(7)</enum><text>in the case of the failure of a participating area to comply with the Early Action Compact Program—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id728660DB844B4BC3B8D2898A294BE6F1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>withdraw approval under this Act of the early action compact plan of the area; but</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA454769B3E5C473DB5A40FD31B98FBC3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide reasonable opportunities for the area to cure deficiencies before withdrawing that approval.</text>
				</subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="id91c3c94223d0461bb5218f1080473080"><enum>6.</enum><header>Winter ozone provisions</header>
 <subsection id="idF1A85E102DEE4D0C806862A7572F8859"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For each early action compact plan under this Act, the Administrator shall establish requirements relating to winter ozone levels, including timelines, that are separate from, but not more burdensome than, the requirements otherwise established under this Act.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="idAF41DF2108EF444A911797E33BE56719"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Regulations</header>
 <paragraph id="idE2A1157DE2C443DD9A1645343A49491F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator shall promulgate regulations—</text> <subparagraph id="id50E6035F81C3416DAF0FE14D6F2A758C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to carry out the Early Action Compact Program; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idDBED2026B29542DA8543F88B6564DAA9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>specifically to address and accommodate unique and complex occurrences of winter ozone in accordance with this section.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idC28843D22C2C46B6BBAD1172155A1396"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The regulations promulgated pursuant to paragraph (1) shall provide—</text> <subparagraph id="id7a7f796347d24d1d86f45a2326448937"><enum>(A)</enum><text>sufficient timelines for the Administrator and State, local, and tribal governments to conduct air shed inventories, scientific research and studies necessary for the Administrator and State, local, and tribal governments to identify winter ozone causes (including precursors), and take appropriate actions necessary—</text>
 <clause id="id42a01f4927704a5ea9c0411f682a9e57"><enum>(i)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id30E59F5179594E1D8C395C13FEA72E57"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to create accurate emissions inventories and carefully model winter ozone using the most current tools available; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id385833E0E5D04B50A3EC3FDB9A7BB551" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>over a sufficient period of time, comprehensively to identify the variety of situations that typically contribute to elevated winter ozone levels;</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="idf7bf00026b9b4ff3a0de29cb1c9b4ee3"><enum>(ii)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id42A1640431304BF3B5A09C42B7814A14"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to fully analyze best available science and data to determine background ozone levels; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="idA35696CFA2464499B54A16CB34150639" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>to identify meteorological, geographical, and other factors leading to elevated winter ozone levels; and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="id59b1492b7a664355b58c703d6845c580"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to effectively identify, develop, and implement air pollution control strategies that the Administrator and State, local, and tribal governments agree are the highest-priority activities to reduce winter ozone levels; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9fc0392117be49ff80571cb8f10dfe04"><enum>(B)</enum><text>notwithstanding section 3(a)(2)(D), given the complexities of winter ozone occurrences, a minimum of 10 years after the date on which the Administrator approves an early action compact plan for the reduction of winter ozone levels under the Early Action Compact Program.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


