<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1787 IS: Full-Service Community Schools Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 1787</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150716">July 16, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S307">Mr. Brown</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S338">Mr. Manchin</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend title V of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to establish a full-service
			 community schools grant program.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
 <section id="HFA3672B60B38485B950D24E5CEAD3DA7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Full-Service Community Schools Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="idA6A714C695404E649CD74F253D870167"><enum>2.</enum><header>Full-Service community schools</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title V of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7201">20 U.S.C. 7201 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id08B543E151284C21A0FB8DA68CAC09AD" style="OLC">
				<part id="idBDEEDBA2D29D4BD0B78B1E6E405AA4D5" style="OLC"><enum>E<?LEXA-Enum E?></enum><header>Full-service community schools</header>
 <section id="HC1BD28AC931F457C934D3B793AF6F214"><enum>5701.</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purposes of this part are to—</text> <paragraph id="HD1C869C6D5894FAE89D42286501503F5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>improve student learning and development by providing supports for students that enable them to graduate college- and career-ready;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDD271A3C7A7243C8805BCAB73317CB37"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide support for the planning, implementation, and operation of full-service community schools;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H864EA875661243768CC57013F34D03AD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>improve the coordination and integration, accessibility, and effectiveness of services for children and families, particularly for students attending high-poverty schools, including high-poverty rural schools;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H591F7B995E3E4B4D81272027030EE8C2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>enable educators and school personnel to complement and enrich efforts to improve academic achievement and other results;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE04394AE876040BEA75EA2BEE7D7BA00"><enum>(5)</enum><text>ensure that children have the physical, social, and emotional well-being to come to school ready to engage in the learning process every day;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEB5517F8E50F4ECCB28B89E6D9E4AFCE"><enum>(6)</enum><text>promote and enable family and community engagement in the education of children;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H1F4ACE60DB2443BA988B6A6B18E2E5BE"><enum>(7)</enum><text>enable more efficient use of Federal, State, local, and private sector resources that serve children and families;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC1E3ED184301494BAB328466ECC4FCA8"><enum>(8)</enum><text>facilitate the coordination and integration of programs and services operated by community-based organizations, nonprofit organizations, and State, local, and tribal governments;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0035EF2931EB464A90EEE6911E8D5681"><enum>(9)</enum><text>engage students as resources to their communities; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF47DB826D9FF43DD854B1AEF2F7C8442"><enum>(10)</enum><text>engage the business community and other community organizations as partners in the development and operation of full-service community schools.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="HFC3C8FDE4A4942A09EF2ACE8DB2564C2"><enum>5702.</enum><header>Definition of full-service community school</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this part, the term <term>full-service community school</term> means a public elementary school or secondary school that—</text> <paragraph id="H6AC59738AE7F466EBCD59BF5777DAAB4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>participates in a community-based effort to coordinate and integrate educational, developmental, family, health, and other comprehensive services through community-based organizations and public and private partnerships; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H926D286F3E7A4E4AB7C465F093BF8501"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provides access to such services to students, families, and the community, such as access during the school year (including before- and after-school hours and weekends), as well as during the summer.</text>
						</paragraph></section><section id="H1438505CA409441B88C389C83C6A17BA"><enum>5703.</enum><header>Local programs</header>
 <subsection id="HE61AE06729D7484288B9A2A31B81A535"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grants</header><text>The Secretary may award grants to eligible entities to assist public elementary schools or secondary schools to function as full-service community schools.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HAF0D0B30C5CE4A88BD0DA4DFE9BD3409"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>Grants awarded under this section shall be used to—</text> <paragraph id="H2EB717F7E6AF4B2B8540F83A68C7AF0A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>coordinate not less than 3 existing qualified services and provide not less than 2 additional qualified services at 2 or more public elementary schools or secondary schools;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFBF63EFD7E274321B4E4C54D4097A377"><enum>(2)</enum><text>integrate multiple services into a comprehensive, coordinated continuum supported by research-based activities that achieve the performance goals established under subsection (c)(4)(E) to meet the holistic needs of children; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE7D03C25C32645E38A3180D261F5B943"><enum>(3)</enum><text>if applicable, coordinate and integrate services provided by community-based organizations and government agencies with services provided by specialized instructional support personnel.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAC007A0E780A4E62B255357C609F45D0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header><text>To seek a grant under this section, an eligible entity shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may require. The Secretary shall require that each such application include the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H10F52D8FE12148B3928CBF0E70657BAC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A description of the eligible entity.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8F52B95B52164E2D97B0B26CC0B79629"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A memorandum of understanding among all partner entities that will assist the eligible entity to coordinate and provide qualified services and that describes the roles the partner entities will assume.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB8CC0FD5F5B3447F9DA5499450AFF30F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A description of the capacity of the eligible entity to coordinate and provide qualified services at 2 or more full-service community schools.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H43D988BC5A534322BA4D79AD3F739AE6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A comprehensive plan that includes descriptions of the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HF37C03B7C8D94FF3B7392EA8A7CEA30A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The student, family, and school community to be served, including information about demographic characteristics that include major racial and ethnic groups, median family income, percentage of students eligible for free- and reduced-price lunch under the Richard B. Russell School Lunch Act, and other information.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H572C6FB72385463B87CDFE7DD627C72B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A needs assessment that identifies the academic, physical, social, emotional, health, mental health, and other needs of students, families, and community residents.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9620F46B172B414CA4BCBCE0ACEE3795"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A community assets assessment which identifies existing resources, as of the date of the assessment, that could be aligned.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H334BC3F08F2144848280AAFBE36331DB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The most appropriate metric to describe the plan’s reach within a community using either—</text> <clause id="H68D33A6D40364AA486EC3392D6EB237F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number of families and students to be served, and the frequency of services; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HDE6478EBD82C4FA0856D9E9AA02B8ACB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the proportion of families and students to be served, and the frequency of services.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H60804B3B1995445EA601DD7854A98A0D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Yearly measurable performance goals, including an increase in the percentage of families and students targeted for services each year of the program, which are consistent with the following objectives:</text>
 <clause id="H09BE01A64D914D8AA17E8C326519A9A5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Children are ready for school.</text> </clause><clause id="HFF3EB49F924B4F57A4058337FA0463C4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Students are engaged and achieving academically.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8C0CB5AD11664FF38745F675E56F831C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Students are physically, mentally, socially, and emotionally healthy.</text> </clause><clause id="H88428129F26E489E841A0A9A4FF0421B"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Schools and neighborhoods are safe and provide a positive climate for learning that is free from bullying or harassment.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H69844FC5BC3842D6B9A007179B997BD6"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Families are supportive and engaged in their children’s education.</text> </clause><clause id="H06E736AF0A904F039104CAF19D202476"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Students and families are prepared for postsecondary education and 21st century careers.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H461DF3FD80E64A6AA11517F348CFCD2A"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>Students are contributing to their communities.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H354C0B04A139488786A0D4F9683CFAC3"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Performance measures to monitor progress toward attainment of the goals established under subparagraph (E), including a combination of the following, to the extent applicable:</text>
 <clause id="HC413F41085B64EC786950806F6FA070B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Multiple objective measures of student achievement, including assessments, classroom grades, and other means of assessing student performance.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1F38D4667DAD4F6E93FC567462F5F0B5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Attendance (including absences related to illness and truancy) and chronic absenteeism rates.</text> </clause><clause id="HBF2630C74272481CB1100575C6A418F7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Disciplinary actions against students, including suspensions and expulsions.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5AAC4341311541448F0CFCF449C8104B"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Access to health care and treatment of illnesses demonstrated to impact academic achievement.</text> </clause><clause id="H5E303BE0BDD7433F930EF210D04E47F7"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Performance in making progress toward intervention services goals as established by specialized instructional support personnel.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB71FCB9C82164C8A951E6244AFC68CF9"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Participation rates by parents and family members in school-sanctioned activities and activities that occur as a result of community and school collaboration, as well as activities intended to support adult education and workforce development.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H67956F7EC7B145668609FB2B56244482"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>Number and percentage of students and family members provided services under this part.</text> </clause><clause id="H16C5440E046640A698826B477B68CB42"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>Valid measures of postsecondary education and career readiness.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8CD14CCD2A6E4AD0A9B1608E476CEC66"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>Service-learning and community service participation rates.</text> </clause><clause id="H63CEE9F9EAA848A3A4151FA4D5F9E0A7"><enum>(x)</enum><text>Student satisfaction surveys.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9BB5CF5147724B65B3B58E729409C2D9"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Qualified services, including existing and additional qualified services, to be coordinated and provided by the eligible entity and its partner entities, including an explanation of—</text>
 <clause id="H804EE8D57B434099856E15CD6A284C8C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>why such services have been selected;</text> </clause><clause id="H24B531C543AE446FB6B25CCCF6BBC099"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>how such services will improve student academic achievement; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H098D5C3304CC494BACD132B70F273B38"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>how such services will address performance goals established under subparagraph (E).</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE2D64D681DAB4849BE13D7002E99B923"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Plans to ensure that each site has full-time coordination of qualified services at each full-service community school, including coordination with the specialized instructional support personnel employed prior to the receipt of the grant.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2DEFD475B9BD44ABABF8C929356328C8"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Planning, coordination, management, and oversight of qualified services at each school to be served, including the role of the school principal, partner entities, parents, and members of the community.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H12F69FD330C34AEBB9E46DA8B7631222"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Funding sources for qualified services to be coordinated and provided at each school to be served, including whether such funding is derived from a grant under this section or from other Federal, State, local, or private sources.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1A4FF2A75EBA41598686AB1E8C8FCCE2"><enum>(K)</enum><text>Plans for professional development for personnel managing, coordinating, or delivering qualified services at the schools to be served.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3E1087908BF54385A06061E0BC7E69E4"><enum>(L)</enum><text>Plans for joint utilization and maintenance of school facilities by the eligible entity and its partner entities.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3F5CEC7A1D024428B51CA6627DAF1B46"><enum>(M)</enum><text>How the eligible entity and its partner entities will focus services on schools eligible for a schoolwide program under section 1114.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3655E9BB65CD4AD3AB4F538985732A05"><enum>(N)</enum><text>Plans for periodic evaluation based upon attainment of the performance measures described in subparagraph (F).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA0DB501B88FA4F47A6D21D85C1F3AD53"><enum>(O)</enum><text>How the qualified services will meet the principles of effectiveness described in subsection (d).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H97E9C83D10554B5F8090196DD93EBA8A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A plan for sustaining the programs and services outlined in this part.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H39E70CA7C35B4FC29F9860A1796A30F0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Principles of effectiveness</header><text>For a program developed pursuant to this section to meet principles of effectiveness, such program shall be based upon—</text>
 <paragraph id="HE9D5FC97AB2844A7B156D7368F03DB67"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an assessment of objective data regarding the need for the establishment of a full-service community school and qualified services at each school to be served and in the community involved;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBCA0E05F3EB644B7A4D7C8A21D6613B5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an established set of performance measures aimed at ensuring the availability and effectiveness of high-quality services; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H801FE81D38FF468A9518A0AF9B8E5128"><enum>(3)</enum><text>if appropriate, scientifically based research that provides evidence that the qualified services involved will help students meet State and local student academic achievement standards.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H1F32947F50084EA494388935B11285AC"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to eligible entities that—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="H3A2C1755424B4C0CA1ED8B4C805F757C"><enum>(1)</enum> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HF066C5E952CE44288797C9A81741DCDC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>will serve a minimum of 2 or more full-service community schools eligible for a schoolwide program under section 1114, as part of a community- or district-wide strategy; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H965009B8DA604EBD997359D6045F4B7C" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include a local educational agency that satisfies the requirements of—</text> <clause commented="no" id="H6CD861CDA1A54009B9DE7F3E4BC1E871"><enum>(i)</enum><text>subparagraph (A) or (B) of section 6211(b)(1); or</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H1DE83159F6A9427DA6E19E0EEBFF4BEA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>subparagraphs (A) and (B) of section 6221(b)(1); and</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HB20884DFF1FE467A82934F9235FD4802"><enum>(2)</enum><text>will be connected to a consortium comprised of a broad representation of stakeholders, or a consortium demonstrating a history of effectiveness.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA4C7CE53F09C48949AA9B4F8DDB2DBC7"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Grant period</header><text>Each grant awarded under this section shall be for a period of 5 years and may be renewed at the discretion of the Secretary based on the eligible entity's demonstrated effectiveness in meeting the performance goals and measures established under subparagraphs (E) and (F) of subsection (c)(4).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC9E3550A90E24F2AB47755442EDA2F1C"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Planning</header><text>The Secretary may authorize an eligible entity to use grant funds under this section for planning purposes in an amount not greater than 10 percent of the total grant amount.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H907A41AB6D7540DBA8190AA3D54506BE"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Minimum amount</header><text>The Secretary may not award a grant to an eligible entity under this section in an amount that is less than $75,000 for each year of the 5-year grant period.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0B7875E4747C41BCBA9C49AD1315211C"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H2D2EF9050B634147A6589BBCE1F6D31D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Additional qualified services</header><text>The term <term>additional qualified services</term> means qualified services directly funded under this part.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H00D70F0A548A444D9079D0B465DF9E4C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means a consortium of 1 or more local educational agencies and 1 or more community-based organizations, nonprofit organizations, or other public or private entities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0CEBA761184C480FA1742ECED5A3BD65"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Existing qualified services</header><text>The term <term>existing qualified services</term> means qualified services already being financed, as of the time of the application, by Federal, State, local, or private sources, or volunteer activities being supported as of such time by civic, business, faith-based, social, or other similar organizations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1D037C4A5B3D404AB20F1536AA320AFF"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Qualified services</header><text>The term <term>qualified services</term> means any of the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H71F828D26E3D473F9946936631CB2549"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Early childhood education.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H44D797DEB00545B4A28A5408B740E1E1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Remedial education activities and enrichment activities, including expanded learning time.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1B91AF8CA84C47ACB36E432042694F45"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Summer or after-school enrichment and learning experiences.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4E2D40FE6BE744BEADC67402656F8E0C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Programs under the Head Start Act, including Early Head Start programs.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2F22117CA5564D5A8CF180C8775D7719"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Nurse home visitation services.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H433C5234967E4E8692485FA5FD6F070C"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Teacher home visiting.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H480DEFF75F6144E3B0848C675C1210B5"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Programs that promote parental involvement and family literacy.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H79BFBEC1EC604F849E275C0D85BF3F5D"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Mentoring and other youth development programs, including peer mentoring and conflict mediation.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H025CD2DE496F4EC3949FF01EE2E5BDEF"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Parent leadership development activities.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD3A206D4153445289928A65A24F916D4"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Parenting education activities.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H27AF87F087DD433E9463FEF6892784DE"><enum>(K)</enum><text>Child care services.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H643BFC34AAF4411A94DD8C4D548C75E7"><enum>(L)</enum><text>Community service and service-learning opportunities.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCD26BB88AB4C467988CEEEBBB1AEA835"><enum>(M)</enum><text>Developmentally appropriate physical education.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5BC05A59AC67440A98A53445773CC7AA"><enum>(N)</enum><text>Programs that provide assistance to students who have been truant, suspended, or expelled.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H79CF843094134AD1991BD451D500B76E"><enum>(O)</enum><text>Job training, internship opportunities, and career counseling services.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H041FA5E0B9C74748828695F33D3173BC"><enum>(P)</enum><text>Nutrition services.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD6D062AD465C4ECEA639526A56B2AB7E"><enum>(Q)</enum><text>Primary health and dental care.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H04EA7AE5055A4030B0465486B92EB462"><enum>(R)</enum><text>Mental health counseling services.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE678E3E8DF5149C8A2E9EDB42ECB78FA"><enum>(S)</enum><text>Adult education, including instruction in English as a second language.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H56EB28E01BD44F24A92126CDCAEE6E14"><enum>(T)</enum><text>Juvenile crime prevention and rehabilitation programs.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H08D756EE890246ABA151F9B33C24D5FE"><enum>(U)</enum><text>Specialized instructional support services.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEDF2B72D41824CC7A2BF6FFC8B1B0B1F"><enum>(V)</enum><text>Homeless prevention services.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0133C2A3A3974D6AB4F4457579D80F7E"><enum>(W)</enum><text>Other services consistent with this part.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H0CF2B00EEF344113A2F71C557A72CEC9"><enum>5704.</enum><header>State programs</header>
 <subsection id="HA46EC89F29B7471AAC1AD77893C4C304"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grants</header><text>The Secretary may award grants to State collaboratives to support the development of full-service community school programs in accordance with this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HEA6114B112894C5A982ACEDD6C914347"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>Grants awarded under this section shall be used only for the following:</text> <paragraph id="HD050E4E5CF1E4D3F89A9B277365276B0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Developing a State comprehensive results and indicators framework to implement full-service community schools, consistent with performance goals described in section 5703(c)(4)(E).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7004461096CD40658D17823491628689"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Planning, coordinating, and expanding the development of full-service community schools in the State, particularly such schools in high-poverty local educational agencies, including high-poverty rural local educational agencies.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H092AC15F849A4E04AE14F594B10E2FD3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Providing technical assistance and training for full-service community schools, including professional development for personnel and creation of data collection and evaluation systems.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBB98C8361532462D9A526C4CA7800582"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Collecting, evaluating, and reporting data about the progress of full-service community schools.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HDB939F515F2E44A18E2FC345552D907E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Evaluating the impact of Federal and State policies and guidelines on the ability of eligible entities (as defined in section 5703(i)) to integrate Federal and State programs at full-service community schools, and taking action to make necessary changes.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0A7DAA1C1A834174B1F5447EBB19D861"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header><text>To seek a grant under this section, a State collaborative shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may require. The Secretary shall require that each such application include the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H04DFA29592F445E2B2800505A3BD2E45"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A memorandum of understanding among all governmental agencies and nonprofit organizations that will participate as members of the State collaborative.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3AFB3105F20B400EA7F9289ECCFE0956"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A description of the expertise of each member of the State collaborative—</text> <subparagraph id="H337489164F94473AA1CA516A53533E92"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in coordinating Federal and State programs across multiple agencies;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H460838069FF64C43AEAD0DD2B241FEE0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in working with and developing the capacity of full-service community schools; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4622DC550E314B698917854C0D2082E2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in working with high-poverty schools or rural schools and local educational agencies.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8E92CF99B3EF4E1D8363421892114733"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A comprehensive plan describing how the grant will be used to plan, coordinate, and expand the delivery of services at full-service community schools.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA872A05F422A4253B059263B64417D16"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A comprehensive accountability plan that will be used to demonstrate effectiveness, including the measurable performance goals of the program and performance measures to monitor progress and assess services’ impact on students and families and academic achievement.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H02C1E4F380744D1A88A15A5B141F11D1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>An explanation of how the State collaborative will work to ensure State policies and guidelines can support the development of full-service community schools, as well as provide technical assistance and training, including professional development, for full-service community schools.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0B54F793D48040B58C27055F01574939"><enum>(6)</enum><text>An explanation of how the State will collect and evaluate information on full-service community schools.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H370499F34F13432F910E6607EDCE1C3F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Grant period</header><text>Each grant awarded under this section shall be for a period of 5 years.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HCC98B299BAB84861AB77BC31D0706E17"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Minimum amount</header><text>The Secretary may not award a grant to a State collaborative under this section in an amount that is less than $500,000 for each year of the 5-year grant period.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1F707C557AC0453EACCDDAC58BD4B618"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section:</text> <paragraph id="H751CC87A37AE455D96E924F09911B160"><enum>(1)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> includes the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, American Samoa, Guam, the United States Virgin Islands, and any other territory or possession of the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HADB8A27B8C304D1CB080193B0CA39FD3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>State collaborative</header><text>The term <term>State collaborative</term> means a collaborative of a State educational agency and not less than 2 other governmental agencies or nonprofit organizations that provide services to children and families.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H7A9B94BBDFAC40CC8B119A214E3911C7"><enum>5705.</enum><header>Advisory committee</header>
 <subsection id="HE3CE9EE5316B47C3B1081F92CBD9E618"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is hereby established an advisory committee to be known as the <quote>Full-Service Community Schools Advisory Committee</quote> (in this section referred to as the <quote>Advisory Committee</quote>).</text> </subsection><subsection id="H8102CA2C74B0485FA02D6050D7818278"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>Subject to subsection (c), the Advisory Committee shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H404526F203C1408196E1B4FD8194D0E0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>consult with the Secretary on the development and implementation of programs under this part;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA39A4807EE8E4DA4BC89282F1204A518"><enum>(2)</enum><text>identify strategies to improve the coordination of Federal programs in support of full-service community schools; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE2CAD17EEE0A4B6AB89D34D87F0379F2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>issue an annual report to Congress on efforts under this part, including a description of—</text> <subparagraph id="HF4B109CCA1C54A979A04FECE965EDB40"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the results of local and national evaluations of such efforts; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE040E229294547BEBABE2D4272D91B9E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the scope of services being coordinated under this part.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF0EABC15D1AD4908AEFC2FABF5FBFCCD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In carrying out its duties under this section, the Advisory Committee shall consult annually with eligible entities awarded grants under section 5703, State collaboratives awarded grants under section 5704, and other entities with expertise in operating full-service community schools.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HBD4C298B4EB74C63BCDF6DAE30E5EBCD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Members</header><text>The Advisory Committee shall consist of 5 members as follows:</text> <paragraph id="HD8AF9E03B8D44B53826DF857DF126448"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary of Education (or the Secretary’s delegate).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF1024FE8E95C44ABAD5704DA24DF1553"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Attorney General of the United States (or the Attorney General’s delegate).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H14E5462AB317431F9B7F752FFC591C06"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Secretary of Agriculture (or the Secretary’s delegate).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H657DC6509B264893AC0985026D705254"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services (or the Secretary’s delegate).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H292C86D4F74146FAB3A7C25211B92744"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Secretary of Labor (or the Secretary’s delegate).</text>
							</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H0D016B38FC40440AB7AC390DD47D4E0A"><enum>5706.</enum><header>General provisions</header>
 <subsection id="HC168B114A57F41F2923C05BF97F84F57"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text>The Secretary, directly or through grants, shall provide such technical assistance as may be appropriate to accomplish the purposes of this part.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0F42FD34BFF54D41BAC268332045EF3A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Evaluations by secretary</header><text>The Secretary shall conduct evaluations on the effectiveness of grants under sections 5703 and 5704 in achieving the purposes of this part.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5FE7F572482C42CABDB671B9160C8711"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Evaluations by grantees</header><text>The Secretary shall require each recipient of a grant under this part—</text> <paragraph id="H6DFA497CC95E4B1AAEFE490F3B50AD9A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to conduct periodic evaluations of the progress achieved with the grant toward achieving the purposes of this part;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4922ECC329C94577A876A01A9B833C02"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to use such evaluations to refine and improve activities conducted with the grant and the performance measures for such activities; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H59D481C7623E45D788911F22C2701EED"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to make the results of such evaluations publicly available, including by providing public notice of such availability.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5E19C5DCB2C04A67817B513BFCFC61F3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Construction clause</header><text>Nothing in this part shall be construed to alter or otherwise affect the rights, remedies, and procedures afforded school or school district employees under Federal, State, or local laws (including applicable regulations or court orders) or under the terms of collective bargaining agreements, memoranda of understanding, or other agreements between such employees and their employers.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H071231FE4BE146F180F6185D14D9E560"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Supplement, not supplant</header><text>Funds made available to a grantee under this part may be used only to supplement, and not supplant, any other Federal, State, or local funds that would otherwise be available to carry out the activities assisted under this part.</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="HAB8DA7D37ED345B29B9B971835887E60"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Matching funds</header>
 <paragraph id="H5F77237430EA4EB1A4F6D58D2F8ACEDE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall require each recipient of a grant under this part to provide matching funds from non-Federal sources in an amount determined under paragraph (2).</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="HE3BE4C54FD3B4640A7799098AEFDFBCF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Determination of amount of match</header>
 <subparagraph id="HB1C4A1EC281A4218809553F569090FDD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Sliding scale</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B), the Secretary shall determine the amount of matching funds to be required of a grantee under this subsection based on a sliding fee scale that takes into account—</text>
 <clause id="H8747E076134A4A5DA7F6C9179E849341"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the relative poverty of the population to be targeted by the grantee; and</text> </clause><clause id="H30E0458072AB46229F5177CC501891B6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the ability of the grantee to obtain such matching funds.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7215EE1A13224D4ABE65B2CC7B5C8C2B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Maximum amount</header><text>The Secretary may not require any grantee under this part to provide matching funds in an amount that exceeds the amount of the grant award.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC1A38BF188664B30B49769252765B22F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>In-kind contributions</header><text>The Secretary shall permit grantees under this part to match funds in whole or in part with in-kind contributions.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H272DADB58BE14D8ABF2BDB6256A5D78A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Consideration</header><text>Notwithstanding this subsection, the Secretary shall not consider an applicant’s ability to match funds when determining which applicants will receive grants under this part.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7E05B6361DB74B6DBAC1C22BD633A31B"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Special rule</header><text>Entities receiving funds under this part shall comply with all existing Federal statutes that prohibit discrimination.</text>
						</subsection></section><section id="H20013D3289004A2C9A7F81908473002D"><enum>5707.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
 <subsection commented="no" id="H26C9F748930D4F01815791277AA0E8D7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this part such sums as may be necessary for each of fiscal years 2016 through 2021.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6D3A2AAA84B546A7A76C4F9066FC9316"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Allocation</header><text>Of the amounts appropriated to carry out this part for each fiscal year—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="H26A01B6976164E7588C96417CFEA894D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">85 percent shall be for section 5703, and of the funds available for new grants awarded under such section after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Full-Service Community Schools Act of 2015</short-title>, not less than 10 percent of such funds shall be made available for local educational agencies that satisfy the requirements of—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HA2E5165303ED4D7CBB9DA1583639392B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>subparagraph (A) or (B) of section 6211(b)(1); or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H94FED62E797848839984FB3BC468EE50"><enum>(B)</enum><text>subparagraphs (A) and (B) of section 6221(b)(1);</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCCBD9BE0312E4700945179C0F9D8A0F3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>10 percent shall be for section 5704; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0A815BCEEB09487287DEFD19A141546B"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">5 percent shall be for subsections (a) and (b) of section 5706, of which not less than $500,000 shall be for technical assistance under section 5706(a).</text>
							</paragraph></subsection></section></part><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body>
</bill>


