<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1926 IS: Protecting Access to Lifesaving Screenings Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-08-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 1926</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150804">August 4, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S182">Ms. Mikulski</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S340">Ms. Ayotte</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To ensure access to screening mammography services.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting Access to Lifesaving Screenings Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PALS Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="id2BFA8BFFE0E54804ABE5F5F2737FD28A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Ensuring access to screening mammography services</header>
 <subsection id="id5342CAFD6D4D456582BD83C726C6B563"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Effective during the period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act and ending January 1, 2018, any provision of law that refers (including through cross-reference to another provision of law) to the current recommendations of the United States Preventive Services Task Force with respect to breast cancer screening, mammography, and prevention shall be administered by the Secretary involved as if—</text>
 <paragraph id="idda9b6e402a4b4dab9b8ba31bdec234e3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>such reference to such current recommendations were a reference to the recommendations of such Task Force with respect to breast cancer screening, mammography, and prevention last issued before 2009; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id2bc6e7249b794840aab6d68cbb183d30"><enum>(2)</enum><text>such recommendations last issued before 2009 applied to any screening mammography modality under section 1861(jj) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x(jj)</external-xref>).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idBB3721288B52423EBDB05D1992BDD7B7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Codification of current Medicare coverage and payment policies</header>
 <paragraph id="id4f71f1aed2fc4119ba04dfa24da01478"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>Section 1861(jj) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x(jj)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>, including any digital modality of such a procedure,</quote> after <quote>radiologic procedure</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="ide5f231603a36412188c66cbc5252538a"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Coinsurance</header><text>Section 1833(a)(1)(Y) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395l">42 U.S.C. 1395l(a)(1)(Y)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>or are services described in section 1861(jj)</quote> after <quote>population</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id96fee5694ba84a00853d9e5fe4279985"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Frequency</header><text>Section 1834(c)(2)(B)(ii) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395m">42 U.S.C. 1395m(c)(2)(B)(ii)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting before the period at the end the following: <quote>for women described only in clause (i) or (ii) of subparagraph (A)</quote>.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id67F0889221B74574B4E979BA1CB67601"><enum>(c)</enum><header>GAO study and report</header>
 <paragraph id="idF7C93C8D830E4438B67BADC369DD439D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Study</header><text>The Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study on the methodologies and processes by which the United States Preventive Services Task Force develops recommendations regarding preventive services, including the transparency of such methodologies and processes, the engagement of stakeholders in such methodologies and processes, the responses of the Task Force to comments from stakeholders regarding draft research plans, draft evidence reviews, and draft recommendations, and the propriety of the data and other information on which the Task Force relies in developing a recommendation regarding a preventive service.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idC56630202DBA424E9C05925ADE522621"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>The Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Secretary of Health and Human Services and to the appropriate committees of Congress, not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, a report on the results of the study conducted under paragraph (1), including any recommendations for administrative or legislative changes the Comptroller General determines necessary or appropriate to improve the methodologies and processes by which the United States Preventive Services Task Force develops recommendations regarding preventive services.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


