<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S787 IS: NTIS Elimination Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 787</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150318">March 18, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S312">Mrs. McCaskill</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S340">Ms. Ayotte</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To streamline the collection and distribution of government information.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body>
 <section id="id4A80B969CC5841638E7836571D71B057" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>NTIS Elimination Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="idF444E8339F7F4801BF1DFCF369870DCC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="id76BAE9F422F34662A177E1E66D63F308"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The National Technical Information Service (referred to in this Act as <quote>NTIS</quote>), the National Archives and Records Administration, the Government Accountability Office (referred to in this Act as <quote>GAO</quote>), and the Library of Congress all collect, categorize, and distribute government information.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idB513AF32E4394AD28D87E0BB17EACDCA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>NTIS was established in 1950, more than 40 years before the creation of the Internet.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idBF6D7E49F0D64802A24915E74501A5BF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>NTIS is tasked with collecting and distributing government-funded scientific, technical, engineering, and business-related information and reports.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idCD4D2A88AE47471CBA42A103C24F219F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>GAO found that NTIS sold only 8 percent of the 2,500,000 reports in its collection between 1995 and 2000.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id6FC37EE2639048639EE7633C81EB42E0"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A November 2012 GAO review of NTIS made the following conclusions:</text> <subparagraph id="idA5306C6203D749DABB9C79AFF619287F"><enum>(A)</enum><text><quote>Of the reports added to NTIS’s repository during fiscal years 1990 through 2011, GAO estimates that approximately 74 percent were readily available from other public sources.</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6E232A1B9B2A4B0C9FDEB54C59C4359C"><enum>(B)</enum><text><quote>These reports were often available either from the issuing organization’s website, the Federal Internet portal (http://www.USA.gov) or from another source located through a web search.</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idFC4BC87329A747009099E01E4F95A916"><enum>(C)</enum><text><quote>The source that most often had the report [GAO] was searching for was another website located through http://www.Google.com.</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA5E2A27AA4B64869B143A8A23EF56645"><enum>(D)</enum><text><quote>95 percent of the reports available from sources other than NTIS were available free of charge.</quote>.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idB4E7B80E9A304B0F9477002E2123F6FB"><enum>(6)</enum><text>No Federal agency should use taxpayer dollars to purchase a report from the National Technical Information Service that is available through the Internet for free.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id17879FE5512644D29BCCA2439FCF8FFD"><enum>(7)</enum><text>In 1999, Secretary of Commerce William Daley—</text> <subparagraph id="idF098EB4B4D424DBEAA9BDAB37159A311"><enum>(A)</enum><text>admitted that the National Technical Information Service would eventually outlive its usefulness and be unable to sustain its revenue-losing profit model;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA1CFE8D4A8C94A66AE9F79D65D0ADAAD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>explained that <quote>declining sales revenues soon would not be sufficient to recover all of NTIS’ operating costs</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idDDB99187C9BE48AEA953F2ABB66BB0D1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>attributed this <quote>decline to other agencies’ practice of making their research results available to the public for free through the Web</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1B5A30B5BCC8436AB0DE8A0DA2F15C63"><enum>(8)</enum><text>According to the November 2012 GAO report referred to in paragraph (5)—</text> <subparagraph id="id9687C1D227AE4D9683F07A242C50A2DD"><enum>(A)</enum><text><quote>NTIS product expenditures exceeded revenues for 10 out of the past 11 fiscal years.</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC4D3C794C54A47C5916DF289562B60F8"><enum>(B)</enum><text><quote>The agency lost, on average, about $1.3 million over the last 11 years on its products.</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id99BC46DEB2CD48DA95A8EA5DCBFB8750"><enum>(C)</enum><text><quote>The decline in revenue for its products continues to call into question whether NTIS’s basic statutory function of acting as a self-financing repository and disseminator of scientific and technical information is still viable.</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idB25FA132862945F19A48804F3CF24158"><enum>(9)</enum><text>NTIS has compensated for its lost revenue by charging other Federal agencies for various services that are not associated with NTIS’s primary mission.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id61E0484C2559417AA8B18A45C11FC4AC"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Future technological advances will ensure that the services offered by NTIS are even more superfluous for essential government functions than they are today.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="id575CCFF83431489EA140A32BDBE99754"><enum>3.</enum><header>National Technical Information Service</header>
 <subsection id="id9D93A330E2E04AE7B1A86E008FB8FCB2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Repeal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Effective on the date that is 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the National Technical Information Act of 1988 (subtitle B of title II of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/100/519">Public Law 100–519</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/3704b">15 U.S.C. 3704b</external-xref>) is repealed.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="idFDF6193FF6544BB1A23224494BE56A78"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Transfer of critical functions</header>
 <paragraph id="idBF27CC4073C34B1699604B5B5F2A3524"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Consultation requirement</header><text>The Secretary of Commerce, the Archivist of the United States, and the Comptroller General of the United States shall consult with the Director of the Office of Management and Budget to determine if any activity or function of the National Technical Information Service—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idD4EFCA567CA8410B8FA0492DC9874DD9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is critical to the national economy; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9876DC9F101046308FB0C15F5E79B4DA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is not being carried out by—</text> <clause id="idBF08BBB43D12440FB699EF748A8C19FE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any other agency or instrumentality of the Federal Government; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="idE83569222D8B4445B962CD21A546D80F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a contractor of the Federal Government.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id6C0392B3F8B74E908B19830BA9D017A0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Transfers authorized</header> <subparagraph id="id27F47FAD76874E8E8ADBB5A6DF36B613"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Before the effective date set forth in subsection (a), the Secretary of Commerce is authorized to transfer the responsibility for any NTIS activity or function that is critical to the national economy and not otherwise being carried out (as determined under paragraph (1)) to another office within the Department of Commerce.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD6731A0D64A9405C946B59E3185250FB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Congressional notification</header><text>Before transferring any activity or function pursuant to subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall submit a report to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate</committee-name>, the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate</committee-name>, the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives</committee-name>, the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives</committee-name> that—</text>
 <clause id="id1184DE18FAF849788E8A4939C1D2136B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>identifies the activities or functions that will be transferred; and</text> </clause><clause id="idF43CC130917C49E08DF7945BFEAE0078"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provides the rationale for determining that such activities or functions are critical to the national economy.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idCF11D72911D8494DAD503F9CD8DE3C5E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Defined term</header><text>As used in this subsection, an activity or function that is <term>critical to the national economy</term> promotes the economic growth of the United States by providing access to information that stimulates innovation and discovery.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idf4ae8fce132d43da90e00b4e270af007"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Repository of nonclassified information</header>
 <paragraph id="id9C3A891C8D58460EAAC375D66C8CAB9E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Commerce is authorized to continue to maintain a permanent repository of nonclassified scientific, technical, and engineering information that contains reports that are scientific, technical, or engineering in nature.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="id5934c286d95241d0a82880abc0b0b19c"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Item to be included</header>
 <subparagraph id="idDC62F883F69D41AEA1EDB3D7BD5396EC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>All Federal entities shall send electronic copies of all nonclassified scientific, technical, and engineering reports and information to the Department of Commerce for inclusion in the repository referred to in paragraph (1).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA04D33C2D7654A918AF73712F7337BD0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Notification requirement</header><text>If any Federal entity regularly fails to comply with the requirement under subparagraph (A), the Secretary of Commerce shall notify—</text>
 <clause id="id9223752D13AD44D8AF718CB2A3899E6E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate</committee-name>; and</text> </clause><clause id="id91072702A3244A3581071616E76AD299"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives</committee-name>.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idb0852167212540f9b595f82f0367d39a"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The repository referred to in paragraph (1) and any document therein shall be publicly available and searchable, including bibliographic information, in a format that is useful to American industry, business, libraries, and research institutions.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idbb203d11f97148ff9564c88146f6e1b6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Digital copies</header><text>The Secretary shall provide digital copies of any document in the repository referred to in paragraph (1) to the public free of charge.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id5b24fa8f22454809890aa6365ae150cf"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to maintain the repository referred to in paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id14501daf1b224927aa6f345faa7eb1de"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Bibliographic information</header><text>The Secretary of Commerce shall continue to make selected bibliographic information products available in a timely manner to depository libraries as part of the Depository Library Program of the Government Publishing Office.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idf8293beb73ce4fb4a5f7db79d4482a20"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Use of technology</header><text>The Secretary of Commerce shall utilize available technology to ensure that the Department of Commerce is collecting all nonclassified scientific, technical, and engineering information to the best of its ability.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="id40980E7247504FAEB415DD82394E3255"><enum>4.</enum><header>NTIS Revolving Fund</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Treasury, after consultation with the Secretary of Commerce, shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="idEE3E940160284EB7A78F3A156CCE2301"><enum>(1)</enum><text>transfer all unexpended balances in the National Technical Information Service Revolving Fund (referred to in this section as the <quote>Fund</quote>), established pursuant to the Department of Commerce Appropriations Act, 1993 (title II of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/102/305">Public Law 102–305</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/3704b">15 U.S.C. 3704b</external-xref> note), to the Department of Commerce to be expended solely for the maintenance of the repository described in section 3(c); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id47F8BC1EE2364ACD9E9803671E16E69A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>dissolve the Fund.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="idCAD1B35BFDE34292A15A4E0CF890000C"><enum>5.</enum><header>Secretary of Commerce certification</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Before the effective date set forth in section 3(a), the Secretary of Commerce shall submit a written certification to the<committee-name committee-id="SSCM00"> Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate</committee-name> and the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives</committee-name> that all of the operations of the National Technical Information Service, except for the activities or functions transferred pursuant to section 3(b)(2)(A), have been terminated.</text></section></legis-body></bill>


