<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S840 IS: Student Loan Borrower Bill of Rights</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 840</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150323">March 23, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S259">Mr. Reed</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require certain protections for student loan borrowers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short
 title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Student Loan Borrower Bill of Rights</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="idE53B4D9CB8254E09964BE185079F8EE0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Truth in Lending
 Act amendments</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Truth in Lending Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1601">15 U.S.C. 1601 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="id6BBC3BA5D05A45FFA0ADD0F9B27218AE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 128 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1638">15 U.S.C. 1638</external-xref>)—</text> <subparagraph id="id9730A070536E4BCA81C835C3F3B7E223"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (e)—</text>
 <clause id="idDAA605DE93ED4071A4D2BF5209150738"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the subsection heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">private</header-in-text></quote>;</text> </clause><clause id="id462F37AA9B284D94890AC52DC7DE39E5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)(O), by striking <quote>paragraph (6)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraph (9)</quote>;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id8A244FE655104366AF4A621983CA95F7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)(L), by striking <quote>paragraph (6)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraph (9)</quote>;</text> </clause><clause id="id6BE236D676DC4CB9A5824EFA62AE39C0"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)(C), by striking <quote>paragraph (7)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraph (10)</quote>;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idFEC64D243E6848D8912EC8D24C8D2860"><enum>(v)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (5) through (11) as paragraphs (8) through (14), respectively;</text> </clause><clause id="id868B901B3F4A4874B06ECDC0730FA307"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (4) the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB01E67A8C0644278997C3201376608FF" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="id27B2EBB013154F4492C509EAACC0AEA1"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Disclosures before first fully amortized payment</header><text>Not fewer than 30 days and not more than 150 days before the first fully amortized payment on a postsecondary education loan is due from the borrower, the postsecondary educational lender shall disclose to the borrower, clearly and conspicuously—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id44803EDBB65C4BE3B4FE23BA628AB10D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the information described in—</text> <clause id="id8a43485ab8034a05b87638f1dfd2578a"><enum>(i)</enum><text>paragraph (2)(A) (adjusted, as necessary, for the rate of interest in effect on the date the first fully amortized payment on a postsecondary education loan is due);</text>
 </clause><clause id="iddca40f4f88464f1a9b9a5c84b40ea6e2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>subparagraphs (B) through (G) of paragraph (2);</text> </clause><clause id="idd690367673f046b0b2fea67a70ef5c34"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>paragraph (2)(H) (adjusted, as necessary, for the rate of interest in effect on the date the first fully amortized payment on a postsecondary education loan is due);</text>
 </clause><clause id="idab3f2e160e0848a9bacfca7a1c0d5126"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>paragraph (2)(K); and</text> </clause><clause id="id7bf6dcbb9c274953982a9365530ade91"><enum>(v)</enum><text>subparagraphs (O) and (P) of paragraph (2);</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4e9b5f3abea94cee90c051bb558eace6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the scheduled date upon which the first fully amortized payment is due;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id79c980433c7f411ea6390f6cbd175f3d"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the name of the lender and servicer, and the address to which communications and payments should be sent including a telephone number and website where the borrower may obtain additional information;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8e85f2f80f8643139680027f383f4d9d"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a description of alternative repayment plans, including loan consolidation or refinancing, and servicemember or veteran benefits under the Servicemembers Civil Relief Act (50 U.S.C. App. 501 et seq.) or other Federal or State law related to postsecondary education loans; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idaca59ef03c1d48aa8a5fa0ad7bea35fc"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a statement that a Servicemember and Veterans Liaison designated under paragraph (15)(I) is available to answer inquiries about servicemember and veteran benefits related to postsecondary education loans, including the toll-free telephone number to contact the Liaison pursuant to paragraph (15)(I).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id4403AB6EB0CF44F69110B068B8B550CA"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Disclosures when borrower is 30 days delinquent</header><text>Not fewer than 5 days after a borrower becomes 30 days delinquent on a postsecondary education loan, the postsecondary educational lender shall disclose to the borrower, clearly and conspicuously—</text>
 <subparagraph id="iddc2479ba64fa4304b4b367ef880e8935"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the date on which the loan will be charged-off (as defined in paragraph (15)(A)) or assigned to collections, including the consequences of such charge-off or assignment to collections, if no payment is made;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0f70280c60544dfe93463465885bf908"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the minimum payment that the borrower must make to avoid the loan being charged off (as defined in paragraph (15)(A)) or assigned to collection, and the minimum payment that the borrower must make to bring the loan current;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide414bbbc822d4de58c025b7b51f0f4de"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a statement informing the borrower that a payment of less than the minimum payment described in subparagraph (B) could result in the loan being charged off (as defined in paragraph (15)(A)) or assigned to collection; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id487c4663c36f4dc19784eff2e1b7a936"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a statement that a Servicemember and Veterans Liaison designated under paragraph (15)(I) is available to answer inquiries about servicemember and veteran benefits related to postsecondary education loans, including the toll-free telephone number to contact the Liaison pursuant to paragraph (15)(I).</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idD6193DA359284E44A3E46469F0AD424B"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Disclosures when borrower is having difficulty making payment or is 60 days delinquent</header>
 <subparagraph id="idF1B1F1AD12934F4F8AEB26DD1804E178"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not fewer than 5 days after a borrower notifies a postsecondary educational lender that the borrower is having difficulty making payment or a borrower becomes 60 days delinquent on a postsecondary education loan, the postsecondary educational lender shall—</text>
 <clause id="id23ee3749b8b5431188807ff27968756f"><enum>(i)</enum><text>complete a full review of the borrower’s postsecondary education loan and make a reasonable effort to obtain the information necessary to determine—</text>
 <subclause id="idb0a0f273d71a478fa2c64383f7617d64"><enum>(I)</enum><text>if the borrower is eligible for an alternative repayment plan, including loan consolidation or refinancing; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id5d7b23f0b4314af79281190ce1244d3c"><enum>(II)</enum><text>if the borrower is eligible for servicemember or veteran benefits under the Servicemembers Civil Relief Act (50 U.S.C. App. 501 et seq.) or other Federal or State law related to postsecondary education loans;</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="id1047573a46c34215b431e1193ba2adc4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provide the borrower, in writing, in simple and understandable terms, information about alternative repayment plans and benefits for which the borrower is eligible, including all terms, conditions, and fees or costs associated with such repayment plan, pursuant to paragraph (8)(D);</text>
 </clause><clause id="id5b86475f07f54d0b8a07d21df190cad4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>allow the borrower not less than 30 days to apply for an alternative repayment plan or benefits, if eligible; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id4723bbfa4ad6434a9c391724fe2e0053"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>notify the borrower that a Servicemember and Veterans Liaison designated under paragraph (15)(I) is available to answer inquiries about servicemember and veteran benefits related to postsecondary education loans, including the toll-free telephone number to contact the Liaison pursuant to paragraph (15)(I).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id23610AE0981E4FC9836711DA97CB9C31"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Forbearance or deferment</header><text>If a borrower notifies the postsecondary educational lender that a long-term alternative repayment plan is not appropriate, the postsecondary educational lender may comply with this paragraph by providing the borrower, in writing, in simple and understandable terms, information about short-term options to address an anticipated short-term difficulty in making payments, such as forbearance or deferment options, including all terms, conditions, and fees or costs associated with such options pursuant to paragraph (8)(D).</text>
								</subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1F91684D7B5F4588A2F8344138DB5601"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Notification process</header>
 <clause id="id5be0c9ffeef24c839184384ec8703481"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each postsecondary educational lender shall establish a process, in accordance subparagraph (A), for a borrower to notify the lender that—</text>
 <subclause id="id4193dd9da4a24c989ecfaf372677759b"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the borrower is having difficulty making payments on a postsecondary education loan; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="id6647504e87144d1a9aa83f1246c906c5"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a long-term alternative repayment plan is not needed.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="idb2767053dcee4fcfa26097caa756f054"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Consumer financial protection bureau requirements</header><text>The Director of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection, in consultation with the Secretary of Education, shall promulgate rules establishing minimum standards for postsecondary educational lenders in carrying out the requirements of this paragraph and a model form for borrowers to notify postsecondary educational lenders of the information under this paragraph.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </clause><clause id="id50F916B174EC43AFA7388BD4DB354654"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>in paragraph (8), as redesignated by clause (v), by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF8A089C5E7854AFEBC8F1D7405401870" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="id8FC58F6B5F90460596BEDDA30EF9B1FE"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Model disclosure form for alternative repayment plans, forbearance, and deferment options</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Student Loan Borrower Bill of Rights</short-title>, the Director of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection, in consultation with the Secretary of Education, shall develop and issue model forms to allow borrowers to compare alternative repayment plans, forbearance, and deferment options with the borrower’s existing repayment plan with respect to a postsecondary education loan. Such forms shall include the following:</text>
 <clause id="idbd14f8098c5c4484b9d3f6a6e9f53e64"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The total amount to be paid over the life of the loan.</text> </clause><clause id="id23c0a2f0f8f74eb085f76446238e5bee"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The total amount in interest to be paid over the life of the loan.</text>
 </clause><clause id="id3331bd25da8a47758ddff6307c4be0ef"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The monthly payment amount.</text> </clause><clause id="id4cc757daad2240b09b379335fb0bdb04"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The expected pay-off date.</text>
 </clause><clause id="id01e19e7be67040cf970e9a2f924a4ad1"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Related fees and costs.</text> </clause><clause id="id55faf8c0deda46dfbbe2733da716cd8a"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Eligibility requirements, and how the borrower can apply for the alternative repayment plan, forbearance, or deferment option.</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="idd15aa4265331475ba5fac4faa52047b0"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>Any relevant consequences due to action or inaction, such as default, including any actions that would result in the loss of eligibility for alternative repayment plans, forbearance, or deferment options.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </clause><clause id="id440862ABD79F49F8AAC47D9AD3D35BAA"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>in paragraph (11), as redesignated by clause (v), by striking <quote>paragraph (7)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraph (10)</quote>;</text> </clause><clause id="id72C0710233D7424E93402F71637CF978"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (13), as redesignated by clause (v), and inserting the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id55F32F3BAD154E3CBA91E415016FD215" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="idEF388715D57E493FA066B3E6F811CE45"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection—</text> <subparagraph id="id9B0965165BE14B53A614AB9736810349"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the terms <term>covered educational institution</term>, <quote>private educational lender</quote>, and <quote>private education loan</quote> have the same meanings as in section 140; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id04199FB9A6D64A928ECB182C8CA88D90"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the term <term>postsecondary education loan</term> means—</text> <clause id="id82C70FFEF30948DE8FDD2D4569FA6387"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a private education loan; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="idC8931565C638449DBD14176C1479C5CE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a loan made, insured, or guaranteed under part B, D, or E of title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1071">20 U.S.C. 1071 et seq.</external-xref>, 1087a et seq., and 1087aa et seq.).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </clause><clause id="id7995ABCFD93F491C925E724AB02E2012"><enum>(x)</enum><text>in paragraph (14), as redesignated by clause (v), by striking <quote>paragraph (5)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraph (8)</quote>; and</text> </clause><clause id="id5A4ECB8F7D38405AB474961204DA865E"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF5469F31C5E24D7BB9189AEE0AA90744" style="OLC">
							<paragraph id="id42045B4F105847DF8B21168E5F4FCC99"><enum>(15)</enum><header>Student loan borrower bill of rights</header>
 <subparagraph id="idBFA750F9B57F4EBCAB929F2EC41E2E4B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this paragraph:</text> <clause id="idf480f6c65ffa4689b169781757c1bcca"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Borrower</header><text>The term <term>borrower</term> means the person to whom a postsecondary education loan is extended.</text>
 </clause><clause id="idd96f7f46ddf14c7faf5632ef3f18b4ec"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Charge off</header><text>The term <term>charge off</term> means charge to profit and loss, or subject to any similar action.</text>
									</clause><clause id="idde18ecc90f1c4143836758547db42a51"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Qualified written request</header>
 <subclause id="id1c385ee5b9af4c73a92996b05454502f"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>qualified written request</term> means a written correspondence of a borrower (other than notice on a payment medium supplied by the student loan servicer) transmitted by mail, facsimile, or electronically through an email address or website designated by the student loan servicer to receive communications from borrowers that—</text>
 <item id="id5801c55588b046e08ba72a154ef3ed76"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>includes, or otherwise enables the student loan servicer to identify, the name and account of the borrower; and</text>
 </item><item id="id735b17456a5f475183b939c67afca34d"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>includes, to the extent applicable—</text> <subitem id="id291c8c226ddb4c138f132b01ba460dac"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>sufficient detail regarding the information sought by the borrower; or</text>
 </subitem><subitem id="idd5ea1510de0c4a409c5ef7f0088a60ae"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>a statement of the reasons for the belief of the borrower that there is an error regarding the account of the borrower.</text>
												</subitem></item></subclause><subclause id="id074b787a1cb640229a5e33b32cad7e82"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Correspondence delivered to other addresses</header>
 <item id="id9ca17b9d739a4906bd0878c59daa038d"><enum>(aa)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A written correspondence of a borrower is a qualified written request if the written correspondence is transmitted to and received by a student loan servicer at a mailing address, facsimile number, email address, or website address other than the address or number designated by that student loan servicer to receive communications from borrowers but the written correspondence meets the requirements under items (aa) and (bb) of subclause (I).</text>
 </item><item id="idddde13bff1e744de8d82d31a3ea9b474"><enum>(bb)</enum><header>Duty to transfer</header><text>A student loan servicer shall, within a reasonable period of time, transfer a written correspondence of a borrower received by the student loan servicer at a mailing address, facsimile number, email address, or website address other than the address or number designated by that student loan servicer to receive communications from borrowers to the correct address or appropriate office or other unit of the student loan servicer.</text>
 </item><item id="id53e2c5cfe13642cca324488dcba40aa7"><enum>(cc)</enum><header>Date of receipt</header><text>A written correspondence of a borrower transferred in accordance with item (bb) shall be deemed to be received by the student loan servicer on the date on which the written correspondence is transferred to the correct address or appropriate office or other unit of the student loan servicer.</text>
 </item></subclause></clause><clause id="idc00573f6bfd74b88935a3669cdf019b6"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Servicer</header><text>The term <term>servicer</term> means the person responsible for the servicing of a postsecondary education loan, including any agent of such person or the person who makes, owns, or holds a loan if such person also services the loan.</text>
 </clause><clause id="idBD3DE2C3BD564009B9AFEF6022245E3E"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Servicing</header><text>The term <term>servicing</term> means—</text> <subclause id="idDC3DB1A6FE8846E5973CB4FEF15D1C07"><enum>(I)</enum><text>receiving any scheduled periodic payments from a borrower pursuant to the terms of a postsecondary education loan;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id9E2AE90E1C3748DA8EFE027A661FE57D"><enum>(II)</enum><text>making the payments of principal and interest and such other payments with respect to the amounts received from the borrower, as may be required pursuant to the terms of the loan; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idFAFC3492EA634B3EA59B99AF38E0235D"><enum>(III)</enum><text>performing other administrative services with respect to the loan.</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6CBD34002F8A4676979753E9CBEF3BEE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Sale, transfer, or assignment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the sale, other transfer, assignment, or transfer of servicing obligations of a postsecondary education loan results in a change in the identity of the party to whom the borrower must send subsequent payments or direct any communications concerning the loan—</text>
 <clause id="id2F110B95BE634EB0992E0B6AAEEA87AA"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the transferor shall—</text> <subclause id="id111ad01e6d364aa0b52bf122ee516228"><enum>(I)</enum><text>notify the borrower, in writing, in simple and understandable terms, not fewer than 45 days before transferring a legally enforceable right to receive payment from the borrower on such loan, of—</text>
 <item id="id68a37143148145138305ca8c64b8c41e"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the sale or other transfer, assignment, or transfer of servicing obligations;</text>
 </item><item id="id988c5b6ce5274713a2c355cb420f9b7a"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the identity of the transferee;</text>
 </item><item id="id591af3c1e3e84149ba7aa829ed04fd72"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>the name and address of the party to whom subsequent payments or communications must be sent;</text>
 </item><item id="ida3576db0aac14f238d43f4a365b97476"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>the telephone numbers and websites of both the transferor and the transferee;</text>
 </item><item id="id3b68590bf5fb4c00acfdcb3298f7fc5d"><enum>(ee)</enum><text>the effective date of the sale, transfer, or assignment;</text>
 </item><item id="id0c981ecd0c6a4661afe33c4cf35d794b"><enum>(ff)</enum><text>the date on which the transferor will stop accepting payment; and</text>
 </item><item id="id337763f175a24071a6871599f789ee60"><enum>(gg)</enum><text>the date on which the transferee will begin accepting payment; and</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause id="id8c7832563b424978886f7b1afcd07097"><enum>(II)</enum><text>forward any payment from a borrower with respect to such postsecondary education loan to the transferee, immediately upon receiving such payment, during the 60-day period beginning on the date on which the transferor stops accepting payment of such postsecondary education loan; and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="id4db3f6de5af045d09d87135383a5b9b6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the transferee shall—</text>
 <subclause id="ide501ad1104f6480da1f9f4edea201cd7"><enum>(I)</enum><text>notify the borrower, in writing, in simple and understandable terms, not fewer than 45 days before acquiring a legally enforceable right to receive payment from the borrower on such loan, of—</text>
 <item id="id275dc11adf7949b1a51843371521cab6"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the sale or other transfer, assignment, or transfer of servicing obligations;</text>
 </item><item id="id66fec84c5f1e46038f0905e92d0ec987"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the identity of the transferor:</text>
 </item><item id="id13dd28ff0cc7429391889ba3ea18fbe5"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>the name and address of the party to whom subsequent payments or communications must be sent;</text>
 </item><item id="idc74bad8099e44c67a81c59db488135d8"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>the telephone numbers and websites of both the transferor and the transferee;</text>
 </item><item id="idcb2d266aaa9c44fcbc3a0e062c2c6200"><enum>(ee)</enum><text>the effective date of the sale, transfer, assignment, or transfer of servicing obligations;</text>
 </item><item id="idb3498199096c42d39d564215085b7ad9"><enum>(ff)</enum><text>the date on which the transferor will stop accepting payment; and</text>
 </item><item id="id9e63e157d63b461f9458d780ac9190e1"><enum>(gg)</enum><text>the date on which the transferee will begin accepting payment;</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause id="id2f4d268566224cac8999127981f4b363"><enum>(II)</enum><text>accept as on-time and may not impose any late fee or finance charge for any payment from a borrower with respect to such postsecondary education loan that is forwarded from the transferor during the 60-day period beginning on the date on which the transferor stops accepting payment, if the transferor receives such payment on or before the applicable due date, including any grace period;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id74e09004767841be90f41947f74462fd"><enum>(III)</enum><text>provide borrowers a simple, online process for transferring existing electronic fund transfer authority; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idd840567c7a404e83a9f2fd4a3c519a4e"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>honor any promotion or benefit offered to the borrower or advertised by the previous owner or transferor of such postsecondary education loan.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2327E13EF3D34E01B48A3AAF948742A2"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Material change in mailing address or procedure for handling payments</header><text>If a servicer makes a change in the mailing address, office, or procedures for handling payments with respect to any postsecondary education loan, and such change causes a delay in the crediting of the account of the borrower made during the 60-day period following the date on which such change took effect, the servicer may not impose any late fee or finance charge for a late payment on such postsecondary education loan.</text>
								</subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5517DF93489743F89091903E963B5C9B"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Application of payments</header>
 <clause id="idb5487d421bd44f25b47ad6e9ef20ac8a"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Unless otherwise directed by the borrower of a postsecondary education loan, upon receipt of a payment, the servicer shall apply amounts first to the interest and fees owed on the payment due date, and then to the principal balance of the postsecondary education loan bearing the highest annual percentage rate, and then to each successive interest and fees and then principal balance bearing the next highest annual percentage rate, until the payment is exhausted. A borrower may instruct or expressly authorize the servicer to apply payments in a different manner.</text>
 </clause><clause id="id831a8db6bd054b5fbe5730a297f5c677"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Application of excess amounts</header><text>Unless otherwise directed by the borrower of a postsecondary education loan, upon receipt of a payment, the servicer shall apply amounts in excess of the minimum payment amount first to the interest and fees owed on the payment due date, and then to the principal balance of the postsecondary education loan balance bearing the highest annual percentage rate, and then to each successive interest and fees and principal balance bearing the next highest annual percentage rate, until the payment is exhausted. A borrower may instruct or expressly authorize the servicer to apply such excess payments in a different manner. A borrower may also voluntarily increase the periodic payment amount, including by increasing their recurring electronic payment, with the right to return to their original amortization schedule at any time. Servicers shall provide a simple, online method to allow borrowers to make voluntary one-time additional payments, voluntarily increase the amount of their periodic payment, and return to their original amortization schedule.</text>
 </clause><clause id="id6cd3f68c592d4ff68a5e81d51f69de3e"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Apply payment on date received</header><text>Unless otherwise directed by the borrower of a postsecondary education loan, a servicer shall apply payments to a borrower’s account on the date the payment is received.</text>
 </clause><clause id="id2debebf4681f441fba5c07016eb6024b"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Promulgation of rules</header><text>The Director of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection, in consultation with the Secretary of Education, may promulgate rules for the application of postsecondary education loan payments that—</text>
 <subclause id="idC52D5C4838F44A379AC3000D379DCCDB"><enum>(I)</enum><text>implements the requirements in this section;</text> </subclause><subclause id="idd660c354749d4c60ae4ae3527826ebd4"><enum>(II)</enum><text>minimizes the amount of fees and interest incurred by the borrower and the total loan amount paid by the borrower;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idf2e148f2258b4f5db4bc48baf70349be"><enum>(III)</enum><text>minimizes delinquencies, assignments to collection, and charge-offs;</text> </subclause><subclause id="id73b9e0da7e3744c0a73f0dbbbc0a3882"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>requires servicers to apply payments on the date received; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="ided81dd9053094d51a611bb75008776cc"><enum>(V)</enum><text>allows the borrower to instruct the servicer to apply payments in a manner preferred by the borrower, including excess payments.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="id39c7fd1cc8c5454cab9b54f0aae72753"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Method that best benefits borrower</header><text>In promulgating the rules under clause (iv), the Director of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection shall choose the application method that best benefits the borrower and is compatible with existing repayment options.</text>
									</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2f267c4ff8b44c93aeaa124b65affb2a"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Late fees</header>
 <clause id="id26494981bab14d3aba35bd39e600f950"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A late fee may not be charged to a borrower for a postsecondary education loan under any of the following circumstances, either individually or in combination:</text>
 <subclause id="id602f163bcf004fb68d9393fb24cf3a45"><enum>(I)</enum><text>On a per-loan basis when a borrower has multiple postsecondary education loans in a billing group.</text> </subclause><subclause id="id0b184863433e4e94bdadfffa32d62ea9"><enum>(II)</enum><text>In an amount greater than 4 percent of the amount of the payment past due.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id337547cea7f04c0286b5d5eb8e9b4214"><enum>(III)</enum><text>Before the end of the 15-day period beginning on the date the payment is due.</text> </subclause><subclause id="id64405e9d14864be58663fcab28ec7772"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>More than once with respect to a single late payment.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id58b787cc39c8473bb0046e893be55152"><enum>(V)</enum><text>The borrower fails to make a singular, non-successive regularly-scheduled payment on the postsecondary education loan.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="id2c0cc2dfc44f4afdbff7a446e15332db"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Coordination with subsequent late fees</header><text>No late fee may be charged to a borrower for a postsecondary education loan relating to an insufficient payment if the payment is made on or before the due date of the payment, or within any applicable grace period for the payment, if the insufficiency is attributable only to a late fee relating to an earlier payment, and the payment is otherwise a full payment for the applicable period.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id5031DE4DFFAD4037AED3EFCBD5760E29"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Rehabilitation of loans</header><text>If a borrower of a private education loan successfully and voluntarily makes 9 payments within 20 days of the due date during 10 consecutive months of amounts owed on the private education loan, or otherwise brings the private education loan current after the loan is charged-off, the loan shall be considered rehabilitated, and the lender or servicer shall request that any consumer reporting agency to which the charge-off was reported remove the delinquency that led to the charge-off and the charge-off from the borrower’s credit history.</text>
								</subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3a6649b880244422a0777f60399907b5"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Borrower inquiries</header>
									<clause id="id0bd3e647a09542cbbd1eaeb050c7c5df"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Duty of student loan servicers to respond to borrower inquiries</header>
 <subclause id="idb3749b2b136b49e88a8263cd29f4df6d"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Notice of receipt of request</header><text>If a borrower of a postsecondary education loan submits a qualified written request to the student loan servicer for information relating to the student loan servicing of the postsecondary education loan, the student loan servicer shall provide a written response acknowledging receipt of the qualified written request within 5 business days unless any action requested by the borrower is taken within such period.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idab9cc043dfef458da06494915e37c57e"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Action with respect to inquiry</header><text>Not later than 30 business days after the receipt from a borrower of a qualified written request under subclause (I) and, if applicable, before taking any action with respect to the qualified written request of the borrower, the student loan servicer shall—</text>
 <item id="idb6ea613c011243a381cbeabadf03f362"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>make appropriate corrections in the account of the borrower, including the crediting of any late fees, and transmit to the borrower a written notification of such correction (which shall include the name and toll-free or collect-call telephone number of a representative of the student loan servicer who can provide assistance to the borrower);</text>
 </item><item id="id2a837e7bed4c4c8cae93cfdf74d436b6"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>after conducting an investigation, provide the borrower with a written explanation or clarification that includes—</text>
 <subitem id="idcf7f153d65494ee2afd71ff56580bfb1"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>to the extent applicable, a statement of the reasons for which the student loan servicer believes the account of the borrower is correct as determined by the student loan servicer; and</text>
 </subitem><subitem id="ide1609b9dbdfa4a2eb1525b629586184c"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>the name and toll-free or collect-call telephone number of an individual employed by, or the office or department of, the student loan servicer who can provide assistance to the borrower; or</text>
 </subitem></item><item id="idd2ee263fb5a64ca2855a973aef1cceeb"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>after conducting an investigation, provide the borrower with a written explanation or clarification that includes—</text>
 <subitem id="id25e00ddbf7a04df693a91b4ed85342a6"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>information requested by the borrower or explanation of why the information requested is unavailable or cannot be obtained by the student loan servicer; and</text>
 </subitem><subitem id="id8b68b3aee24744a184060632c46eda31"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>the name and toll-free or collect-call telephone number of an individual employed by, or the office or department of, the student loan servicer who can provide assistance to the borrower.</text>
												</subitem></item></subclause><subclause id="idc9eabfc392ed45a59380913233909c64"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Limited extension of response time</header>
 <item id="idff79ba5cb6984289974503d8e64a7dcd"><enum>(aa)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There may be 1 extension of the 30-day period described in subclause (II) of not more than 15 days if, before the end of such 30-day period, the student loan servicer notifies the borrower of the extension and the reasons for the delay in responding.</text>
 </item><item id="idbf33a5f976704284aeab28e844324852"><enum>(bb)</enum><header>Reports to bureau</header><text>Each student loan servicer shall, on an annual basis, report to the Bureau the aggregate number of extensions sought by the student loan servicer under item (aa).</text>
 </item></subclause></clause><clause id="id85ed46cb8c8e4e5a833b887cc83c4354"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Protection of credit information</header><text>During the 60-day period beginning on the date on which a student loan servicer receives a qualified written request from a borrower relating to a dispute regarding payments by the borrower, a student loan servicer may not provide negative credit information to any consumer reporting agency (as defined in section 603 of the Fair Credit Reporting Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1681a">15 U.S.C. 1681a</external-xref>)) relating to the subject of the qualified written request or to such period, including any information relating to a late payment or payment owed by the borrower on the borrower’s postsecondary education loan.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2063491e380e4e5495898f7476cb548b"><enum>(H)</enum><header>Single point of contact for certain borrowers</header><text>A student loan servicer shall designate an office or other unit of the student loan servicer to act as a point of contact regarding postsecondary education loans for—</text>
 <clause id="id628df1104727430fa101b993e0d86ecc"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a borrower who is not less than 60 days delinquent under the postsecondary education loan;</text> </clause><clause id="id0344d37068294bf2b345e7e94910b794"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a borrower who seeks information regarding, seeks to enter an agreement for, or seeks to resolve an issue under a repayment option that requires subsequent submission of supporting documentation; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id9fe773de597e46858077cab4ec8887f1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a borrower who seeks to modify the terms of the repayment of the postsecondary education loan because of hardship.</text>
									</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2A62AE57EB984ABA892B6D9683E1FE38"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Servicemembers, veterans, and postsecondary education loans</header>
 <clause id="idb7e8276033d44b1090c8f8a22bcdd2cb"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Servicemember and veterans liaison</header><text>Each servicer shall designate an employee to act as the servicemember and veterans liaison who is responsible for answering inquiries from servicemembers and veterans, and is specially trained on servicemember and veteran benefits under the Servicemembers Civil Relief Act (50 U.S.C. App. 501 et seq.) and other Federal or State laws related to postsecondary education loans.</text>
 </clause><clause id="id34888acc8649428cbedd2ee5e8bb1556"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Toll-free telephone number</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each servicer shall maintain a toll-free telephone number that shall—</text> <subclause id="idBCF2E2A5945E4BC4B55A544C5D40F012"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">connect directly to the servicemember and veterans liaison designated under clause (i); and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idCA298D01EF334B429E45AE6B8072DF16"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be made available on the primary internet website of the servicer and on monthly billing statements.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="id154549aad2fc43f39c2568ea2f5899ff"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Prohibition on charge offs and default</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A lender or servicer may not charge off or report a postsecondary education loan as delinquent, assigned to collection (internally or by referral to a third party), in default, or charged-off to a credit reporting agency if the borrower is on active duty in the Armed Forces (as defined in section 101(d)(1) of title 10, United States Code) serving in a combat zone (as designated by the President under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/112">section 112(c)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986).</text>
 </clause><clause id="idcdfd280d40034678b106bcafb6c3ce29"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Additional liaisons</header><text>The Secretary shall determine additional entities with whom borrowers interact, including guaranty agencies, that shall designate an employee to act as the servicemember and veterans liaison who is responsible for answering inquiries from servicemembers and veterans and is specially trained on servicemembers and veteran benefits and option under the Servicemembers Civil Relief Act (50 U.S.C. App. 501 et seq.).</text>
									</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3FA080721D9845FDBC37898E6C4DD7A4"><enum>(J)</enum><header>Borrower's loan history</header>
									<clause id="id6873941855fa4b54aec220fa366d2e5b"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>A servicer shall make available through a secure website, or in writing upon request, the loan history of each borrower for each postsecondary education loan, separately designating—</text>
 <subclause id="id103aeae5439446b5a57b561d0549544f"><enum>(I)</enum><text>payment history;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idd212a18d8bde4a7197310f7801e98875"><enum>(II)</enum><text>loan history, including any forbearances, deferrals, delinquencies, assignment to collection, and charge offs;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idb6ed47d1cbb04cea8b47005054adac33"><enum>(III)</enum><text>annual percentage rate history; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idbf7efa0ac4ab4228ba26dd084836d64a"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>key loan terms, including application of payments to interest, principal, and fees, origination date, principal, capitalized interest, annual percentage rate, including any cap, loan term, and any contractual incentives.</text>
										</subclause></clause><clause id="idcb451ce328b147d5af4909c1edd0b03b"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Original
 documentation</header><text>A servicer shall make available to the borrower, if requested, at no charge, copies of the original loan documents and the promissory note for each postsecondary education loan.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id19E3319E9F714E0BB603DF2C8554F9CD"><enum>(K)</enum><header>Error resolution</header><text>The Director of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection, in consultation with the Secretary of Education, shall promulgate rules requiring servicers to establish error resolution procedures to allow borrowers to inquire about errors related to their postsecondary education loans and obtain timely resolution of such errors.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC2560DCC98CB45EAB320041ADED704EA"><enum>(L)</enum><header>Additional servicing standards</header><text>The Director of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection, in consultation with the Secretary of Education, may establish additional servicing standards to reduce delinquencies, assignment to collections, defaults, and charge-offs, and to ensure borrowers understand their rights and obligations related to their postsecondary education loans.</text>
								</subparagraph><subparagraph id="idAA9EE2CBC3E24762829DEADE7D596E2F"><enum>(M)</enum><header>Arbitration</header>
									<clause id="id5251c609a65842909c843c934cec057f"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Waiver of
 rights and remedies</header><text>Any rights and remedies available to borrowers against servicers may not be waived by any agreement, policy, or form, including by a predispute arbitration agreement.</text>
									</clause><clause id="id4203a3554bc84754ba7ee0bd85eb0afd"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Predispute
 arbitration agreements</header><text>No predispute arbitration agreement shall be valid or enforceable by a servicer, including as a third-party beneficiary or by estoppel, if the agreement requires arbitration of a dispute with respect to a postsecondary education loan. This subparagraph applies to predispute arbitration agreements entered into before the date of enactment of the <short-title>Student Loan Borrower Bill of Rights</short-title>, as well as on and after such date of enactment, if the violation that is the subject of the dispute occurred on or after such date of enactment.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idEF0C428D549C4A55A103B69C9A8F8AFD"><enum>(N)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text>The provisions of this paragraph shall be enforced by the agencies specified in subsections (a) through (d) of section 108, in the manner set forth in that section or under any other applicable authorities available to such agencies by law.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id636BAACDC47B4F0BBF00D3C194D55C41"><enum>(O)</enum><header>Preemption</header><text>Nothing in this paragraph may be construed to preempt any provision of State law regarding postsecondary education loans where the State law provides stronger consumer protections.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id33D62CE93F834781A29678D0B96E29CC"><enum>(P)</enum><header>Civil liability</header><text>A servicer that fails to comply with any requirement imposed under this paragraph shall be deemed a creditor that has failed to comply with a requirement under this chapter for purposes of liability under section 130 and such servicer shall be subject to the liability provisions under such section, including the provisions under paragraphs (1), (2)(A)(i), (2)(B), and (3) of section 130(a).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id25E89E8EE0254422BC83107CD6B4B1CC"><enum>(Q)</enum><header>Eligibility for discharge</header><text>The Director of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection, in consultation with the Secretary of Education, shall promulgate rules requiring lenders and servicers of loans described in paragraph (13)(B)(ii) to—</text>
 <clause id="ida023418f96f1493e9d6654023e9fc4b0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>identify and contact borrowers who may be eligible for student loan discharge by the Secretary;</text> </clause><clause id="id1F6D0190932346B8AEAE092C2C234F9B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provide the borrower, in writing, in simple and understandable terms, information about obtaining such discharge; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idCEDCF46E18FE4140AADE754059D875E5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>create a streamlined process for eligible borrowers to apply for and receive such discharge.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE5E19FD3BA02462A9BBF39F2FA3E7E72"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id55f50a1b7ecd495881fccfcb219633a5" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="id59bbd01ca42e40e9b783df1d47a6f29e"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Information To be available at no charge</header><text>The information required to be disclosed under this section shall be made available at no charge to the borrower.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1EF3DE47EE604E949293773ACFBC973F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 130(a)—</text> <subparagraph id="id9CD9D5C3A15C4D129247DD568D869CF6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>128(e)(7)</quote> and inserting <quote>128(e)(10)</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6F7B2601CA0F49679A473F74BAE4608C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the flush matter at the end, by striking <quote>or paragraph (4)(C), (6), (7), or (8) of section 128(e),</quote> and inserting <quote>or paragraph (4)(C), (9), (10), or (11) of section 128(e),</quote>.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="idf6324496fa4a4242988f77dd89bb5d3d"><enum>3.</enum><header>Student loan information by eligible lenders</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 433 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1083">20 U.S.C. 1083</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="id9E376338F0EB4725AB767581F4006541"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text> <subparagraph id="id0C9C3F590E344F319C393FCF43008C22"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (12), by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD3062D4F1EC64D3088CDA5CA826B7E03"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (13), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3E64A3D6F3F44264AA39876DDC402912"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1194624922EE4B5F8140039749A4070D" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="id8493D7AA0DB143BAA956013CE234A9FD"><enum>(14)</enum><text>a statement that—</text> <subparagraph id="idd0637210b812433ab0a1d64318c0da0a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the borrower may be entitled to servicemember and veteran benefits under the Servicemembers Civil Relief Act (50 U.S.C. App. 501 et seq.) and other Federal or State laws; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6e7ca45d210c45498a96e60088d12aab"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a Servicemember and Veterans Liaison designated under section 128(e)(15)(I)(i) of the Truth in Lending Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1638">15 U.S.C. 1638(e)(15)(I)(i)</external-xref>) is available to answer inquiries about servicemember and veteran benefits, including the toll-free telephone number to contact the Liaison pursuant to such section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idB8B242288B2A409F8B6F591AA26BCA6B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (e)—</text> <subparagraph id="id9C329F2E9BB541DCB86794DD6CD077F3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB63231FF6F464DBEBF6C584C5C37BA97" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="id728758D5E8854E47B057E5FC67A496BC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A statement that—</text> <clause id="id23E51D9E25B44C48B6FA29777347FD33"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the borrower may be entitled to servicemember and veteran benefits under the Servicemembers Civil Relief Act (50 U.S.C. App. 501 et seq.) and other Federal or State laws; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idEF3D991A7607489783A495555BC0E0D2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a Servicemember and Veterans Liaison designated under section 128(e)(15)(I)(i) of the Truth in Lending Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1638">15 U.S.C. 1638(e)(15)(I)(i)</external-xref>) is available to answer inquiries about servicemember and veteran benefits, including the toll-free telephone number to contact the Liaison pursuant to such section.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and </after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id054E5B6FAB5B41038E436AE577367CCE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idC8AB693C05B847D3A14F5C7B2A41B456" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="idBA2EF5D576464BE1A35AB20AB6E69B73"><enum>(F)</enum><text>A statement that—</text>
 <clause id="id126C0505C1944D6387FEFF723618B982"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the borrower may be entitled to servicemember and veteran benefits under the Servicemembers Civil Relief Act (50 U.S.C. App. 501 et seq.) and other Federal or State laws; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id054CBEF7201D41EC8A070320C6B0BD3F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a Servicemember and Veterans Liaison designated under section 128(e)(15)(I)(i) of the Truth in Lending Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1638">15 U.S.C. 1638(e)(15)(I)(i)</external-xref>) is available to answer inquiries about servicemember and veteran benefits, including the toll-free telephone number to contact the Liaison pursuant to such section.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="id1C35A100CD9F49ADAC98103C545D7E4E"><enum>4.</enum><header>Know before you owe</header>
			<subsection id="H63EDB492B2524F8EB9D51BA76B7B663D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Amendments to the
			 Truth in Lending Act</header>
				<paragraph id="H59C8AE6A67804A8089F44F8CE97D7D1F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 128(e) of the Truth in Lending Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1638">15 U.S.C. 1638(e)</external-xref>), as amended by section 2, is further amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H13E5BE5B9FBC4D43A3C58E126AFCADFD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (3) and inserting the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF5660560C92A4EDBA43744D10E089927" style="OLC">
							<paragraph id="H472577DACD4F4499BF255C0A6D5A5653"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Institutional
				certification required</header>
								<subparagraph id="HF72E1B1708CA480EA9C654E83C782ACB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In
 General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), before a creditor may issue any funds with respect to an extension of credit described in this subsection, the creditor shall obtain from the relevant institution of higher education where such loan is to be used for a student, such institution's certification of—</text>
 <clause id="id939DFBD31AAB4EF6A140126CF1B2FB43"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the enrollment status of the student;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idA677056F8CF344F482D106FB10473B7A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the student's cost of attendance at the institution as determined by the institution under part F of title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id916BF93F0C0B45CD92D566CE30EA64D6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the difference between—</text>
 <subclause id="id571777B485DD4A41A35E60C2C0A466A7"><enum>(I)</enum><text>such cost of attendance; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idFC64EAB7C324480D867476618E00A3C3"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the student's estimated financial assistance, including such assistance received under title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 and other financial assistance known to the institution, as applicable.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id81966939A15F4F218DA80A89D38F3BD1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Notwithstanding subparagraph (A), a creditor may issue funds, not to exceed the amount described in subparagraph (A)(iii), with respect to an extension of credit described in this subsection without obtaining from the relevant institution of higher education such institution’s certification if such institution fails to provide within 15 business days of the creditor’s request for such certification—</text>
 <clause id="id35695E0FBD434609B07D12C88AF57EB4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>notification of the institution's refusal to certify the request; or</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="id18D5B19AD21943B79F8C5D21898D3E6D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>notification that the institution has received the request for certification and will need additional time to comply with the certification request.</text>
									</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8FF43BBAE86943E59F4EEF99BC49A040"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Loans Disbursed
 Without Certification</header><text>If a creditor issues funds without obtaining a certification, as described in subparagraph (B), such creditor shall report the issuance of such funds in a manner determined by the Director of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6F65E1472F9D441DB58B3BE7CCDA2F9B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA68EB881F5FD46029344F445D2B5B823" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H7F79FA602E9A459EA607267254837DD3"><enum>(16)</enum><header>Provision of information</header> <subparagraph id="idAF559CC21E544903B9E496869810C210"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Provision of Information to Students</header> <clause id="id37AD26E23562423BBD1681098C870E06"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Loan Statement</header><text>A creditor that issues any funds with respect to an extension of credit described in this subsection shall send loan statements, where such loan is to be used for a student, to borrowers of such funds not less than once every 3 months during the time that such student is enrolled at an institution of higher education.</text>
									</clause><clause id="id8640F952A4C0485CA8DE25CCC450D665"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Contents of
 Loan Statement</header><text>Each statement described in clause (i) shall—</text>
 <subclause id="idE8BA85B364054C29AE38B0CB554B4237"><enum>(I)</enum><text>report the borrower's total remaining debt to the creditor, including accrued but unpaid interest and capitalized interest;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idA126C58CC2B24A69AD43D95F4A5A27DB"><enum>(II)</enum><text>report any debt increases since the last statement; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id0D027B9E2866459A8A3AE46EBFDC656E"><enum>(III)</enum><text>list the current interest rate for each loan.</text>
										</subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB19DF52DB4504105943A5313BA863461"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Notification of
 loans disbursed without certification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On or before the date a creditor issues any funds with respect to an extension of credit described in this subsection, the creditor shall notify the relevant institution of higher education, in writing, of the amount of the extension of credit and the student on whose behalf credit is extended. The form of such written notification shall be subject to the regulations of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection.</text>
								</subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id5789E0DD1F874532BFF3ECA40475A9E5"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Annual
 Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A creditor that issues funds with respect to an extension of credit described in this subsection shall prepare and submit an annual report to the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection containing the required information about private student loans to be determined by the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection, in consultation with the Secretary of Education.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF5283B186C6F4C05A2A33197C88AAB3E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Definition of
 Private Education Loan</header><text>Section 140(a)(7)(A) of the Truth in Lending Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1650">15 U.S.C. 1650(a)(7)(A)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idE78821ED0506469F8DA908021999438D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating clause (ii) as clause (iii);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4BF1C0F321A64152A224367C950853BF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in clause (i), by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7064D05098F94643B7157860B7218403"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding after clause (i) the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id62E5ECDBD2FB4D3E9850FFDF1C6360DD" style="OLC">
 <clause id="id75CF24FA1B2C4CA6BEAC14F9B785EB3C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is not made, insured, or guaranteed under title VII or title VIII of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/292">42 U.S.C. 292 et seq.</external-xref> and 296 et seq.); and</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id38D763C1C2EB492EA113B832A9906A51"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 365 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection shall issue regulations in final form to implement paragraphs (3) and (16) of section 128(e) of the Truth in Lending Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1638">15 U.S.C. 1638(e)</external-xref>), as amended by paragraph (1). Such regulations shall become effective not later than 6 months after their date of issuance.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF6D6CA21E96C45DFA309E8E33FF63E88"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Amendments to the
			 Higher Education Act of 1965</header>
 <paragraph id="H55160EC5E5774D40A2F2E0746EAD9CA9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Program participation agreements</header><text>Section 487(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1094">20 U.S.C. 1094(a)</external-xref>) is amended by striking paragraph (28) and inserting the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H02BB41F4C1344F60AD3C95BC0361977D" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H58E19FA8528E45F18A9D4C6329B7F8A3"><enum>(28)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idC8395848CD68432E87E3223246CD129A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon the request of a private educational lender, acting in connection with an application initiated by a borrower for a private education loan in accordance with section 128(e)(3) of the Truth in Lending Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1638">15 U.S.C. 1638(e)(3)</external-xref>), the institution shall within 15 days of receipt of a certification request—</text>
 <clause id="HAEAF1174238B45588CDA29DF8728FD7A" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide such certification to such private educational lender—</text> <subclause id="H0D47F7FFA10D465D8982A3B8D61C8AB2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>that the student who initiated the application for the private education loan, or on whose behalf the application was initiated, is enrolled or is scheduled to enroll at the institution;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H45FEAE928F3D48B4B6B726691F1A84B0"><enum>(II)</enum><text>of such student's cost of attendance at the institution as determined under part F of this title; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H0E504C179901414D898C726BB708BBBB"><enum>(III)</enum><text>of the difference between—</text>
 <item id="idDC5D3E36FE644D1F88ED77F4D66E197B"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the cost of attendance at the institution; and</text>
 </item><item id="idBB92F5286A344FE3A7B0724A0A0AD6F0"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the student's estimated financial assistance received under this title and other assistance known to the institution, as applicable;</text>
 </item></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" id="id9667A0FEA20A4352A67636EBC22544FD" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>notify the creditor that the institution has received the request for certification and will need additional time to comply with the certification request; or</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="idC5C8A9BEAD4F4B2C84CA1FAD9E2022B5" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>provide notice to the private educational lender of the institution’s refusal to certify the private education loan under subparagraph (D).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2FB2C18AAD2D4F3BB227C54FB6FF26C2" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to a certification request described in subparagraph (A), and prior to providing such certification under subparagraph (A)(i) or providing notice of the refusal to provide certification under subparagraph (A)(iii), the institution shall—</text>
 <clause id="id6DA46EC3B9A64672AD1A6F2216808F4F"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">determine whether the student who initiated the application for the private education loan, or on whose behalf the application was initiated, has applied for and exhausted the Federal financial assistance available to such student under this title and inform the student accordingly; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id5F7355FCBD964649B660831904B48B38"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide the borrower whose loan application has prompted the certification request by a private education lender, as described in subparagraph (A)(i), with the following information and disclosures:</text>
 <subclause id="id945D57799ED6410D9993D0346DA7B0C0"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The availability of, and the borrower’s potential eligibility for, Federal financial assistance under this title, including disclosing the terms, conditions, interest rates, and repayment options and programs of Federal student loans.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HB0EE22DE36494A73A49A41E4F4D26EAD"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The borrower's ability to select a private educational lender of the borrower's choice.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H87DFE167FD2949B79F3628C84F1B653A"><enum>(III)</enum><text>The impact of a proposed private education loan on the borrower's potential eligibility for other financial assistance, including Federal financial assistance under this title.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H006DF4FEBB3F4CD793F46201CFECC4D1"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The borrower’s right to accept or reject a private education loan within the 30-day period following a private educational lender’s approval of a borrower’s application and about a borrower’s 3-day right to cancel period.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H08D109067EAD4259BD211935BAAAE1C3" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the terms <quote>private educational lender</quote> and ‘private education loan’ have the meanings given such terms in section 140 of the Truth in Lending Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1650">15 U.S.C. 1650</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idAD38A1F679514EA3962278652318D923" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id476238D90C3847A1A03C54CB09839752"><enum>(i)</enum><text>An institution shall not provide a certification with respect to a private education loan under this paragraph unless the private education loan includes terms that provide—</text>
 <subclause id="idCA36817E02C741BCA8E5B9063E448F77" indent="up1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the borrower alternative repayment plans, including loan consolidation or refinancing; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="id760B7014C077463E96087FF84FE79626" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>that the liability to repay the loan shall be cancelled upon the death or disability of the borrower or co-borrower.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="id5CBE9A8053B1479BA761CA61D4620A19" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>In this paragraph, the term <term>disability</term> means a permanent and total disability, as determined in accordance with the regulations of the Secretary of Education, or a determination by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs that the borrower is unemployable due to a service-connected disability.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HBA065A4B342D4A6EB1406E132C4EED69"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effective
 date</header><text>The amendment made by paragraph (1) shall take effect on the effective date of the regulations described in subsection (a)(3).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idAB07F5C250A641A5B3789213D550B1FE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Preferred lender arrangement</header><text>Section 151(8)(A)(ii) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1019">20 U.S.C. 1019(8)(A)(ii)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>certifying,</quote> after <quote>promoting,</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9226E04CFA2241429EC762E8788A4C34"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 24 months after the issuance of regulations under subsection (a)(3), the Director of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection and the Secretary of Education shall jointly submit to Congress a report on the compliance of institutions of higher education and private educational lenders with section 128(e)(3) of the Truth in Lending Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1638">15 U.S.C. 1638(e)</external-xref>), as amended by subsection (a), and section 487(a)(28) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1094">20 U.S.C. 1094(a)</external-xref>), as amended by subsection (b). Such report shall include information about the degree to which specific institutions utilize certifications in effectively encouraging the exhaustion of Federal student loan eligibility and lowering student private education loan debt.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="ide2ed65fa3851449e8f5cf4b287ff72ec"><enum>5.</enum><header>Marketing limitation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 456 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087f">20 U.S.C. 1087f</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id57EBF5C3EC044679BA05DC067ED45CB2" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="id4B89B796264A4149879BD91120CD30EF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Limitation on contracts for the servicing of loans</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A servicer may not market to the borrower of a student loan made, insured, or guaranteed under this title which the servicer services, a financial product or service using data obtained through the servicing relationship, or otherwise during the servicing process.</text>
				</subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="ide2caeb0558c74020bb4556d755bdade4"><enum>6.</enum><header>Servicer choice</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 456 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087f">20 U.S.C. 1087f</external-xref>), as amended by section 5, is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id28ea65dee1ca40d486d51e58c6c9e98d" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="id7837cbe652a74867891ab6a92224e257"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Switching servicers</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a program that allows a borrower of a loan made under this part after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Student Loan Borrower Bill of Rights</short-title> to switch from the assigned servicer of such loan to a new servicer based on a random reassignment by the Secretary.</text>
				</subsection><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="idf93c912e52c7425dab577f8463a0558d"><enum>7.</enum><header>Centralized point of access</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part G of title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1088">20 U.S.C. 1088 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8599C73770D849DDB1384DCB57B066D1" style="OLC">
 <section id="id5870D8779EAE47FD8644B6789A76D6B4"><enum>493E.</enum><header>Centralized point of access</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Student Loan Borrower Bill of Rights</short-title>, the Secretary shall establish a centralized point of access for all borrowers of loans that are made, insured, or guaranteed under this title that are in repayment, including a central location for account information and payment processing for such loan servicing, regardless of the specific servicer.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="idb4053f490db0431180c1c88320b97982"><enum>8.</enum><header>Report on student loan servicers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection, in consultation with the Secretary of Education, shall submit a report to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate, the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate, the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Education and the Workforce of the House of Representatives on private and Federal student loan servicers, including—</text>
 <paragraph id="idcc354aa03afb4be4b5e9819974b97d83"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any legislative recommendations to improve student loan servicing standards; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="ide1f22e2bd37c49088a158801e2f35464"><enum>(2)</enum><text>information on proactive early intervention methods by servicers to help distressed student loan borrowers enroll in any eligible repayment plans.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


