<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1204 IS: Corolla Wild Horses Protection Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1204</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150506">May 6, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S300">Mr. Burr</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S384">Mr. Tillis</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEV00">Committee on Environment and Public Works</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To direct the Secretary of the Interior to enter into an agreement to provide for management of the
			 free-roaming wild horses in and around the Currituck National Wildlife
			 Refuge.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H552461DD3D214D5285E52A8456860306" style="OLC">
 <section id="H77C7AEDB2CC146069624A2ED4D2EDBB9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Corolla Wild Horses Protection Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="HF578D661F7814C10AC059F58F1B157C1" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Wild horses in and
			 around the Currituck National Wildlife Refuge</header>
			<subsection id="HF841975C351A406D8A21C2380BBBC20D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Agreement
			 required</header>
				<paragraph id="H3AABFB12DCFE4E38B7B74F316DABCAE1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Interior (referred to in this Act as the <term>Secretary</term>) shall enter into an agreement with the Corolla Wild Horse Fund (a nonprofit corporation established under the laws of the State of North Carolina), the County of Currituck, North Carolina, and the State of North Carolina to provide for management of free-roaming wild horses in and around the Currituck National Wildlife Refuge.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H68FACFAA2D8848F49B33988C466BA1BF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Terms</header><text>The agreement shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H9786732CF95643BFA0483ED4DBD2272F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>allow a herd of not fewer than 110 and not more than 130 free-roaming wild horses in and around the refuge, with a target population of between 120 and 130 free-roaming wild horses;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H69BADCD761204191A2D8EA9C0220F4E9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide for cost-effective management of the horses while ensuring that natural resources within the refuge are not adversely impacted;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H671A932359664F40A41F22962908B377"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide for introduction of a small number of free-roaming wild horses from the herd at Cape Lookout National Seashore as is necessary to maintain the genetic viability of the herd in and around the Currituck National Wildlife Refuge; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB67BFE2F8B0B4606B64DF453DD3A392B"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">specify that the Corolla Wild Horse Fund shall pay the costs associated with—</text>
 <clause id="HF8F73305D59E4F5B929C207FD74A4078"><enum>(i)</enum><text>coordinating a periodic census and inspecting the health of the horses;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6551D1718C4E4223ABD4CBABE5C77902"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>maintaining records of the horses living in the wild and in confinement;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H2F27B6FE789245B2B6BC0FDD2699D9D4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>coordinating the removal and placement of horses and monitoring of any horses removed from the Currituck County Outer Banks; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6A7F036D6AF84154B124E068CE82943E"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>administering a viable population control plan for the horses, including auctions, adoptions, contraceptive fertility methods, and other viable options.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H69FD1CA9FF7249D580480736A72E437C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conditions for
 excluding wild horses from refuge</header><text>The Secretary shall not exclude free-roaming wild horses from any portion of the Currituck National Wildlife Refuge unless—</text>
 <paragraph id="HF20905BE373B4661B6A67A2C6396BD3D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Secretary finds that the presence of free-roaming wild horses on a portion of that refuge threatens the survival of an endangered species for which that land is designated as critical habitat under the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1531">16 U.S.C. 1531 et seq.</external-xref>);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H593FF8712C2E42648472D4848DD8E742"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the finding is based on a credible peer-reviewed scientific assessment; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCE990A925AC446F2A3FA27BF4140A8E1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Secretary provides a period of public notice and comment on that finding.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC282E1CC3CB54AE9BBC98213EADC50B7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Requirements for
 introduction of horses from Cape Lookout National Seashore</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the effective period of the memorandum of understanding between the National Park Service and the Foundation for Shackleford Horses, Inc. (a non-profit corporation organized under the laws of and doing business in the State of North Carolina) signed in 2007, no horse may be removed from Cape Lookout National Seashore for introduction at Currituck National Wildlife Refuge except—</text>
 <paragraph id="HD189B2391F5C4DD481EC393635EBC1A5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with the approval of the Foundation; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE2CFCE0E1911441BBF43F6ADB2A100E2"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consistent with the terms of the memorandum (or any successor agreement) and the Management Plan for the Shackleford Banks Horse Herd signed in January 2006 (or any successor management plan).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H18FCD118168840B18672197429E5F57E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>No liability
 created</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section creates liability for the United States for any damage caused by the free-roaming wild horses to any person or property located inside or outside the boundaries of the Currituck National Wildlife Refuge.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


