<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1218 IS: Nexus of Energy and Water for Sustainability Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1218</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150506">May 6, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S288">Ms. Murkowski</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To establish an interagency coordination committee or subcommittee with the leadership of the
			 Department of Energy and the Department of the Interior, focused on the
			 nexus between energy and water production, use, and efficiency, and for
			 other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause">
 <section id="ida1b36da7-ec40-4bcc-ba99-a2c17ad7e44a" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Nexus of Energy and Water for Sustainability Act of 2015</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>NEWS Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </section><section id="id2d0522dc-be06-4d73-aa6f-692e1ca3253e"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="id5a068741-6da0-4812-8579-582e9877d467"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Committee or Subcommittee</header><text>The term <term>Committee or Subcommittee</term> means the Committee on the Nexus of Energy and Water for Sustainability (or the <quote>NEWS Committee</quote>) or the Subcommittee on the Nexus of Energy and Water for Sustainability (or the <quote>NEWS Subcommittee</quote>), whichever is established by section 3(a).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idC9511AF1D88E475285B71087A7A65B9E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The term <term>Director</term> means the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id128be35a5ead4210bd09045ba7883b39"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Energy-water nexus</header><text>The term <term>energy-water nexus</term> means the links between—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idb6caa6ee1945418ab44fc40cc49891b9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the water needed to produce fuels, electricity, and other forms of energy; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id981286e87dc84744ac4a86f6b342ed04"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the energy needed to transport, reclaim, and treat water and wastewater.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id7A34B905908B426F9810B28B3E760CF3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Grand Challenges</header><text>The term <term>Grand Challenges</term> means the 21st Century Grand Challenges program coordinated by the Office of Science and Technology Policy.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idae5ca199-cdb7-44d4-ab6c-6b8db8cf8b82"><enum>(5)</enum><header>NSTC</header><text>The term <term>NSTC</term> means the National Science and Technology Council.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idBD13E9E57C0C42B3A205BE649284BFA7"><enum>(6)</enum><header>RD&amp;D activities</header><text>The term <term>RD&amp;D activities</term> means research, development, and demonstration activities.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="ida6a03dde-603b-4862-962a-7c84b76af840"><enum>3.</enum><header>Interagency Coordination Committee</header>
 <subsection id="id050dc123-4a52-4f62-a19b-642205355f04"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Director shall establish either a committee or a subcommittee under the NSTC, to be known as either the Committee on the Nexus of Energy and Water for Sustainability (or the <quote>NEWS Committee</quote>) or the Subcommittee on the Nexus of Energy and Water for Sustainability (or the <quote>NEWS Subcommittee</quote>), to carry out the duties described in subsection (c).</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="id445cc781-21bc-485f-90ff-aa74995f50d2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Administration</header>
 <paragraph id="idf24c6c4b-f35c-4ae3-9e9c-3ecb951f8eb6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Chairs</header><text>The Secretary of Energy and Secretary of the Interior shall serve as co-chairs of the Committee or Subcommittee.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idbb8157f4-9b76-4d4f-88c3-273da1627876"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Membership; staffing</header><text>Membership and staffing shall be determined by the NSTC.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idd9d53498-ecc5-4bee-8a67-3abcbcacba84"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Committee or Subcommittee shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="id9c0bd237-0013-4f89-b5f1-5132ad0faee9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>serve as a forum for developing common Federal goals and plans on energy-water nexus RD&amp;D activities;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id0F095EB952CB4DA1BE1C83C9596E0334"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and biannually thereafter, issue a strategic plan on energy-water nexus RD&amp;D activities priorities and objectives;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id15151824-0d1e-4576-a26b-9e319426a836"><enum>(3)</enum><text>promote coordination of the activities of Federal departments and agencies on energy-water nexus RD&amp;D activities, including the activities of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="ida6304b41-8c59-49a2-af2c-a2ad647e1ed8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Department of Energy;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd76b5022-f441-4084-992c-8b8ede97db8a"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Department of the Interior;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id597a4a03-c4c5-4b32-b6df-dd6306facbf0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Corps of Engineers;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id01dba510-3b68-44ce-aca6-66904c1a6bd5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Department of Agriculture;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida1534df1-1594-491a-aea1-bd0a226a8dcf"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Department of Defense;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idaae9ab06-58eb-44f9-82b1-60137cbe5814"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the Department of State;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id256fcdd9-5744-4789-a0db-e3403b73b631"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the Environmental Protection Agency;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2318d291-949f-463e-aaaa-dd3b9e3bce2c"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the Council on Environmental Quality;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id948692c4-cbda-4c1c-8588-6e546d0a9c09"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the National Institute of Standards and Technology;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbfb89ee5-5dd7-4ab0-8b41-449fa90efe79"><enum>(J)</enum><text>the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id027bea06-ae98-4896-983a-fc9a324e2e3a"><enum>(K)</enum><text>the National Science Foundation;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5be33d2c-a26c-4b7d-b329-0da2caea7138"><enum>(L)</enum><text>the Office of Management and Budget;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7af631cb-0950-4091-aa13-fd04459b06cb"><enum>(M)</enum><text>the Office of Science and Technology Policy; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5549c98a-558f-4f91-b2e7-13f342f6c59b"><enum>(N)</enum><text>such other Federal departments and agencies as the Director or the Committee or Subcommittee consider appropriate; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id265a5278-88f0-4d21-ba18-0f0503bac3ba"><enum>(4)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id5dcb0c8b-efde-4a19-80c3-2ed58292bba5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>coordinate and develop capabilities and methodologies for data collection, management, and dissemination of information related to energy-water nexus RD&amp;D activities from and to other Federal departments and agencies; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2b015065-3f68-4706-ab07-3c21c957bd44" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>promote information exchange between Federal departments and agencies—</text> <clause id="idd74670c7-0e48-4847-98ba-bf3425a25ff0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to identify and document Federal and non-Federal programs and funding opportunities that support basic and applied research, development, and demonstration proposals to advance energy-water nexus related science and technologies;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id2a280bea-1f75-4d88-99c0-53dcc072ff42"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if practicable, to leverage existing programs by encouraging joint solicitations, block grants, and matching programs with non-Federal entities; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idde27fed1-00f2-47aa-823b-47181c7b6024"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to identify opportunities for domestic and international public-private partnerships, innovative financing mechanisms, information and data exchange, and Grand Challenges.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id892C3DB380294204992A76F75DA64312"><enum>(d)</enum><header>No regulation</header><text>Nothing in this section grants to the Committee or Subcommittee (including the members of the Committee or Subcommittee) the authority to promulgate regulations or set standards.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idbaca2190-c6b8-44a6-bba7-a3a3aec28ca6"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Review; report</header><text>At the end of the 10-year period beginning on the date on which the Committee or Subcommittee is established, the Director—</text>
 <paragraph id="id1e19541b-b39f-492c-8c6a-e16c35036c69"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall review the activities, relevance, and effectiveness of the Committee or Subcommittee; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id8f3280cd-5124-4d84-8b3a-58d246916274"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submit to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committees on Science, Space, and Technology, Energy and Commerce, and Natural Resources of the House of Representatives, a report describing the results of the review conducted under paragraph (1) and a recommendation on whether the Committee or Subcommittee should continue.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idc287e694-64ba-4a3d-8373-55153bddcf79"><enum>4.</enum><header>Crosscut budget</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the President submits the budget of the United States Government under section 1105 of title 31, United States Code, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committees on Science, Space, and Technology, Energy and Commerce, and Natural Resources of the House of Representatives, an interagency budget crosscut report that displays at the program-, project-, and activity-level for each of the Federal agencies that carry out or support (including through grants, contracts, interagency and intraagency transfers, multiyear and no-year funds) basic and applied RD&amp;D activities to advance the energy-water nexus related science and technologies—</text>
 <paragraph id="id17B1C4E73AEB4D1388CB32C430750C52"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the budget proposed in the budget request of the President for the upcoming fiscal year;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idE16483E9E4BA458585550EE80820BC39"><enum>(2)</enum><text>expenditures and obligations for the prior fiscal year; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id38953DA96B4B4EA782A240A60C8C243D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>estimated expenditures and obligations for the current fiscal year.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

