<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S87 IS: Show Your Exemption Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 87</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150107">January 7, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S299">Mr. Vitter</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the disclosure of determinations with respect to which Congressional staff will be
 required to obtain health insurance coverage through an Exchange.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Show Your Exemption Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idD02CDDBC5DDF4737897C2C76D94027CF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Transparency of coverage determination</header><subsection id="idabe4629483a84e139b5f5d1578bdbaa5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives and the Financial Clerk of the Senate shall make publically available the determinations of each member of the House of Representatives and each Senator, as the case may be, regarding the designation of their respective congressional staff (including leadership and committee staff) as <quote>official</quote> for purposes of requiring such staff to enroll in health insurance coverage provided through an Exchange as required under section 1312(d)(1)(D) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18032">42 U.S.C. 18032(d)(1)(D)</external-xref>), and the regulations relating to such section.</text></subsection><subsection id="id77e054fee9a14c6b96e2dc3e907f20e5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Failure To submit</header><text>The failure by any member of the House of Representatives or Senator to designate any of their respective staff, whether committee or leadership staff, as <term>official</term> (as described in subsection (a)), shall be noted in the determination made publically available under subsection (a) along with a statement that such failure permits the staff involved to remain in the Federal Employee Health Benefits Program.</text></subsection><subsection id="id7928f20ccc594b539bcf79942bd89fa0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Privacy</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to permit the release of any individually identifiable information concerning any individual, including any health plan selected by an individual.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


