<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S2163 IS: Streamlining and Investing in Broadband Infrastructure Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-10-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 2163</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151007">October 7, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S375">Mr. Daines</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S377">Mr. Gardner</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEV00">Committee on Environment and Public Works</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend title 23, United States Code, to direct the Secretary of Transportation to require that
			 broadband conduits be installed as a part of certain highway construction
			 projects, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Streamlining and Investing in Broadband Infrastructure Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </section><section id="id2A7C115A9755405AA7070F1B009E19B9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Improving coordination at State level</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Administrator of the National Telecommunications and Information Administration shall develop and issue best practices relating to broadband infrastructure and installation for State broadband coordination offices, with an emphasis on rural areas.</text>
		</section><section id="H1A1D8271D742413BA3E33DA08E270DE2"><enum>3.</enum><header>Inclusion of
		broadband conduit installation in certain highway construction
		projects</header>
 <subsection id="idD8B65FB53F3E4BCD8A87A3EBEE4BE1AA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/23/3">Chapter 3</external-xref> of title 23, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAF702741CBCA4A5DB39D98383B9F24EA" style="USC">
					<section id="H957E3D2EAA314BA68DE24F29B3BEE35B"><enum>330.</enum><header>Inclusion of
		  broadband conduit installation in certain highway construction
		  projects</header>
 <subsection id="HAB87BDE785574454B8C35DA4274B1729"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text>
 <paragraph id="H321E0788AB874FC39BB31BD379A5213C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Broadband</header><text>The term <term>broadband</term> means an Internet Protocol-based transmission service that enables users to send and receive voice, video, data, or graphics, or a combination of those items.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="HCFDABB40F2D1411EB4B1772671813070"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Broadband
 conduit</header><text>The term <term>broadband conduit</term> means a conduit for materials that support broadband or, where appropriate, wireless facilities for broadband service.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="HDE0812A734CB4C32BAE1864CF1C09D50"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered highway
 construction project</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered highway construction project</term> means a project to construct a new highway or to construct an additional lane for an existing highway that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id84C6D24573474CA29674DB57B5392641"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is commenced after the date of enactment of this section; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE48F62F909084B5E8771D2C2EDEBFE65"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">receives funding under this title.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB841D18147BA4368912DEE6E3A3729C5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall require States to install 1 or more broadband conduits in accordance with this section as part of any covered highway construction project.</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="H4C2AAB5D46F743418E7F0202AD7604BF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Installation
 requirements</header><text>In carrying out subsection (b), the Secretary shall ensure, to the maximum extent practicable with respect to a covered highway construction project, that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H9E5C02C6C96040EF82AB7F1E1AB9F94B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an appropriate number of broadband conduits, as determined by the Secretary, are installed along the highway to accommodate multiple broadband providers, with consideration given to the availability of existing conduits;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4FC9326D314F40E0B42534D4CDA0FDE9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the size of each such conduit is consistent with industry best practices and is sufficient to accommodate potential demand, as determined by the Secretary; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8C32672496D54A90AA93A7A7A4BA0B78"><enum>(3)</enum><text>hand holes and manholes for fiber access and pulling with respect to each such conduit are placed at intervals consistent with industry best practices, as determined by the Secretary.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0E9279F468B845589694D1AC18227EFF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Standards</header>
 <paragraph id="id59F8DF4B3B82437C90D4BBCF24BB48D0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In establishing standards to carry out subsection (c), the Secretary shall take into consideration—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id3C52A61A3746438086924742E942BABB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>population density in the area of a covered highway construction project;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3838E16BDF834B1A91BA0AE194E42A26"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the type of highway involved in the project; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idDFD44C26A21D42749310A338AAC0A055"><enum>(C)</enum><text>existing broadband access in the area of the project.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id8283FF76EFBE4CBABF804503C11ED644"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rural areas</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that the standards established to carry out subsection (c) apply to all areas, including rural and remote areas with low population density.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H49647B1679E8426193993E272F93CB61"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Pull
 tape</header><text>Each broadband conduit installed pursuant to this section shall include a pull tape and be capable of supporting fiber optic cable placement techniques consistent with industry best practices, as determined by the Secretary.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="IDb233cd23c6014780bc5db8b875cf5588"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Access</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that any requesting broadband provider has access to each broadband conduit installed pursuant to this section, on a competitively neutral and nondiscriminatory basis, for a charge not to exceed a cost-based rate.</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="HDA265232C5CC4733B736005AE92F458C"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Depth of
 installation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each broadband conduit installed pursuant to this section shall be placed at a depth consistent with industry best practices, as determined by the Secretary, after consideration is given to the location of existing utilities and the cable separation requirements of State and local electrical codes.</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="HB659F53A91DC4271880580271A24454C"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Waiver
 authority</header><text>The Secretary may waive the application of this section or any provision of this section if the Secretary determines that, upon a showing of undue burden or that a covered highway construction project is not necessary based on the availability of existing broadband conduit infrastructure, cost-benefit analysis, or consideration of other relevant factors, the waiver is appropriate with respect to a covered highway construction project.</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="H13B8F5DA433D487AA39D7FD6EB216081"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Coordination
 with FCC and NTIA Administrator</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall coordinate with the Federal Communications Commission and the Administrator of the National Telecommunications and Information Administration, including with respect to determinations regarding—</text>
 <paragraph id="id54189213B9A94F548C9F1F199665F66F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>potential demand under subsection (c)(2);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id2F733CC80C214FAA9529047F9ADE570A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>existing broadband access under subsection (d)(1)(C);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id1D5102EDE85D4BB0BAD244252A6A4E0A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>pull tape requirements under subsection (e); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id949EE0D73AA14F3BAAF2416CE3A40C47"><enum>(4)</enum><text>depth-of-installation standards under subsection (g).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idCA3EEAC60D594D17A58D5D9D86101301"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Registry</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary shall establish and maintain a registry that contains information regarding the broadband conduit projects carried out under this section.</text>
						</subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="idB373B05466CE4EA5ADE306100A61CBA4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The analysis for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/23/3">chapter 3</external-xref> of title 23, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB0C439A6C3104C678A6FB71C7C637EFC" style="USC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="section">330. Inclusion of broadband conduit
		  installation in certain highway construction
		  projects.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection></section><section id="idD085E00A4A0B4BAD99526093873D859A"><enum>4.</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, and every 2 years thereafter until the date that is 10 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation shall submit to Congress a report on the implementation and installation of broadband conduit projects under section 330 of title 23, United States Code.</text>
		</section><section id="idB1CCB93877C842CB8BD403D1990056FD"><enum>5.</enum><header>Telecommunications facilities deployment</header>
 <subsection id="id1949C8747034457E9E9B90B1A8344F03"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 6409 of the Middle Class Tax Relief and Job Creation Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1455">47 U.S.C. 1455</external-xref>) is amended by striking subsections (b) through (d) and inserting the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id70D966260D8A4A829C4D05963B91D4DC" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="id67c86529e9714b8ab266a5682d38864e"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Federal lands</header>
 <paragraph id="idC4097514271A48A5817D872355F4E67A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection—</text> <subparagraph id="id4AF005EDE4044BB6B501A69A01AF4358"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of General Services;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9bfd848d281c4e42b3a7b6349ce23045"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the term <term>communications facility installation</term> includes—</text> <clause id="id2CB0C599932C4606B8DAE790724549C5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any wireless or wireline infrastructure for the transmission of writing, signs, signals, data, images, pictures, and sounds of all kinds;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id36CA4BFD1AA7463ABA140470C4E9FB7A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the transmitting device, tower, or support structure, and any equipment, switches, wiring, cabling, power sources, shelters, or cabinets, associated with the provision of communications services; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id83402E3778704F5EA64E9A0A796469D8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any antenna or apparatus that—</text> <subclause id="id805CFCC54B6F4652BD816ED7CA38FB83"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is designed for the purpose of emitting radio frequency;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id5AF6B10317AB403D98193F4D7011EE34"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is designed to be operated, or is operating, from a fixed location pursuant to authorization by the Commission; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id574617C616524285B0B8E0F6E886AC5D"><enum>(III)</enum><text>is added to a tower, building, or other structure;</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8EA8B08AE92745698317E9DDD38EF900"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the term <term>covered agency</term> means—</text>
 <clause id="idE80DB61263BC442182C3C04E66083F7E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Department of Defense;</text> </clause><clause id="id1746A8AD9D7F4CB0A16491E9B9B7ABE5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Department of the Interior;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id21745C46723F42D5927A218FD5E75AF4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the Department of Agriculture;</text> </clause><clause id="idF6FA53695E754EF99BC787628184EE34"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the Department of Commerce;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id50DAC57AD39D4BF68668A74457026CC5"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the Department of Transportation;</text> </clause><clause id="idF53EE20B92834F21A5E7A8C9D05A6C36"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the Department of Veterans Affairs;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idE55ECDE1D22C4AA7BC26475B4BA4D0C2"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>the United States Postal Service;</text> </clause><clause id="id97AA249092A946CA8C8DA5EF9C688907"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>the Federal Communications Commission;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id11D37F4EDEB044AA91357D08CAC03D4C"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>the Council on Environmental Quality;</text> </clause><clause id="id79591113721C41628914D0278FA8D0B8"><enum>(x)</enum><text>the Advisory Council on Historic Preservation;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id734C3EEDC1DB44E88F2D2CF7FC6249A7"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>the Department of Homeland Security; and</text> </clause><clause id="idA36A52B5234547DA89EFB465AC440738"><enum>(xii)</enum><text>the Executive Office of the President;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id775A090A5DEA4D8CB4CB723E8A3F1CA5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the term <term>executive agency</term> has the meaning given the term in section 102 of title 40, United States Code; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB75CA1DB9BDF418A80F2E5A3404B2019"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the term <term>placement</term>, with respect to a communications facility installation, includes the installation, construction, modification, or maintenance of the communications facility installation.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id24736db89149474b9b1a1ad8647ebd2d"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federal property</header>
 <subparagraph id="id3c6c07ad07694596b609c37fa072885e"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Grant</header><text>If an executive agency, a State, a political subdivision or agency of a State, or a person, firm, or organization applies for the grant of a real property interest, including a lease, license, easement, or right-of-way, to, in, over, or on a building or other property owned by the Federal Government for the right to install, construct, modify, and maintain a communications facility installation, the executive agency that owns the building or other property on behalf of the Federal Government shall grant to the applicant, if technically feasible, a real property interest to perform such installation, construction, modification, and maintenance.</text>
							</subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE9A9A0DECDC143CDBC0506747304BE6E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Applications</header>
 <clause id="id8B4F6F5C1A2B42E28C33C28E9E97ED1A"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Multiple tenants</header><text>Competitive procurement requirements shall not apply to an application for a grant of a real property interest under subparagraph (A).</text>
 </clause><clause id="idA70C18A592FA44E1AD64CDA40D833D2B"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Multiple grants</header><text>An executive agency that owns a building or other property and receives applications described in subparagraph (A) for multiple grants of real property interests, either from the same applicant or different applicants, shall provide multiple grants if technically feasible.</text>
								</clause><clause id="id92A52CE3395E452183EEE72FC3AACF17"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Determinations</header>
 <subclause id="id388FA8B7C2EE4FAA9A7D1E6D2073EB8C"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An executive agency that receives an application for a grant of real property interest under subparagraph (A) shall make a determination as to whether to provide the grant not later than 90 days after the date on which the application is submitted.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idADD4B230987845A187BF8D1771B0AA1C"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Denial of grant</header><text>If an executive agency determines not to provide a grant of real property interest under subparagraph (A), the executive agency shall notify the applicant, in writing, of the reasons for the determination.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="idD1425CFF19B741969443E17BFF386503"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Term of years</header><text>The standard term of the grant of a real property interest under subparagraph (A) shall be 25 years with allowances for reexamination of the fee schedule at the end of each 5-year period within the 25-year period.</text>
 </clause><clause id="idA6ABB846564146B9A382BC6E4E8515C3"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Renewal</header><text>The grant of a real property interest shall enjoy an expectancy of renewal of the real property interest upon the expiration of the term described in clause (iv).</text>
								</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id08dc5c835c2842819e540b01c5315c27"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Fees</header>
								<clause commented="no" id="id60CC09DE74C74F6EAB2CC172D0A9BF05"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Standard fee</header>
 <subclause commented="no" id="idC62ACB182E374C8DBE937350EE3EACA9"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Administrator, in consultation with the head of each covered agency, shall establish a standard fee schedule for the grant of a real property interest under subparagraph (A) based on direct cost recovery.</text>
									</subclause><subclause id="id14f7debfa48349ff8d8a9e4cc814f561"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Initial fee</header>
 <item id="idD4CDD548DDD4452086581356F599008A"><enum>(aa)</enum><header>Amount of fee</header><text>The initial amount of the standard fee established under subclause (I) shall be equal to the average fee charged by the Federal Government for the grant of a real property interest for the placement of a communications facility installation during the most recent 3-year period.</text>
 </item><item id="idc4de372e3f8049458060d81a211246eb"><enum>(bb)</enum><header>Publication of proposed fee</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Streamlining and Investing in Broadband Infrastructure Act</short-title>, the Administrator shall publish a notice in the Federal Register that—</text> <subitem id="idBB5955DE84E149FC92594270414556D5"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>proposes an initial amount of the standard fee under subclause (I);</text>
 </subitem><subitem id="id0147AD19ECCF4297B233994A1DADE521"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>describes the data on which the proposed initial amount is based; and</text>
 </subitem><subitem id="id04F7233A4ACF4A198F1F2251EE827C71"><enum>(CC)</enum><text>invites public comment on the proposed initial amount.</text> </subitem></item><item id="idbf9d5195fed4409bbc27e73bbbb047b9"><enum>(cc)</enum><header>Deadline for finalized standard fee</header><text>Not later than 150 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Streamlining and Investing in Broadband Infrastructure Act</short-title>, the Administrator shall publish a decision in the Federal Register that sets the initial amount of the standard fee.</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause id="id436A600D5D644C6F829FFFA7ECB8AC69"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Limit on annual increases</header><text>During any year, the Administrator may not increase the standard fee established under subclause (I) or clause (ii) by a percentage that is greater than the lower of—</text>
 <item id="id341DB7336E2644CABAE2F711F599FFE4"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the percentage increase in the Consumer Price Index for All Urban Consumers (all items, United States city average) published by the Bureau of Labor Statistics for the most recent 12-month period; or</text>
 </item><item id="id7ED5B871CEBE40ADAADB06D5D5AABD27"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>3 percent.</text> </item></subclause></clause><clause id="idf4829dca41854159ae012f6d77b15631"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Agency-specific fee</header> <subclause id="id7223138A883145CB92AB5E8718609383"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An executive agency shall charge the standard fee established by the Administrator under clause (i) for a grant of a real property interest unless, not later than 90 days after the date on which the Administrator publishes the amount of the finalized initial fee under clause (i)(II)(cc), the executive agency establishes an agency-specific fee in an amount that is equal to the average fee charged by the executive agency for the placement of a communications facility installation during the most recent 3-year period.</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="id796BC68B88A244E1B5F39B9D13C7D347"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Public comment</header><text>During the process of establishing an agency-specific fee under subclause (I), an executive agency shall—</text>
 <item commented="no" id="id73AB81F5CF654984A10527E54D363199"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>make a description of the data on which the fee is based publically available; and</text> </item><item commented="no" id="id4FDB3EB24EF74BF58CFF3780EFCA9CBB"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>allow opportunity for public comment.</text>
 </item></subclause></clause><clause id="id091ef18cbd0a4a7391c76ee1b359069a"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Entirety of fees</header><text>The Administrator or an executive agency may not charge any additional fee for the grant of a real property interest for the placement of a communications facility installation other than what has been established in the standard fee under clause (i) or an agency-specific fee established under clause (ii).</text>
 </clause><clause id="id926e55dc2070462d9731b90e881e9bea"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Waivers</header><text>In consideration of the public benefit provided by a grant of a real property interest under subparagraph (A), the Administrator or an executive agency may grant a full or partial waiver of the fee required under clause (i) or (ii).</text>
 </clause><clause id="id4ffad0475c24404a8b01dfe55dad9274"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Use of fees collected</header><text>Any fee amount collected under this paragraph for the grant of a real property interest by an executive agency under subparagraph (A) shall be made available, as provided in appropriations Acts, to the executive agency to cover the cost of granting the real property interest.</text>
								</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id2e7cdf478b1e44eb8d4da969aa446a18"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Master contracts for communications facility installations</header>
 <subparagraph id="id9cbd0eee3a734b7b9adf7da3bb4bdc8c"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding section 704 of the Telecommunications Act of 1996 or any other provision of law, the Administrator, in consultation with the head of each covered agency, shall—</text>
 <clause id="id161a275984f14a909124501e08aa76de"><enum>(i)</enum><text>not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this subsection, develop and adopt 1 or more master application forms and standard contracts, including lease and easement contracts, for all executive agencies, that shall govern the placement of a communications facility installation to, in, over, or on a building or other property owned by the Federal Government;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idbfb0d802540f41e682ffab4a2d4f3724"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in developing the master application forms and standard contracts under subparagraph (A)—</text> <subclause id="id6a1cfbce6ab54f3d8a5f25439788bbf3"><enum>(I)</enum><text>include in each master application form or standard contract the standard fee schedule and standard fee established under paragraph (2)(C)(i)(I); and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id7d5f263d95564e088e2a56f332cc35dd"><enum>(II)</enum><text>standardize the treatment of—</text> <item id="id6e1bd840adff4b7d82ac9f0fd623bea3"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the placement of a communications facility installation to, in, over, or on the rooftop or facade of a building or inside a building;</text>
 </item><item id="idcd7df00c159c408991588f44328c3f9d"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the technology used in connection with a communications facility installation placed on a Federal building or other property; and</text>
 </item><item id="id6d4743bea8a841b89bec7dd3d4eb7bd7"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>any other key issues the Administrator considers appropriate;</text> </item></subclause></clause><clause id="idb0c9a5e91e7548b9ac821aa2547e79a9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>not later than 30 days after the date on which the Administrator adopts the master application forms and standard contracts under clause (i), publish the master application forms and standard contracts in the Federal Register; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idb7443da86c6c42609dae12b6a08211e0"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>direct each executive agency to begin accepting the master application forms and standard contracts from applicants not later than 30 days after the date on which the Administrator adopts the master application forms and standard contracts under clause (i).</text>
								</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbf28a3ad6b524c0090ad4e018e60dae1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Applicability</header>
 <clause id="idE4BB83AEB5B2478CB104E74E69909D96"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in clause (ii), the master application forms and standard contracts developed by the Administrator under subparagraph (A)(i) shall apply to each building or other property owned by the Federal Government.</text>
 </clause><clause id="id843C1F10676641DCAD67024751DE0E94"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>If the Administrator determines that the master application forms and standard contracts developed under subparagraph (A)(i) are not adequate for a specific building or other property, the Administrator shall—</text>
 <subclause id="idB41BC2B82D25411CBE18726EC497148E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>not later than 10 days after the date on which the Administrator makes the determination, provide written notification to the applicant, which shall detail the reasons why the application forms and contracts are not adequate for a specific building or property; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idA3FAB763A84145849470F2534F5E81FF"><enum>(II)</enum><text>work in coordination with the heads of the appropriate agencies to address the inadequacies and provide, not later than 60 days after the date on which the notification was provided under subclause (I), an adequate application form or contract to the applicant.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8870f93519df4f529152c1806551f23b"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Negotiation and approval</header><text>If the Administrator fails to adopt master application forms and standard contracts as required under subparagraph (A)(i) during the 1-year period beginning on the date of enactment of the <short-title>Streamlining and Investing in Broadband Infrastructure Act</short-title>, beginning on the day after the expiration of that period and until the date on which the Administrator adopts such forms and contracts—</text>
 <clause id="id06C6812DC86244128D74503B772B98A0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an applicant for a grant of a real property interest from an executive agency under paragraph (2)(A) may use an existing application form or contract with the executive agency; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id6FB3B8E0274C43D3897A2CE127FDF0A5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the executive agency shall accept the existing application form or contract.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id22049533f36d40dc88de3baad320bee5"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Escalation and review</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Streamlining and Investing in Broadband Infrastructure Act</short-title>, each executive agency shall establish a supervisory review process under which an executive working group or established agency executive with negotiation and approval authority shall review any communications facility installation application, lease, or easement if an applicant requests such review.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2f9a444defff4c53a41c5e14aa69981e"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Incorporation of subsection (<enum-in-header>a</enum-in-header>)</header><text>An executive agency may not deny, and shall approve, any eligible facilities request (as defined in subsection (a)(2)) for a modification of an existing wireless tower or base station that does not substantially change the physical dimensions of the tower or base station.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idaa6c2ac1ef9743e99a7b5ba89269e32f"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Progress reports</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Streamlining and Investing in Broadband Infrastructure Act</short-title>, and every 2 years thereafter until the date that is 10 years after the date of enactment of that Act, the Administrator shall submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives a report that describes, with respect to each executive agency—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idD1B6005CA3E94B99BB080D71355F5C64"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of sites sought in applications for the placement of a communications facility installation, including upgrades and collocations;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id19DCCAA4FAB04A1CA7E3CAE430325388"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of sites approved; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8956DFF5F04E411E9B700B16D30B54CB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the number of sites completed.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="id9DB0BF6A9007419885339B1431A8FC9B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Savings provision</header><text>Notwithstanding the amendment made by subsection (a), an executive agency may make a grant of a real property interest and may collect fees in accordance with subsection (b) of section 6409 of the Middle Class Tax Relief and Job Creation Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1455">47 U.S.C. 1455(b)</external-xref>) (as in effect on the day before the date of enactment of this Act) until the effective date of the regulations issued by the head of the executive agency to carry out the amendment made by subsection (a).</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


