<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1675 IS: Plum Island Conservation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-06-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1675</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150624">June 24, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S270">Mr. Schumer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S364">Mr. Murphy</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S331">Mrs. Gillibrand</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend certain appropriations Acts to repeal the requirement directing the Administrator of
			 General Services to sell Federal property and assets that support the
			 operations of the Plum Island Animal Disease Center in Plum Island, New
			 York, to provide for a report on the potential transfer of Plum Island,
			 and for other purposes. </official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H5CF28DAE34214AF2965CBACB129CF6F8" style="OLC">
 <section id="id0E7F1FACD4F04C36813284032465322B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Plum Island Conservation Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="idB17E64A060A747F39E0164A3AA37A40F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Repeal of requirement to sell certain Federal property in Plum Island, New York</header> <subsection id="H50E13CE42E184D0E92B850DAAFCB4BCD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Repeal of requirement in Public Law <enum-in-header>110–329</enum-in-header></header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 540 of the Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2009 (division D of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/329">Public Law 110–329</external-xref>; 122 Stat. 3688) is repealed.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H003CC2402EA347F7B4DD6506C712479E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Repeal of
 requirement in Public Law <enum-in-header>112–74</enum-in-header></header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 538 of the Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/190">6 U.S.C. 190</external-xref> note; division D of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/74">Public Law 112–74</external-xref>) is repealed.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="id40559F1C57D647B38E9056BF1D78FEC6"><enum>3.</enum><header>Report on potential transfer of Plum Island</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security, in conjunction with the Administrator of General Services, the Secretary of the Interior, and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report that includes—</text>
 <paragraph id="id994CCF21EB064EDDB480E1231E5DC412"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recommendations for the transfer of administrative jurisdiction over Plum Island from the Department of Homeland Security to the Federal agency that is most capable of conserving the undeveloped land, critical habitat, vulnerable and rare species, and historic, cultural, and other environmental resources of Plum Island; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idD64D2CCE362B46D2B908C32B687E3911"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an analysis of any remediation responsibilities with respect to Plum Island, the costs associated with assuming administrative jurisdiction over Plum Island, the timing of the transfer, and the need for any legislative changes to execute the transfer.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


