<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1086 IS: International Insurance Capital Standards Accountability Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 1086</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150427">April 27, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S352">Mr. Heller</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S314">Mr. Tester</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To establish an insurance policy advisory committee on international capital standards, and for
			 other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>International Insurance Capital Standards Accountability Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </section><section id="id0697be1f5ebd45c6b6170c3999a7556a"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text> <paragraph id="id4403ae2202b74965905714076809f034"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Secretary of the Treasury, Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, and Director of the Federal Insurance Office shall support increasing transparency at any global insurance or international standard-setting regulatory or supervisory forum in which they participate, including supporting and advocating for greater public observer access to working groups and committee meetings of the International Association of Insurance Supervisors; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id14fd595c92304e0f88b16484f612268e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to the extent that the Secretary of the Treasury, Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, and Director of the Federal Insurance Office take a position or reasonably intend to take a position on an insurance proposal by a global insurance regulatory or supervisory forum, the Secretary of the Treasury, Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, and Director of the Federal Insurance Office shall achieve consensus positions with State insurance regulators through the National Association of Insurance Commissioners, when they are United States participants in negotiations on insurance issues before the International Association of Insurance Supervisors, Financial Stability Board, or any other international forum of financial regulators or supervisors that considers such issues.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="id58fb66a3ff7e433286dded6eb2b53d0c"><enum>3.</enum><header>Insurance policy advisory committee</header>
 <subsection id="id3a32413592f946d2ab005f0e4fd8e1e0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established the Insurance Policy Advisory Committee on International Capital Standards and Other Insurance Issues at the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id85bf35a246d34a07aa6226b6ef7d362c"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>The Commission shall be composed of not more than 21 members, all of whom represent a diverse set of expert perspectives from the various sectors of the United States insurance industry, including life insurance, property and casualty insurance and reinsurance, agents and brokers, academics, consumer advocates, or experts on issues facing underserved insurance communities and consumers.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="idc72d9ed0e6574e22bfa88d285871f87d"><enum>4.</enum><header>Reports</header>
			<subsection id="id3e379a9aa10342e2935ca71a75e1e835"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header>
				<paragraph id="idef6b6839e476451986bda47a46df33e9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Reports and testimony by Secretary of the Treasury and Chairman of the Federal Reserve</header>
 <subparagraph id="idc7b01a2bc421432aae86a6a650a05aa3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury and the Chairman of the Federal Reserve, or their designee, shall submit to the Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs Committee of the Senate, and the Financial Services Committee of the House of Representatives, an annual report and provide annual testimony to the Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs Committee of the Senate, and the Financial Services Committee of the House of Representatives on the efforts of the Secretary and the Chairman with the National Association of Insurance Commissioners with respect to global insurance regulatory or supervisory forums, including—</text>
 <clause id="id21a2507a21784fa795d028c69d5aad64"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a description of the insurance regulatory or supervisory standard-setting issues under discussion at international standard-setting bodies, including the Financial Stability Board and the International Association of Insurance Supervisors;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id3c3f930ead064ba5b570b7615458aa44"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a description of the effects that proposals discussed at international insurance regulatory or supervisory forums of insurance could have on consumer and insurance markets in the United States;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idb88aff900d4540db998c9f5c438f2455"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a description of any position taken by the Secretary of the Treasury, Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, and Director of the Federal Insurance Office in international insurance discussions; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id216c822bdbc64aff8bb7b10136cb674f"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a description of the efforts by the Secretary of the Treasury, Director of the Federal Insurance Office, and the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System to increase transparency at the Financial Stability Board with respect to insurance proposals and the International Association of Insurance Supervisors, including efforts to provide additional public access to working groups and committees of the International Association of Insurance Supervisors.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id38dc4f2714d7468497c2f815652dfb7e"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>This paragraph shall terminate on December 31, 2018.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id65443ed9f5e241fd9609a6a1186c3133"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reports and testimony by national association of insurance commissioners</header><text>The National Association of Insurance Commissioners may provide testimony to Congress on the issues described in paragraph (1)(A).</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="idb53cd2fa56b64ab69fd67779f93a8e14"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Joint report by the chairman of the Federal reserve and the director of the Federal insurance
			 office</header>
 <subparagraph id="id807ca631d995432a80f892592b15a400"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury, Chairman of the Federal Reserve, and the Director of the Federal Insurance Office shall, in consultation with the National Association of Insurance Commissioners, complete a study on, and submit to Congress a report on the results of the study, the impact on consumers and markets in the United States before supporting or consenting to the adoption of any key elements in any international insurance proposal or international insurance capital standard.</text>
					</subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4d750740ceec41e282ace75fc681b3aa"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Notice and comment</header>
 <clause id="id4DDDC274104B4F99835EA7B203D2843F"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury, Chairman of the Federal Reserve, and the Director of the Federal Insurance Office shall provide notice before the date on which drafting the report is commenced and after the date on which the draft of the report is completed.</text>
 </clause><clause id="idAA030BDCE3064C15A2793B9E1D0B2D64"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Opportunity for comment</header><text>There shall be an opportunity for public comment for a period beginning on the date on which the report is submitted under subparagraph (A) and ending on the date that is 60 days after the date on which the report is submitted.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idea081513da634368bab04101e70a88f4"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Review by comptroller general</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury, Chairman of the Federal Reserve, and the Director of the Federal Insurance Office shall submit to the Comptroller General of the United States the report described in subparagraph (A) for review.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0f6d90d45df24887be8aef62d57c6f32"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Report on reduction in transparency</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Chairman of the Federal Reserve and the Secretary of the Treasury, or their designees, shall submit to Congress a report and provide testimony to Congress on the efforts of the Chairman and the Secretary to increase transparency at meetings of the International Association of Insurance Supervisors.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


