<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1885 IS: Veteran Housing Stability Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 1885</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150729">July 29, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S313">Mr. Sanders</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S307">Mr. Brown</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSVA00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend title 38, United States Code, to improve the provision of assistance and benefits to
			 veterans who are homeless, at risk of becoming homeless, or occupying
			 temporary housing, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Veteran Housing Stability Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3DA22D07769B4C95AEF15EB7BCE177EE" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Expansion of
			 definition of homeless veteran for purposes of benefits under the laws
 administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2002(1) of title 38, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>in section 103(a) of the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/11302">42 U.S.C. 11302(a)</external-xref>)</quote> and inserting <quote>in subsection (a) or (b) of section 103 of the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/11302">42 U.S.C. 11302</external-xref>)</quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="id39FDF0970AE840A0AF379DA1F3C69667"><enum>3.</enum><header>Program on provision of intensive case management interventions to homeless veterans who
			 receive the most health care from the Department of Veterans Affairs</header>
			<subsection id="idF4502661CD15409A8D49186788DEFB5C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Program required</header>
 <paragraph id="idCF36DC0DDB2F4A1491FDE23087A613C4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subchapter VII of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/20">chapter 20</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0E8D89BAE9984E97A03AF96BEA1C9705" style="USC">
						<section id="id6E6A134845914F4C97C8831511FD7E48"><enum>2067.</enum><header>Intensive case management interventions</header>
 <subsection id="id472DBD600D524BAA93A466FADF1A8E45"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Program required</header><text>The Secretary shall carry out a program under which the Secretary shall provide intensive case management interventions to covered veterans.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idBDA2288D0D82482382A5A44EF19BB38A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Covered veterans</header><text>For purposes of the program, a covered veteran is a veteran who is enrolled in—</text> <paragraph id="idECE07643D06D40C8A7C35489427A7CEB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the homeless registry of the Department; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id8BD001D0735148AFBB5718C9CF9BC3F2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the system of annual patient enrollment established and operated by the Secretary under section 1705(a) of this title.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idBCC4FE6A148740B5AE6B19E80729FFD0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Location</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id6D1F756D56E94E94BC227E1AD26E0C78"><enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>The Secretary shall carry out the program at not fewer than six locations selected by the Secretary for purposes of the program as follows:</text>
 <subparagraph id="id7DAAB1DEAB9C4445A05ACC51EFC19667" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Not fewer than three locations in cities that have the largest populations of homeless veterans in the United States.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB3F9DB31486741F3B28E461AEED419EC" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Not fewer than three locations in suburban or rural settings.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id98CEC4BF7E554B30AF90866801268051" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In selecting locations under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall only select locations in areas in which the Secretary determines that there is a high degree of interaction and coordination between the Department and community organizations that provide housing and social services for veterans, such as outreach, employment, and financial assistance for homeless veterans, veterans at risk of becoming homeless, and low-income veterans.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id76F5286E6BEB4952AE3DC2703E04EBED"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Provision of intensive case management interventions</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id4C2A76C6F3234437AB5D47DFD7F3AD6B"><enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>In carrying out the program at each location selected under subsection (c), the Secretary shall provide intensive case management interventions to not fewer than 20 covered veterans at each such location who the Secretary determines are the covered veterans at such location who receive the most health care and related services furnished by the Department.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id5EC4DA49C1B949429CA923A942C21D3A" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The intensive case management interventions provided to covered veterans under paragraph (1) shall include assistance with gaining and maintaining access to such housing and services, including benefits and services to which covered veterans may be entitled or eligible under the laws administered by the Secretary, as may be necessary to improve the stability of their housing and the appropriateness of the health care that they receive.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idA0B49DB7AFB944AF9B72697CCAD4A968"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of chapter 20 of such title is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 2066 the following new item:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2F0C5B628533472798276999ABE02161" style="OLC"><toc><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">2067. Intensive case management interventions.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id8D4877626B67498D9B1C7A61D31D6B4F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Commencement</header><text>Not later than September 1, 2016, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall commence carrying out the program required by section 2067(a) of such title, as added by subsection (a)(1).</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="id2B28DD332C344B5B93743F23C8B3BAD0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header>
 <paragraph id="idB7810B6601DD41CE8CDF9AA281C0AD87"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than December 1, 2018, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on the program carried out under section 2067 of such title, as added by subsection (a)(1).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id1E0EDBD421AA41C5A5326F4E651E69B4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report submitted under paragraph (1) shall include assessments of the following:</text> <subparagraph id="idFC7338CB8C4D4517BD58BDEB4C743DF9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The types and frequencies of intensive case management interventions provided under the program.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2DECC41B64BF4DFD8A29E6DD368D5FE2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The housing status of each veteran who received an intensive case management intervention under the program.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0ACCC75084EE4722873CC07BD023D569"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The employment status of each veteran who received an intensive case management intervention under the program, including a comparison of the employment status of such veteran before and after receiving such intervention.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE7864B58FCF1477EAD97AB475C1D555E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The use by veterans who received intensive case management interventions under the program of health care and related services furnished by the Department of Veterans Affairs and the costs incurred by the Department in furnishing such care and services, including a comparison of the use by such veterans of such care and services and the costs incurred from furnishing such care and services before and after receiving such interventions.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idCC29428182A44FBA8A3844ADD3F8A12A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The number of veterans who received intensive case management interventions under the program, disaggregated by whether the intensive case management intervention was provided in a location described in subparagraph (A) or (B) of section 2067(c)(1) of such title, as added by subsection (a)(1).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0472011F1BA74676A3058C008DCD3349"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The costs incurred by the Department in carrying out the program, disaggregated by provision of intensive case management interventions in locations described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of such section.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2773CE8D23A64C92B3EA755080F9F8C8"><enum>(G)</enum><text>An estimate of the costs the Department would have incurred for the provision of health care and associated services to covered veterans (as described in subsection (b) of section 2067 of such title, as added by subsection (a)(1)) but for the provision of intensive case management interventions under the program, disaggregated by provision of intensive case management interventions in locations described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of subsection (c) of such section.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id7F34FC4D31944BD482E807DF001D4DEC"><enum>4.</enum><header>Program to improve retention of housing by formerly homeless veterans and veterans at risk of
			 becoming homeless</header>
			<subsection id="id152970E22CD7428888EC95445B129988"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Program required</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4C37B2B4A3904899A0E742F1F0EF2949"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/20">chapter 20</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idC75C65EA5DAA49EC842EEB53B9122814"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating section 2013 as section 2014; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8CF478450CE2494A97747725465840BE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after section 2012 the following new section 2013:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE82F4287AC2E4D04B5D2D71FBD736053" style="USC"> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF77C8DAE574848ABB662724DAB05158A"><enum>2013.</enum><header>Program to improve retention of housing by formerly homeless veterans and veterans at risk of becoming homeless</header> <subsection id="id280ACB62E6A44660B2CD1E4DF7B0B10B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Program required</header><text>The Secretary shall carry out a program under which the Secretary shall provide case management services to improve the retention of housing by veterans who were previously homeless and are transitioning to permanent housing and veterans who are at risk of becoming homeless.</text>
								</subsection><subsection id="id8C20691C58BA403BBE5B10EED3946149"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grants</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idE5048A54C2E94135A81E27AAAC3CD42F"><enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>The Secretary shall carry out the program through the award of grants.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idA6B7938A9D9C485FB6891C673D0C6919" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id2BE6D292B77949988B0C1158DBF069D5"><enum>(A)</enum> <text>In awarding grants under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall give priority to organizations that demonstrate a capability to provide case management services as described in subsection (a), particularly organizations that are successfully providing or have successfully provided transitional housing services using amounts provided by the Secretary under sections 2012 and 2061 of this title.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id685A8A77BE934AB99138F7ED1480A513" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>In giving priority under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall give extra priority to an organization described in such subparagraph that—</text>
 <clause id="idBB10A7B2F87049B0A841D9DDDCDBC3C3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>voluntarily stops receiving amounts provided by the Secretary under sections 2012 and 2061 of this title; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idCDEF33E4ED914F3B9632C756CE8BF6EB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>converts a facility that the organization used to provide transitional housing services into a facility that the organization uses to provide permanent housing that meets housing quality standards established under section 8(o)(8)(B) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437f">42 U.S.C. 1437f(o)(8)(B)</external-xref>).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1207736DD1BD4B6BA87C11012D9463A5" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>In any case in which a facility, with respect to which a person received a grant for construction, rehabilitation, or acquisition under section 2011 of this title, is converted as described in subparagraph (B)(ii), such conversion shall be considered to have been carried out pursuant to the needs of the Department and such person shall not be considered in non-compliance with the terms of such grant by reason of such conversion.</text>
										</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id87DFD82E2252421CBC7A498B8F6282C1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of chapter 20 of such title is amended by striking the item relating to section 2013 and inserting the following new items:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3D69898BBD3B4A06886B7CFAE52E16D7" style="OLC"><toc><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">2013. Program to improve retention of housing by formerly homeless veterans and veterans at risk of
			 becoming homeless.</toc-entry><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">2014. Authorization of appropriations.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1EEEBB54BED84E6BA34F965A1A0A3602"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall prescribe regulations to carry out section 2013 of such title, as added by subsection (a)(1)(B).</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="idD7EC2D706EC8457BA72DC9326F6982CA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header>
 <paragraph id="id0EE9099B0AE149B281A17CC1C69CA96D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than June 1, 2019, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on the program required by section 2013 of such title, as added by subsection (a)(1)(B).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idA0703EBA76AB4CCC9B4769F157F4D085"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report submitted under paragraph (1) shall include assessments of the following:</text> <subparagraph id="idC54C22F737504EAF951C900DAB0BD9C2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The percentage of veterans who received case management services under the program who were able to retain permanent housing by the end of the pilot program, disaggregated by each recipient of a grant under such section.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0ADBEEB03AA544BB82991D9B2B70DBC7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The percentage of veterans who received case management services under the program who were not in permanent housing at the end of the program, disaggregated by housing status and reason for failing to retain permanent housing under the program.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7781A14AD1604E0D961A91F6ADE5F166"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The use by veterans who received case management services under the program of housing assistance furnished by the Department of Veterans Affairs, including a comparison of the use of such assistance by such veterans before and after receiving such services.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id05E0E9E94EAF497F8A8F024BA19ED2A3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>An assessment of the employment status of veterans who received case management services under the program, including a comparison of the employment status of such veterans before and after receiving such services.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idD64D026A11934A7F890CEEA79FBD4680"><enum>5.</enum><header>Expansion of housing assistance program of Department of Veterans Affairs</header>
 <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idAA0AA2F3745140CCBEE4DAD6510C2F47"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2041 of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id81E8C56E4C424DA293412253557DF92D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the section heading, by adding at the end the following: <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="USC">, veterans in temporary housing, and very low-income veteran families</header-in-text></quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6DCD66C0B88049ED8CA38C756E014237"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id75162A81F2144E5CBC00D8AEC43774C1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (1), in the matter before subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>To assist homeless veterans and their families in acquiring shelter</quote> and inserting <quote>To assist homeless veterans and their families, veterans and their families who are at risk of becoming homeless, and very low-income veteran families (as defined in section 2044(f) of this title) in acquiring shelter, in acquiring and transitioning to permanent housing, and in maintaining occupancy in permanent housing</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7E85706F50234649895442C2E76DB74B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>homeless veterans</quote> and inserting <quote>veterans and families described in paragraph (1)</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idD2E2B8F07E6342B48892ACA0C8CA73F9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)(B)—</text>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idDD8239AF81654E48B93A29E3959CE424"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in clause (i), by striking <quote>solely as a shelter primarily for homeless veterans and their families</quote> and inserting <quote>to provide permanent or transitional housing for veterans and families described in paragraph (1)</quote>;</text> </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id29CDF5DBCFDC4A598797F08BC34240E0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in clause (iii), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE2342BFFD646484FAB5557137D5C44B0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by redesignating clause (iv) as clause (v);</text> </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id026B343BAFB24E4FBF977067C68AB9C0"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>by inserting after clause (iii) the following new clause (iv):</text>
							<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id60BC341B737C4D3D87BD105134C2780A" style="OLC">
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1A98B2E1E999412A8D6B3D8B8824384D" indent="up1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>ensure that veterans who receive housing at the property also receive referrals for the benefits and services to which they may be entitled or eligible under this title, and</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id988B99E9953C4714B1D367EBBF5AB573"><enum>(v)</enum><text>in clause (v), as redesignated by clause (iii) of this subparagraph, by striking <quote>homeless veterans</quote> and inserting <quote>veterans and families described in paragraph (1)</quote>.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF1F23FECB278478489BF15C2B5B9C661"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections at the beginning of chapter 20 of such title is amended by striking the item relating to section 2041 and inserting the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE8A182FB146D40CC977588CD814C8C63" style="OLC"><toc><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">2041. Housing assistance for homeless veterans, veterans in temporary housing, and very low-income
			 veteran families.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idA02B5C8950F74E79AB3A48AE2D2571BE"><enum>6.</enum><header>Outreach relating to increasing the amount of housing available to veterans</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall, in collaboration with the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, public housing authorities, tribally designated housing entities, realtors, landlords, property management companies, developers, and such other persons as the Secretary considers appropriate, conduct outreach to realtors, landlords, property management companies, and developers to educate them about the housing needs of veterans and the benefits of having veterans as tenants.</text>
		</section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idBF234D2C862140C9B420A4D982E7F90B"><enum>7.</enum><header>Establishment of National Center on Homelessness Among Veterans</header>
 <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id76C194AF8DE04C068B684F3672FDB9BB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subchapter VII of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/20">chapter 20</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, as amended by section 3(a)(1), is further amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idC161F9A145954AE49FC2986D8B5F8D62" style="USC">
					<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB1A2E2DD88CA4DD381B1F940C2AC487E"><enum>2068.</enum><header>National Center on Homelessness Among Veterans</header>
 <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3F65C16EC0D4406AB37616498B2CC605"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id22CB76D47134446885AE26CDECC4FBED"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary shall establish and operate a center to carry out the functions described in subsection (b).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2EA86140B29F47A1BC97885ADC70F215" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The center establish under paragraph (1) shall be known as the <quote>National Center on Homelessness Among Veterans</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9A211927192245AA81F905752CD4B463" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>To the degree practicable, the Secretary shall operate the center established under paragraph (1) independently of the other programs of the Department that address homelessness among veterans.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idAE14E52CDCD54F289990EC01B5B5568A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Functions</header><text>The functions described in this subsection are as follows:</text> <paragraph id="id1137a5ed4f7e4cd6b54ec590d15b1574"><enum>(1)</enum><text>To carry out and promote research into the causes and contributing factors to veteran homelessness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idC040D061CF564131828220D0563458F6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>To assess the effectiveness of programs of the Department to meet the needs of homeless veterans.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idea200a47bff147d3a688cc2efc049f7e"><enum>(3)</enum><text>To identify and disseminate best practices with regard to housing stabilization, income support, employment assistance, community partnerships, and such other matters as the Secretary considers appropriate with respect to addressing veteran homelessness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id5f27fc6e14464e2896ca5305da140e98"><enum>(4)</enum><text>To integrate evidence-based and best practices, policies, and programs into programs of the Department for homeless veterans and veterans at risk of homelessness and to ensure that the staff of the Department and community partners can implement such practices, policies, and programs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ide245fa53ef85428198723d9ec9201155"><enum>(5)</enum><text>To serve as a resource center for, and promote and seek to coordinate the exchange of information regarding, all research and training activities carried out by the Department and by other Federal and non-Federal entities with respect to veteran homelessness.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id50A27F805F094ED89E97093E7384224B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of chapter 20 of such title, as amended by section 3(a)(2), is further amended by inserting after the item relating to section 2067 the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4F248C0AB136462BA9513B15B510D16B" style="OLC"><toc><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">2068. National Center on Homelessness Among Veterans.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection></section><section id="id2EBDF2092E1D4A2C821DE35B22DEE6FA"><enum>8.</enum><header>Administrative improvements to grant and per diem programs of Department of Veterans Affairs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2012 of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="idE6DD976D7A374AA783CD47375C771BCD"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (a)(1), in the matter before subparagraph (A), by inserting <quote>and except as otherwise provided in this section</quote> after <quote>such purpose</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id707F5FF9B21747D795D3E984ED05C4C6"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id244FEFE491B04B53B590A53536F174EA" style="OLC"> <subsection id="id37C02E2B35984FD39097BBB468EAEBF9"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Review and conditional renewal</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id45F812C3BDC241CF93DAAB622DA1ABE9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Each year, the Secretary shall review each grant recipient and eligible entity that received a per diem payment under this section for a service furnished to a veteran during the one-year period preceding the review to evaluate the performance of the grant recipient or eligible entity during that period with respect to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id32CBC7D31F68421091CFC5F71570150B" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the success of the grant recipient or eligible entity in assisting veterans obtain, transition into, and retain permanent housing; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id82DA756E26FD491F954CFC2EF88827A1" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>increasing the income of veterans, whether by helping veterans obtain employment or by helping veterans obtain income-related benefits to which such veterans may be eligible or entitled.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idAEB2D9EF338D4008B770FAEAD3C3644A" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>For any grant recipient or eligible entity whose performance was evaluated for a year under paragraph (1), the Secretary may only provide per diem under this section to that grant recipient or eligible entity in the following year if the Secretary determines that such performance merits continued receipt of per diem under this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id4B6D4F2B4A5F4BBB8B9F0A6610293FAE" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Secretary shall establish uniform performance targets throughout the United States for all grant recipients and eligible entities that receive per diem payments under this section for purposes of evaluating the performance of each such grant recipient and eligible entity under this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body>
</bill>


