<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S745 IS: National Debt and Taxation Transparency Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code> 
<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>S. 745</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20150316">March 16, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S287">Mr. Cornyn</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title>To provide debt and tax transparency to taxpayers.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HA584D4ADF208462BAE898AE50D4BCBFB"> 
<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>National Debt and Taxation Transparency Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="id5DFCC7E718404090B389EF19FD49C0C2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings and purposes</header> <subsection id="id9B346AFE81C04127B2D27701CAECFFE6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress makes the following findings:</text> 
<paragraph id="id440F5EB39D6B4FED92F53C8EE84039CE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>United States taxpayers work on average almost 3 months of every year to pay for the operations of the Federal Government.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="idF3E1381464884E4E87BE9593FFEA942C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>United States taxpayers spent on average 20 percent of their total income on Federal taxes in 2014.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="id9B9A8905852542D98B9930A0EDAFEB9F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In 2014, United States taxpayers spent more on taxes than on food, clothing, and housing combined.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="idC248742455C04345B3DE5744DEED7BC7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Federal Government spent the equivalent of more than $28,800 per United States household in 2014, adding $4,000 per household to the Federal deficit.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="id5A2B9021123D4CB5B865790401BC3012"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The national debt as of January 2015 exceeds $145,000 per United States household.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="id8A5165B5373A4E92990B99B179E5390F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of this Act are—</text> 
<paragraph id="idAE67380DA57C43E0B911123845EE2C89"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to bring more transparency to the tax-and-spend habit of the Federal Government;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="id58BD9D9326FE442FA87A83FC1AE3BF25"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to provide for better accountability in the Federal budget and appropriations process; and</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="id37A10C26630B46ABA7D919E2D0E864ED"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to increase the participation of United States citizens in their government.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="idF5DD161672AC46649314B4E425519A53"><enum>3.</enum><header>A taxpayer financial statement to taxpayers</header> <subsection id="ide13f728fa74b4a1da168380edb789c6e"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Provision of statement upon request</header><text>Beginning not later than October 1, 2017, the Secretary of the Treasury (or the Secretary's delegate) shall provide to each eligible individual a <quote>taxpayer account statement</quote> for such individual.</text> </subsection>
<subsection id="idd6169278aef4443999e4e75836c5cc95"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Taxpayer account statement</header><text>The taxpayer account statement required under subsection (a) shall include—</text> <paragraph id="id1c9787fd98f34c80a448285fec9119f7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a summary of the most recent Financial Report of the United States Government, including the Statement of Long Term Fiscal Projections;</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="ide98225661ea1413399fc898322c87cfe"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a calculation by the Secretary of the Treasury of the eligible individual’s share of the total obligations of the Federal Government, including those incurred in Medicare, Social Security, other civilian and military retirement benefit programs, publicly-held debt, and any other liabilities and expenses, as reported by the most recent Financial Report of the United States Government; and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="ideeee2306c39449a39e5c7679555f6e01"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a 30-year calculation of the proportional increase in the Federal income tax rates, as established under chapter 1 of subtitle A of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, necessary to entirely finance the current fiscal path of the Federal Government, assuming no changes in current fiscal policy and assuming no budget deficit.</text> </paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="id5e9114f426ca4a85bf6a61682bd42daa"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Additional calculation</header><text>Not later than 5 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall also provide an estimate of the marginal tax rate and the income and payroll tax liability of the individual under the assumptions stated under subsection (b)(6).</text> </subsection> <subsection id="id8d1494eb7df549db84fcf2cdfa2b105d"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Eligible individual</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>eligible individual</term> means an individual who—</text> 
<paragraph id="id09bda6a11656425ca05c8d9d65b3c868"><enum>(1)</enum><text>has a valid social security number issued by the Social Security Administration;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="id1296f85ce1244e42a47f5a429cecff3b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>received a Form W–2 in the previous taxable year; and</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="id23512ed986714f9c884e5bf43ffe7140"><enum>(3)</enum><text>has filed a return of tax in any previous taxable year.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="id2d1141b34ff8465d8544be96f8aca528"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall, to the maximum extent practicable, take such steps as are necessary to assure that eligible individuals are informed of the availability of the statement required under subsection (a).</text> </subsection>
<subsection id="id3accac1221b242d99a124261cc2681a1"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Mandatory provision of initial statements</header><text>By not later than September 30, 2020, the Secretary of the Treasury (or the Secretary's delegate) shall provide a taxpayer account statement containing the information required under subsection (b) to each eligible individual for whom a current mailing address can be determined. The Secretary shall provide with each such statement notice that an updated version of such statement is available annually upon request.</text> </subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

