<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1259 IS: National Laboratory Technology Maturation Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1259</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150507">May 7, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S359">Mr. Heinrich</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To establish a grant program to allow National Laboratories to provide vouchers to small business
			 concerns to improve commercialization of technologies developed at
			 National Laboratories and the technology-driven economic impact of
			 commercialization in the regions in which National Laboratories are
			 located, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body>
 <section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>National Laboratory Technology Maturation Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </section><section id="id3E8C0FA0F1FC409CB5FB9577FE861633"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="id8C597DC559F548A3B53063E7545F2CE7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>National laboratory</header><text>The term <quote>National Laboratory</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 2 of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/15801">42 U.S.C. 15801</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id300F8180654E43E49E2F42091E48D6A9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of Energy.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idA4D762A084024806BFCDEB7E666A5C57"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Small business concern</header><text>The term <quote>small business concern</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 3 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/632">15 U.S.C. 632</external-xref>).</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="id5A802C75132A4E93BEDB339AEBFEEF80"><enum>3.</enum><header>Establishment of technology maturation grant program</header>
 <subsection id="idA0219DDD068D4F7F84F0C1D8722C9CD9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall establish the National Laboratory technology maturation program under which the Secretary shall make grants to National Laboratories for the purpose of increasing the successful transfer of technologies licensed from National Laboratories to small business concerns by providing a link between an innovative process or technology and a practical application with potential to be successful in commercial markets.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="idCA573BED9BB5425F8E1FF6713E782E11"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application for grant from the Secretary</header>
 <paragraph id="idD84626ACBE354D0B89B785351E321290"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each National Laboratory that elects to apply for a grant under subsection (a) shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may reasonably require.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id83A1AB1E1E504641866AFABE9EEBB90E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>In an application submitted under this subsection, a National Laboratory shall describe how the National Laboratory will—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idC8E08CBAA6F04B98842197F8CA6BCF69"><enum>(A)</enum><text>manage a technology maturation program;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0040065F6E79458EAA8278CE3D8A5843"><enum>(B)</enum><text>encourage small business concerns, with an emphasis on businesses in the region in which the National Laboratory is located, to participate in the technology maturation program;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7BBE792068984C47AD8DC414C06E5EEB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>select small business concerns and technologies to participate in the technology maturation program using a selection board (referred to in this section as the <quote>selection board</quote>) made up of technical and business members, including venture capitalists and investors; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1F50A45CC83A43ADA31EF23BD7A90E07"><enum>(D)</enum><text>measure the results of the program and the return on investment, including—</text> <clause id="id9E89412F005240E1BE57C6CE5BC3A35A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number of technologies licensed to small business concerns;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id27CEAB77F1EB45A0A098DD66087FAFB2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the number of new small business concerns created;</text> </clause><clause id="id7C4CD3DA07B248C79D2CF7CD5D8D59AD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the number of jobs created or retained;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id9183DB3EEBB84DF4901EBDAFDF20F3C5"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>sales of the licensed technologies; and</text> </clause><clause id="id5187CA28F5044185A8090B39D867B6A7"><enum>(v)</enum><text>any additional external investment attracted by participating small business concerns.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id3EB3F41F01514EFC8C13F5A40B16523C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Maximum grant</header><text>The maximum amount of a grant received by a National Laboratory under subsection (a) shall be $5,000,000 for each fiscal year.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="idCFA7E73AF3CE4077B75C3BE4774133ED"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Vouchers to small business concerns from National Laboratories</header>
 <paragraph id="idABABF9821AA440AEA185BF058C97A401"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A National Laboratory receiving a grant under subsection (a) shall use the grant funds to provide vouchers to small business concerns that hold a technology license from a National Laboratory to pay the cost of providing assistance from scientists and engineers at the National Laboratory to assist in the development of the licensed technology and further develop related products and services until the products and services are market-ready or sufficiently developed to attract private investment.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idF2A0D80981D448BF9FF6F23F28B7D172"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of voucher funds</header><text>A small business concern receiving a voucher under paragraph (1) may use the voucher—</text> <subparagraph id="id41804C3E66784A54B8219E8377F0D878"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to gain access to special equipment or facilities at the National Laboratory that awarded the voucher;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5669ACB2CB3749849083CA988FF0591A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to partner with the National Laboratory on a commercial prototype; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id66B97BB7123242DAAD787B3AC41D557C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to perform early-stage feasibility or later-stage field testing.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idED443590C0AC44B7B17F6DB1982F2873"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligible projects</header><text>A National Laboratory receiving a grant under subsection (a) may provide a voucher to small business concerns and partnerships between a small business concern and an institution of higher education (as defined in section 101(a) of the <act-name parsable-cite="HEA65">Higher Education Act of 1965</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001(a)</external-xref>)) for projects—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id519F9611E9AD4F8FAD7C7982BBB41FE0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>involving—</text> <clause id="id4B160A45FD254FAF96828995E7F0DDB5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>commercial prototypes;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id65C5120A638A4AC8ACC6EECEDCC3B68F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>scale-up and field demonstrations; or</text> </clause><clause id="id65273A154056491CA6348F13F7BFD686"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>other activities that move the technology closer to successful commercialization; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1C6335B73A3F45EEA634A4FD2B733A4B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that do not exceed 1 year.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5E9302A16CE1428D80EB8267F4625275"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Application for voucher from National Laboratory</header><text>Each small business concern that holds a technology license from a National Laboratory that elects to apply for a voucher under paragraph (1) shall submit an application to the selection board at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the selection board may reasonably require.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idF9D448E6838941469913B52870A09E9C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Criteria</header><text>The selection board may award vouchers based on—</text> <subparagraph id="id52BA2936714B4F4DB5171DBD01706E5C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the viability of the technology for commercial success;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF5A0AACCF743464FAA4195C2E213EF8B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a robust commercialization business plan for transition of the technology into a marketplace success;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id654E9641AD80474EB3CAC2831327C8F2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a significant opportunity for growth of an existing company;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5F1283D17D8A4E2EA2303EDED4C59C01"><enum>(D)</enum><text>access to a strong, experienced business and technical team;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idAA0F958BA3B5471E9C9E5D57359C207A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>clear, market-driven milestones for the project;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id736933A9127344A3AE089478F53173E4"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the potential of the technology to enhance the economy of the region in which the National Laboratory is located;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id68428332FD4842B08B9A885B43B5837F"><enum>(G)</enum><text>availability and source of matching funds for the project, including in-kind contributions; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id90388E81AC084B19A688E056FF9AB7C6"><enum>(H)</enum><text>compatibility with the mission of the National Laboratory.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id89553823CC564F9D9D861AE33C44BD6C"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Maximum voucher</header><text>The maximum amount of a voucher received by a small business concern under paragraph (1) shall be $250,000.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="idAC9405B2BB824E05B5CE8132FB2B0EA9"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Progress tracking</header>
 <subparagraph id="id5F2255734B6343F69F383431859FD5C6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The National Laboratory that awards a voucher to carry out a project under paragraph (1) shall establish a procedure to monitor interim progress of the project toward commercialization milestones.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id65EBCC0FC24B4D56B8F18E61D7F5157D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Termination of voucher</header><text>If the National Laboratory determines that a project is not making adequate progress toward commercialization milestones under the procedure established pursuant to subparagraph (A), the project shall not continue to receive funding or assistance under this subsection.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idA7497E20FD304883BA58F33487E7022A"><enum>4.</enum><header>Annual report</header>
 <subsection id="id625510678E79410A95B243879B355F52"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each National Laboratory receiving a grant under section 3 shall submit to the Secretary an annual report, at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may reasonably require.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idA0AFA7C733D2408684C5C8BF8FF02734"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents of report</header><text>The report submitted under subsection (a) shall—</text> <paragraph id="idBDE6BC4E5C4747738B9AB02E7F6F2C35"><enum>(1)</enum><text>include a list of each recipient of a voucher and the amount of each voucher awarded; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id7517097FAF5940B4B12B47FB4BC084F3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide an estimate of the return on investment, including—</text> <subparagraph id="idAB10BAFCA2974B759195E975F778E022"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the increase in the number of technologies licensed to small business concerns;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9E478CA3EC2D48C9803E1FC32D19F556"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of jobs created or retained;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2E9EFF4FF24B45E8B1BB92DC4B10536B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>sales of the licensed technologies; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id60E6CAB514F344FDBFDAF4AA96FF0F70"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any additional external investment attracted by participating small business concerns.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idDAFF3F95F3D84B39981DC6C63AA1FA02"><enum>5.</enum><header>Final report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 5 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services and Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committees on Armed Services and Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives a report on the results of the program established under section 3, including—</text>
 <paragraph id="idDD25B702F3D6440AB41DB3A1F30BEE3C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the return on investment; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id3BF4DEE721234E2FBA7520DD0F835E70"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any recommendations for improvements to the program.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="id04BA330A785742ED8FEE589DFAB1D061"><enum>6.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act $25,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2016 through 2020.</text></section></legis-body></bill>


