<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1738 IS: Safer Communities Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1738</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150709">July 9, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To protect individuals by strengthening the Nation’s mental health infrastructure, improving the
			 understanding of violence, strengthening firearm prohibitions and
			 protections for at-risk individuals, and improving and expanding the
			 reporting of mental health records to the National Instant Criminal
			 Background Check System.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H31371250699449EAA9810E65AB85C227" style="OLC">
 <section id="HD286774F1073498CB29A702800517FEC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Safer Communities Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H09CE9E705D1543AA870758A7A53D9D7B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The table of contents of this Act is as follows:</text><toc><toc-entry idref="HD286774F1073498CB29A702800517FEC" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H09CE9E705D1543AA870758A7A53D9D7B" level="section">Sec. 2. Table of contents.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H2F24E67ECF524C0EB3B6B8E080ABB86A" level="section">Sec. 3. Statement of purpose.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H25FAD8ECD6834C81A9635F1423DF95DE" level="title">TITLE I—Strengthening and improving intervention efforts</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H03A739D846A14792BF9CF0FCA08F76AF" level="section">Sec. 101. Mental health crisis assessment, prevention, and education grant program.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HE23E2D8D83EF4178BCC12F3695CA0DE0" level="section">Sec. 102. School-based mental health programs.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HCB06D2AF42C544FDBACEAE7309515C25" level="section">Sec. 103. Justice and mental health collaboration.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H6863C4A6CB264E01B4E8222D2149E143" level="title">TITLE II—Improving research on violence</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H489C2F193E5A452AB98C8A62E9EA6741" level="section">Sec. 201. Research with respect to violence.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H68C44C72EA534609842E3AACD878BA50" level="title">TITLE III—Understanding the epidemic of gun violence</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HE7A9AA3FBE254E53B5AE8B8C32A77E96" level="section">Sec. 301. National violent death reporting system.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H887CB959A606453B93B9493F8F23CD9A" level="section">Sec. 302. Reaffirming Centers for Disease Control’s authority.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H9E6AAAFEEDAB40918023EF229CE18E79" level="section">Sec. 303. Protecting confidential doctor-patient relationship.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HEB6F5703C0804403B110AE6EAFC8703C" level="title">TITLE IV—Ensuring safe communities</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HCD8720B4DAF64880960DC8C99F34B70C" level="section">Sec. 401. Ban on firearm possession by person committed involuntarily to mental institution on an
			 outpatient basis.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H767D29A554C1408394BCE8E4FA2BE781" level="section">Sec. 402. Grant program regarding firearms.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H2A3CE19C40294151BCD1DD950B830609" level="section">Sec. 403. Notification of State and local law enforcement authorities of attempt to purchase
			 firearm by ineligible person.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H57323BA28D5A4B0EB79AF89CC9E3E2CA" level="title">TITLE V—Restoration</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HB7A95B1B77FB4D9C9BBEC78FB062430B" level="section">Sec. 501. Federal agency relief program.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H5B445F0C5EA74F1C9F12E521B4757596" level="section">Sec. 502. State relief programs.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H3BEC813304034F6BA2AF21C918EB41F6" level="section">Sec. 503. Ineligibility due to disqualifying mental status.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H0EBDF690F792499EA6848A9F44E40D1F" level="title">TITLE VI—Submission of Records to National Instant Criminal Background Check System</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HFA080FA653BC43AEAF997FB5907E27B3" level="section">Sec. 601. Reports relating to submission of information to NICS.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H2F4D986990244F16B932FC0C7A1865A0" level="section">Sec. 602. Reauthorization of the National Criminal History Records Improvement Program.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H53C1B6C742DC49AD923BE66E759370EC" level="section">Sec. 603. Improvement of metrics and incentives.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HFF4588394D4A443DAB35132D7BC3F42C" level="section">Sec. 604. Grants to States to improve coordination and automation of NICS record reporting.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H88C10C84B29E49CA88441E50C124646E" level="section">Sec. 605. Sharing of records by Federal departments and agencies with NICS.</toc-entry>
			</toc>
 </section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2F24E67ECF524C0EB3B6B8E080ABB86A"><enum>3.</enum><header>Statement of purpose</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purpose of this Act is to ensure the public safety and welfare of communities by promoting evidence-based approaches that will prevent the tragic toll of gun violence on families and communities. This purpose can be accomplished by—</text>
 <paragraph id="H8F767B8E580748ACB97A5B8F3BE5E828"><enum>(1)</enum><text>strengthening and improving intervention efforts by increasing investments in programs designed to appropriately identify, respond to, treat, and mitigate future behavioral health crises;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA7639302DCF246069AAACCD407DAF858"><enum>(2)</enum><text>prioritizing research on reducing the threat of gun violence to self or others and identifying further risk factors for violence, including gender, culture, substance abuse, and history of violence; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9355C462262F4E2A9D38324293BEE4E4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>restricting gun access by individuals found to be at an elevated risk of committing future acts of violence against self or others.</text>
			</paragraph></section><title id="H25FAD8ECD6834C81A9635F1423DF95DE"><enum>I</enum><header>Strengthening and improving intervention efforts</header>
			<section id="H03A739D846A14792BF9CF0FCA08F76AF"><enum>101.</enum><header>Mental health crisis assessment, prevention, and education grant program</header>
 <subsection id="HAFF89D827DF74AC4B00C51C9B09517FA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section, the following definitions shall apply:</text> <paragraph id="HEB351AC6FA7C48A59013149D93DC0150"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible Entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible entity</term> means a State, political subdivision of a State, or nonprofit private entity.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3C4B878162234B969780155E4FDB5EE9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6A0DE6A62593483D91298980503E6646"><enum>(3)</enum><header>State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>State</term> means each State of the United States, the District of Columbia, each commonwealth, territory or possession of the United States, and each federally recognized Indian tribe.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5711DC5AA9104B78815253F52538C263"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment of Grant Program</header>
 <paragraph id="HB97E267909EE4412B9F41879C89F191A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a program to award grants to eligible entities to carry out the activities described in paragraph (2).</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="HB005331813254D30A392467852CCA2BB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of Funds</header>
 <subparagraph id="HBE382C82AFD04552B4417884BC4D24FC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Grants under this section may be used to carry out programs that—</text> <clause id="HC30ED4118EB6453E82C231F7C96E6BD8"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">expand early intervention and treatment services to improve access to mental health crisis assistance and address unmet mental health care needs;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7B9A3AEB78BC46D4A7B506998236B227"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">expand the continuum of services to address crisis intervention and crisis stabilization;</text> </clause><clause id="HCD5BACAD44AF4D7E94F6454958E4B614"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reduce recidivism due to mental health crises and mitigate unnecessary expenditures by local law enforcement; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H619667BFCA5B4EE6A8C6581A67FB35C6"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>reduce unnecessary hospitalizations by appropriately utilizing community-based services and improving access to timely mental health crisis assistance.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H51391F2383884D7AAA95DA3F0886E69E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Authorized Activities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The programs described in subparagraph (A) may include any or all of the following activities:</text> <clause id="HF180742E274541DB9CAEA2072FB49407"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Mental health crisis intervention and response training for law enforcement (to increase officers’ understanding and recognition of mental illnesses).</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8CA8158481C9481F82896EFE90BC3ABB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Mobile support that provides field-based behavioral health assistance to law enforcement and members of the community and links individuals in crisis to appropriate services.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HBB11906216AA48AB92850D0B09755BCA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">School and community-based early intervention and prevention programs that provide mobile response, screening and assessment, training and education, and peer-based and family services.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3239F5D7123F445C8C91D851C6C7767C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be considered for a grant under this section, an eligible entity shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require. At minimum, such application shall include a description of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HC368C849E3DE44BBA9495B1C248368A9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the activities to be funded with the grant;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7E9E528E51D0433AA4AA06EBF45E27C0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>community needs;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H43278AA34F1742DFA5C65DD9D6667802"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the population to be served; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H53547511648D4DC890BAED532BC85962"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the interaction between the activities described in subparagraph (A) and public systems of health and mental health care, law enforcement, social services, and related assistance programs.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4EFA4D72864143A8BF6414D10378FBB8"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Selecting among applicants</header>
 <subparagraph id="H45B4C2ED316049F1B0D9B37431DD4B96"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In General</header><text>Grants shall be awarded to eligible entities on a competitive basis.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H87DCDDBC7C854367A3973B3A344CB4C0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Selection Criteria</header><text>The Secretary shall evaluate applicants based on such criteria as the Secretary determines to be appropriate, including the ability of an applicant to carry out the activities described in paragraph (2).</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDCB9CF07CCF9417998D5A36922F53F3A"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Reports</header>
						<subparagraph id="H6767729E2DE44863AF22FBA7BE4705F9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Annual Reports</header>
 <clause id="H49C5283ABB4A46638061837D5DC30A00"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Eligible Entities</header><text>As a condition of receiving a grant under this section, an eligible entity shall agree to submit a report to the Secretary, on an annual basis, describing the activities carried out with the grant and assessing the effectiveness of such activities.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HDCAFA4BD4CB54453A5E3CAC8516BBA3E"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The Secretary shall, on an annual basis, and using the reports received under clause (i), report to Congress on the overall impact and effectiveness of the grant program under this section.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDD56E7DB849A4257BC48E55C35F7FB9D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Final Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than January 15, 2019, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a final report that includes recommendations with respect to the feasibility and advisability of extending or expanding the grant program.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H27BD5F9F01EF4734B8779EE0611E4DF9"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Collection of Data</header>
 <subparagraph id="H746FEA671BF5431A9CC70F5CBD12E88C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall collect data on the grant program to determine its effectiveness in reducing the social impact of mental health crises and the feasibility and advisability of extending the grant program.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA521FAD3143D4A6DA015F88037E07AC9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Manner of Collection</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Data described in subparagraph (A) shall be collected and analyzed using a scientific peer-reviewed system and valid and reliable results-based research methodologies.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H996500F7B37D41D4A2C8B83D3AEE52D8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Funding</header>
 <paragraph id="HF5BBA726C2654DD194601E738D0718B4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Grant Amount</header><text>A grant under this section shall be in an amount that is not more than $100,000 for each of fiscal years 2016 through 2020. Subject to the preceding sentence, the Secretary shall determine the amount of each grant.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H19E3AEF93E0D42F392C124E7ED109C75"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authorization of Appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2016 through 2020.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HE23E2D8D83EF4178BCC12F3695CA0DE0"><enum>102.</enum><header>School-based mental health programs</header>
 <subsection id="HF69651B4031647418265D0233621F2EB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Technical amendments</header><text>The second part G (relating to services provided through religious organizations) of title V of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290kk">42 U.S.C. 290kk et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H529F4A25A9E54E2AA92018EA5CE98D52"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating such part as part J; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HAEBBA67E4B80428C8ECF52DC2138F299"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating sections 581 through 584 as sections 596 through 596C, respectively.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF8F288DCB52D4C49A8F5F7D363EFD976"><enum>(b)</enum><header>School-Based mental health and children and violence</header><text>Section 581 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290hh">42 U.S.C. 290hh</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC32A4EA0952F472DA547AA25412B28F5" style="OLC"> <section id="H5003A697607145FCAADA497E78A38FD2"><enum>581.</enum><header>School-based mental health and children and violence</header> <subsection id="H98969A92856646FE90F7970D386C4023"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in collaboration with the Secretary of Education and in consultation with the Attorney General, shall, directly or through grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements awarded to public entities and local educational agencies, assist local communities and schools in applying a public health approach to mental health services both in schools and in the community. Such approach should provide comprehensive age-appropriate services and supports, be linguistically and culturally appropriate, be trauma-informed, and incorporate age-appropriate strategies of positive behavioral interventions and supports. A comprehensive school mental health program funded under this section shall assist children in dealing with trauma and violence.</text>
 </subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0706ED02BAC5428E8CE72F8B08ADCE76"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Activities</header><text>Under the program under subsection (a), the Secretary may—</text> <paragraph id="HE94D51BF8B9B4040B468E8A0CCB709E1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide financial support to enable local communities to implement a comprehensive culturally and linguistically appropriate, trauma-informed, and age-appropriate, school mental health program that incorporates positive behavioral interventions, client treatment, and supports to foster the health and development of children;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE9E62DB2FC5646219DC762C2623DDD83"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide technical assistance to local communities with respect to the development of programs described in paragraph (1);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3ADB4F973E22430595C042691F2CC7B5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provide assistance to local communities in the development of policies to address child and adolescent trauma and mental health issues and violence when and if it occurs;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9B7DC956F9BE42C5827665BD712CC4C4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>facilitate community partnerships among families, students, law enforcement agencies, education systems, mental health and substance use disorder service systems, family-based mental health service systems, welfare agencies, health care service systems (including physicians), faith-based programs, trauma networks, and other community-based systems; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4F0B07B637FD4E86B57962254A0B3F5D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>establish mechanisms for children and adolescents to report incidents of violence or plans by other children, adolescents, or adults to commit violence.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7747D43E551344BEBC2791F228F091F7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Requirements</header>
 <paragraph id="H0487EE9C0A63470F9CE883EE8DF17383"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible for a grant, contract, or cooperative agreement under subsection (a), an entity shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HCDD622A0925C4251B04AC45DC4A07D80"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be a partnership between a local educational agency and at least one community program or agency that is involved in mental health; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2A8BE58A0784413FB30A3D8E20562088"><enum>(B)</enum><text>submit an application, that is endorsed by all members of the partnership, that contains the assurances described in paragraph (2).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H36E1FBA333B541D5A1D5F6776F1993FE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Required assurances</header><text>An application under paragraph (1) shall contain assurances as follows:</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H58C340CB1E604442A3C6EA2AB18BEA29"><enum>(A)</enum><text>That the applicant will ensure that, in carrying out activities under this section, the local educational agency involved will enter into a memorandum of understanding—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="HFFD211CF6AEE42F1AABDFEAF15A19B9A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>with at least one public or private mental health entity, health care entity, law enforcement or juvenile justice entity, child welfare agency, family-based mental health entity, family or family organization, trauma network, or other community-based entity; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H890AF43296B245FFBB117606DDDF1E56"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that clearly states—</text> <subclause commented="no" id="HB68B3CA2C80F4785900418A4FE3343CE"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how school-employed mental health professionals (such as school psychologists, school counselors, and school social workers) will be utilized in the comprehensive school mental health program;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H612052DDD1284FA4A502DEE87E529176"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the responsibilities of each partner with respect to the activities to be carried out;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H15EECB36FCFB404BAD4B7E0623290F6C"><enum>(III)</enum><text>how each such partner will be accountable for carrying out such responsibilities; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HA60E3A53A53843D8B00A4C0B1E646AD5"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the amount of non-Federal funding or in-kind contributions that each such partner will contribute in order to sustain the program.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H505025B28AE24C86BF3CA6FB3BE33259"><enum>(B)</enum><text>That the comprehensive school-based mental health program carried out under this section supports the flexible use of funds to address—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="HDF168AC5455444EA9754B5B8BB913F5E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the promotion of the social, emotional, mental, and behavioral health and wellness of all students in an environment that is conducive to learning;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H67EDA608E4E34179AEF91F2D3CF42EF8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the reduction in the likelihood of at risk students developing social, emotional, mental, and behavioral health problems, or substance use disorders;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H331BA583E08748E69933FA483C662C76"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the early identification of social, emotional, mental, and behavioral problems, or substance use disorders and the provision of early intervention services;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H4256888AF15B42A887EEBFFE7BE0507D"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the treatment or referral for treatment of students with existing social, emotional, mental, and behavioral health problems, or substance use disorders; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H7D4B8244D6FE43EE813F3AF0AF5E8E2C"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the development and implementation of programs to assist children in dealing with trauma and violence.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H232533C11E8F4CF7A2D15314CD3D8AC2"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the comprehensive school-based mental health program carried out under this section will provide for in-service training of all school personnel, including ancillary staff and volunteers, in—</text>
 <clause id="H7A99A55DCC924A90BAA8CFFC3EAA934E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the techniques and supports needed to identify early children with trauma histories and children with, or at risk of, mental illness;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H37DD56B775314406BF5B396DA68A9A0B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the use of referral mechanisms that effectively link such children to appropriate treatment and intervention services in the school and in the community and to follow-up when services are not available;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5D370783158B46E0AD03EBB241B6AE8D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>strategies that promote the social, emotional, mental, and behavioral health and wellness of all students;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HFED048E113FC4691A55EE80EEA6A223F"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">strategies for promoting the social, emotional, mental, and behavioral health of all students; and</text> </clause><clause id="H6DF24DDA522C40D0AFC3EFD307017996"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">strategies to increase the knowledge and skills of school and community leaders about the impact of trauma and violence and on the application of a public health approach to comprehensive school-based mental health programs.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD363DAC3218F4BFF9B2CABEC4F29D9AF"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the comprehensive school-based mental health program carried out under this section will include comprehensive training for parents, siblings, and other family members of children with mental health disorders, and for concerned members of the community in—</text>
 <clause id="HB03A631DD1854DD5A7DC9971D35F3DE4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the techniques and supports needed to identify early children with trauma histories, and children with, or at risk of, mental illness;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H2C89AF9C3F8B4E0EBCD3E9657C6915C3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the use of referral mechanisms that effectively link such children to appropriate treatment and intervention services in the school and in the community and follow-up when such services are not available; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA7FAB70A23284DD89656A9EDD6653128"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>strategies that promote a school-wide positive environment.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H38A2F41F6CDB4052B2A16A7879706661"><enum>(E)</enum><text>That the comprehensive school-based mental health program carried out under this section will demonstrate the measures to be taken to sustain the program after funding under this section terminates.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HFC9D65217F5942A7B16B024EF59527A5"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the local educational agency partnership involved is supported by the State educational and mental health system to ensure that the sustainability of the programs is established after funding under this section terminates.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H96301B2B9ED841699090345CF7D009B5"><enum>(G)</enum><text>That the comprehensive school-based mental health program carried out under this section will be based on trauma-informed and evidence-based practices.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HF0C4DAA65F5447E898DE6641B30487D0"><enum>(H)</enum><text>That the comprehensive school-based mental health program carried out under this section will be coordinated with early intervening activities carried out under the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HAC43ED2AD70F4AA7AFCA3139E52A9CC6"><enum>(I)</enum><text>That the comprehensive school-based mental health program carried out under this section will be trauma-informed and culturally and linguistically appropriate.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2860158B30D14782827463901884361C"><enum>(J)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the comprehensive school-based mental health program carried out under this section will include a broad needs assessment of youth who drop out of school due to policies of <quote>zero tolerance</quote> with respect to drugs, alcohol, or weapons and an inability to obtain appropriate services.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC238C128169B48AC83C72C0B79447D7E"><enum>(K)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the mental health services provided through the comprehensive school-based mental health program carried out under this section will be provided by qualified mental and behavioral health professionals who are certified or licensed by the State involved and practicing within their area of expertise.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H50CEF3051808487D8EB01E26E0FA0F81"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Coordinator</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any entity that is a member of a partnership described in paragraph (1)(A) may serve as the coordinator of funding and activities under the grant if all members of the partnership agree.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB7146F4088384AC7AE92EC0D3B4E06E9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Compliance with HIPAA</header><text>A grantee under this section shall be deemed to be a covered entity for purposes of compliance with the regulations promulgated under section 264(c) of the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 with respect to any patient records developed through activities under the grant.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4D0892908D2944DBAED62429C5284233"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Geographical distribution</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements under subsection (a) will be distributed equitably among the regions of the country and among urban and rural areas.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1020827F1E1644A19C85A0439934E0DC"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Duration of awards</header><text>With respect to a grant, contract, or cooperative agreement under subsection (a), the period during which payments under such an award will be made to the recipient shall be 6 years. An entity may receive only one award under this section, except that an entity that is providing services and supports on a regional basis may receive additional funding after the expiration of the preceding grant period.</text>
							</subsection><subsection id="H528755FE21C741FAB21E54DBD9841C47"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Evaluation and measures of outcomes</header>
 <paragraph id="H5410BAB0040E466C8062A3BB05AD19DB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Development of process</header><text>The Administrator shall develop a fiscally appropriate process for evaluating activities carried out under this section. Such process shall include—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H1EB05F02FAD34E66B31CDAEAC9CB34E7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the development of guidelines for the submission of program data by grant, contract, or cooperative agreement recipients;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4CE481FB40A44EA7A58CBE3D7BFD0486"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the development of measures of outcomes (in accordance with paragraph (2)) to be applied by such recipients in evaluating programs carried out under this section; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9FA7D7AB80F94AB8810C7CC1894F77BB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the submission of annual reports by such recipients concerning the effectiveness of programs carried out under this section.</text>
									</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H11B7D4698D574E098B472FDCAB509888"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Measures of outcomes</header>
 <subparagraph id="H29506F83337B455DB10FC99DAE2490B0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator shall develop measures of outcomes to be applied by recipients of assistance under this section, and the Administrator, in evaluating the effectiveness of programs carried out under this section. Such measures shall include student and family measures as provided for in subparagraph (B) and local educational measures as provided for under subparagraph (C).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9EB0C658F97543ABBEC157BF0330F09B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Student and family measures of outcomes</header><text>The measures of outcomes developed under paragraph (1)(B) relating to students and families shall, with respect to activities carried out under a program under this section, at a minimum include provisions to evaluate whether the program is effective in—</text>
 <clause id="H96893DEB665241658D25187916D8FC82"><enum>(i)</enum><text>improving social, emotional, mental, and behavioral health and wellness;</text> </clause><clause id="H5B309D11670A4AAFA3D78670BE813A78"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>increasing academic competency (as defined by Secretary);</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1C51C54186314C3599291D6DF999B4DC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>reducing disruptive and aggressive behaviors;</text> </clause><clause id="HACC5BD9EA82D4AD3B316C0EE4DF42DA2"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>improving child functioning;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA3175875A6A64D18BC165A31FCDB760C"><enum>(v)</enum><text>reducing substance use disorders;</text> </clause><clause id="H362AC10974EB41DFB79D186F894A1CF7"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>reducing suspensions, truancy, expulsions and violence;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD2DBA5E64CCC4BC2928389413D791229"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>increasing graduation rates (as defined in section 1111(b)(2)(C)(vi) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965); and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF97085F45D4547208FF8827926C1545D"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>improving access to care for mental health disorders.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBA94D30D9DC646A2AB3ADD2B2BE622C7"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Local educational outcomes</header><text>The outcome measures developed under paragraph (1)(B) relating to local educational systems shall, with respect to activities carried out under a program under this section, at a minimum include provisions to evaluate—</text>
 <clause id="HBBC4C66358F44EA398A92AEEACC55B0D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the effectiveness of comprehensive school mental health programs established under this section;</text> </clause><clause id="H5C7835C2EE5C453D9A42364851800E07"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the effectiveness of formal partnership linkages among child and family serving institutions, community support systems, and the educational system;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H515A8B8349E749B099CD329C9189996E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the progress made in sustaining the program once funding under the grant has expired;</text> </clause><clause id="HB6C302468A64417988B252C2BF898349"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the effectiveness of training and professional development programs for all school personnel that incorporate indicators that measure cultural and linguistic competencies under the program in a manner that incorporates appropriate cultural and linguistic training;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H76E657EEB7824F12893320754A9A11D9"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the improvement in perception of a safe and supportive learning environment among school staff, students, and parents;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H63A18FC7BBE74BCA8A2FAFF605A13D48"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the improvement in case-finding of students in need of more intensive services and referral of identified students to early intervention and clinical services;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H050C5FA3CB4946ED9F514F2A7EA52E01"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>the improvement in the immediate availability of clinical assessment and treatment services within the context of the local community to students posing a danger to themselves or others;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H2653206D790A43789AEEF86D4219A858"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>the increased successful matriculation to postsecondary school; and</text> </clause><clause id="H0B8C4EDC265F419B9AB6509AECBE7DE2"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>reduced referrals to juvenile justice.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAC3A36B890FE498BAACE7E2A4FAE9EE6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Submission of annual data</header><text>An entity that receives a grant, contract, or cooperative agreement under this section shall annually submit to the Administrator a report that includes data to evaluate the success of the program carried out by the entity based on whether such program is achieving the purposes of the program. Such reports shall utilize the measures of outcomes under paragraph (2) in a reasonable manner to demonstrate the progress of the program in achieving such purposes.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H77E3C18AC303418BBB42D86AE07F1C6F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Evaluation by Administrator</header><text>Based on the data submitted under paragraph (3), the Administrator shall annually submit to Congress a report concerning the results and effectiveness of the programs carried out with assistance received under this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H10C4A3E816B44CA79BFAAA12C27D73FD"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>A grantee shall use not to exceed 10 percent of amounts received under a grant under this section to carry out evaluation activities under this subsection.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7AA10CABF21D47BB93790D35F70400EC"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Information and education</header><text>The Secretary shall establish comprehensive information and education programs to disseminate the findings of the knowledge development and application under this section to the general public and to health care professionals.</text>
							</subsection><subsection id="HD3F06FABA68B4164A92F4C276053D890"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Amount of grants and authorization of appropriations</header>
 <paragraph id="H0F385B2336724265AE1733A36CF261EC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Amount of grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A grant under this section shall be in an amount that is not more than $1,000,000 for each of grant years 2016 through 2020. The Secretary shall determine the amount of each such grant based on the population of children up to age 21 of the area to be served under the grant.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB43BE819EF244DF6B203FA52EDDEDC99"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section, $200,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2016 through 2020.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H54FDAB26223149618CF54F73614E5C8E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Part G of title V of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290hh">42 U.S.C. 290hh et seq.</external-xref>), as amended by this section, is further amended by striking the part heading and inserting the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1798152F5F95449E9B1E76EDCB4F95CB" style="OLC">
						<part id="H1C08C87324CE4AD397F25AC56D91722A"><enum>G<?LEXA-Enum G?></enum><header>School-based mental health</header></part><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</subsection></section><section id="HCB06D2AF42C544FDBACEAE7309515C25"><enum>103.</enum><header>Justice and mental health collaboration</header>
				<subsection id="H434E186A892B49008522579C6314670B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Assisting Veterans</header>
 <paragraph id="HC2E1459058474FC4A01DF606CE0CE3A9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Redesignation</header><text>Section 2991 of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3797aa">42 U.S.C. 3797aa</external-xref>) is amended by redesignating subsection (i) as subsection (l).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6B11ED9D08B94704944FF2AA702BCF36"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Assisting veterans</header><text>Section 2991 of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3797aa">42 U.S.C. 3797aa</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after subsection (h) the following:</text>
						<quoted-block id="H9C6690CAAF3D4F7D8762477193C90397" style="OLC">
							<subsection id="HAF97D599E2324BC6A961EAA275A52690"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Assisting Veterans</header>
 <paragraph id="HB8AAB14836C540638D565AADE35D02AD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text> <subparagraph id="H052CA5345A05442A9DF40C8AAE968F50"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Peer to peer services or programs</header><text>The term <term>peer to peer services or programs</term> means services or programs that connect qualified veterans with other veterans for the purpose of providing support and mentorship to assist qualified veterans in obtaining treatment, recovery, stabilization, or rehabilitation.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5206E353AAED427694431073A4246BEB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Qualified veteran</header><text>The term <term>qualified veteran</term> means a preliminarily qualified offender who—</text> <clause id="H0824E9319D564DBC94902A91FBE72694"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has served on active duty in any branch of the Armed Forces, including the National Guard and reserve components; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6B4D8E8AD7574DA99622C2DF36CE4FDC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>was discharged or released from such service under conditions other than dishonorable.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3188551B708447E183B7A6219D9B9663"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Veterans treatment court program</header><text>The term <term>veterans treatment court program</term> means a court program involving collaboration among criminal justice, veterans, and mental health and substance abuse agencies that provides qualified veterans with—</text>
 <clause id="HFA9BB996EBC7455B8D76762322D94A61"><enum>(i)</enum><text>intensive judicial supervision and case management, which may include random and frequent drug testing where appropriate;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HCAA9E2207AE447F49B90608E786559CA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a full continuum of treatment services, including mental health services, substance abuse services, medical services, and services to address trauma;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H135EFCD80B304FA289C9D634308EBBE7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>alternatives to incarceration; or</text> </clause><clause id="H41BEA5DA59A14EBEB8DF71BD927FDFEF"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>other appropriate services, which may include housing, transportation, mentoring, employment, job training, education, and assistance in applying for and obtaining available benefits.</text>
										</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9DDD7D7C81A34FFBAFE3D0D8C818DAE0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Veterans assistance program</header>
 <subparagraph id="H475753786A404BDE8159E9665F3BC08D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, may award grants under this subsection to applicants to establish or expand—</text>
 <clause id="HBE321613BD6B4EEF82DB10F15BCFB1C7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>veterans treatment court programs;</text> </clause><clause id="H50799D99AEA9486AA6B22B38163557B6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>peer to peer services or programs for qualified veterans;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5426B2F71AFB4263A736E5D09B50FC4B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>practices that identify and provide treatment, rehabilitation, legal, transitional, and other appropriate services to qualified veterans who have been incarcerated; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF31093F0A02047568E9C1B3930E6CEE4"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>training programs to teach criminal justice, law enforcement, corrections, mental health, and substance abuse personnel how to identify and appropriately respond to incidents involving qualified veterans.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5460EF32A93046219D889E2D97917894"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding grants under this subsection, the Attorney General shall give priority to applications that—</text>
 <clause id="H60E76E05D50F439386AC90BC05F1159B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>demonstrate collaboration between and joint investments by criminal justice, mental health, substance abuse, and veterans service agencies;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF52A50D9E46D403CA4D80795202F0CA8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>promote effective strategies to identify and reduce the risk of harm to qualified veterans and public safety; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HBE1D1716BB7B4C6DAA52A6BF7D15C409"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>propose interventions with empirical support to improve outcomes for qualified veterans.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD32438265FCC47FD8D0F24AF32792428"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Correctional Facilities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2991 of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3797aa">42 U.S.C. 3797aa</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after subsection (i), as so added by subsection (a), the following:</text>
					<quoted-block id="H9AF3A0422743478FB15DE1A1BD5CBC7F" style="OLC">
						<subsection id="HF8DF637D2BC34CD3A42F8670FE647C45"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Correctional facilities</header>
							<paragraph id="HC89E6D2005A24DFCA38B6BF5D9091393"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header>
 <subparagraph id="H1B2EBC5AEFA2483AB7E4717479DB599E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Correctional facility</header><text>The term <term>correctional facility</term> means a jail, prison, or other detention facility used to house people who have been arrested, detained, held, or convicted by a criminal justice agency or a court.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB68EDA77933042D8B6A038EC0F2CA968"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Eligible inmate</header><text>The term <term>eligible inmate</term> means an individual who—</text> <clause id="H3804554818BA405681D828EBE7491F1B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is being held, detained, or incarcerated in a correctional facility; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1098A407B118422C8F208B57AA482766"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>manifests obvious signs of a mental illness or has been diagnosed by a qualified mental health professional as having a mental illness.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD798C6E641BF4A9C854754322BE50A26"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Correctional facility grants</header><text>The Attorney General may award grants to applicants to enhance the capabilities of a correctional facility—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE345679C4D764AA38AB0B0B430C98A53"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to identify and screen for eligible inmates;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDDD844B732394BB8BE040349AF4A0BE0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to plan and provide—</text>
 <clause id="H36FFCFE38CF14EFAACBFF3FFDC8965A9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>initial and periodic assessments of the clinical, medical, and social needs of inmates; and</text> </clause><clause id="H4AB54E654E8D4533B86B6D5C907D1EEC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>appropriate treatment and services that address the mental health and substance abuse needs of inmates;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8008997C71AF45388B70CC30CADE1543"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to develop, implement, and enhance—</text> <clause id="HE19D0ED143B744D68C3B9F20FE0E2B07"><enum>(i)</enum><text>post-release transition plans for eligible inmates that, in a comprehensive manner, coordinate health, housing, medical, employment, and other appropriate services and public benefits;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC7DDFDC98BB145C1A58AB76E13DC942A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the availability of mental health care services and substance abuse treatment services; and</text> </clause><clause id="H56F4408A2E32489CB64FC8440A748A0C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>alternatives to solitary confinement and segregated housing and mental health screening and treatment for inmates placed in solitary confinement or segregated housing; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H64133F7C916B4AB187403FCAD7ACFE5C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to train each employee of the correctional facility to identify and appropriately respond to incidents involving inmates with mental health or co-occurring mental health and substance abuse disorders.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HCBCA4908E24F4921B9DAAA5B5FFA41A9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>High utilizers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2991 of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3797aa">42 U.S.C. 3797aa</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after subsection (j), as added by subsection (b), the following:</text>
					<quoted-block id="H15513C0748364900B9A2A4F5E9889A0D" style="OLC">
						<subsection id="HDE2190C190F6449ABDB7A3D047F9AB47"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Demonstration grants responding to high utilizers</header>
 <paragraph id="HAE4273EDA633484DB147E6A87EEEE820"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>high utilizer</term> means an individual who—</text> <subparagraph id="H8DE8BCA6CDF3423C997A451AC23922C4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>manifests obvious signs of mental illness or has been diagnosed by a qualified mental health professional as having a mental illness; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5BC5EA233FCB471FA9A5A15C115D7744"><enum>(B)</enum><text>consumes a significantly disproportionate quantity of public resources, such as emergency, housing, judicial, corrections, and law enforcement services.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA85CE2409D924EA0B2756FF519BDBA2E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Demonstration grants responding to high utilizers</header>
 <subparagraph id="H765E30C67A594770AE409CF30B9B4E3B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Attorney General may award not more than 6 grants per year under this subsection to applicants for the purpose of reducing the use of public services by high utilizers.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB16B4A6E4E6642F39C0D6F5BC08CA448"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Use of grants</header><text>A recipient of a grant awarded under this subsection may use the grant—</text> <clause id="H97A7B064409B41388F72280D00B9FC1D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to develop or support multidisciplinary teams that coordinate, implement, and administer community-based crisis responses and long-term plans for high utilizers;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H38029A4BBF9F43A381D44E501BAC8D2C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to provide training on how to respond appropriately to the unique issues involving high utilizers for public service personnel, including criminal justice, mental health, substance abuse, emergency room, healthcare, law enforcement, corrections, and housing personnel;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HDEEFC44505D545CEBC004D692C1EB364"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to develop or support alternatives to hospital and jail admissions for high utilizers that provide treatment, stabilization, and other appropriate supports in the least restrictive, yet appropriate, environment; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF99BB9B83F1243DD8940A8F133485DB8"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>to develop protocols and systems among law enforcement, mental health, substance abuse, housing, corrections, and emergency medical service operations to provide coordinated assistance to high utilizers.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H694BD98D30804551B47C59564776D9E3"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than the last day of the first year following the fiscal year in which a grant is awarded under this subsection, the recipient of the grant shall submit to the Attorney General a report that—</text>
 <clause id="HA55973948A3D4684A4DCCEC1D168E61A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>measures the performance of the grant recipient in reducing the use of public services by high utilizers; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H430CB4D0A76E4FFC89F203514F584173"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provides a model set of practices, systems, or procedures that other jurisdictions can adopt to reduce the use of public services by high utilizers.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H95DE06B6D89A4BE0840AF77A72DF581D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Academy training</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2991(h) of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3797aa">42 U.S.C. 3797aa(h)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HEEE0B26B7FA74565A789086BAB7F9A41"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H691819C02C9F42E5BB7BE4247072C69C" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H742B5E78378E4167825585DCF9847DA2"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Academy training</header><text>To provide support for academy curricula, law enforcement officer orientation programs, continuing education training, and other programs that teach law enforcement personnel how to identify and respond to incidents involving individuals with mental illness or co-occurring mental illness and substance abuse disorders.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0EB86B5ECFE240D1B268948C68B38905"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H7270BE843FCB485FB59FE27D11BEBF30" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H851D94D6ACFF4CBDA21383988D0DAFFE"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Priority consideration</header><text>The Attorney General, in awarding grants under this subsection, shall give priority to programs that law enforcement personnel and members of the mental health and substance abuse professions develop and administer cooperatively.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9550F475AE8F43259C3D81EF9708B75B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Evidence-Based practices</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2991(c) of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3797aa">42 U.S.C. 3797aa(c)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HAB77A7AA69F44D88988523DE14807BC0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA4873AC9CB0E469297F3C563434BC122"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (4) as paragraph (6); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFA303CC9BB8D42FC8F77ECA98FB60609"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (3), the following:</text> <quoted-block id="HA31A849B16FF4502A797A416F117F94C" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H1B9E444685DA42BDA95CA9033A1163AE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>propose interventions that have been shown by empirical evidence to reduce recidivism;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4CFA90739C0C4445A8276172938DFFE0"><enum>(5)</enum><text>when appropriate, use validated assessment tools to target preliminarily qualified offenders with a moderate or high risk of recidivism and a need for treatment and services; or</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H50DA4E45EAC34596BAC3063C07E7726A"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Safe communities</header>
 <paragraph id="H9A124115A7DE42A59C6293CEFD229679"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2991(a) of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3797aa">42 U.S.C. 3797aa(a)</external-xref>) is amended by striking paragraph (9) and inserting the following:</text>
						<quoted-block id="HAFF089AD3B6B4BFFA35E60311AA32E9A" style="OLC">
							<paragraph id="H2F32D2F0FCE345C5B258D6CAA237EFA2"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Preliminarily qualified offender</header>
 <subparagraph id="HD3F7D2632D8E4B939494AF31354CED0B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>preliminarily qualified offender</term> means an adult or juvenile accused of an offense who—</text> <clause id="HC04BE090E763458A93FBB07D04C69FDA"><enum>(i)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HBC40C572D2064703B1F3AF50F651BA78"><enum>(I)</enum><text>previously or currently has been diagnosed by a qualified mental health professional as having a mental illness or co-occurring mental illness and substance abuse disorders;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H6B2BC56E88094A0ABE546C752C55B675" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>manifests obvious signs of mental illness or co-occurring mental illness and substance abuse disorders during arrest or confinement or before any court; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HC71DA9609816495CB2C54A9217C0EE47" indent="up1"><enum>(III)</enum><text>in the case of a veterans treatment court provided under subsection (i), has been diagnosed with, or manifests obvious signs of, mental illness or a substance abuse disorder or co-occurring mental illness and substance abuse disorder; and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HDAC73C25725D4FD6A846E9140B6170DC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has been unanimously approved for participation in a program funded under this section by, when appropriate, the relevant—</text>
 <subclause id="HE9144508A7564DABB71745A6A41C7CC3"><enum>(I)</enum><text>prosecuting attorney;</text> </subclause><subclause id="HC690974DF0CB4C439E17B801097BFBF1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>defense attorney;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H0D1A994E772C4C36B77A0DC4029543D7"><enum>(III)</enum><text>probation or corrections official;</text> </subclause><subclause id="HCE4D517E36A4493584078703E1B93259"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>judge; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H0EB968632F734272A58130FBDE8C3245"><enum>(V)</enum><text>representative from the relevant mental health agency described in subsection (b)(5)(B)(i).</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H90C8AFA7C72C49699A0CE5B7EFFF9A0A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Determination</header><text>In determining whether to designate an individual as a preliminarily qualified offender, the relevant prosecuting attorney, defense attorney, probation or corrections official, judge, and mental health or substance abuse agency representative shall take into account—</text>
 <clause id="HA25C6085F4364322806BD9CAA37393DC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>whether the participation of the individual in the program would pose a substantial risk of violence to the community;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7B87C686D17D45789603CA56B8EF6EBD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the criminal history of the individual and the nature and severity of the offense for which the individual is charged;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4F858339E6B1430E93C7F735EBD18674"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the views of any relevant victims to the offense;</text> </clause><clause id="HF731D1257DF143A9947CD10E49D4ACBC"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the extent to which the individual would benefit from participation in the program;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8A131914807743019330B8CAE6BB97E3"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the extent to which the community would realize cost savings because of the individual’s participation in the program; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H981258F605AD4A35A820C6C92B6AF257"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether the individual satisfies the eligibility criteria for program participation unanimously established by the relevant prosecuting attorney, defense attorney, probation or corrections official, judge and mental health or substance abuse agency representative.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H84E9A168357841E0B1C038C5102D901E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendment</header><text>Section 2927(2) of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3797s-6">42 U.S.C. 3797s–6(2)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>has the meaning given that term in section 2991(a).</quote> and inserting</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H89B053C5DC434D308A469501EFDC245B" style="OLC">
 <text>means an offense that—</text><subparagraph id="H12BBB711E4214048B2B7E484382070B7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>does not have as an element the use, attempted use, or threatened use of physical force against the person or property of another; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2CF09F0709CD4723B8D4C32D161D7B5B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is not a felony that by its nature involves a substantial risk that physical force against the person or property of another may be used in the course of committing the offense.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6EC5599634F84A358E7CB44B5D05A976"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Reauthorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (l) of section 2991 of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3797aa">42 U.S.C. 3797aa</external-xref>), as redesignated in subsection (a)(1), is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HDE6A4E7D32E341D7A711B222CAF56FD7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text> <subparagraph id="H93CD8C136C1046E19B7CEE862FE97073"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0A8D4E841D8640DF87BAAFA0E17B0C47"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking the period and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7F949828DAC54F988EC07A8E6F542C97"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
							<quoted-block id="H66BA7AD6CF21484DAF833E9DD4F4E06E" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H234076B4DDBB48A9B701CE012303FA28"><enum>(D)</enum><text>$40,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2016 through 2020.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB0793CF9E8B84449963801352588CCFF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
						<quoted-block id="H5362256D0F4344BBA506224E80F7BC6C" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="HD16DDB69C7544DC88E702E6F2EA1F8B5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Not more than 20 percent of the funds authorized to be appropriated under this section may be used for purposes described in subsection (i) (relating to veterans).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
					</paragraph></subsection></section></title><title id="H6863C4A6CB264E01B4E8222D2149E143"><enum>II</enum><header>Improving research on violence</header>
			<section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H489C2F193E5A452AB98C8A62E9EA6741"><enum>201.</enum><header>Research with respect to violence</header>
 <subsection id="HC0636E3C7F8146E6BAB7E2E519661FFF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services, in consultation with the Director of the National Institutes of Health, shall expand and intensify research on self-directed and other-directed violence associated with mental illness and substance abuse disorders.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF0B0809A65B84C2592AA7E260C077F7B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitations on authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To carry out subsection (a), there are authorized to be appropriated $100,000, without fiscal year limitation, which is authorized to remain available until expended.</text>
				</subsection></section></title><title id="H68C44C72EA534609842E3AACD878BA50"><enum>III</enum><header>Understanding the epidemic of gun violence</header>
 <section id="HE7A9AA3FBE254E53B5AE8B8C32A77E96" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>301.</enum><header>National violent death reporting system</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, shall improve the National Violent Death Reporting System, as authorized by title III of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/241">42 U.S.C. 241 et seq.</external-xref>), particularly through the expansion of the application of such system to include the 50 States. Participation in the system by the States shall be voluntary.</text>
			</section><section id="H887CB959A606453B93B9493F8F23CD9A"><enum>302.</enum><header>Reaffirming Centers for Disease Control’s authority</header>
 <subsection id="H89202E4973264412AD7BAF2D5C73E31A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 391 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/280b">42 U.S.C. 280b</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H12CC670F6E6840748DE79B24780D0E3C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (a)(1), by striking <quote>research relating to the causes, mechanisms, prevention, diagnosis, treatment of injuries, and rehabilitation from injuries;</quote> and inserting</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H77BBF8104C5C46198ECD622131DD3459" style="OLC">
 <text>research, including data collection, relating to—</text><subparagraph id="H3BCE245AAD5040E19920A4F751F51DF6" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the causes, mechanisms, prevention, diagnosis, and treatment of injuries, including with respect to gun violence; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF2696B45E05841F0ABC1B8CF57052386" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">rehabilitation from such injuries;</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph id="H68CAF621625949308A6AFA12D0E9A5A9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H82C712BE5DE04E39AE0F148980278903" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="HA434810376224AF48CC8838B01AF098B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>No advocacy or promotion of gun control</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed to—</text> <paragraph id="H4080AB70C080412CBBB3AF3E18286115"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">authorize the Secretary to give assistance, make grants, or enter into cooperative agreements or contracts for the purpose of advocating or promoting gun control; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H71AEEBF355DD48EA87F35D097B38627E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">permit a recipient of any assistance, grant, cooperative agreement, or contract under this section to use such assistance, grant, agreement, or contract for the purpose of advocating or promoting gun control.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD101E686497A47908754148DE94CABBB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 394A of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/280b-3">42 U.S.C. 280b–3</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>authorized to be appropriated</quote> and all that follows through the end and inserting the following: <quote>authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary for each of fiscal years 2016 through 2020.</quote>.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H9E6AAAFEEDAB40918023EF229CE18E79"><enum>303.</enum><header>Protecting confidential doctor-patient relationship</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2717(c) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg-17">42 U.S.C. 300gg–17(c)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H76789F97FF3C4DF191F7771CCD7D5C04" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H521B69A530E24E5E848503C9B741359C"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding the previous provisions of this subsection, none of the authorities provided to the Secretary under this subsection, <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/148">Public Law 111–148</external-xref>, or an amendment made by such Public Law shall be construed to prohibit a physician or other health care provider from—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8A27C5C42A7A4B06A8B261A79D9BD99C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>asking a patient about the ownership, possession, use, or storage of a firearm or ammunition in the home of such patient;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5F3F729728834EA5AFA2C9B9578F5C52"><enum>(B)</enum><text>speaking to a patient about gun safety; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H79DA7FB5C0DC4C1ABE764D7B40FDB66B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>reporting to the authorities a patient’s threat of violence.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</section></title><title id="HEB6F5703C0804403B110AE6EAFC8703C"><enum>IV</enum><header>Ensuring safe communities</header>
			<section id="HCD8720B4DAF64880960DC8C99F34B70C"><enum>401.</enum><header>Ban on firearm possession by person committed involuntarily to mental institution on an outpatient
 basis</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 922 of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="idF1134872F2184E1CAF2260812652ABAD"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (d)(4), by inserting <quote>on an involuntary inpatient or involuntary outpatient basis</quote> before the semicolon; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idD962F23322C44F2996A3C89FE05C0A95"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (g)(4), by inserting <quote>on an involuntary inpatient or involuntary outpatient basis</quote> before the semicolon.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="H767D29A554C1408394BCE8E4FA2BE781"><enum>402.</enum><header>Grant program regarding firearms</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 506(b) of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3756">42 U.S.C. 3756(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H173453E41A334A00BB734070536C85AB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by striking <quote>to 1 or more States or units of local government, for 1 or more of the purposes specified in section 501, pursuant to his determination that the same is necessary</quote> and inserting <quote>to—</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H30F4163D43904EF8993E62CD4D69B0F1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (1) and (2) as subparagraphs (A) and (B), respectively, and adjusting the margins accordingly;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idD292836E645F40C1B8C34737849915CC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting before subparagraph (A), as redesignated, the following:</text> <quoted-block id="HCB063CDFC8444EAF8F46706FAB5398E3" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H4BB950D846BB48C9ADA98A13003D3AB4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>1 or more States or units of local government, for 1 or more of the purposes specified in section 501, pursuant to his determination that the same is necessary—</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6E3B609D05C74906AA77AA1B1563FB30"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)(B), as redesignated, by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H46884891442543FD83F255B781B60502"><enum>(5)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE4D96E4231A84655AD19987BC63ACEAA" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H5F01E7841C0D4CA78D5F380632FB7B02"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">1 or more States, if that State has demonstrated, in the determination of the Attorney General, that the State has adopted policies, procedures, protocols, laws or regulations pertaining to the possession or transfer of firearms or ammunition that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HAE801B04C8C34A4B8AA7D01E4B30325E"><enum>(A)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HD33C2D9F2F434A4ABF80C4FDE074B494"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">give State and local law enforcement the authority, to the extent allowable under Federal laws and the United States Constitution, to seize firearms or ammunition from an individual pursuant to a warrant, where there is probable cause to believe that the individual in possession of such firearms or ammunition poses an elevated risk of harm to himself or herself or to another individual, which may be determined by considering whether the individual has caused harm to himself or herself or another individual, has detailed plans to cause harm to himself or herself or another individual, has a history of substance abuse, or lacks impulse control; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9F768659483D40B091DAA582D585A901" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide that not later than 14 days after such a seizure, an individual from whom a firearm or ammunition was so seized shall be given an opportunity to contest such seizure in court, and any firearm or ammunition so seized shall be returned to the individual, unless a State or local law enforcement officer demonstrates in court by a preponderance of the evidence that the individual from whom a firearm or ammunition was seized poses an elevated risk of harm to himself or herself or to another individual; or</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA081432CA8B54FEA80741307C3E38E18"><enum>(B)</enum><text>temporarily prohibit an individual who has been involuntarily hospitalized for a period of not less than 48 hours for mental illness on an emergency basis, from possessing a firearm or ammunition.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></section><section id="H2A3CE19C40294151BCD1DD950B830609"><enum>403.</enum><header>Notification of State and local law enforcement authorities of attempt to purchase firearm by
			 ineligible person</header>
 <subsection id="H37426A11A6B340569C0834B9212B8F65"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General shall establish a system for the prompt notification of the relevant State and local law enforcement agencies when the National Instant Criminal Background Check System established under section 103 of the Brady Handgun Violence Prevention Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/922">18 U.S.C. 922</external-xref> note) notifies a licensed dealer that the information available to the system indicates that the possession of a firearm by an individual attempting to obtain a firearm from the licensed dealer would violate subsection (g) or (n) of section 922 of title 18, United States Code, or State law, except when it is determined, on a case-by-case basis, that law enforcement purposes would best be served by not providing such a notice.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H845DE3E1F1784F43837DD54FC9F17B2E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the terms <term>firearm</term> and <term>licensed dealer</term> shall have the meanings given such terms in section 921(a) of title 18, United States Code.</text> </subsection></section></title><title id="H57323BA28D5A4B0EB79AF89CC9E3E2CA"><enum>V</enum><header>Restoration</header> <section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB7A95B1B77FB4D9C9BBEC78FB062430B" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>501.</enum><header>Federal agency relief program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 101(c) of the NICS Improvement Amendments Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/922">18 U.S.C. 922</external-xref> note) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HE6E813AC97164641BBB1095410DBEFCC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)(A)(i), by inserting after <quote>imposed by such subsections</quote> the following: <quote>if such person is a person described in subparagraph (C) and submits the opinion (and records and information supporting the opinion) of a psychiatrist, a clinical psychologist, or a licensed or qualified mental health professional who can provide adequate information who has personally evaluated the person</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFE805C40CDBA4253A8D4377625923188"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD9A8A09933644D1195F80848DA907B92" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H5CB9C5F05D2448D08C53B2795B560421"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Person described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person is described in this subparagraph if, beginning not earlier than 1 year after the person is subject to the disabilities imposed by subsection (d)(4) or (g)(4) of section 922 of title 18, United States Code, and after affording the Federal department or agency the opportunity to request an additional evaluation, by a psychiatrist, a clinical psychologist, or a licensed or qualified mental health professional who can provide adequate information appointed by the department or agency, the department or agency determines by a preponderance of the evidence received that—</text>
 <clause id="H82925480643A43E8AC9D50E8E04D8E41"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the person no longer manifests the symptoms of mental disorder that resulted in that person’s adjudication as ineligible due to disqualifying mental status or involuntary commitment or that otherwise significantly elevate the risk of harm to self or others;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6C6F824A8C994B0D8A20B2B9F5025B1E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the person has adhered consistently to any prescribed treatment for a substantial period of time preceding the date of the application and has expressed a willingness to continue treatment under an appropriate mental health professional;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3F57566942D64C0283B8643F890FCC3E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>if ongoing treatment is required, that adherence to that treatment is likely to minimize the risk that the person will revert to a mental state that would present a danger to self or others; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H2F56725F774E4FA79159B6D43C2BBE0C"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the granting of the relief would not be contrary to the public interest.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></section><section id="H5B445F0C5EA74F1C9F12E521B4757596"><enum>502.</enum><header>State relief programs</header> <subsection id="H0A6093A9F1E84FBB8275F91F3BD8DCA7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 105 of the NICS Improvement Amendments Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/922">18 U.S.C. 922</external-xref> note) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H9492A0DEECFD4B7684591492250D3C00"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(2), by striking <quote>if the circumstances regarding the disabilities referred to in paragraph (1), and the person's record and reputation, are such that the person will not be likely to act in a manner dangerous to public safety and that the granting of the relief would not be contrary to the public interest; and</quote> and inserting the following: <quote>beginning not earlier than 1 year after the person is first adjudicated as described in subsection (g)(4) of section 922 of title 18, United States Code, if the person submits the opinion (and records and information supporting the opinion) of a psychiatrist, a clinical psychologist, or a licensed or qualified mental health professional who can provide adequate information who has personally evaluated the person, and after affording the State the opportunity to request an additional evaluation, by a psychiatrist, clinical psychologist, or other licensed or qualified mental health professional who can provide adequate information appointed by the court, board, commission, or other lawful authority, only if the court, board, commission, or other lawful authority determines by a preponderance of the evidence received that the person is a person described in subsection (c); and</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H371B97DEAD9E4998B3BBA065069B9FB8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1F4CAEDF2E7644B8960526454BFCA164" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HE8224348B3CC4BD8BCEBAED67BEC1569"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligible person described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person described in this subsection is any person who submits with the application for relief under subsection (a)(1), the opinion (and records and information supporting the opinion) of a psychiatrist, a clinical psychologist, or a licensed or qualified mental health professional who can provide adequate information who has personally evaluated the petitioner and which attests that—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB47E2762C2A84EEBA265EB2043F5DBFB"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the person no longer manifests the symptoms of disqualifying mental status that resulted in that person’s adjudication as a mental defective or involuntary commitment;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAF5DF2B7D08D4D1596AD6F85C089C259"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the person appears to have adhered consistently to any prescribed treatment for a substantial period of time preceding the date of the application and has expressed a willingness to continue treatment under an appropriate mental health professional;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3DE08EB5E7FC4747AAD392ED118008C5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>if ongoing treatment is required, that adherence to that treatment is likely to minimize the risk that the person will revert to a mental state that would present a danger to self or others; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF0F9553A89D247EC8AE9C9F4D0CFC9E1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the granting of the relief would not be contrary to the public interest.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB7C4C03F89B544DA9F2D5B4D2BAE17DF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>The Attorney General may, by rule, define terms used in this section to ensure conformity with Federal programs providing relief from disabilities imposed under subsections (d) and (g) of section 922 of title 18, United States Code.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H988D0006D69D4783BEFAF050B9BB7C9E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Transition rule</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendment made by subsection (a) shall apply only beginning on the date that is 5 years after the date of enactment of this Act, in the case of any State that has a program described in section 105 of the NICS Improvement Amendments Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/922">18 U.S.C. 922</external-xref> note) in effect on the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="H3BEC813304034F6BA2AF21C918EB41F6"><enum>503.</enum><header>Ineligibility due to disqualifying mental status</header>
 <subsection id="id814BBE99C0DD44AC8197383A11518040"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Title 18</header><text>Part I of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="idC8614B60F94E44198D867DCE86E5455C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 175b(d)(2)(F), by striking <quote>adjudicated as a mental defective</quote> and inserting <quote>adjudicated as ineligible due to disqualifying mental status</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idBA325E8F15944B4CB5C79BB0E4AEB417"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 842—</text> <subparagraph id="id17CE8987E7C9414D8C623E83A8A5BD55"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (d)(6), by striking <quote>adjudicated as a mental defective</quote> and inserting <quote>adjudicated as ineligible due to disqualifying mental status</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id90E355C0A37349498B91F109D1D43151"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (i)(4), by striking <quote>adjudicated as a mental defective</quote> and inserting <quote>adjudicated as ineligible due to disqualifying mental status</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id3200B34D660C4D20AB7DCFE6B03FCD7B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in section 922—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idD9FFB19DE4C74309861EB1A0659DE777"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (d)(4), as amended by section 401, by striking <quote>adjudicated as a mental defective</quote> and inserting <quote>adjudicated as ineligible due to disqualifying mental status</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id08C1A52052A84BDE831154F218B02910"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (g)(4), as amended by section 401, by striking <quote>adjudicated as a mental defective</quote> and inserting <quote>adjudicated as ineligible due to disqualifying mental status</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA6C5CF511926476C9ACFB13DCEB51D4F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subsection (s)(3)(B)(iv), by striking <quote>adjudicated as a mental defective</quote> and inserting <quote>adjudicated as ineligible due to disqualifying mental status</quote>.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC579A57DF7234CB18624B421CA4A97DD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>NICS Improvement Amendments Act of 2007</header><text>The NICS Improvement Amendments Act of 2007 is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="id64CB671FB13F4720B6E5551C2E6E1C44"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 3(2), by striking <quote>adjudicated as a mental defective</quote> and inserting <quote>adjudicated as ineligible due to disqualifying mental status</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id68B8F2B92C02484094F9E6DF2DEC39DD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 101(b)(2)(C)(ii), by striking <quote>adjudicated as a mental defective</quote> and inserting <quote>adjudicated as ineligible due to disqualifying mental status</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idD6DA8E9527AC470785D5200561C63F69"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in section 101(c)(1)(C), by striking <quote>adjudicated as a mental defective</quote> and inserting <quote>adjudicated as ineligible due to disqualifying mental status</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idAF14376938584C06A7EE22EAA956343F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in section 101(c)(3)—</text> <subparagraph id="idDB4596655C13462AB48553F4A432CC64"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>adjudicate a person as a mental defective,</quote> and insert <quote>adjudicate a person as ineligible due to disqualifying mental status</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idCC0DB706F20243728603DACDFCB59D1B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>adjudicate the person as a mental defective,</quote> and insert <quote>adjudicate the person as ineligible due to disqualifying mental status</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id582C9B0F7B584CF8B468CFF36ED9B77D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in section 102(b)(1)(C)(iv), by striking <quote>adjudicated as a mental defective</quote> and inserting <quote>adjudicated as ineligible due to disqualifying mental status</quote>.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section></title><title id="H0EBDF690F792499EA6848A9F44E40D1F"><enum>VI</enum><header>Submission of Records to National Instant Criminal Background Check System</header>
 <section id="HFA080FA653BC43AEAF997FB5907E27B3"><enum>601.</enum><header>Reports relating to submission of information to NICS</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 201 of the NICS Improvement Amendments Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/922">18 U.S.C. 922</external-xref> note) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H78F65B127D5C4D459B6E9D0D9C5EA80C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by amending subsection (b) to read as follows:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDF388730646A4415A75D73AAFB3E8FBE" style="OLC">
						<subsection id="H88C135E4F0ED4B8987449C07E08AC2D1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report on persons prohibited from obtaining firearms as a result of a conviction of a misdemeanor
 crime of domestic violence</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than January 31 of each year, the Director shall submit to Congress a report containing the number of persons reported by each State to the National Instant Criminal Background Check System who are prohibited from possessing or receiving a firearm under section 922(g)(9) of title 18, United States Code.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H984D1B0B7774435A8182C6222AC099A3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (d) as (e); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H25426290C6E749ECAB210FA576404638"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (c) the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD7AC46A6A5D14F2FA619264E295FB736" style="OLC">
						<subsection id="H5964ED9825FA4F5CB22C163ADD3C0853"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report on promising practices</header>
 <paragraph id="H0F9D2879B8AE4EC9964A09E94DAD36B5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Safer Communities Act of 2015</short-title>, and annually thereafter, the Director shall submit to Congress and to each State participating in the National Criminal History Improvement Program, a report of the practices of the States that the Director considers to be promising practices.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4AB5499FA21C47958E11891085E0291E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Promising practice defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>promising practice</term> means a program, activity, or strategy of a State regarding the collection, maintenance, automation, and transmittal of information relevant to determining whether a person is prohibited from possessing or receiving a firearm by Federal or State law, by the State or any other agency, or any other records relevant to the National Instant Criminal Background Check System, that the Director determines—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H56801E22733248409ECBAE05BB2733B3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has been used by a State or other agency to successfully increase or expand its ability to collect, maintain, automate, and transmit the information described in the matter preceding this subparagraph;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H981449FCC6D04E27812583501D3D1482"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shows promise in its early stages of becoming a best practice under subsection (c), with long-term sustainable impact; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE5754805896543DE9E41C26B45BCCCB0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>may be replicated by other States or agencies.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></section><section id="H2F4D986990244F16B932FC0C7A1865A0"><enum>602.</enum><header>Reauthorization of the National Criminal History Records Improvement Program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 106(b) of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/103/159">Public Law 103–159</external-xref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/922">18 U.S.C. 922</external-xref> note) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H6E9D8820FB944295A6A1A95C7D31C0DC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>of this Act</quote> and inserting <quote>of the <short-title>Safer Communities Act of 2015</short-title></quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H12C0F09BCF3E40AE92DFD7833C69D95E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (2) and inserting the following:</text>
					<quoted-block id="HEDEF2D426D6C45A98E69EBD65D89F82A" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H9D19A6EC4C0846669C7C0ED80C45BE26"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated for grants under this subsection $100,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2016 through 2019.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H53C1B6C742DC49AD923BE66E759370EC"><enum>603.</enum><header>Improvement of metrics and incentives</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 102(b) of the NICS Improvement Amendments Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/922">18 U.S.C. 922</external-xref> note) is amended to read as follows:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H525B4FD99E4C448D899D5F9A299B0167" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="H33378FCEAF964B31932731C042FE15BA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Implementation plan</header>
 <paragraph id="H24BE8F15EACF4A9581662F5CC1815C5F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Safer Communities Act of 2015</short-title>, the Attorney General, in coordination with the States, shall establish for each State or Indian tribal government applying for a grant under section 103 a 4-year implementation plan to ensure maximum coordination and automation of the reporting of records or making records available to the National Instant Criminal Background Check System.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7F9ADEE4C9F84B47AAEAB44D3B58E675"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Benchmark requirements</header><text>Each 4-year plan established under paragraph (1) shall include annual benchmarks, including both qualitative goals and quantitative measures, to assess implementation of the 4-year plan.</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="H91A2027AF12E458EA30631B241727691"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Penalties for non-compliance</header>
 <subparagraph id="H1E7594E2FC8445A5A20BE2BEB4145773"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>During the 4-year period covered by a 4-year plan established under paragraph (1), the Attorney General shall withhold—</text>
 <clause id="H10EAFF04AAC74F5188C9971690ED6EBB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>10 percent of the amount that would otherwise be allocated to a State under section 505 of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3755">42 U.S.C. 3755</external-xref>) if the State does not meet the benchmark established under paragraph (2) for the first year in the 4-year period;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HDB9D90EB569944ABB5A0E378621564DF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>11 percent of the amount that would otherwise be allocated to a State under section 505 of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3755">42 U.S.C. 3755</external-xref>) if the State does not meet the benchmark established under paragraph (2) for the second year in the 4-year period;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HAB02980F0E234CE292C07D6E8494CD8F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>13 percent of the amount that would otherwise be allocated to a State under section 505 of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3755">42 U.S.C. 3755</external-xref>) if the State does not meet the benchmark established under paragraph (2) for the third year in the 4-year period; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H0A11F6A40CD443309C4E6DBD9E16E307"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>15 percent of the amount that would otherwise be allocated to a State under section 505 of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3755">42 U.S.C. 3755</external-xref>) if the State does not meet the benchmark established under paragraph (2) for the fourth year in the 4-year period.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA3BC5E8889B34F9F890CB3ACB076B26B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Failure to establish a plan</header><text>A State that fails to establish a plan under paragraph (1) shall be treated as having not met any benchmark established under paragraph (2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</section><section id="HFF4588394D4A443DAB35132D7BC3F42C"><enum>604.</enum><header>Grants to States to improve coordination and automation of NICS record reporting</header>
 <subsection id="H736E0D9DE5974965B6FDE1321A1A9729"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The NICS Improvement Amendments Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/922">18 U.S.C. 922</external-xref> note) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H1AB79D92D2584F1C8207743337F91EDC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking section 103 and inserting the following:</text>
						<quoted-block id="HBB1560F0B124441BAFEC78A51ADC9CDB" style="OLC">
							<section id="H2CA4425344F242429F7245BC36D2AD39"><enum>103.</enum><header>Grants to States for improvement of coordination and automation of NICS record reporting</header>
 <subsection id="HBC65C26BED0F41E8860113C35E2022EC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text>From amounts made available to carry out this section, the Attorney General shall make grants to States, Indian Tribal governments, and State court systems, in a manner consistent with the National Criminal History Improvement Program and consistent with State plans for integration, automation, and accessibility of criminal history records, for use by the State, or units of local government of the State, Indian Tribal government, or State court system to improve the automation and transmittal of mental health records and criminal history dispositions, records relevant to determining whether a person has been convicted of a misdemeanor crime of domestic violence, court orders, and mental health adjudications or commitments to Federal and State record repositories in accordance with section 102 and the National Criminal History Improvement Program.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H9C9D3BD55E1F489E96DA6262E6ABED4F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of grant amounts</header><text>Grants awarded to States, Indian Tribal governments, or State court systems under this section may only be used to—</text>
 <paragraph id="H9AA86A34CB194764BBBF62B27EDD5BA4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>carry out, as necessary, assessments of the capabilities of the courts of the State or Indian Tribal government for the automation and transmission of arrest and conviction records, court orders, and mental health adjudications or commitments to Federal and State record repositories;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8CA76268188C43DBA975B03C89FC7D57"><enum>(2)</enum><text>implement policies, systems, and procedures for the automation and transmission of arrest and conviction records, court orders, and mental health adjudications or commitments to Federal and State record repositories;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H95A6B31847644848849B161775AB565E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>create electronic systems that provide accurate and up-to-date information which is directly related to checks under the National Instant Criminal Background Check System, including court disposition and corrections records;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H867E824ECBE94A6F8B16F3A543C93A63"><enum>(4)</enum><text>assist States or Indian Tribal governments in establishing or enhancing their own capacities to perform background checks using the National Instant Criminal Background Check System; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H31493D6CD7304128A4E3AABAD7325068"><enum>(5)</enum><text>develop and maintain the relief from disabilities program in accordance with section 105.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6973A2F44FCC4000AE878B54FE54E7F8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligibility</header> <paragraph id="HC4743BD306C04B4E8579A12E1E076E2B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To be eligible for a grant under this section, a State, Indian Tribal government, or State court system shall certify, to the satisfaction of the Attorney General, that the State, Indian Tribal government, or State court system—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H9B9020B8960345B4A010ACBBB59F1B8D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is not prohibited by State law or court order from submitting mental health records to the National Instant Criminal Background Check System; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8F92223C7F134222A40EA3AA452CCE35"><enum>(B)</enum><text>subject to paragraph (2), has implemented a relief from disabilities program in accordance with section 105.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H706DB1A5F7114940BE985D6957FA12A5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Relief from disabilities program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of obtaining a grant under this section, a State, Indian Tribal government, or State court system shall not be required to meet the eligibility requirement described in paragraph (1)(B) until the date that is 2 years after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Safer Communities Act of 2015</short-title>.</text>
									</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8C724A9B88684B6C8396900F8E7C29CF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Federal share</header>
 <paragraph id="H0483B1F1BAA74D48B8939CF52306733F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Studies, assessments, non-material activities</header><text>The Federal share of a study, assessment, creation of a task force, or other non-material activity, as determined by the Attorney General, carried out with a grant under this section shall be not more than 25 percent.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0FC005220FD84E2F99BB992046961289"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Infrastructure or system development</header><text>The Federal share of an activity involving infrastructure or system development, including labor-related costs, for the purpose of improving State or Indian Tribal government record reporting to the National Instant Criminal Background Check System carried out with a grant under this section may amount to 100 percent of the cost of the activity.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H040ADE12C88C4F6D85EBBC6885F12497"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Grants to indian tribes</header><text>Up to 5 percent of the grant funding available under this section may be reserved for Indian tribal governments for use by Indian tribal judicial systems.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC0EA482E66AB428892549017D8214CEC"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $100,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2016 through 2019.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H45BCF0F34EBE4E81B29324FC9D0D7DA6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking title III; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H47ACE959218F44D7BFC2C9F45980123A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in section 401(b), by inserting after <quote>of this Act</quote> the following: <quote>and 18 months after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Safer Communities Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H583B5C9852D049AE9D3B21EC19CD8087"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendment</header><text>The table of sections in section 1(b) of the NICS Improvement Amendments Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/922">18 U.S.C. 922</external-xref> note) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="id2E769F07EADD42868574893FCA827AF1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking the item relating to section 103 and inserting the following:</text>
						<quoted-block id="H7383F295D0D344519E074BF46A57232E" style="OLC"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 103. Grants to States for improvement of coordination and automation of NICS record reporting.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idDD03EA95E9F842638F69E43A1AFF6127"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking the item relating to title III; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idA939183043D84E97A67B779B67EE5BDD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking the item relating to section 301.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H88C10C84B29E49CA88441E50C124646E"><enum>605.</enum><header>Sharing of records by Federal departments and agencies with NICS</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 101(b) of the NICS Improvement Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/922">18 U.S.C. 922</external-xref> note) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HE9280F7D83E14895A1A465DF384C09DD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H02E8953E73C34C65AA5259FD093B1442"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H719809A4F3EC4587B4C129F0A2B13DC4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0695402D826244749863B1A1AA42528A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2BF9672402514EFAA99076E2D0B16164" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="HD077013190F34FCC9715BA69DD3E2FF0"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of the Safer Communities Act of 2015, and annually thereafter, submit a report to Congress on the compliance of the heads of Federal departments and agencies with the requirements of paragraphs (1) and (3).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8EEC771846584748BDC210FD9181F939"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF0E0F52D692E4AFE95A26FBFDF36DD7C" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HC860A3C2FC954524AD7B6890CDAC5460"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Other Federal departments and agencies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of each Federal department or agency in possession of records which are relevant to a determination of whether a person is disqualified from possessing or receiving a firearm under subsection (g) or (n) of section 922 of title 18, United States Code, shall make available to the Attorney General, such records, updated not less than quarterly, for use in the background checks performed by the National Instant Criminal Background Check System.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></title></legis-body></bill>


