<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1971 IS: California Coastal National Monument Expansion Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-08-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 1971</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150805">August 5, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S223">Mrs. Boxer</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S221">Mrs. Feinstein</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To expand the boundary of the California Coastal National Monument, and for other purposes. </official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
 <section id="id76B76C130725475AAB62AC7D85CA4982" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>California Coastal National Monument Expansion Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="id08d353461f0e45c68dd88aa564cf01d5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purposes</header> <subsection id="idaf067e96c62247f6b9691d2a26c23ef3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds that—</text>
 <paragraph id="id1d74c94aab9946a3b99163af603bdcb0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Presidential Proclamation Number 7264, dated January 11, 2000 (65 Fed. Reg. 2821), designated over 20,000 islands, rocks, and pinnacles along the 1,100-mile California coastline as the California Coastal National Monument to protect the biological treasures situated offshore on thousands of unappropriated or unreserved areas of land owned or controlled by the Federal Government within 12 nautical miles of the shoreline;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ide93fd92023e14f21bead3cb4903ba5e3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Presidential Proclamation Number 9089, dated March 11, 2014 (79 Fed. Reg. 14603), expanded the boundary of the Monument to include 1,665 acres of Federal land administered by the Bureau of Land Management along the Northern California coastline in Mendocino County, commonly known as the <quote>Point Arena-Stornetta Unit</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id72675136d59d4165981bafbb058e33fc"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Point Arena-Stornetta Unit is the first onshore expansion of the Monument; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id31001255f9c44cfab5e73a6147aa2990"><enum>(4)</enum><text>numerous governmental entities, community organizations, businesses, and individuals have made significant contributions to maintain the unique character, management, and preservation of the individual parcels of Federal land along the California coast.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id9ec2e2208d7f47bda3bf880bd4f6467a"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of this Act are—</text> <paragraph id="idf68bfb04c5a74daeab8f3b8d7a0718bd"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to protect, conserve, and enhance for the benefit and enjoyment of present and future generations the nationally significant historical, natural, cultural, scientific, educational, and scenic values of the Federal land along and adjacent to the shoreline of the State of California, and for the purposes for which the Monument was designated; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id470cab0a9b504f109a86cce715f2edc6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>further to support the land management partnerships of the Bureau of Land Management with the State of California, local governments, communities, and stakeholders, and to enhance the relationships those entities have with the Bureau of Land Management and Federal land, as appropriate.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id3bb500060c82490a8a0c16848a391c9b"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="id0DA1774F7D5D47BA84F51E55EA55BEC0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Federal land</header><text>The term <term>Federal land</term> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id1d1beb1153ac467c9eb0804c1734ee66"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Federal land comprising 13 acres in Humboldt County, California, that is identified as <quote>Trinidad Head</quote> on the map;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida2b92e326a9c42cebceb9fa2f3da3fac"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Federal land comprising 440 acres in Humboldt County, California, that is identified as <quote>Lost Coast Headlands</quote> on the map;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id21B7B923C95D4681AC4B6DE04A14F16D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Federal land comprising approximately 5,780 acres in Santa Cruz County, California, that is identified as <quote>Cotoni-Coast Dairies Public Land</quote> on the map;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id46B068373D6A4EA89F549DD4B28516D1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Federal land comprising approximately 20 acres in San Luis Obispo County, California, that is identified as <quote>Piedras Blancas Light Station Outstanding Natural Area</quote> on the map; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb607a04edd0e4ed0a3c44d00154138a7"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Federal land comprising approximately 8 acres in Humboldt County, California, that is identified as <quote>Lighthouse Ranch</quote> on the map.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id07657ad5badf42d59390863573db49e5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Map</header><text>The term <term>map</term> means the Bureau of Land Management map entitled <quote>California Coastal National Monument Addition</quote> and dated July 24, 2015.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id645cb563096b44628db80573aa7b6595"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Monument</header><text>The term <term>Monument</term> means the California Coastal National Monument established by Presidential Proclamation 7264.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idfbee642a2e7241b4a640365c4d79c319"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Presidential Proclamation 7264</header><text>The term <term>Presidential Proclamation 7264</term> means Presidential Proclamation Number 7264, dated January 11, 2000 (65 Fed. Reg. 2821), creating the Monument.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id5e6ac2e6c0c04e02a15a18a34b36ba95"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Presidential Proclamation 9089</header><text>The term <term>Presidential Proclamation 9089</term> means Presidential Proclamation Number 9089, dated March 11, 2014 (79 Fed. Reg. 14603), expanding the Monument.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id21420362f12b46e787e2e338bd96b0a9"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="id3189f1ad2f7a495c95090e83888dbb06"><enum>4.</enum><header>Expansion of California Coastal National Monument</header> <subsection id="id790b092ae85a41db91d2d20665fd017f"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The boundary of the Monument is expanded to include the Federal land.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="id23bac3170cac43f49a915a93b0cbb389"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Map and legal description</header>
 <paragraph id="id5ab2ef6dbeb64042be43781c82d9331e"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As soon as practicable after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall develop a map and boundary description of the Federal land added to the Monument by this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id99c947f8e58a4f7e9622e30a007f09e2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Force and effect</header><text>The map and boundary description developed under paragraph (1) shall have the same force and effect as if included in this Act, except that the Secretary may correct any minor errors in the map and boundary descriptions.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id6a21950fbe624339b15e356903551655"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Availability of map and boundary description</header><text>The map and boundary description developed under paragraph (1) shall be on file and available for public inspection in appropriate offices of the Bureau of Land Management.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id2768bd92c2fd4d04bf317fda74de19a9"><enum>5.</enum><header>Administration</header>
 <subsection id="ided36991dc80648629e7f5de2910dc066"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights and deed restrictions in place as of the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall manage the Federal land added to the Monument by this Act—</text>
 <paragraph id="id4f06b02a3e794a84925dbdb2d7d552b8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>as part of the Monument; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id0d2c2421cc20406b891bc48abd4f9645"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in accordance with Presidential Proclamations 7264 and 9089.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idb6f79c635d564356aabf52bf7834dbbf"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Management plan</header>
 <paragraph id="idcca3f092b1534be2a0732522a61cd974"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As soon as practicable after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall finalize an amendment, or multiple amendments as applicable for the individual Federal land areas, to the Monument management plan for the long-term protection and management of the Federal land added to the Monument by this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ida69e43fa45e14bf2b9ca954bca3e8774"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The plan amendment under paragraph (1) shall—</text> <subparagraph id="idfc9b2fb4f2584d0bbdd308504af82078"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be developed in consultation with, at a minimum—</text>
 <clause id="id000087BBAE30454BB41647195A106C60"><enum>(i)</enum><text>affected State, tribal, and local governments;</text> </clause><clause id="idE96868BB48674F6F9CD5C8F2075C066D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the public; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id17168B765DFF450FBB0E614727B34105"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>interested Federal agencies;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8541f0167f7642a9bba1adefd3b55c63"><enum>(B)</enum><text>describe the appropriate uses and management of the Federal land, consistent with this Act;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id08b159ae2b3744a69f00f9f3114b1b24"><enum>(C)</enum><text>contain individual plans and considerations specific to each individual Federal land area;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA5070AFD401C4389B831C9925E1DDDE3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>take into consideration existing uses of the Federal land;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id938600038e2740f49a547825c1c3d7fc"><enum>(E)</enum><text>include components regarding stewardship, visitor services, facilities management and maintenance, public access, traffic, public safety, emergency services, and law enforcement;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7e7b1d03b7e54bd4bd8c9f10d4eb09d0"><enum>(F)</enum><text>include a component regarding potential education and interpretation activities, with recognition of the specific character and history of each Federal land area; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7f5f939a71594422b0ffa334b274e9d3"><enum>(G)</enum><text>include a component regarding Native American cultural resources management, with emphasis on the preservation of resources within the individual Federal land areas.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1f38da9df3e549e3a64f8300483a86c9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Interim management</header><text>During the period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act and ending on the date of completion of the management plan, the Secretary shall manage the Federal land in accordance with the purposes described in section 2(b).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id347ee5820b4b4edfa77e51c45c49a92a"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Motorized and mechanized transport</header><text>Except as needed for emergency or authorized administrative purposes, in the Monument—</text> <paragraph id="idF9ADD05E6D5A4AE092681518CC7BC1E1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>motorized vehicle use shall be permitted only on designated roads; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id29AD7F807FD4487FA2C1DC82AF39361D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>mechanized vehicle use shall be permitted only on roads and trails designated for the use of those vehicles.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5f5ff6f629474da7832c0b894bdb1b51"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Incorporation of land and interests</header>
 <paragraph id="idef410fe0126542278aab6e08edbe6638"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authority</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (3), the Secretary may acquire non-Federal land or interests in land within or adjacent to the Federal land added to the Monument by this Act only through exchange, donation, or purchase from a willing seller.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idd26d31f2ae6f4fd68801566c94c8f9f1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Management</header><text>Any land or interests in land within or adjacent to the Federal land added to the Monument by this Act acquired by the United States after the date of enactment of this Act shall be—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id1EB1C480847B4D148EC35F43DD512724"><enum>(A)</enum><text>added to and administered as part of the Monument; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8780690572b94533890d37505f1cebaf"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to inclusion in the management plan, taken into consideration through an appropriate amendment to that plan.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id80c46c792ea248f49fa7dfb913c0095a"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>An addition to the Cotoni-Coast Dairies unit of Federal land referred to in section 3(1)(C) shall be limited to the acreage contained within the boundary of the Monument, as established by this Act.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id9e21ce6719a940599a4446a0f257e108"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Existing cooperative management agreements</header><text>Any cooperative management agreement in existence on the date of enactment of this Act between the Federal land areas and other land management entities shall not be affected due to the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id1eb1bfa6cff24cba9b854c622f0bafe2"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Cooperative agreements with local governments and entities</header><text>To better implement the management plan and to continue the successful partnerships with local communities and land administered by the State of California and other partners, the Secretary may enter into cooperative agreements with the appropriate Federal, State, and local agencies and organizations pursuant to section 307(b) of the <act-name parsable-cite="FLPMA">Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1737">43 U.S.C. 1737(b)</external-xref>).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id7b446f2621f449089926a44af9ead54d"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Withdrawals</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, all Federal land within the Monument and all land and interests in land acquired for the Monument by the United States after the date of the enactment of this Act are withdrawn from—</text>
 <paragraph id="id03ffbde70696446cac09ba8ce16c8074"><enum>(1)</enum><text>all forms of entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id0a6a47f59e254d88a9b9f82a74e0144b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="iddd8e6b8dda62499ebb423d333670c7c9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>operation of the mineral leasing, mineral materials, and geothermal leasing laws.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id7bde3b74b5f0493bab1948c6e00437e8"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Native American uses and interests</header> <paragraph id="id9677F1BC50EB4C6C8E011302D831FFB6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall, to the maximum extent permitted by law and in consultation with affected Indian tribes, ensure the protection of Indian sacred sites and traditional cultural properties in the Monument and provide access by members of Indian tribes for traditional cultural and customary uses, consistent with <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/95/341">Public Law 95–341</external-xref> (commonly known as the <quote>American Indian Religious Freedom Act</quote>) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1996">42 U.S.C. 1996</external-xref>) and Executive Order 13007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1996">42 U.S.C. 1996</external-xref> note; relating to Indian sacred sites).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id2D2F019D2C984F9AB825AABDB678FF85"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Relationship to other rights</header><text>Notwithstanding paragraph (1), nothing in this Act enlarges, diminishes, or modifies the rights of any Indian tribe or Indian religious community.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ide95b09f6bef34982bd25c324096cbc16"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Buffer zones</header>
 <paragraph id="id51e02dee2b174cdd94e0282f2b858ab2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The expansion of the Monument by this Act is not intended to lead to the establishment of protective perimeters or buffer zones around the Federal land included in the Monument by this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id6fb005650b82495aa023da6b1a9bc5a5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Activities outside Monument</header><text>The fact that activities outside the Monument can be seen or heard within the Federal land added to the Monument by this Act shall not, of itself, preclude those activities or uses up to the boundary of the Monument.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id3eb23f0aa5aa43abbf5c5627abc91c44"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Grazing</header><text>Nothing in this Act affects the grazing of livestock within the Federal land described in section 3(1)(C).</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide87613bdd424498a939e36eabb970b4c"><enum>(k)</enum><header>National Landscape Conservation System</header><text>The Secretary shall manage the Monument as part of the National Landscape Conservation System.</text> </subsection></section><section id="id401dca881e3248c6b143a02c9b5689ef"><enum>6.</enum><header>Advisory councils</header> <subsection id="id400c8a637172436c9ea5ce7062ce99c3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not less than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall establish an advisory council for each unit of Federal land described in subparagraphs (A) through (E) of section 3(1) within the Monument.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id41ba14ed6d73405da88371e5e71fd069"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The advisory councils shall advise the Secretary with respect to the preparation and implementation of the management plan under section 5(b) (or amendments to an existing applicable management plan) for each relevant unit of Federal land.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id1509c86b0324455e99c28c3edb6dbf24"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applicable law</header><text>The advisory councils shall be subject to—</text> <paragraph id="idb90f0895bf2343efbf1a8d52c33129cd"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id2a4301766cc245cfa035df7eae36a8ce"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1701">43 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idd6a797661e074a339d6726b37e7b5bf8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>all other applicable laws (including regulations).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0c589f819c4f4b48a08adbbeb10a24b9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Members</header><text>Each advisory council shall include 7 members, to be appointed by the Secretary, of whom, to the maximum extent practicable—</text>
 <paragraph id="id7e3187790ad84b4e9de1cb43c6f97755"><enum>(1)</enum><text>1 shall be appointed after taking into consideration the recommendations of the local county board of supervisors of the applicable unit of Federal land; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id3f253f313bc646adb2739906db33ffd3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>6 shall—</text> <subparagraph id="id15281C3840E64BBBB16A6B73EF33C490"><enum>(A)</enum><text>reside within a reasonable proximity to the applicable unit of Federal land; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE1E3516F22314804A651465341BB2B85"><enum>(B)</enum><text>demonstrate experience that reflects—</text> <clause id="idc53519eb35be4cb7bea1996eeb6d3788"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the purposes for which the Monument was established; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id96a019f3496c4ab9afe5bd4d57d10f12"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the interest of the stakeholders that are affected by the planning and management of the unit of Federal land, which may include stakeholders representing private land-ownership, Native American interests, environmental, recreational, economic, or other non-Federal land interests.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idd8b8ad5a51154c1692b8e3a506095c6d"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Representation</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that the memberships of the advisory councils are fairly balanced with respect to the points of view represented, and the functions to be performed, by each advisory council.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="id734780f734ab4c8ea8e55214a3ebf9a9"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Quorum</header>
 <paragraph id="id297BDAF4D6814B49B0FBAB729E60CB6B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>4 members of an advisory council shall constitute a quorum.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id6718D4460664499CBB426534E6666435"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Unappointed members</header><text>The operation of an advisory committee shall not be affected if—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id9D26CC099669477A8E119B436619BCE3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a member has not yet been appointed to the advisory committee; but</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9A05E01762EF45588ED5818BEA17E454"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a quorum has been attained.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id06e85344371e4754a13e5a91c3a1fd9e"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Chairperson and procedures</header><text>Each advisory council shall—</text> <paragraph id="id1D43F31513A04CAD8E20C9B69D0D88BE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>elect a chairperson from among the members of the advisory council; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idB66E583062964964A5E9FBC74FA9502A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>establish such rules and procedures as the advisory council determines to be necessary or appropriate.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ida83f0d0c61c948e495c364d9c9e8bf73"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Service without compensation</header><text>The members of each advisory council shall serve without pay.</text> </subsection><subsection id="id0ea402abebe44cc6a5ef9288e4a7517f"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The advisory councils shall terminate—</text>
 <paragraph id="idc2b0a3c5f2f542dc9a925d6d34aa18de"><enum>(1)</enum><text>on the date that is 2 years after the date on which the management plan (or amendment to an existing management plan) is officially adopted by the Secretary; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id2abe8df316ab4f9490994f4e19ce6034"><enum>(2)</enum><text>on such later date as the Secretary considers to be appropriate.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idb3bcd2479f8344a09aa90cca7ef56479"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Existing advisory bodies</header><text>The Secretary may elect not to establish an advisory council for a unit of Federal land if a regularly scheduled, organized public forum or entity exists—</text>
 <paragraph id="id29DE96DAD3284468A61DB4A3A5318212"><enum>(1)</enum><text>of which the Bureau of Land Management is an active or leading participant; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id6845DE58188E4098BB6332862977C22B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>that fulfills the duties described in subsection (b).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ide5449357f52d48d4af726e79c0b55c23"><enum>7.</enum><header>Rocks and small islands along coast of Orange County, California</header>
 <subsection id="idf0832f48476046c4a677b207d802c233"><enum>(a)</enum><header>California Coastal National Monument</header><text>The Act of February 18, 1931 (46 Stat. 1172, chapter 226), is amended by striking <quote>be, and the same are hereby, temporarily reserved</quote> and all that follows through <quote>United States</quote> and inserting <quote>are part of the California Coastal National Monument and shall be administered as part of the Monument</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="ide225b65c9b194807b34578826ebedb92"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Repeal of reservation</header><text>Section 31 of the Act of May 28, 1935 (49 Stat. 309, chapter 155), is repealed.</text></subsection></section></legis-body> </bill> 

