<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1253 IS: Patient Access to Disposable Medical Technology Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1253</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150507">May 7, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S300">Mr. Burr</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide coverage of certain disposable medical
			 technologies under the Medicare program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HAFBEDC80FF354D3B889773327B91470B" style="OLC">
 <section id="id1B8D06C1ABB946208DE361DCAFC052DE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Patient Access to Disposable Medical Technology Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="id20FDFFD7AA3546B498F89BF608C74DC6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Coverage of certain disposable medical technologies under the Medicare program</header> <subsection id="H6C2B56A85FB2429E90793A1A6996BD14"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Coverage</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1861 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="id7E714F0AFDB94111B78F336B759FA31B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (n)—</text> <subparagraph id="idb50056a4747e4a6184a3e51761e248ff"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>substitute disposable medical technologies (as defined in subsection (iii)) and services and supplies used in conjunction with such technologies,</quote> after <quote>hospital beds,</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id02078B32F7594EBFBBC6E8A8FC733765"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>(unless such equipment is a substitute disposable medical technology or a service or supply used in conjunction with such a technology)</quote> after <quote>rental basis</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAAE893D5693F4F268562F7295C25766B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
 <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5117724E54A64D77A1A619559684C9BD" other-style="archaic" style="other"><subsection id="H398A57ABCC3044C686570A08682A8774"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Substitute disposable medical technology</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>substitute disposable medical technology</quote> means medical equipment that—</text> <paragraph id="HB967ECA86E4D49DE99B056F439F4CFAE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is primarily and customarily used to serve a medical purpose;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF270143719B044E4A9AC22001413D65D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">would otherwise be covered as durable medical equipment under this title but for the fact that such equipment is not durable (as defined by the Secretary for purposes of coverage of durable medical equipment under this title); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6575C5857C974209874232118AEF37B4"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary determines substitutes for durable medical equipment.</text> </paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">In making the determination under paragraph (3), the Secretary shall consult with medical specialty societies, medical device manufacturers, patient groups, and other stakeholders as part of the annual rulemaking process for durable medical equipment under this title.</continuation-text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB7A8CAA89C5F40BC861856DB5D0306E7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Payment provisions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1834(a) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395m">42 U.S.C. 1395m(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0D36B469A9304833943968D9551082E0" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="HADD8F5870B8649D3B4A9887F5412BB36"><enum>(23)</enum><header>Special payment rule for substitute disposable medical technologies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding the preceding provisions of this subsection, the Secretary shall determine the payment amount under this subsection for a substitute disposable medical technology (as defined in section 1861(iii)), and for any related supplies and service fees incurred in conjunction with the use and maintenance of such technology, in accordance with the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H32CB4BE57F4B42E5B1FE66CDA2DA4C17"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Single payment amount</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall determine a single payment amount that shall be paid for a substitute disposable medical technology and for any related supplies and service fees incurred in conjunction with the use and maintenance of such technology. A payment for such a technology and for any such related supplies and service fees made in the amount of such single payment amount shall constitute full payment under this title for such technology and such related supplies and service fees.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCB7D01558D5B476B9658DF02D123B283"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Calculation of payment amount</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The single payment amount described in subparagraph (A) for a substitute disposable medical technology and for any related supplies and service fees incurred in conjunction with the use and maintenance of such technology shall be calculated by—</text>
 <clause id="H2AB4F0BC86634966B8FC1981A25D6882"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">calculating the sum of the amounts of payment that otherwise would be made under this section for—</text> <subclause id="H71EBDCEBE30042CABE8185236C7E8638"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the item of durable medical equipment for which the Secretary determines, pursuant to section 1861(iii)(3), that such substitute disposable medical technology substitutes; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HE17769B1D9054D7391EC5EDFF42D6895"><enum>(II)</enum><text>all related supplies and service fees incurred in conjunction with the use and maintenance of such item of durable medical equipment;</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H3A2192BD3E6B4CFDA37747C92DE718B1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>calculating the amount that is 95 percent of the sum calculated under clause (i); and</text> </clause><clause id="H3D58D6908C434CE6874FF3E03D22DA58"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">calculating the single payment amount for the substitute disposable medical technology and for any related supplies and service fees incurred in conjunction with the use and maintenance of such technology such that the sum of the payments under this subsection for—</text>
 <subclause id="H625CCFB48083468F8A59890EB398A3E6"><enum>(I)</enum><text>all substitute disposable medical technologies that the Secretary determines, pursuant to section 1861(iii)(3), will be necessary to provide a substitute for the item of durable medical equipment described in clause (i)(I); and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H86C248DA93754A0C9EAC3E57433E4F7C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any related supplies and service fees incurred in conjunction with the use and maintenance of such technologies,</text>
								</subclause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="clause">and is equal to the amount calculated under clause (ii). In making such calculation, the Secretary
			 shall consult with medical specialty societies, medical device
			 manufacturers,
			 patient groups, and other stakeholders to ensure that an appropriate
			 comparison is made that captures use of the various technologies
			 (including related supplies, if any) over an average course of therapy for
 a typical patient.</continuation-text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H55D465CCFD43423E987F2498175B4F16"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Lump-sum payment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The single payment amount described in subparagraph (A) for a substitute disposable medical technology and for any related supplies and service fees incurred in conjunction with the use and maintenance of such technology shall be made in a lump-sum amount.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idae804c3cf5e24df8af7d71200db0a7e9"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Payment for physicians' and hospital outpatient department services</header><text>Nothing in this paragraph should be construed as limiting or changing payment for items or services for which payment is made under section 1848 or section 1833(t).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H581FB4554CD14F1E93CD3CC27AF38CE2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1847(a)(7)(B) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-3">42 U.S.C. 1395w–3(a)(7)(B)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HCE345DEECC144CF2952BD02D444678AB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in clause (i), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4549A6BB66E74AF2A785CC70AC5174AA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD20499704355417AB09D1B5F02EADCC5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new clause:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H58A6B083D3A1406F865194AD31A285DA" style="OLC">
 <clause id="H9EECF490F8D2410DA072B459CDB5CE8A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that are substitute disposable medical technologies (as defined in section 1861(iii)).</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H262D3DDBA64949DE9D6A5B04E0702EDA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The provisions of, and amendments made by, this section shall apply with respect to items and services furnished on or after January 1, 2016.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="idae7514581688447c8773a972f6f2eccf"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Rule of construction; implementation</header>
 <paragraph id="idf6203c4f8865490fa28812bcda7f3ca7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section or the amendments made by this section shall be construed as—</text> <subparagraph id="id75f2460b74044262856c37a89a9bf1e0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>affecting the ability of a physician (or any other prescribing practitioner) to exercise their judgment in prescribing or ordering for a Medicare beneficiary appropriate durable medical equipment or other medical device or technology for the treatment of an illness, injury, or condition of the Medicare beneficiary; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id09a3bb5741fd4dc7a8b28b84aeda10da"><enum>(B)</enum><text>affecting the ability of the Medicare beneficiary to access appropriate durable medical equipment or other appropriate medical device or technology for such treatment.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idfccfce84fd1c469aa0901f7a40f63d42"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>The Secretary shall implement the provisions of, and amendments made by, this section in a manner such that the methodologies for determining coverage of an item of durable medical equipment (as defined in section 1861(n) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x(n)</external-xref>)) (other than such an item that is a substitute disposable medical technology (as defined in section 1861(iii))) and the payment amount for the item of durable medical equipment (other than such an item that is a substitute disposable medical technology (as so defined)) under section 1834 or 1847 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395m">42 U.S.C. 1395m</external-xref>, 1395w–3), as the case may be, is not affected by the coverage of and payment amount for a substitute disposable medical technology under sections 1861(iii) and 1834(a)(23) of such Act, respectively, as added by subsections (a) and (b), respectively.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


