<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S352 IS: Equitable Access to Care and Health Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 352</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150203">February 3, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S340">Ms. Ayotte</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S353">Mr. Schatz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S354">Ms. Baldwin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S342">Mr. Blunt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S307">Mr. Brown</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S372">Mrs. Capito</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S252">Ms. Collins</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S339">Mr. Kirk</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S347">Mr. Moran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S349">Mr. Portman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S260">Mr. Roberts</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S323">Mr. Risch</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/5000A">section 5000A</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide an additional religious
			 exemption from the individual health coverage mandate, and for other
 purposes. </official-title></form><legis-body id="HC68F9FE0BE924BFEA1629BE104E605F5" style="OLC"><section id="HD7D11C1E28484CCBB0845F97C758BA93" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Equitable Access to Care and Health Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>EACH Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HB2879EA8B710424E89C7B5C06A04587D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Additional religious exemption from health coverage responsibility requirement</header><subsection id="H0249C151AB304AD6BEEBB7767B309837"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subparagraph (A) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/5000A">section 5000A(d)(2)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H851A8B22E8EB4475BC21F04D762431B6" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="H189E8A673400489B8684342A6959236D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Religious conscience exemptions</header><clause id="H4DF07D5BDB064BB7B4C29BCA05105FE4"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Such term shall not include any individual for any month if such individual has in effect an exemption under section 1311(d)(4)(H) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act which certifies that—</text><subclause id="H676D506526A24AA9BE1FD3B79285F427"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such individual is a member of a recognized religious sect or division thereof which is described in section 1402(g)(1), and is adherent of established tenets or teachings of such sect or division as described in such section, or</text></subclause><subclause id="HA46B585B92A141F9B742169A2BAD39E5"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such individual is a member of a religious sect or division thereof which is not described in section 1402(g)(1), who relies solely on a religious method of healing, and for whom the acceptance of medical health services would be inconsistent with the religious beliefs of the individual.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HC0E77B79A896406992FCDEE8DB4532F6"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Special rules</header><subclause id="HD9BA69F7C5B148D980F2CC22E145F1D7"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Medical health services defined</header><text>For purposes of this subparagraph, the term <term>medical health services</term> does not include routine dental, vision, and hearing services, midwifery services, vaccinations, necessary medical services provided to children, services required by law or by a third party, and such other services as the Secretary of Health and Human Services may provide in implementing section 1311(d)(4)(H) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act.</text></subclause><subclause id="HF56A953EF01A49F0A274A45AEDFB5C9F"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Attestation required</header><text>This clause shall apply to an individual for months in a taxable year only if the information provided by the individual under section 1411(b)(5)(A) of such Act includes an attestation that the individual has not received medical health services during the preceding taxable year.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H5697C4FE16CB4FF0BA57412A29489853"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (a) shall take effect as if included in the amendments made by section 1501 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H9965D906B2604FE6A76C27694F8544E2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Construction</header><text>Nothing in the amendment made by subsection (a) shall preempt any State law requiring the provision of medical treatment for children, especially those who are seriously ill.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


