<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S234 IS: Regulatory Fairness Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 234</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150122">January 22, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S299">Mr. Vitter</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S338">Mr. Manchin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S352">Mr. Heller</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S174">Mr. McConnell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S254">Mr. Enzi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S323">Mr. Risch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S266">Mr. Crapo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S317">Mr. Barrasso</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S379">Mr. Perdue</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEV00">Committee on Environment and Public Works</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to confirm the scope of the authority of the
			 Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to deny or restrict
 the use of defined areas as disposal sites.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="idA134E06E618D4251AD1276AA6BD59D6A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Regulatory Fairness Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id163556216394468A896C537481B44B14" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Permits for dredged or
 fill material</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 404 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1344">33 U.S.C. 1344</external-xref>) is amended by striking subsection (c) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1D948C160AA14B5C94442D28D1C43670" style="OLC"><subsection id="idAD38B739406540D88CB66C9FC46088C2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Denial or
 restriction of use of specified disposal sites</header><paragraph id="idcce65c4152f9487791e1c15c16258fbb"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>During and only during the period beginning on the date on which the Secretary publishes the notice required under subsection (a) of this section and ending once the Secretary issues a permit under such subsection, the Administrator may deny or restrict the use of any defined area identified in such notice as a specified disposal site if the Administrator determines, after notice and opportunity for public comment, that the discharge of dredged or fill material into such defined area will have an unacceptable adverse effect on municipal water supplies, shellfish beds and fishery areas (including spawning and breeding areas), wildlife, or recreational areas.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb2e87441b2ad427d999fe4f8bf9ccf27"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>Before making a determination under paragraph (1), the Administrator shall consult with the Secretary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2cb25518ecdc453a82a6430d9481ef4a"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Explanation of determination</header><text>The Administrator shall set forth in writing and make publicly available—</text><subparagraph id="ide03c8f1d4e864f749662e8925aee5bd1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any findings of the Administrator;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida0255ded7b464438865690f9257ffc3a"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the basis of and reasons for making a determination under paragraph (1); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4b350bb4ced14d4fb78ff18c3918e110"><enum>(C)</enum><text>all information and data reviewed in making any determination under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id267414e1446b4632be0d2950106bf323"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Previous action in absence of notice invalid</header><text>No previous action by the Administrator to deny or restrict the use or prohibit the specification of any defined area as a disposal site, and which occurred in the absence of the Secretary’s publishing of a notice under subsection (a) of this section, is valid or otherwise enforceable.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2ab51f3f899448bfab9d6b7ce45d89b2"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Previous action after permit issued invalid</header><text>No previous action by the Administrator to deny or restrict the use or prohibit the specification of any defined area as a disposal site and for which the Secretary had issued a permit under subsection (a) of this section, and which occurred after the Secretary issued the permit, is valid or otherwise enforceable.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill>


