<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S2123 IS: Sentencing Reform and Corrections Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-10-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 2123</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151001">October 1, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S153">Mr. Grassley</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S287">Mr. Cornyn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S346">Mr. Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S270">Mr. Schumer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S293">Mr. Graham</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S057">Mr. Leahy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S365">Mr. Scott</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To reform sentencing laws and correctional institutions, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header>
			<subsection id="id5AFBAFFCB31F417CAAD00A7A037938B2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Sentencing Reform and Corrections Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id8EF1002D25BF4B2CB8D701D18752A5B4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text><toc><toc-entry idref="S1" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id21bc764ee3704dfea2d342154e6ae655" level="title">TITLE I—Sentencing Reform</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id935c29ef25dc408aaab8ff307cb7f028" level="section">Sec. 101. Reduce and restrict enhanced sentencing for prior drug felonies.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id1d11d4de0c0b418eb2ba842f9158b550" level="section">Sec. 102. Broadening of existing safety valve.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id4a8fec6fd0cf4896b3b744f8f3e78218" level="section">Sec. 103. Limitation on application of the 10-year mandatory minimum.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id8aacf504b8c64f799ad8fe5180d5144e" level="section">Sec. 104. Clarification of section 924(<enum-in-header>c</enum-in-header>) of title 18, United States Code.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id7c8c6f979ae34f2cbca20b7d152c2f76" level="section">Sec. 105. Amendment to certain penalties for certain firearm offenses and armed career criminal provision.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="idc37a89cc72414a9d9af3eae6c6e17bda" level="section">Sec. 106. Application of Fair Sentencing Act.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="idee39b00d0e7a4fa79c132c1d1c6a1cdd" level="section">Sec. 107. Mandatory minimum sentences for domestic violence offenses.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id9b636f87654c43dfbe82745acc4a1f91" level="section">Sec. 108. Minimum term of imprisonment for certain acts relating to the provision of controlled goods or services to terrorists or proliferators of weapons of mass destruction.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id38D594CD407246D9910A08EA071E2D30" level="section">Sec. 109. Inventory of Federal criminal offenses.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="idf35b597f690d4a20a4436dd26a6d8608" level="title">TITLE II—Corrections Act</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="idaefa3e4e468f442ba8b510e7f8e7f292" level="section">Sec. 201. Short title.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="idf17a662507474501b6c7069a88631b44" level="section">Sec. 202. Recidivism reduction programming and productive activities.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id12146796f6f04bd28cc33b972bc455c7" level="section">Sec. 203. Post-sentencing risk and needs assessment system.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="idf182c46e12d147d4a852bd27a7e423cc" level="section">Sec. 204. Prerelease custody.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="idcdbf22be303448328da92206f346efe1" level="section">Sec. 205. Reports.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id367b9c21ffb2476aa993aaf7761bb45a" level="section">Sec. 206. Additional tools to promote recovery and prevent drug and alcohol abuse and dependence.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id119763415ce548d489a248ccfce1f8ca" level="section">Sec. 207. Eric Williams Correctional Officer Protection Act.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id76f1c9370821413fb76fbf3e8d7badd1" level="section">Sec. 208. Promoting successful reentry.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id584f1324e7d5439c9711f6877bfa5858" level="section">Sec. 209. Parole for juveniles.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id4220392EC9F54C85870927817BCE88B3" level="section">Sec. 210. Compassionate release initiative.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="idf4523b8c8bdb422d907527c0f6544028" level="section">Sec. 211. Juvenile sealing and expungement.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="idd22ff1ce4ee14b5b807cd87ffe80d7f6" level="section">Sec. 212. Juvenile solitary confinement.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="id2835f8c17d2246909313eee422804cc2" level="section">Sec. 213. Ensuring accuracy of Federal criminal records.</toc-entry> </toc> </subsection></section><title id="id21bc764ee3704dfea2d342154e6ae655"><enum>I</enum><header>Sentencing Reform</header> <section id="id935c29ef25dc408aaab8ff307cb7f028"><enum>101.</enum><header>Reduce and restrict enhanced sentencing for prior drug felonies</header> <subsection id="id96aae012919c4b1684b3861a334e5f7d"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Controlled substances act amendments</header><text>The Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/801">21 U.S.C. 801 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="idf541e6fa26ed4f4a8a99c59d3536b45c"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 102 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/802">21 U.S.C. 802</external-xref>), by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5cfdafdb0b2d41b5b12bb000d5a4c112" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="id7682048d3d194cb5832997a247ecbe3f"><enum>(57)</enum><text>The term <term>serious drug felony</term> means an offense described in section 924(e)(2)(A) of title 18, United States Code, for which the offender served a term of imprisonment of more than 12 months.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idc7fe36e26f654f09a6dd4bd885a04004"><enum>(58)</enum><text>The term <term>serious violent felony</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="iddd8a27810db34de59f21519ab90d73f7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an offense described in section 3559(c)(2)(F) of title 18, United States Code, for which the offender served a term of imprisonment of more than 12 months; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcfb2296dc6f049b794ab64e21df7dfed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any offense that would be a felony violation of section 113 of title 18, United States Code, if the offense were committed in the special maritime and territorial jurisdiction of the United States, for which the offender served a term of imprisonment of more than 12 months.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idbbd08250420944bdb07a05b86d841f7a"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 401(b)(1) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/841">21 U.S.C. 841(b)(1)</external-xref>)—</text> <subparagraph id="idd5ae14ba39e042cbb87933f886533766"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), in the flush text following clause (viii)—</text>
 <clause id="id0236eb8c37664230911ce8addd2c73c4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>If any person commits such a violation after a prior conviction for a felony drug offense has become final, such person shall be sentenced to a term of imprisonment which may not be less than 20 years</quote> and inserting the following: <quote>If any person commits such a violation after a prior conviction for a serious drug felony or serious violent felony has become final, such person shall be sentenced to a term of imprisonment of not less than 15 years</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idd4272abd00dc4621ac20eceada15d089"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>after two or more prior convictions for a felony drug offense have become final, such person shall be sentenced to a mandatory term of life imprisonment without release</quote> and inserting the following: <quote>after 2 or more prior convictions for a serious drug felony or serious violent felony have become final, such person shall be sentenced to a term of imprisonment of not less than 25 years</quote>; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id63a42a1c19234a349d6dcc3251149787"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), in the flush text following clause (viii), by striking <quote>If any person commits such a violation after a prior conviction for a felony drug offense has become final</quote> and inserting the following: <quote>If any person commits such a violation after a prior conviction for a serious drug felony or serious violent felony has become final</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id291f898d6c9a45b0a39ef59390da6370"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Controlled substances Import and Export Act amendments</header><text>Section 1010(b) of the Controlled Substances Import and Export Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/960">21 U.S.C. 960(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="id8957d024060f486489633416f7715542"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), in the flush text following subparagraph (H), by striking <quote>If any person commits such a violation after a prior conviction for a felony drug offense has become final, such person shall be sentenced to a term of imprisonment of not less than 20 years</quote> and inserting <quote>If any person commits such a violation after a prior conviction for a serious drug felony or serious violent felony has become final, such person shall be sentenced to a term of imprisonment of not less than 15 years</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ida85ee7c126fd43bd9a6ba4e5129a759a"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), in the flush text following subparagraph (H), by striking <quote>felony drug offense</quote> and inserting <quote>serious drug felony or serious violent felony</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id97b0604da8cc4d07a237a1cdc9b948de"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applicability to pending and past cases</header> <paragraph id="id674874d4f26948e8ada42fee23e208b4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Pending cases</header><text>This section, and the amendments made by this section, shall apply to any offense that was committed before the date of enactment of this Act, if a sentence for the offense has not been imposed as of such date of enactment.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id096658883b5b454589e83841a8aadc8f"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Past cases</header><text>In the case of a defendant who, before the date of enactment of this Act, was convicted of an offense for which the penalty is amended by this section and was sentenced to a term of imprisonment for the offense, the sentencing court may, on motion of the defendant or the Director of the Bureau of Prisons, or on its own motion, upon prior notice to the Government, reduce the term of imprisonment for the offense, after considering the factors set forth in section 3553(a) of title 18, United States Code, the nature and seriousness of the danger to any person or the community, and the post-sentencing conduct of the defendant, if such a reduction is consistent with this section and the amendments made by this section.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id1d11d4de0c0b418eb2ba842f9158b550"><enum>102.</enum><header>Broadening of existing safety valve</header>
 <subsection id="idc60cee12192845e9b879954d501e3a7c"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Amendments</header><text>Section 3553 of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="idc2226ec49a374a029cafe6089aee7c31"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (f), by striking paragraph (1) and inserting the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb2226a526d5449e193da55e01ba1cd61" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="id20522fc253fd4dc6a142bce4c11f9f1e"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the defendant does not have—</text> <subparagraph id="id8280abbe44a6493c865ff711d5471d24"><enum>(A)</enum><text>more than 4 criminal history points as determined under the sentencing guidelines;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida71a5fbdccf34a04bd45297eca374a93"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a prior 3-point offense, as determined under the sentencing guidelines; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id917fe26c0e5e4306a34dcb2c35410cb0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a prior 2-point drug trafficking or violent offense, as determined under the sentencing guidelines;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id421bad0663fa48629dd67a90c1bb54f9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd45f61645770419fbdc7930802dd1ed8" style="OLC"> <subsection id="idcde1cd4e3e494f79a98dbdbca2396c8c"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Inadequacy of criminal history</header> <paragraph id="id66a255170dc14c6abfe16e6a8da6ad53"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If subsection (f) does not apply to a defendant because the defendant does not meet the requirements described in subsection (f)(1) (relating to criminal history), the court may, upon prior notice to the Government, waive subsection (f)(1) if the court specifies in writing the specific reasons why reliable information indicates that excluding the defendant pursuant to subsection (f)(1) substantially overrepresents the seriousness of the defendant’s criminal history or the likelihood that the defendant will commit other crimes.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idfce73f597c2b46ef97e1fb7a4e1a7521"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>This subsection shall not apply to any defendant who has been convicted of a serious drug felony or a serious violent felony as defined in paragraphs (57) and (58), respectively, of section 102 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/802">21 U.S.C. 802</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id7624ba844575496180a4239e41618c06"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>As used in this section—</text> <paragraph id="idf7390d8f675849a587fe053a211927c8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>drug trafficking offense</term> means an offense that is punishable by imprisonment under any law of the United States, or of a State or foreign country, that prohibits or restricts the importation, manufacture, or distribution of controlled substances or the possession of controlled substances with intent to distribute; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id575b1520add044e1a8a9c7fd05f43457"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>violent offense</term> means a <term>crime of violence</term>, as defined in section 16, that is punishable by imprisonment.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id779edd58c4304a6da72a445bd174a13b"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply only to a conviction entered on or after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="id4a8fec6fd0cf4896b3b744f8f3e78218"><enum>103.</enum><header>Limitation on application of the 10-year mandatory minimum</header>
 <subsection id="id052c9f2e98f94d14998935895cddc73a"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Amendment</header><text>Section 3553 of title 18, United States Code, as amended by section 102, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idAF57D89501F14B888BB8706B1CBFE2CF" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="ida32f0870177d4141b4d1e7fefa6a3827"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Limitation on applicability of certain statutory minimums</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, in the case of a conviction under section 401 or 406 of the Controlled Substances Act (21 U.S.C. 841 and 846) or section 1010 or 1013 of the Controlled Substances Import and Export Act (21 U.S.C. 960 and 963) for which the statutory minimum term of imprisonment is 10 years, the court may impose a sentence as if the statutory minimum term of imprisonment was 5 years, if the court finds at sentencing, after the Government has been afforded the opportunity to make a recommendation, that—</text>
 <paragraph id="id90e6bb94463b491492a64fce31aaea38"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the defendant does not have a prior conviction for a serious drug felony or serious violent felony as defined in paragraphs (57) and (58), respectively, of section 102 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/802">21 U.S.C. 802</external-xref>) that was made final prior to the commission of the instant offense;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id2d941eded68e452cbb2fd85823f6d613"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the defendant did not use violence or credible threats of violence or possess a firearm or other dangerous weapon (or induce another participant to do so) in connection with the offense, and the offense did not result in death or serious bodily injury to any person;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idabd1ec8cc0a64699a4fbc5c3544b98cb"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the defendant did not play an enhanced role in the offense by acting as an organizer, leader, manager, or supervisor of other participants in the offense, as determined under the sentencing guidelines, or by exercising substantial authority or control over the criminal activity of a criminal organization, regardless of whether the defendant was a member of such organization;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idbdf3237f33b444be84c5d49f8bc49c7c"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the defendant did not act as an importer, exporter, high-level distributor or supplier, wholesaler, or manufacturer of the controlled substances involved in the offense or engage in a continuing criminal enterprise, as defined in section 408 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/848">21 U.S.C. 848</external-xref>);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idd1e61bf73a874b2a81581178361ae952"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the defendant did not distribute a controlled substance to or with a person under 18 years of age; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id8694d1de4f4c4b03b57767cfaaaa558d"><enum>(6)</enum><text>not later than the time of the sentencing hearing, the defendant has truthfully provided to the Government all information and evidence the defendant has concerning the offense or offenses that were part of the same course of conduct or of a common scheme or plan, but the fact that the defendant has no relevant or useful other information to provide or that the Government is already aware of the information shall not preclude a determination by the court that the defendant has complied with this requirement.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idf0d6fb48c0374e19b52d6bd349b5d9c5"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>As used in subsection (i) of this section—</text> <paragraph id="id210c6d98579841b1811e9f68122c727d"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>importer, exporter, or high-level distributor or supplier</term>—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id7176D8B0908F406DBC3AD79F5ACAFB7A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means a defendant who imported, exported, or otherwise distributed or supplied large quantities of a controlled substance to other drug distributors; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id14F0C78C1AD6432B9AAD6CF8B46700E8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include a defendant whose role was limited to transporting drugs or money at the direction of others;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idE52D16D718984808B9C74E815A3C82CC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>manufacturer</term> means a defendant who grew, produced, or manufactured a controlled substance and was the principal owner of such controlled substance; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id8019bc639eaf4c81be768f77ec0a33ee"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>wholesaler</term> means a defendant who sold non-retail quantities of a controlled substance to other dealers or distributors.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="id6954390aee894062af839132124c946f"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>The amendment made by this section shall apply only to a conviction entered on or after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="id8aacf504b8c64f799ad8fe5180d5144e"><enum>104.</enum><header>Clarification of section 924(<enum-in-header>c</enum-in-header>) of title 18, United States Code</header>
 <subsection id="id7009282f780d4c9197b8d8b8ff3d9b9f"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 924(c)(1)(C) of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="ide0252378e6ad49d4a07190d8b90c3812"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the matter preceding clause (i), by striking <quote>second or subsequent conviction under this subsection</quote> and inserting <quote>violation of this subsection that occurs after a prior conviction under this subsection or under State law for a crime of violence that contains as an element of the offense the carrying, brandishing, or use of a firearm has become final</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idd38385da6ccb4e7f9f00c11941b3c53a"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in clause (i), by striking <quote>not less than 25 years</quote> and inserting <quote>not less than 15 years</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idfbfd9091ff3a4f568b9be13bf89773e6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicability to pending and past cases</header> <paragraph id="idfc4ffec6b99c41408de074ce76119ada"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Pending cases</header><text>This section, and the amendments made by this section, shall apply to any offense that was committed before the date of enactment of this Act, if a sentence for the offense has not been imposed as of such date of enactment.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idcfc6ee7ebba74b34a468b91546fdb81f"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Past cases</header><text>In the case of a defendant who, before the date of enactment of this Act, was convicted of an offense for which the penalty is amended by this section and was sentenced to a term of imprisonment for the offense, the sentencing court may, on motion of the defendant or the Director of the Bureau of Prisons, or on its own motion, upon prior notice to the Government, reduce the term of imprisonment for the offense, after considering the factors set forth in section 3553(a) of title 18, United States Code, the nature and seriousness of the danger to any person or the community, and the post-sentencing conduct of the defendant, if such a reduction is consistent with this section and the amendments made by this section.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id7c8c6f979ae34f2cbca20b7d152c2f76"><enum>105.</enum><header>Amendment to certain penalties for certain firearm offenses and armed career criminal provision</header>
 <subsection id="id7039c4c314414b048532221bb88c5036"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Amendments</header><text>Section 924 of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="id7ebdc80ec50e462da0305f12a398b351"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(2), by striking <quote>not more than 10 years</quote> and inserting <quote>not more than 15 years</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id9e90e9dd9d80460795641a8741a2369a"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (e)(1), by striking <quote>not less than 15 years</quote> and inserting <quote>not less than 10 years</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ida9f878b1fb5a4158bf255b4b59cf2e89"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicability to pending and past cases</header> <paragraph id="ideda5f8fb4a08470fb31fd7716d8bb00b"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Pending cases</header><text>This section, and the amendments made by this section, shall apply to any offense that was committed before the date of enactment of this Act, if a sentence for the offense has not been imposed as of such date of enactment.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idffb75cd1ef12476ba0e32f98e1d20d81"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Past cases</header><text>In the case of a defendant who, before the date of enactment of this Act, was convicted of an offense for which the penalty is amended by this section and was sentenced to a term of imprisonment for the offense, the sentencing court may, on motion of the defendant or the Director of the Bureau of Prisons, or on its own motion, upon prior notice to the Government, reduce the term of imprisonment for the offense, after considering the factors set forth in section 3553(a) of title 18, United States Code, the nature and seriousness of the danger to any person or the community, and the post-sentencing conduct of the defendant, if such a reduction is consistent with this section and the amendments made by this section.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idc37a89cc72414a9d9af3eae6c6e17bda"><enum>106.</enum><header>Application of Fair Sentencing Act</header>
 <subsection id="id8fa227ac0e404aeba0d11a4038e90e57"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition of covered offense</header><text>In this section, the term <term>covered offense</term> means a violation of a Federal criminal statute, the statutory penalties for which were modified by section 2 or 3 of the Fair Sentencing Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/220">Public Law 111–220</external-xref>; 124 Stat. 2372), that was committed before August 3, 2010.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="ida7c8b679cf5a49b3b0137bb3e5b0a49a"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Defendants previously sentenced</header><text>A court that imposed a sentence for a covered offense, may, on motion of the defendant, the Director of the Bureau of Prisons, the attorney for the Government, or the court, impose a reduced sentence as if sections 2 and 3 of the Fair Sentencing Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/220">Public Law 111–220</external-xref>; 124 Stat. 2372) were in effect at the time the covered offense was committed.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id25c56227907d4751a1eef688c58f124b"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Limitations</header><text>No court shall entertain a motion made under this section to reduce a sentence if the sentence was previously imposed or previously reduced in accordance with the amendments made by sections 2 and 3 of the Fair Sentencing Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/220">Public Law 111–220</external-xref>; 124 Stat. 2372) or if a motion made under this section to reduce the sentence was previously denied. Nothing in this section shall be construed to require a court to reduce any sentence pursuant to this section.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="idee39b00d0e7a4fa79c132c1d1c6a1cdd"><enum>107.</enum><header>Mandatory minimum sentences for domestic violence offenses</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2261(b) of title 18, United States Code, is amended by striking paragraphs (1), (2), and (3) and inserting the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id04e532f17b044fc7accc2ce0f0d425ba" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="id428baecc843b401ebbb16ef9328e5b34"><enum>(1)</enum><text>if death of the victim results—</text> <subparagraph id="id136a7945084b4cc9a382364c19370936"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of a violation of this section, for any term of years not less than 10 or for life; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd44ead85b02a4b919084b4d421e2303c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of a violation of section 2261A, for life or any term of years;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idff989fe452fe4868b04d0a4045f1a009"><enum>(2)</enum><text>if permanent disfigurement or life threatening bodily injury to the victim results—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idf8faeb1f64b84648b20ef09d231dbe87"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of a violation of this section, for not more than 25 years; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida9dee79f07cc4c72b98fd55073ca50f2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of a violation of section 2261A, for not more than 20 years;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id6509313617c0476ab8e6cb086c0417a8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>if serious bodily injury to the victim results or if the offender uses a dangerous weapon during the offense—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idbb5eba49373f47b58ddbf077ea51504c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of a violation of this section, for not more than 15 years; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd59f13ab48294d9c83dfb8e87f622ed9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of a violation of section 2261A, for not more than 10 years;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</section><section id="id9b636f87654c43dfbe82745acc4a1f91"><enum>108.</enum><header>Minimum term of imprisonment for certain acts relating to the provision of controlled goods or
 services to terrorists or proliferators of weapons of mass destruction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 206 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1705">50 U.S.C. 1705</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="idcfd6f0e987fe47cd811447338433be92"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (c), by striking <quote>A person</quote> and inserting <quote>Subject to subsection (d), a person</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id244384dc527449bebb1f9e38da7564b7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf312fe38ddde452c914f61fdca04349b" style="OLC"> <subsection id="id295d03c7e1884d9a989b2477256c8907"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Minimum term of imprisonment for certain acts relating to the provision of controlled goods or services to terrorists or proliferators of weapons of mass destruction</header> <paragraph id="id4a11b5288ba24fdbbee16e74cf98f71a"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A person who willfully commits, willfully attempts to commit, or willfully conspires to commit, solicits the commission of, or aids or abets in the commission of, an unlawful act described in paragraph (2) shall, upon conviction, be imprisoned for a term of not less than 5 years. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a court shall not place on probation any person sentenced under this subsection.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id13b6fa40e03e48d5b441978bcda95330"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Unlawful acts described</header><text>An unlawful act described in this paragraph is an unlawful act described in subsection (a) that involves—</text>
 <subparagraph id="iddb2a20adec184533bbfe3a5b7980c16f"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the provision of controlled goods or services to or for the use of—</text> <clause id="id0b3aed159ed34ec0803f6980f5df0461"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a state sponsor of terrorism;</text>
 </clause><clause id="ide2d22ec504be4c9b91b665fb30ce7929"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an organization designated as a foreign terrorist organization under section 219(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1189">8 U.S.C. 1189(a)</external-xref>); or</text>
 </clause><clause id="ida1087402e6794940a570e1f5dc07d7ca"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a person on the list of specially designated nationals and blocked persons maintained by the Office of Foreign Assets Control of the Department of the Treasury;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0de264667fe149e5ba2f4479d458f6e6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the provision of goods or services, without a license or other written approval of the United States Government, to any person in connection with a program or effort of a foreign country or foreign person to develop weapons of mass destruction; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc46c4936e92744178d0f992acd509a5e"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the provision of defense articles or defense services, without a license or other written approval of the Department of State, to, or for the use of, a country subject to an arms embargo by the United States.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id3ba1dda16daa4aa5974bd49a548ca00f"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text> <subparagraph id="id7a53c45328f64360a9f0d451fad64595"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Controlled goods or services</header><text>The term <term>controlled goods or services</term> means any article, item, technical data, service, or technology listed or included in—</text>
 <clause id="id98f55de6ac854799807af37f8931eda4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the United States Munitions List maintained pursuant to part 121 of title 22, Code of Federal Regulations;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id67196aec91ba4dafb547442d0526a934"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Commerce Control List maintained pursuant to part 774 of title 15, Code of Federal Regulations; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="idfa06ed42c9894748a23f337b7645174f"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any successor to the United States Munitions List or the Commerce Control List.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id890eca8367414765b5d983025a5d3c1d"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Country subject to an arms embargo</header><text>The term <term>country subject to an arms embargo</term> means any foreign country listed in section 126.1 of title 22, Code of Federal Regulations (or any corresponding similar regulation or ruling), for which—</text>
 <clause id="idf6ebe620eb454414a8b04e28dc300e0d"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an embargo or prohibition exists on the export of defense articles or defense services; or</text> </clause><clause id="iddb08a42a5ae748758254ca383f38bf94"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the policy of the United States is to deny licenses and other approvals for the export of defense articles and defense services.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd1b57ac2073d4bcfbead32d7f8dc2d05"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Defense article; defense service</header><text>The terms <quote>defense article</quote> and <quote>defense service</quote> have the meanings given those terms in section 47 of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2794">22 U.S.C. 2794</external-xref>).</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ideb74a32e36d04b25adcf4aa9fec0136b"><enum>(D)</enum><header>State sponsor of terrorism</header><text>The term <term>state sponsor of terrorism</term> means any foreign country, or political subdivision, agency, or instrumentality of a foreign country, if the Secretary of State has determined that the government of the country has repeatedly provided support for acts of international terrorism pursuant to—</text>
 <clause id="id38706fc729d04c5c9379e0bc8cc6e2e5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>section 6(j)(1)(A) of the Export Administration Act of 1979 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc-appendix" parsable-cite="usc-appendix/50/2405">50 U.S.C. App. 2405(j)(1)(A)</external-xref>) (as in effect pursuant to this Act);</text>
 </clause><clause id="id1793a89df22a4ee4b381045cbd5a9f2c"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>section 40(d) of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2780">22 U.S.C. 2780(d)</external-xref>);</text> </clause><clause id="id024b067c8e1c4701a3d1e3f3cc146b57"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>section 620A(a) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2371">22 U.S.C. 2371(a)</external-xref>); or</text>
 </clause><clause id="idec5dc22e152549c495f3781334528a52"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>any other provision of law.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf2fa73c9ef2e45edabe1fc71a655bb36"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Weapon of mass destruction</header><text>The term <term>weapon of mass destruction</term> has the meaning given that term in section 2332a of title 18, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></section><section id="id38D594CD407246D9910A08EA071E2D30"><enum>109.</enum><header>Inventory of Federal criminal offenses</header>
 <subsection id="id4CA56E26AC0B4BC681E1029D4830BEC8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text> <paragraph id="id307FFE8424C94798B252F7E0E31A26BB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>criminal regulatory offense</term> means a Federal regulation that is enforceable by a criminal penalty; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idB1A6B2759A874D4B9368CD076D52644B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>criminal statutory offense</term> means a criminal offense under a Federal statute.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id214041F9C25B4779BFA347E7CB6B0F69"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report on criminal statutory offenses</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall submit to the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives a report, which shall include—</text>
 <paragraph id="id11EB397AD2F34DDA940D7A23F263769E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a list of all criminal statutory offenses, including a list of the elements for each criminal statutory offense; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id87B6126150324846BA896F70BA24D89E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for each criminal statutory offense listed under paragraph (1)—</text> <subparagraph id="id3DF0980BAEBB4FDC82D92E4E9A234F8F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the potential criminal penalty for the criminal statutory offense;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id51ED1A38A4624B3490AECDD4DE047904"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of prosecutions for the criminal statutory offense brought by the Department of Justice each year for the 15-year period preceding the date of enactment of this Act; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE69429613F2E402FAD1B96368583612C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the mens rea requirement for the criminal statutory offense.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id057BC290B586418BBDFBBFE685B34DFA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report on criminal regulatory offenses</header> <paragraph id="idFEFB37C5092F4E6E9589FF072CBFCF07"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Reports</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the head of each Federal agency described in paragraph (2) shall submit to the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives a report, which shall include—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id23F2ED10A11A4341BFB02D7C692E4ABB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a list of all criminal regulatory offenses enforceable by the agency; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA90DDB1EBB614B1B839940489F2CBD11"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for each criminal regulatory offense listed under subparagraph (A)—</text>
 <clause id="id5F55E282816149F0A872F66EBD512BCF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the potential criminal penalty for a violation of the criminal regulatory offense;</text> </clause><clause id="id6CF3425D53274B16B4924CF213F1E749"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the number of violations of the criminal regulatory offense referred to the Department of Justice for prosecution in each of the years during the 15-year period preceding the date of enactment of this Act; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id32EB79275A4D40F59F95C5E56A9E516F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the mens rea requirement for the criminal regulatory offense.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idD7284D07CA2E49D69CE5D872DDA2BE64"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Agencies described</header><text>The Federal agencies described in this paragraph are the Department of Agriculture, the Department of Commerce, the Department of Education, the Department of Energy, the Department of Health and Human Services, the Department of Homeland Security, the Department of Housing and Urban Development, the Department of the Interior, the Department of Labor, the Department of Transportation, the Department of the Treasury, the Commodity Futures Trading Commission, the Consumer Product Safety Commission, the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, the Export-Import Bank of the United States, the Farm Credit Administration, the Federal Communications Commission, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, the Federal Election Commission, the Federal Labor Relations Authority, the Federal Maritime Commission, the Federal Mine Safety and Health Review Commission, the Federal Trade Commission, the National Labor Relations Board, the National Transportation Safety Board, the Nuclear Regulatory Commission, the Occupational Safety and Health Review Commission, the Office of Compliance, the Postal Regulatory Commission, the Securities and Exchange Commission, the Securities Investor Protection Corporation, the Environmental Protection Agency, the Small Business Administration, the Federal Housing Finance Agency, and the Office of Government Ethics.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idE5DFD580173D42589A1E7CFD7E506234"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Index</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act—</text> <paragraph id="id9A76736D16F04659809F10DE5BE8322A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Attorney General shall establish a publically accessible index of each criminal statutory offense listed in the report required under subsection (b) and make the index available and freely accessible on the website of the Department of Justice; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id2CE1346801B14B3DAAE21B6CBB8B223A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the head of each agency described in subsection (c)(2) shall establish a publically accessible index of each criminal regulatory offense listed in the report required under subsection (c)(1) and make the index available and freely accessible on the website of the agency.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id30835691041646EBB6798DFEF0F685AE"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to require or authorize appropriations.</text> </subsection></section></title><title id="idf35b597f690d4a20a4436dd26a6d8608"><enum>II</enum><header>Corrections Act</header> <section id="idaefa3e4e468f442ba8b510e7f8e7f292"><enum>201.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This title may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Corrections Oversight, Recidivism Reduction, and Eliminating Costs for Taxpayers In Our National System Act of 2015</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>CORRECTIONS Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
			</section><section id="idf17a662507474501b6c7069a88631b44"><enum>202.</enum><header>Recidivism reduction programming and productive activities</header>
 <subsection id="id119641ca9f594c16b1ba105e0c2fa5b2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall—</text> <paragraph id="idaaea59092de04402bf773330006fbe89"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct a review of recidivism reduction programming and productive activities, including prison jobs, offered in correctional institutions, including programming and activities offered in State correctional institutions, which shall include a review of research on the effectiveness of such programs;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="iddf4c061c85c64a61924d002dc008a0ef"><enum>(2)</enum><text>conduct a survey to identify products, including products purchased by Federal agencies, that are currently manufactured overseas and could be manufactured by prisoners participating in a prison work program without reducing job opportunities for other workers in the United States; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id8672a7e72db341c6997a355447a0e748"><enum>(3)</enum><text>submit to the Committee on the Judiciary and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate and the Committee on the Judiciary and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives a strategic plan for the expansion of recidivism reduction programming and productive activities, including prison jobs, in Bureau of Prisons facilities required by section 3621(h)(1) of title 18, United States Code, as added by subsection (b).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id3f64ebb4dbd044d2bf96d78c1c97026a"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Amendment</header><text>Section 3621 of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8fa582354a88408ba85c65b6be794deb" style="OLC"> <subsection id="id829149e52d3b4060ad4f4e48dd290e30"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Recidivism reduction programming and productive activities</header> <paragraph id="id01d02c77e656425091e1c0c803a2e32b"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director of the Bureau of Prisons, shall, subject to the availability of appropriations, make available to all eligible prisoners appropriate recidivism reduction programming or productive activities, including prison jobs, in accordance with paragraph (2).</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="id5bc0c33c8c3b413c84dc837a59a26e5e"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Expansion period</header>
 <subparagraph id="id3f0c7ad9cc1343ecba42c5eb02caf6d7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In carrying out this subsection, the Director of the Bureau of Prisons shall have 6 years beginning on the date of enactment of this subsection to ensure appropriate recidivism reduction programming and productive activities, including prison jobs, are available for all eligible prisoners.</text>
								</subparagraph><subparagraph id="id92e3043a8c384effb31d921f060fe208"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Certification</header>
 <clause id="idaf3105028e81417e9f41e7a7e6f7f536"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The National Institute of Corrections shall evaluate all recidivism reduction programming or productive activities that are made available to eligible prisoners and determine whether such programming or activities may be certified as evidence-based and effective at reducing or mitigating offender risk and recidivism.</text>
 </clause><clause id="id3f2e942dc84541d194867fc36b1abc19"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In determining whether or not to issue a certification under clause (i), the National Institute of Corrections shall consult with internal or external program evaluation experts, including the Office of Management and Budget and the Comptroller General of the United States to identify appropriate evaluation methodologies for each type of program offered, and may use analyses of similar programs conducted in other correctional settings.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ida2b649991e5a44d3870e545bb8885c79"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Recidivism reduction partnerships</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this subsection, the Attorney General shall issue regulations requiring the official in charge of each correctional facility to ensure, subject to the availability of appropriations, that appropriate recidivism reduction programming and productive activities, including prison jobs, are available for all eligible prisoners within the time period specified in paragraph (2), by entering into partnerships with the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="id2482997020f84acf855af03edd94cc71"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Nonprofit and other private organizations, including faith-based and community-based organizations, that provide recidivism reduction programming, on a paid or volunteer basis.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idad56ce2a57ac48a48b839c13ae026486"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Educational institutions that will deliver academic classes in Bureau of Prisons facilities, on a paid or volunteer basis.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbf3f08b054414206939f485af1dc8512"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Private entities that will, on a volunteer basis—</text> <clause id="idbf47073b6b384551a144ce74f38b99e4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>deliver occupational and vocational training and certifications in Bureau of Prisons facilities;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idb447f4cbbe754047b4173d38c119f283"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provide equipment to facilitate occupational and vocational training or employment opportunities for prisoners;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id7edf072901c142d1aea4e02bed544a52"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>employ prisoners; or</text> </clause><clause id="id9f5cf792cf954a71b4ae0182cd030fb2"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>assist prisoners in prerelease custody or supervised release in finding employment.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4917bd4d18cd44629680cf5411a72f8f"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Industry-sponsored organizations that deliver workforce development and training that lead to recognized certification and employment.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id6c2734e39f504e0fa367762c09a72a42"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Assignments</header><text>In assigning prisoners to recidivism reduction programming and productive activities, the Director of the Bureau of Prisons shall use the Post-Sentencing Risk and Needs Assessment System described in section 3621A and shall ensure that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idaad383011e2a4873998e0589ce45b5a9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to the extent practicable, prisoners are separated from prisoners of other risk classifications in accordance with best practices for effective recidivism reduction;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id71880ca510674f68928c71ee19b8abe3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a prisoner who has been classified as low risk and without need for recidivism reduction programming shall participate in and successfully complete productive activities, including prison jobs, in order to maintain a low-risk classification;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8f4979a8762042f399babfc1e5ad372c"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a prisoner who has successfully completed all recidivism reduction programming to which the prisoner was assigned shall participate in productive activities, including a prison job; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id40923043260d4ee281b269908b4ec0d4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to the extent practicable, each eligible prisoner shall participate in and successfully complete recidivism reduction programming or productive activities, including prison jobs, throughout the entire term of incarceration of the prisoner.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id377c2f27e2bb465dbf91b005503a31db"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Mentoring services</header><text>Any person who provided mentoring services to a prisoner while the prisoner was in a penal or correctional facility of the Bureau of Prisons shall be permitted to continue such services after the prisoner has been transferred into prerelease custody, unless the person in charge of the penal or correctional facility of the Bureau of Prisons demonstrates, in a written document submitted to the person, that such services would be a significant security risk to the prisoner, persons who provide such services, or any other person.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id595aafc68cd346deb52c6a4f4bdc7989"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Recidivism reduction program incentives and rewards</header><text>Prisoners who have successfully completed recidivism reduction programs and productive activities shall be eligible for the following:</text>
								<subparagraph id="id912e2146b37b4221bd20045eb6dbad37"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Time credits</header>
 <clause id="id59f8dafa9a224ad8bc34a02f90eb9ca5"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to clauses (ii) and (iii), a prisoner who has successfully completed a recidivism reduction program or productive activity that has been certified under paragraph (2)(B) shall receive time credits of 5 days for each period of 30 days of successful completion of such program or activity. A prisoner who is classified as low risk shall receive additional time credits of 5 days for each period of 30 days of successful completion of such program or activity.</text>
 </clause><clause id="idcd207dbe402e4ef2b00b12441b47bdfa"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>A prisoner may not receive time credits under this subparagraph for successfully completing a recidivism reduction program or productive activity—</text>
 <subclause id="id2fd8adcee9584c57937fe8f098e72c4c"><enum>(I)</enum><text>before the date of enactment of this subsection; or</text> </subclause><subclause id="idec8a10adda1e486e9fc29f56f0a18248"><enum>(II)</enum><text>during official detention before the date on which the prisoner’s sentence commences under section 3585(a).</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="id98a4ee9337cf41eb8156ac33da9b5412"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Exclusions</header><text>No credit shall be awarded under this subparagraph to a prisoner serving a sentence for a second or subsequent conviction for a Federal offense imposed after the date on which the prisoner’s first such conviction became final, which shall not include any offense under section 1152 or section 1153 for which the prisoner was sentenced to less than 13 months. No credit shall be awarded under this subparagraph to a prisoner with 13 or more criminal history points, as determined under the sentencing guidelines, at the time of sentencing, unless the court determines in writing at sentencing that the defendant’s criminal history category substantially overrepresents the seriousness of the defendant’s criminal history or the likelihood that the defendant will commit other crimes. No credit shall be awarded under this subparagraph to any prisoner serving a sentence of imprisonment for conviction for any of the following offenses:</text>
 <subclause id="ide3f5e706b2c942ecbdeb8c691d07af75"><enum>(I)</enum><text>A Federal crime of terrorism, as defined under section 2332b(g)(5).</text> </subclause><subclause id="ide3a3e9f401344f7782455a59c3e07155"><enum>(II)</enum><text>A Federal crime of violence, as defined under section 16.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id04aeeeef550445fa805585e21fa74133"><enum>(III)</enum><text>A Federal sex offense, as described in section 111 of the Sex Offender Registration and Notification Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/16911">42 U.S.C. 16911</external-xref>).</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id941ddc944c484202adb216f9823f8ee2"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>Engaging in a continuing criminal enterprise, as defined in section 408 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/848">21 U.S.C. 848</external-xref>).</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id64c1ae8d3141424a8ea62cc0cb4cfaa5"><enum>(V)</enum><text>A Federal fraud offense for which the prisoner received a sentence of imprisonment of more than 15 years.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id93baa02572234c64a486427763620f30"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>A Federal crime involving child exploitation, as defined in section 2 of the PROTECT Our Children Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/17601">42 U.S.C. 17601</external-xref>).</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id6cff5041da7942de89a3ed212ffce9f7"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>A violation of—</text> <item id="idaee2ea16a0e44b02b47742764d998c98"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>chapter 11 (relating to bribery, graft, and conflicts of interest);</text>
 </item><item id="id84ba092d381d4d848d67c4ab66923e0f"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>chapter 29 (relating to elections and political activities);</text> </item><item id="id9aabd2d5ba5e4339994ca380d5d34ce9"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>section 1028A, 1031, or 1040 (relating to fraud);</text>
 </item><item id="idc692dbb193044444a1e065683363fd2a"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>chapter 63 involving a scheme or artifice to deprive another of the intangible right of honest services;</text>
 </item><item id="idebe18b101274427b95fcb8a0bf0e39d7"><enum>(ee)</enum><text>chapter 73 (relating to obstruction of justice);</text> </item><item id="id5037cc63d4dd4c1bad9363f91bcdc51a"><enum>(ff)</enum><text>chapter 95 or 96 (relating to racketeering and racketeer influenced and corrupt organizations); or</text>
 </item><item id="idf9979211c19c4405bc8631c00c131225"><enum>(gg)</enum><text>chapter 110 (relating to sexual exploitation and other abuse of children).</text> </item></subclause></clause><clause id="id98eb5867526d4f03b153a9b5630869b0"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Identification of covered offenses</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this subsection, the United States Sentencing Commission shall prepare and submit to the Director of the Bureau of Prisons a list of all Federal offenses described in subclauses (I) through (VII) of clause (iii), and shall update such list on an annual basis.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2bfd994b51d146da9cac8d661e3e43a9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Other incentives</header><text>The Bureau of Prisons shall develop policies to provide appropriate incentives for successful completion of recidivism reduction programming and productive activities, other than time credit pursuant to subparagraph (A), including incentives for prisoners who are precluded from earning credit under subparagraph (A)(iii). Such incentives may include additional telephone or visitation privileges for use with family, close friends, mentors, and religious leaders.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id070de2602fd64ffcbe1886d52b50c559"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>The Bureau of Prisons may reduce rewards a prisoner has previously earned under subparagraph (A) for prisoners who violate the rules of the penal or correctional facility in which the prisoner is imprisoned, a recidivism reduction program, or a productive activity.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbca78bd75b084729b173ce566c5e385a"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Relation to other incentive programs</header><text>The incentives described in this paragraph shall be in addition to any other rewards or incentives for which a prisoner may be eligible, except that a prisoner shall not be eligible for the time credits described in subparagraph (A) if the prisoner has accrued time credits under another provision of law based solely upon participation in, or successful completion of, such program.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id3288476d3c2b46d6a0d67bae6de9f55b"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Successful completion</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, a prisoner—</text> <subparagraph id="id31e6644b89824c10870db8225be9c94e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall be considered to have successfully completed a recidivism reduction program or productive activity, if the Bureau of Prisons determines that the prisoner—</text>
 <clause id="idf54ec2a442414c4d869cc6dfa9cd53fb"><enum>(i)</enum><text>regularly attended and participated in the recidivism reduction program or productive activity;</text> </clause><clause id="id2b457c9262ac46569aaa6c2e151cdc5f"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>regularly completed assignments or tasks in a manner that allowed the prisoner to realize the criminogenic benefits of the recidivism reduction program or productive activity;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id285571cfeae64e38be8ae9959d7b5586"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>did not regularly engage in disruptive behavior that seriously undermined the administration of the recidivism reduction program or productive activity; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id2ab915e5327d45e38d8456770ee6ccac"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>satisfied the requirements of clauses (i) through (iii) for a time period that is not less than 30 days and allowed the prisoner to realize the criminogenic benefits of the recidivism reduction program or productive activity; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2c244e11b12b401789ce633fcd9f084a"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for purposes of paragraph (6)(A), may be given credit for successful completion of a recidivism reduction program or productive activity for the time period during which the prisoner participated in such program or activity if the prisoner satisfied the requirements of subparagraph (A) during such time period, notwithstanding that the prisoner continues to participate in such program or activity.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id6efc5dfe994d45d2b9ffbe7f565902aa"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text> <subparagraph id="id80afbd933d5e476ba23dce2b43a3ea28"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Eligible prisoner</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>eligible prisoner</term>—</text>
 <clause id="id0ebe6ec2927b46f99ec6ea7b570f5223"><enum>(i)</enum><text>means a prisoner serving a sentence of incarceration for conviction of a Federal offense; and</text> </clause><clause id="id9c0f2c9017224784a70ae2a6a22479d3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>does not include any prisoner who the Bureau of Prisons determines—</text>
 <subclause id="id3df26df5132f4e2294f7979524abe32d"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is medically unable to successfully complete recidivism reduction programming or productive activities;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id687eb1133c3240399c21ea73d18f97e9"><enum>(II)</enum><text>would present a security risk if permitted to participate in recidivism reduction programming; or</text> </subclause><subclause id="id119968d101b14e72a05bb4852ba80c0c"><enum>(III)</enum><text>is serving a sentence of incarceration of less than 1 month.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0395f22b83cf403d942e600a86da5604"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Productive activity</header><text>The term <term>productive activity</term>—</text> <clause id="ide7888d6f5647490581b48c0e608872af"><enum>(i)</enum><text>means a group or individual activity, including holding a job as part of a prison work program, that is designed to allow prisoners classified as having a lower risk of recidivism to maintain such classification, when offered to such prisoners; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idf598ce08b98d4cb9afd4815fc0ccffd9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>may include the delivery of the activities described in subparagraph (C)(i)(II) to other prisoners.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idec7f901d993c4415a149e784a98e2474"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Recidivism reduction program</header><text>The term <term>recidivism reduction program</term> means—</text>
 <clause id="id8fd43d19452240a49093a3855c499498"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a group or individual activity that—</text> <subclause id="id68f8b82ccdaf4034a85dbe3517807427"><enum>(I)</enum><text>has been certified to reduce recidivism or promote successful reentry; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idf744872bbca24a989b5aed224838e896"><enum>(II)</enum><text>may include—</text> <item id="idba92e1aaf9394341a69ead033681994e"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>classes on social learning and life skills;</text>
 </item><item id="idcca0e1e2ac064f2f8e03b6ad513e22bf"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>classes on morals or ethics;</text> </item><item id="id75b131e3d6a64d7abf5cf42fe8f542b6"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>academic classes;</text>
 </item><item id="id2daf238f86694465974240addf5b862d"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>cognitive behavioral treatment;</text> </item><item id="idab273cba8b574e8eb99c45eae696d981"><enum>(ee)</enum><text>mentoring;</text>
 </item><item id="id133eba52ceed4d60abb2c0a7413f8271"><enum>(ff)</enum><text>occupational and vocational training;</text> </item><item id="id3d4ff2bc17e24227bf9814a3cb159be7"><enum>(gg)</enum><text>faith-based classes or services;</text>
 </item><item id="iddda5b37e9b4d4abd9aab72d12ef85a69"><enum>(hh)</enum><text>domestic violence education and deterrence programming;</text> </item><item id="id49c0930f5e744b179d5f799cd6e58f4c"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>victim-impact classes or other restorative justice programs;</text>
 </item><item id="id9d665aa24eba436a94eee0cd4e3d7bb8"><enum>(jj)</enum><text>industry-sponsored workforce development, education, or training; and</text> </item><item id="idF1679D4819B74D9B948D8D5A80D4B977"><enum>(kk)</enum><text>a prison job; and</text>
 </item></subclause></clause><clause id="id2537fd4dae11485b8ded1500695541be"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>shall include—</text> <subclause id="id184b0b5292e946bbb1ddfd804cf5c633"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a productive activity; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idfbc0b03ad2f248acbf6898379b15f7ed"><enum>(II)</enum><text>recovery programming.</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb43309b31e374fbeb5e9521cb613d288"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Recovery programming</header><text>The term <term>recovery programming</term> means a course of instruction or activities, other than a course described in subsection (e), that has been demonstrated to reduce drug or alcohol abuse or dependence among participants, or to promote recovery among individuals who have previously abused alcohol or drugs, to include appropriate medication-assisted treatment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</subsection><subsection id="id4360ffe0915445e7aef7cbfd40fe399a"><enum>(c)</enum><header>No consideration of earned time credit eligibility during sentencing</header>
 <paragraph id="id2F77CE35127643D2B71A78CD4E930A02"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 3553 of title 18, United States Code, as amended by sections 102 and 103 of this Act, is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id701F27A958AD4E1192ADEA5E63D68900"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (b) through (j) as subsections (c) through (k), respectively;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id175B70B3D9B24CCA962201EBE4B0B36D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (e)(3), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>subsection (c)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (d)</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id30CB80D0ADBA4905BD8BFB83F577FCB8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (a) the following:</text>
							<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide42a4ecd1bea4594969d9e898d9b36e3" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="idab6cbdb7eea0481ea5c79b0d0cca0f40"><enum>(b)</enum><text>In imposing a sentence, the court shall not consider the defendant’s eligibility or potential eligibility for credit under section 3621(e), 3621(h), or 3624(b) or any similar provision of law.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1414931181BF47F392CE2B31A3211BBD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendments</header><text>Section 3742 of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="id6CDB45B44EE64CE580C8F982B24AF57A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (e)(3)—</text>
 <clause id="id4F638B8B90044306A3BC2EE323027472"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>section 3553(c)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 3553(d)</quote>;</text> </clause><clause id="id88FBE79E59064D4C9C8FA9D26D8B8108"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)(ii), by striking <quote>section 3553(b)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 3553(c)</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idEDAAD765EF4F4120A5620A760531A5F7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>section 3553(c)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 3553(d)</quote>;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE693DCBCA7D340E088F43D639DCB4FF4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (g)(2), by striking <quote>section 3553(c)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 3553(d)</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id25295BCAA86D44DDB901414C7A09BD97"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subsection (j)(1)(B), by striking <quote>section 3553(b)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 3553(c)</quote>.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id12146796f6f04bd28cc33b972bc455c7"><enum>203.</enum><header>Post-sentencing risk and needs assessment system</header> <subsection id="idbe9bd790ec734008af9ff8a0980b558b"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subchapter C of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/229">chapter 229</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/3621">section 3621</external-xref> the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idEDAC0742755E4BCC8752E0EDCAA3C371" style="USC">
						<section id="id2351AE1EE52041A5B0E60A19E4383528"><enum>3621A.</enum><header>Post-sentencing risk and needs assessment system</header>
 <subsection id="id36C46012957E4C30B8A4584AB26CBC80"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 30 months after the date of the enactment of this section, the Attorney General shall develop for use by the Bureau of Prisons an offender risk and needs assessment system, to be known as the <quote>Post-Sentencing Risk and Needs Assessment System</quote> or the <quote>Assessment System</quote>, which shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="id39cea5a36097408a9fb9db24e68f4747"><enum>(1)</enum><text>assess and determine the recidivism risk level of all prisoners and classify each prisoner as having a low, moderate, or high risk of recidivism;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id172486c675d64bc99107faaff40e7065"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to the extent practicable, assess and determine the risk of violence of all prisoners;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idd25bdd414ab74b5db0ff89fc14cb3b20"><enum>(3)</enum><text>ensure that, to the extent practicable, low-risk prisoners are grouped together in housing and assignment decisions;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idc174633e3b604a0c9f9e3ce6f28fd661"><enum>(4)</enum><text>assign each prisoner to appropriate recidivism reduction programs or productive activities based on the prisoner’s risk level and the specific criminogenic needs of the prisoner, and in accordance with section 3621(h)(4);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id1c1b9ed032514981b8bb966b53cb2257"><enum>(5)</enum><text>reassess and update the recidivism risk level and programmatic needs of each prisoner pursuant to the schedule set forth in subsection (c)(2), and assess changes in the prisoner’s recidivism risk within a particular risk level; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id6605f88a33994671a8cfc123c1ad1193"><enum>(6)</enum><text>provide information on best practices concerning the tailoring of recidivism reduction programs to the specific criminogenic needs of each prisoner so as to effectively lower the prisoner’s risk of recidivating.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id029c84d606784806b93972baf0de4783"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Development of system</header>
 <paragraph id="ide97755e516f04a0092f2262c680d6698"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In designing the Assessment System, the Attorney General shall—</text> <subparagraph id="id15caa1cbaec24ed3ba1d7edd13a52402"><enum>(A)</enum><text>use available research and best practices in the field and consult with academic and other criminal justice experts as appropriate;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id60fc604d273f44d0b7b83550f47ca3c2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensure that the Assessment System measures indicators of progress and improvement, and of regression, including newly acquired skills, attitude, and behavior changes over time, through meaningful consideration of dynamic risk factors, such that—</text>
 <clause id="id1821673a4c754dfab4bb6c82ecc9e6ae"><enum>(i)</enum><text>all prisoners at each risk level other than low risk have a meaningful opportunity to progress to a lower risk classification during the period of the incarceration of the prisoner through changes in dynamic risk factors; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idb8b28398ce5442cbb9e93f4fbdb7d3c6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>all prisoners on prerelease custody, other than prisoners classified as low risk, have a meaningful opportunity to progress to a lower risk classification during such custody through changes in dynamic risk factors;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id00a73d6ca9874ca19d1706b32132e748"><enum>(C)</enum><text>ensure that the Assessment System is adjusted on a regular basis, but not less frequently than every 3 years, to take account of the best statistical evidence of effectiveness in reducing recidivism rates; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3e5dc218ff6e4f30b705633bf9db94b2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>ensure that the Assessment System does not result in unwarranted disparities, including by—</text> <clause id="id1cd940cfb7a14bfd8393f65fa4a721bc"><enum>(i)</enum><text>regularly evaluating rates of recidivism among similarly classified prisoners to identify any unwarranted disparities in such rates, including disparities among similarly classified prisoners of different racial groups; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id33ad6023cd29407c87cea5f57ddd12fe"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>adjusting the Assessment System to reduce such disparities to the greatest extent possible.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idd745cb4ee25347d0b1b97a6185e58da8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Risk and needs assessment tools</header><text>In carrying out this subsection, the Attorney General shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id50580d4ad0614bdea1cb28dd6e02c3b9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>develop a suitable intake assessment tool to perform the initial assessments and determinations described in subsection (a)(1), and to make the assignments described in subsection (a)(3);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3a7bd2287c6f4b57ab9cb2566baa6b57"><enum>(B)</enum><text>develop a suitable reassessment tool to perform the reassessments and updates described in subsection (a)(4); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9fc4c6a039ea47e3b41cb6c0b7adf5ca"><enum>(C)</enum><text>develop a suitable tool to assess the recidivism risk level of prisoners in prerelease custody.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id67ad6624653b4fcf9f9426e294a22cf7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Use of existing risk and needs assessment tools permitted</header><text>In carrying out this subsection, the Attorney General may use existing risk and needs assessment tools, as appropriate, for the assessment tools required under paragraph (2).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idc5b75d538a49463d9ef99c4dfeeb4671"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Use of presentence report</header><text>In carrying out this subsection, the Attorney General shall coordinate with the United States Probation and Pretrial Services to ensure that the findings of the Presentence Report of each offender are available and considered in the Assessment System.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id2b1d38cd59404607952c8cf2882b0d57"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Validation</header><text>In carrying out this subsection, the Attorney General shall statistically validate the risk and needs assessment tools on the Federal prison population, or ensure that the tools have been so validated. To the extent such validation cannot be completed with the time period specified in subsection (a), the Attorney General shall ensure that such validation is completed as soon as is practicable.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id264e24ddaead4dce883f3c3be8b02c29"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Relationship with existing classification systems</header><text>The Bureau of Prisons may incorporate its existing Inmate Classification System into the Assessment System if the Assessment System assesses the risk level and criminogenic needs of each prisoner and determines the appropriate security level institution for each prisoner. Before the development of the Assessment System, the Bureau of Prisons may use the existing Inmate Classification System, or a pre-existing risk and needs assessment tool that can be used to classify prisoners consistent with subsection (a)(1), or can be reasonably adapted for such purpose, for purposes of this section, section 3621(h), and section 3624(c).</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idd6bc3eba0dcb4a16be2302a9bab5b376"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Risk assessment</header>
 <paragraph id="id3f4f7167c11140869e8619b220e9d31a"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial assessments</header><text>Not later than 30 months after the date on which the Attorney General develops the Assessment System, the Bureau of Prisons shall determine the risk level of each prisoner using the Assessment System.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ide5b300a328d64fa9b25042d70e88fc7c"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reassessments and updates</header><text>The Bureau of Prisons shall update the assessment of each prisoner required under paragraph (1)—</text> <subparagraph id="idff1f6dbda3314cdb809b2fb98f21f0ec"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not less frequently than once each year for any prisoner whose anticipated release date is within 3 years;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd375d1b1e1d64bbd882c20ca31fb71fe"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not less frequently than once every 2 years for any prisoner whose anticipated release date is within 10 years; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1c5ae60f24b84a27be8bf78b2fe34a8a"><enum>(C)</enum><text>not less frequently than once every 3 years for any other prisoner.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id128d8cebae0e460f967cc36427ee4d7c"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Assignment of recidivism reduction programs or productive activities</header><text>The Assessment System shall provide guidance on the kind and amount of recidivism reduction programming or productive activities appropriate for each prisoner.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idb055bf2115694452926f34042a44fc06"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Bureau of prisons training</header><text>The Attorney General shall develop training protocols and programs for Bureau of Prisons officials and employees responsible for administering the Assessment System. Such training protocols shall include a requirement that personnel of the Bureau of Prisons demonstrate competence in using the methodology and procedure developed under this section on a regular basis.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id4ad7e512b9d142f8b55ea256aedaf660"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Information from presentence report</header><text>The Attorney General shall ensure that the Bureau of Prisons uses relevant information from the Presentence Report of each offenders when conducting an assessment under this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id279f0a0015bd469ca3a1ba4be05e7f7f"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Quality assurance</header><text>In order to ensure that the Bureau of Prisons is using the Assessment System in an appropriate and consistent manner, the Attorney General shall monitor and assess the use of the Assessment System and shall conduct periodic audits of the use of the Assessment System at facilities of the Bureau of Prisons.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idd15820a8eb274c8981ae60d18e97f517"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Determinations and classifications unreviewable</header><text>Subject to any constitutional limitations, there shall be no right of review, right of appeal, cognizable property interest, or cause of action, either administrative or judicial, arising from any determination or classification made by any Federal agency or employee while implementing or administering the Assessment System, or any rules or regulations promulgated under this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id350385b32c774b03bd3c2a1c6414f26a"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="idce055d55847148cdafd88b77fff7309f"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Dynamic risk factor</header><text>The term <term>dynamic risk factor</term> means a characteristic or attribute that has been shown to be relevant to assessing risk of recidivism and that can be modified based on a prisoner’s actions, behaviors, or attitudes, including through completion of appropriate programming or other means, in a prison setting.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idd5ceb76d53db421d84149f8178a30c63"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Recidivism risk</header><text>The term <term>recidivism risk</term> means the likelihood that a prisoner will commit additional crimes for which the prisoner could be prosecuted in a Federal, State, or local court in the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id1d81562767b2446781d7dccc279786f4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Recidivism reduction program; productive activity; recovery programming</header><text>The terms <quote>recidivism reduction program</quote>, <quote>productive activity</quote>, and <quote>recovery programming</quote> shall have the meaning given such terms in section 3621(h)(8).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="id241363dfe3134c76a2c97695847fe891"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendment</header><text>The table of sections for subchapter C of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/229">chapter 229</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/3621">section 3621</external-xref> the following:</text>
					<quoted-block id="idc3119372-8a3d-4ee2-bf7f-886049de7494" style="OLC"><toc><toc-entry level="section">3621A. Post-sentencing risk and needs assessment system.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</subsection></section><section id="idf182c46e12d147d4a852bd27a7e423cc"><enum>204.</enum><header>Prerelease custody</header>
 <subsection id="idaf8c755ed36546c2aff81f7338e1f29f"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 3624(c) of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="idd35cd703e8694f4686f0e0dd1ad0b5ae"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking the period at the end of the second sentence and inserting <quote>or home confinement, subject to the limitation that no prisoner may serve more than 10 percent of the prisoner’s imposed sentence in home confinement pursuant to this paragraph.</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id7263d10ba6ea40dea88046024d968213"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking paragraphs (2) and (3) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9c0a12e21ec24b42801b7c03f6d62380" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="id6500f78d761542589914c3f12dc56204"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Credit for recidivism reduction</header><text>In addition to any time spent in prerelease custody pursuant to paragraph (1), a prisoner shall spend an additional portion of the final months of the prisoner’s sentence, equivalent to the amount of time credit the prisoner has earned pursuant to section 3621(h)(6)(A), in prerelease custody, if—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id9815d86cf4234ef1bca2561e8202d0cf"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the prisoner’s most recent risk and needs assessment, conducted within 1 year of the date on which the prisoner would first be eligible for transfer to prerelease custody pursuant to paragraph (1) and this paragraph, reflects that the prisoner is classified as low or moderate risk; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0dcfe8c4a1004c98bc41d24296c7440c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for a prisoner classified as moderate risk, the prisoner’s most recent risk and needs assessment reflects that the prisoner’s risk of recidivism has declined during the period of the prisoner’s incarceration.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id057d07bfd8b44c7b90481957288d544d"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Types of prerelease custody</header><text>A prisoner eligible to serve a portion of the prisoner’s sentence in prerelease custody pursuant to paragraph (2) may serve such portion in a residential reentry center, on home confinement, or, subject to paragraph (5), on community supervision.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id6959c464893647ccb337a665e03de3f7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (4) through (6) as paragraphs (9) through (11), respectively;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id00b6ca92e67b41dda4f339149cdaf563"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by inserting the following after paragraph (3):</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id71e528f3ff0b4e279f0e26c0962bf99c" style="OLC">
							<paragraph id="idaced90ea5a25457983ab127cf0a0fc81"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Home confinement</header>
 <subparagraph id="id83c786dc17a04801b924a2e62ed10a16"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Upon placement in home confinement pursuant to paragraph (2), a prisoner shall—</text> <clause id="id1d27c6d4b58f40f09e99ec4106c83488"><enum>(i)</enum><text>be subject to 24-hour electronic monitoring that enables the prompt identification of any violation of clause (ii);</text>
 </clause><clause id="id105e721d1b134f07853a0f47597c14e8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>remain in the prisoner’s residence, with the exception of the following activities, subject to approval by the Director of the Bureau of Prisons—</text>
 <subclause id="id7975a24b93e74c1a8c4507332ccbec7b"><enum>(I)</enum><text>participation in a job, job-seeking activities, or job-related activities, including an apprenticeship;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id91d91b1203fa40928558868417fb9a4e"><enum>(II)</enum><text>participation in recidivism reduction programming or productive activities assigned by the Post-Sentencing Risk and Needs Assessment System, or similar activities approved in advance by the Director of the Bureau of Prisons;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id59f0d934bb4d46aa96489c7dfe9e4c8b"><enum>(III)</enum><text>participation in community service;</text> </subclause><subclause id="id9485c247d7034f96989a9f3029e43a2d"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>crime victim restoration activities;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idd7caea234be5460bb1bafcc37035c9da"><enum>(V)</enum><text>medical treatment; or</text> </subclause><subclause id="id02c62443cb444aedb5dcc75e8fee09ac"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>religious activities; and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="id00c9cdad337c46b58bf29a155880041d"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>comply with such other conditions as the Director of the Bureau of Prisons deems appropriate.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1647cc3926ea4fe0b5afdd27225a2e7a"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Alternative means of monitoring</header><text>If compliance with subparagraph (A)(i) is infeasible due to technical limitations or religious considerations, the Director of the Bureau of Prisons may employ alternative means of monitoring that are determined to be as effective or more effective than electronic monitoring.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id60d9fdebad524b539d10c703ebcdad18"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Modifications</header><text>The Director of the Bureau of Prisons may modify the conditions of the prisoner’s home confinement for compelling reasons, if the prisoner’s record demonstrates exemplary compliance with such conditions.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id54ea24a4c5d44181be6d079ac87ad2eb"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Community supervision</header>
 <subparagraph id="idc88a5a6ee14443e586cf0c3b37475939"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Time credit less than 36 months</header><text>Any prisoner described in subparagraph (D) who has earned time credit of less than 36 months pursuant to section 3621(h)(6)(A) shall be eligible to serve no more than one-half of the amount of such credit on community supervision, if the prisoner satisfies the conditions set forth in subparagraph (C).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idefd61418c4ae430c98cd161bb9c6f02d"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Time credit of 36 months or more</header><text>Any prisoner described in subparagraph (D) who has earned time credit of 36 months or more pursuant to section 3621(h)(6)(A) shall be eligible to serve the amount of such credit exceeding 18 months on community supervision, if the prisoner satisfies the conditions set forth in subparagraph (C).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id100bd43da6ff47cf92400b4368e85adf"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Conditions of community supervision</header><text>A prisoner placed on community supervision shall be subject to such conditions as the Director of the Bureau of Prisons deems appropriate. A prisoner on community supervision may remain on community supervision until the conclusion of the prisoner’s sentence of incarceration if the prisoner—</text>
 <clause id="id06298abf87f441c9992c7b141c8359ba"><enum>(i)</enum><text>complies with all conditions of prerelease custody;</text> </clause><clause id="ida3c0a631f0b04a6fa36ef38080c46084"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>remains current on any financial obligations imposed as part of the prisoner’s sentence, including payments of court-ordered restitution arising from the offense of conviction; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idb8d25235603a4d5ca22efc1355a4916d"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>refrains from committing any State, local, or Federal offense.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4b9732c524c34e42ab5d46f6a199e03b"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Covered prisoners</header><text>A prisoner described in this subparagraph is a prisoner who—</text>
 <clause id="id74687be572944198a384a14c5ad988aa"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is classified as low risk by the Post-Sentencing Risk and Needs Assessment System in the assessment conducted for purposes of paragraph (2); or</text>
 </clause><clause id="idc3a5d11b5fda45098d6703f9b120b38b"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is subsequently classified as low risk by the Post-Sentencing Risk and Needs Assessment System.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ida5a56e3fd1544fe2be92948fd392e76c"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Violations</header><text>If a prisoner violates a condition of the prisoner’s prerelease custody, the Director of the Bureau of Prisons may revoke the prisoner’s prerelease custody and require the prisoner to serve the remainder of the prisoner’s term of incarceration, or any portion thereof, in prison, or impose additional conditions on the prisoner’s prerelease custody as the Director of the Bureau of Prisons deems appropriate. If the violation is nontechnical in nature, the Director of the Bureau of Prisons shall revoke the prisoner’s prerelease custody.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idba666245b80f43cab656a092e0472b2c"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Credit for prerelease custody</header><text>Upon completion of a prisoner’s sentence, any term of supervised release imposed on the prisoner shall be reduced by the amount of time the prisoner served in prerelease custody pursuant to paragraph (2).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ide5ed3b80bec040f7a3f958875e669ade"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Agreements with united states probation and pretrial services</header><text>The Director of the Bureau of Prisons shall, to the greatest extent practicable, enter into agreements with the United States Probation and Pretrial Services to supervise prisoners placed in home confinement or community supervision under this subsection. Such agreements shall authorize United States Probation and Pretrial Services to exercise the authority granted to the Director of the Bureau of Prisons pursuant to paragraphs (4), (5), and (12). Such agreements shall take into account the resource requirements of United States Probation and Pretrial Services as a result of the transfer of Bureau of Prisons inmates to prerelease custody and shall provide for the transfer of monetary sums necessary to comply with such requirements. United States Probation and Pretrial Services shall, to the greatest extent practicable, offer assistance to any prisoner not under its supervision during prerelease custody under this subsection.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idf5df449facee45ce8da40828d9c85733"><enum>(5)</enum><text>by inserting at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddd23dfb9818549648d07d4d0521cc3ba" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="idd7ca9faf64af473a96828e6ee6f54713"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Determination of appropriate conditions for prerelease custody</header><text>In determining appropriate conditions for prerelease custody pursuant to this subsection, and in accordance with paragraph (5), the Director of the Bureau of Prisons shall, to the extent practicable, subject prisoners who demonstrate continued compliance with the requirements of such prerelease custody to increasingly less restrictive conditions, so as to most effectively prepare such prisoners for reentry. No prisoner shall be transferred to community supervision unless the length of the prisoner’s eligibility for community supervision pursuant to paragraph (5) is equivalent to or greater than the length of the prisoner’s remaining period of prerelease custody.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id1676fa0818f3484aa4d161c5a009b8e4"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Aliens subject to deportation</header><text>If the prisoner is an alien whose deportation was ordered as a condition of supervised release or who is subject to a detainer filed by Immigration and Customs Enforcement for the purposes of determining the alien’s deportability, the Director of the Bureau of Prisons shall, upon the prisoner’s transfer to prerelease custody pursuant to paragraphs (1) and (2), deliver the prisoner to United States Immigration and Customs Enforcement for the purpose of conducting proceedings relating to the alien’s deportation.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="idee0c6f0f3b4c49dcada2c7f33ac602a0"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Notice of transfer to prerelease custody</header>
 <subparagraph id="id7aef7c6c5d0c4d4db0f821a0f28c4198"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director of the Bureau of Prisons may not transfer a prisoner to prerelease custody pursuant to paragraph (2) if the prisoner has been sentenced to a term of incarceration of more than 3 years, unless the Director of the Bureau of Prisons provides prior notice to the sentencing court and the United States Attorney’s Office for the district in which the prisoner was sentenced.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide2b354eb5f4a47e98e25768685cad1ed"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Time requirement</header><text>The notice required under subparagraph (A) shall be provided not later than 6 months before the date on which the prisoner is to be transferred.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9e98dba6c771488c91c2664df031b347"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Contents of notice</header><text>The notice required under subparagraph (A) shall include the following information:</text> <clause id="ida21c91a013414657845dee9505ac59ef"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The amount of credit earned pursuant to paragraph (2).</text>
 </clause><clause id="idb7e3106038204701a8ef32de745e12b4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The anticipated date of the prisoner’s transfer.</text> </clause><clause id="id636540971bb649dda62dd2a767218d57"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The nature of the prisoner’s planned prerelease custody.</text>
 </clause><clause id="id70e0d019e03d4d3f95bd74c41bfad163"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The prisoner’s behavioral record.</text> </clause><clause id="id9a6c6d5c72634d6e84743725e5484eac"><enum>(v)</enum><text>The most recent risk assessment of the prisoner.</text>
									</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd69073a598504ed789e4cceec023a3c9"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Hearing</header>
 <clause id="id785b8d05649849798b2c3ff52b154f41"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>On motion of the Government, the sentencing court may conduct a hearing on the prisoner’s transfer to prerelease custody.</text>
 </clause><clause id="idb1d99302e8ca4b579aa73cc458e4e4b0"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Prisoner’s presence</header><text>The prisoner shall have the right to be present at a hearing described in clause (i), unless the prisoner waives such right. The requirement under this clause may be satisfied by the defendant appearing by video teleconference.</text>
 </clause><clause id="id4fe2558a593d4a30a6079645c18c985c"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Motion</header><text>A motion filed by the Government seeking a hearing—</text> <subclause id="id8000e0e3ce4b447a8e11329766fe58bb"><enum>(I)</enum><text>shall set forth the basis for the Government’s request that the prisoner’s transfer be denied or modified pursuant to subparagraph (E); and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id700d6aff3c4f4cc49c1f1edb51799a55"><enum>(II)</enum><text>shall not require the Court to conduct a hearing described in clause (i).</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2314f60c8a37488eb059dba95ebe69e5"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Determination of the court</header><text>The court may deny the transfer of the prisoner to prerelease custody or modify the terms of such transfer, if, after conducting a hearing pursuant to subparagraph (D), the court finds in writing, by a preponderance of the evidence, that the transfer of the prisoner is inconsistent with the factors specified in paragraphs (2), (6), and (7) of section 3553(a).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id31d830f8ff67418a9cf82212a67858b3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall take effect 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="idcdbf22be303448328da92206f346efe1"><enum>205.</enum><header>Reports</header>
				<subsection id="id7bf7f964bdad4350afa518ab9bec3ca7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Annual reports</header>
 <paragraph id="idf9d1f51fe4e246ce9a7634e5220946f6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Reports</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and every year thereafter, the Attorney General, in coordination with the Comptroller General of the United States, shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report that contains the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="idf16ab5b920f94955bf435e3f6e6991f6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A summary of the activities and accomplishments of the Attorney General in carrying out this title and the amendments made by this title.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6748c03bab904e0cbf3afbc2d572cc1d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An assessment of the status and use of the Post-Sentencing Risk and Needs Assessment System by the Bureau of Prisons, including the number of prisoners classified at each risk level under the Post-Sentencing Risk and Needs Assessment System at each facility of the Bureau of Prisons.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb2400fdfacb5483bb9bc3d15cecc8c59"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A summary and assessment of the types and effectiveness of the recidivism reduction programs and productive activities in facilities operated by the Bureau of Prisons, including—</text>
 <clause id="ide0ed8253fe63408086eba5cf568cb530"><enum>(i)</enum><text>evidence about which programs and activities have been shown to reduce recidivism;</text> </clause><clause id="id96067c0d82a44ff3a6a3750bc735a4a2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the capacity of each program and activity at each facility, including the number of prisoners along with the risk level of each prisoner enrolled in each program and activity; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id6527b2677df44c1892f2ae6b67f8cc3b"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>identification of any problems or shortages in capacity of such programs and activities, and how these should be remedied.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida8789925094a446b89146daf89e9b9b9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>An assessment of budgetary savings resulting from this title and the amendments made by this title, to include—</text>
 <clause id="idd920afa2fb6a4b7782afbc1ea1faa94d"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a summary of the amount of savings resulting from the transfer of prisoners into prerelease custody under this title and the amendments made by this title, including savings resulting from the avoidance or deferral of future construction, acquisition, or operations costs;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idc29a2bd46bb24db8b8fe71fc97649137"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a summary of the amount of savings resulting from any decrease in recidivism that may be attributed to the implementation of the Post-Sentencing Risk and Needs Assessment System or the increase in recidivism reduction programs and productive activities required by this title and the amendments made by this title; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id18c05b8f79de458bbb6a848d7861beba"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a strategy to reinvest such savings into other Federal, State, and local law enforcement activities and expansions of recidivism reduction programs and productive activities in the Bureau of Prisons.</text>
							</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id436e9e4b4dc743a2b573a430402a1c88"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reinvestment of savings to fund public safety programming</header>
 <subparagraph id="ide0ea8db674a545afb89eace2c3e9c857"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Beginning in the first fiscal year after the first report is submitted under paragraph (1), and every fiscal year thereafter, the Attorney General shall—</text>
 <clause id="ide12b8b8923f146eeac216c1bfc2b0d87"><enum>(i)</enum><text>determine the covered amount for the previous fiscal year in accordance with subparagraph (B); and</text> </clause><clause id="id25ce2321ef124302951078db4d3f7af1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>use an amount of funds appropriated to the Department of Justice that is not less than 90 percent of the covered amount for the purposes described in subparagraph (C).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id53c2a55097af4d35a863341a700665e7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Covered amount</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>covered amount</term> means, using the most recent report submitted under paragraph (1), the amount equal to the sum of the amount described in paragraph (1)(D)(i) for the fiscal year and the amount described in paragraph (1)(D)(ii) for the fiscal year.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4d6cc0cae6074e5aa477748bf2be6061"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>The funds described in subparagraph (A)(ii) shall be used, consistent with paragraph (1)(D)(iii), to—</text>
 <clause id="ide72f793b67e64f9c943fbe1a7b8e4205"><enum>(i)</enum><text>ensure that, not later than 6 years after the date of enactment of this Act, recidivism reduction programs or productive activities are available to all eligible prisoners;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idc6e0bd9d37f74fea9fe7869ebeb7dc97"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ensure compliance with the resource needs of United States Probation and Pretrial Services resulting from an agreement under section 3624(c)(8) of title 18, United States Code, as added by this title; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id042fa02c6b8d487683ab45b764d145b4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>supplement funding for programs that increase public safety by providing resources to State and local law enforcement officials, including for the adoption of innovative technologies and information sharing capabilities.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0ae569745c5e44539d0cea70b137c555"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prison work programs report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on the status of prison work programs at facilities operated by the Bureau of Prisons, including—</text>
 <paragraph id="id2573fbf0b24c4491af749a144886ec0c"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a strategy to expand the availability of such programs without reducing job opportunities for workers in the United States who are not in the custody of the Bureau of Prisons;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idea0467259f70475caf3a8aacf5632ef0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an assessment of the feasibility of expanding such programs, consistent with the strategy required under paragraph (1), so that, not later than 5 years after the date of enactment of this Act, not less than 75 percent of eligible low-risk offenders have the opportunity to participate in a prison work program for not less than 20 hours per week; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ida8804d0172004e499545ab083777c53e"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a detailed discussion of legal authorities that would be useful or necessary to achieve the goals described in paragraphs (1) and (2).</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id84dcdbb1317a45959828e00991973139"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reporting on recidivism rates</header>
 <paragraph id="id323ef56d3d0a4380860e5899256d74c6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Beginning 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and every year thereafter, the Attorney General, in consultation with the Administrative Office of the United States Courts, shall report to the appropriate committees of Congress on rates of recidivism among individuals who have been released from Federal prison and who are under judicial supervision.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id640dbc74db7644dd9231b96e84a9d79e"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report required under paragraph (1) shall contain information on rates of recidivism among former Federal prisoners, including information on rates of recidivism among former Federal prisoners based on the following criteria:</text>
 <subparagraph id="iddda4fb61d9034a1180aefc06370085a9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Primary offense charged.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida84fb6a3fa5247cd88b7e8d81dd6cf56"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Length of sentence imposed and served.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id22ca5752027b4eb1972139b9c72039d5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Bureau of Prisons facility or facilities in which the prisoner’s sentence was served.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ideefa35ded9ff4a38890bf75ff3884490"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Recidivism reduction programming that the prisoner successfully completed, if any.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id432cf3b581644fa6b96bc234cb98d65c"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The prisoner’s assessed risk of recidivism.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ida68b3bf562b04b569f957b4978e0774e"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Assistance</header><text>The Administrative Office of the United States Courts shall provide to the Attorney General any information in its possession that is necessary for the completion of the report required under paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id2337e59f33844b49a351874580ba42e9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reporting on excluded prisoners</header><text>Not later than 8 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on the effectiveness of recidivism reduction programs and productive activities offered to prisoners described in section 3621(h)(6)(A)(iii) of title 18, United States Code, as added by this title, as well as those ineligible for credit toward prerelease custody under section 3624(c)(2) of title 18, United States Code, as added by this title, which shall review the effectiveness of different categories of incentives in reducing recidivism.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idaedb2703f00741e8924a3025b46fe39f"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>The term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text> <paragraph id="ida6a46e6c038145ba84f2686cbda694aa"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on the Judiciary and the Subcommittee on Commerce, Justice, Science, and Related Agencies of the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id89aec9f8e5dc4aadb75372ed91f9ab29"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on the Judiciary and the Subcommittee on Commerce, Justice, Science, and Related Agencies of the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id367b9c21ffb2476aa993aaf7761bb45a"><enum>206.</enum><header>Additional tools to promote recovery and prevent drug and alcohol abuse and dependence</header>
				<subsection id="id588fbc8a22674c1c830a708525f64d35"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reentry and recovery planning</header>
 <paragraph id="id9f718a6d75514e05966c1be71bde99cc"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Presentence reports</header><text>Section 3552 of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="id18fea1e0fca74a428989e182da2fdc13"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (b), (c), and (d) as subsections (c), (d), and (e), respectively;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id935c00050a46468aa3cb0f8124afcdd8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (a) the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5823ac13ace0438f8e5785f1d06b4043" style="OLC"> <subsection id="idcb032c7687954000a9b6c947e1577ea1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reentry and recovery planning</header> <paragraph id="id417204fa468b474da332a37b4812ce7e"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In addition to the information required by rule 32(d) of the Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure, the report submitted pursuant to subsection (a) shall contain the following information, unless such information is required to be excluded pursuant to rule 32(d)(3) of the Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure or except as provided in paragraph (2):</text>
 <subparagraph id="idd6d605ecdfb8497bbdf68ee159067a1c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Information about the defendant’s history of substance abuse and addiction, if applicable.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id42c6dbbe911f46858855e67f86b64415"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Information about the defendant’s service in the Armed Forces of the United States and veteran status, if applicable.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idad9a3f4ef55a4280b3e4e67c4f3e6b19"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A detailed plan, which shall include the identification of programming provided by the Bureau of Prisons that is appropriate for the defendant’s needs, that the probation officer determines will—</text>
 <clause id="idcdc74228594040759f037aa4aed1fd2d"><enum>(i)</enum><text>reduce the likelihood the defendant will abuse drugs or alcohol if the defendant has a history of substance abuse;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id3dce0162b38e4cb1954d2ee4b192e16b"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>reduce the defendant’s likelihood of recidivism by addressing the defendant’s specific recidivism risk factors; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idfef50618a8314b4badf0ad60927c8304"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>assist the defendant preparing for reentry into the community.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idce22dfc4634d4c6d919882275e5d222d"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>The information described in paragraph (1)(C)(iii) shall not be required to be included under paragraph (1), in the discretion of the Probation Officer, if the applicable sentencing range under the sentencing guidelines, as determined by the probation officer, includes a sentence of life imprisonment or a sentence of probation.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id77fcf426c1bc4c2dad41f94c17f9f431"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subsection (c), as redesignated, in the first sentence, by striking <quote>subsection (a) or (c)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (a) or (d)</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0244179c7aba466ca11ecf7e3b6ddad8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in subsection (d), as redesignated, by striking <quote>subsection (a) or (b)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (a) or (c)</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id215bccc1228b487fb9dfbe1c91a293fa"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendment</header><text>Section 3672 of title 18, United States Code, is amended in the eighth undesignated paragraph by striking <quote>subsection (b) or (c)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (c) or (d)</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idf68f29d87c234f8095f3fb85dbbef014"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Promoting full utilization of residential drug treatment</header><text>Section 3621(e)(2) of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0a68e63378494728934fc465a3fdf7c7" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="id2068edc6a0c54b89be58144b274ae15b"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Commencement of treatment</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this subparagraph, the Director of the Bureau of Prisons shall ensure that each eligible prisoner has an opportunity to commence participation in treatment under this subsection by such date as is necessary to ensure that the prisoner completes such treatment not later than 1 year before the date on which the prisoner would otherwise be released from custody prior to the application of any reduction in sentence pursuant to this paragraph.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc45b4b6b13034a3598e3e35a0d82fe10"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Other credits</header><text>The Director of the Bureau of Prisons may, in the Director’s discretion, reduce the credit awarded under subsection (h)(6)(A) to a prisoner who receives a reduction under subparagraph (B), but such reduction may not exceed one-half the amount of the reduction awarded to the prisoner under subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</subsection><subsection id="id6a1d976863ac41009e8228fd2dcf3489"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Supervised release pilot program To reduce recidivism and improve recovery from alcohol and drug
			 abuse</header>
 <paragraph id="id3db0681f23754942b007190eb842a858"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrative Office of the United States Courts shall establish a recidivism reduction and recovery enhancement pilot program, premised on high-intensity supervision and the use of swift, predictable, and graduated sanctions for noncompliance with program rules, in Federal judicial districts selected by the Administrative Office of the United States Courts in consultation with the Attorney General.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idc32aeba3b4b94dd6a952b002e977373c"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements of program</header><text>Participation in the pilot program required under paragraph (1) shall be subject to the following requirements:</text>
 <subparagraph id="id5ad197800e1d41f1ba220d1f849a1a20"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Upon entry into the pilot program, the court shall notify program participants of the rules of the program and consequences for violating such rules, including the penalties to be imposed as a result of such violations pursuant to subparagraph (E).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb29c9abca2a8428d982d2a8c54005441"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Probation officers shall conduct regular drug testing of all pilot program participants with a history of substance abuse.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8180904ad1f94b50bf7b488a4396a623"><enum>(C)</enum><text>In the event that a probation officer determines that a participant has violated a term of supervised release, the officer shall notify the court within 24 hours of such determination, absent good cause.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id477e61d316a149fa8cc50566a75e3b5f"><enum>(D)</enum><text>As soon as is practicable, and in no case more than 1 week after the violation was reported by the probation officer, absent good cause, the court shall conduct a hearing on the alleged violation.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idba159258b66848e19fb39af268403087"><enum>(E)</enum><text>If the court determines that a program participant has violated a term of supervised release, it shall impose an appropriate sanction, which may include the following, if appropriate:</text>
 <clause id="idb8eeeda70636445fbf5039f79d2e47e7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Modification of the terms of such participant’s supervised release, which may include imposition of a period of home confinement.</text>
 </clause><clause id="id81951309d9e241cab09f6c977f39d3bd"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Referral to appropriate substance abuse treatment.</text> </clause><clause id="id67caf176023f46ef86cc4af6630147cf"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Revocation of the defendant’s supervised release and the imposition of a sentence of incarceration that is no longer than necessary to punish the participant for such violation and deter the participant from committing future violations.</text>
 </clause><clause id="id807ffb7b25654dcc805c91651a4c8c3c"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>For participants who habitually fail to abide by program rules or pose a threat to public safety, termination from the program.</text>
							</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idf90361dcc630446785006b8b602622eb"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Status of participant if incarcerated</header>
 <subparagraph id="id79dc5173f9f644d38a452acc331c71a2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the event that a program participant is sentenced to incarceration as described in paragraph (2)(E)(iii), the participant shall remain in the program upon release from incarceration unless terminated from the program in accordance with paragraph (2)(E)(iv).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5bb2c85fc77140528b03d35f302320cb"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Policies for maintaining employment</header><text>The Bureau of Prisons, in consultation with the Chief Probation Officers of the Federal judicial districts selected for participation in the pilot program required under paragraph (1), shall develop policies to enable program participants sentenced to terms of incarceration as described in paragraph (2)(E) to, where practicable, serve the terms of incarceration while maintaining employment, including allowing the terms of incarceration to be served on weekends.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idfa8f466eaada49fd9b4d75003792ff6a"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Advisory sentencing policies</header>
 <subparagraph id="id6bdc9954b14a4a0b8799b4dc556dbb69"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The United States Sentencing Commission, in consultation with the Chief Probation Officers, the United States Attorneys, Federal Defenders, and Chief Judges of the districts selected for participation in the pilot program required under paragraph (1), shall establish advisory sentencing policies to be used by the district courts in imposing sentences of incarceration in accordance with paragraph (2)(E).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id48bfd08b1cc4498d9d2290de254d42ef"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>The advisory sentencing policies established under subparagraph (A) shall be consistent with the stated goal of the pilot program to impose predictable and graduated sentences that are no longer than necessary for violations of program rules.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id8c3aabece1ef45819a1b0a376d88a2b4"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Duration of program</header><text>The pilot program required under paragraph (1) shall continue for not less than 5 years and may be extended for not more than 5 years by the Administrative Office of the United States Courts.</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="id5c4fcd6d66de4edbb79a7f6e4b76ce47"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Assessment of program outcomes and report to congress</header>
 <subparagraph id="id2b74bb5e02c546ada6d1e7f546606785"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 6 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrative Office of the United States Courts shall conduct an evaluation of the pilot program and submit to Congress a report on the results of the evaluation.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8cf392725d7c452c89580584b10113f4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report required under subparagraph (A) shall include—</text> <clause id="idb87e169a2f09410385644fe7f3af04ba"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the rates of substance abuse among program participants;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id0d430bed45f74c9dbc041ee1739a26fd"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the rates of violations of the terms of supervised release by program participants, and sanctions imposed;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idb55913037b7e4807aad599e003a92273"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>information about employment of program participants;</text> </clause><clause id="ide1ad567b00a64eb3b03245e5a793ccae"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a comparison of outcomes among program participants with outcomes among similarly situated individuals under the supervision of United States Probation and Pretrial Services not participating in the program; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id2282b313fc394b2e9e562da81668a4f6"><enum>(v)</enum><text>an assessment of the effectiveness of each of the relevant features of the program.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id119763415ce548d489a248ccfce1f8ca"><enum>207.</enum><header>Eric Williams Correctional Officer Protection Act</header> <subsection id="id610fbd7b33564210bc678dfc5c5a74b1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/303">Chapter 303</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4201876C5C5E408CA8B6B165CB12D77B" style="USC">
						<section id="id7193C36F457B49D7B4B59EB49BEC2816"><enum>4049.</enum><header>Officers and employees of the Bureau of Prisons authorized to carry oleoresin capsicum spray</header>
 <subsection id="idb71345b58f2c4c5ba489d58b5c077dc4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director of the Bureau of Prisons shall issue, on a routine basis, oleoresin capsicum spray to—</text> <paragraph id="id84b998143d8749cab2f6633cc5274805"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any officer or employee of the Bureau of Prisons who—</text>
 <subparagraph id="iddaecc562140f48d8996c025595f83370"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is employed in a prison that is not a minimum or low security prison; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id461ebb55f71e43dc9f89e7c376a3c5db"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may respond to an emergency situation in such a prison; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idaef1b8b75b114babafae755f05cc2600"><enum>(2)</enum><text>such additional officers and employees of prisons as the Director determines appropriate, in accordance with this section.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idc73fd81b1de34963818deb462ab41689"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Training requirement</header>
 <paragraph id="id3cdae589206442009e597314bec38ffa"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In order for an officer or employee of the Bureau of Prisons, including a correctional officer, to be eligible to receive and carry oleoresin capsicum spray pursuant to this section, the officer or employee shall complete a training course before being issued such spray, and annually thereafter, on the use of oleoresin capsicum spray.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id7cc2cd7bb73543b6bb8c1cc2b55694b8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Transferability of training</header><text>An officer or employee of the Bureau of Prisons who completes a training course pursuant to paragraph (1) and subsequently transfers to employment at a different prison, shall not be required to complete an additional training course solely due such transfer.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idc2d4234a62b54297a1f1d25025056913"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Training conducted during regular employment</header><text>An officer or employee of the Bureau of Prisons who completes a training course required under paragraph (1) shall do so during the course of that officer or employee’s regular employment, and shall be compensated at the same rate that the officer or employee would be compensated for conducting the officer or employee’s regular duties.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id8848a9ca6bcd42d4bde25c5fa4b20d54"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of oleoresin capsicum spray</header><text>Officers and employees of the Bureau of Prisons issued oleoresin capsicum spray pursuant to subsection (a) may use such spray to reduce acts of violence—</text>
 <paragraph id="idc0c4ecbabd514a6b86baeb8c4f5aefa1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>committed by prisoners against themselves, other prisoners, prison visitors, and officers and employees of the Bureau of Prisons; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id2e9330003b434dd289d3e971b952242a"><enum>(2)</enum><text>committed by prison visitors against themselves, prisoners, other visitors, and officers and employees of the Bureau of Prisons.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="id65bf7fdc7a8e467ca2a7da237a3c9767"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for chapter 303 of part III of title 18, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 4048 the following:</text>
					<quoted-block id="id23143418-49f7-43df-a788-715957720d9c" style="OLC"><toc><toc-entry level="section">4049. Officers and employees of the Bureau of Prisons authorized to carry oleoresin capsicum spray.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="idd08802c3d731408b8a09a31dba028367"><enum>(c)</enum><header>GAO report</header><text>Not later than the date that is 3 years after the date on which the Director of the Bureau of Prisons begins to issue oleoresin capsicum spray to officers and employees of the Bureau of Prisons pursuant to section 4049 of title 18, United States Code (as added by this title), the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report that includes the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="id7bfc6998e4aa4f17912741ec5136e13c"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An evaluation of the effectiveness of issuing oleoresin capsicum spray to officers and employees of the Bureau of Prisons in prisons that are not minimum or low security prisons on—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idd4f2477ac6ca4ed1964334a9de9aee93"><enum>(A)</enum><text>reducing crime in such prisons; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id267f1106852145b88f2852cbed447be8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>reducing acts of violence committed by prisoners against themselves, other prisoners, prison visitors, and officers and employees of the Bureau of Prisons in such prisons.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="iddbecbcb052314cd8ad16d8bc525390d7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An evaluation of the advisability of issuing oleoresin capsicum spray to officers and employees of the Bureau of Prisons in prisons that are minimum or low security prisons, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idc608a879755148e88eef1d12493a2edb"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the effectiveness that issuing such spray in such prisons would have on reducing acts of violence committed by prisoners against themselves, other prisoners, prison visitors, and officers and employees of the Bureau of Prisons in such prisons; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6bf0c1c2a59142879f05d753cabc8ec5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the cost of issuing such spray in such prisons. Recommendations to improve the safety of officers and employees of the Bureau of Prisons in prisons.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id76f1c9370821413fb76fbf3e8d7badd1"><enum>208.</enum><header>Promoting successful reentry</header>
				<subsection id="ide8c2f92cf709496180c5a13b412d6b2c"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Federal reentry demonstration projects</header>
 <paragraph id="idb4442f8a686a482c9e9afe50cd0ce3ea"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Evaluation of existing best practices for reentry</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General, in consultation with the Administrative Office of the United States Courts, shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id9d99e1a05e7e46c68b1b76a74f05415d"><enum>(A)</enum><text>evaluate best practices used for the reentry into society of individuals released from the custody of the Bureau of Prisons, including—</text>
 <clause id="id2f5a56f5d6454226ad8b51e48e67f478"><enum>(i)</enum><text>conducting examinations of reentry practices in State and local justice systems; and</text> </clause><clause id="idcaa811dea50445fc96d108c316528ac3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>consulting with Federal, State, and local prosecutors, Federal, State, and local public defenders, nonprofit organizations that provide reentry services, and criminal justice experts; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc52fa9f70937416cb302e6540452c1ae"><enum>(B)</enum><text>submit to the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives a report that details the evaluation conducted under subparagraph (A).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id92e4d88deaf1494996395cdbb6dcd162"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Creation of reentry demonstration projects</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General, in consultation with the Administrative Office of the United States Courts, shall, subject to the availability of appropriations, select an appropriate number of Federal judicial districts to conduct Federal reentry demonstration projects using the best practices identified in the evaluation conducted under paragraph (1). The Attorney General shall determine the appropriate number of Federal judicial districts to conduct demonstration projects under this paragraph.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idedb187bc0fa14a4bbab643ca3d9deaeb"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Project design</header><text>For each Federal judicial district selected under paragraph (2), the United States Attorney, in consultation with the Chief Judge, Chief Federal Defender, the Chief Probation Officer, the Bureau of Justice Assistance, the National Institute of Justice, and criminal justice experts shall design a Federal reentry demonstration project for the Federal judicial district in accordance with paragraph (4).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id304bee2b41394ba78ff61ad65d79865f"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Project elements</header><text>A project designed under paragraph (3) shall coordinate efforts by Federal agencies to assist participating prisoners in preparing for and adjusting to reentry into the community and may include, as appropriate—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id116fe874b2014fb8aecffdec7f38a596"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the use of community correctional facilities and home confinement, as determined to be appropriate by the Bureau of Prisons;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6ec943eb69a64e49950115051f6a414a"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a reentry review team for each prisoner to develop a reentry plan specific to the needs of the prisoner, and to meet with the prisoner following transfer to monitor the reentry plan;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcc81d7a9731f497aa096fe4be5de39c4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>steps to assist the prisoner in obtaining health care, housing, and employment, before the prisoner’s release from a community correctional facility or home confinement;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5cc72ae99dce4ea5995abb3ac41e0c32"><enum>(D)</enum><text>regular drug testing for participants with a history of substance abuse;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id844cf65dfb5243079717bb78fe6ef9f0"><enum>(E)</enum><text>substance abuse treatment, which may include addiction treatment medication, if appropriate, medical treatment, including mental health treatment, occupational, vocational and educational training, apprenticeships, life skills instruction, recovery support, conflict resolution training, and other programming to promote effective reintegration into the community;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc76e269979714850912e92a82949224f"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the participation of volunteers to serve as advisors and mentors to prisoners being released into the community;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5936855682a942c29e26f588fa3db468"><enum>(G)</enum><text>steps to ensure that the prisoner makes satisfactory progress toward satisfying any obligations to victims of the prisoner’s offense, including any obligation to pay restitution; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idaf81b70054f94ada87419258c83920d2"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the appointment of a reentry coordinator in the United States Attorney’s Office.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idcffbb42698f84f909d501c6fca1eb6f7"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Review of project outcomes</header><text>Not later than 5 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrative Office of the United States Courts, in consultation with the Attorney General, shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idae7ca7da0fb047b4a38e3760982dcd32"><enum>(A)</enum><text>evaluate the results from each Federal judicial district selected under paragraph (2), including the extent to which participating prisoners released from the custody of the Bureau of Prisons were successfully reintegrated into their communities, including whether the participating prisoners maintained employment, and refrained from committing further offenses; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfc062ad345c84a3eb3f930570eac88ad"><enum>(B)</enum><text>submit to the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives a report that contains—</text>
 <clause id="ida86d89932d384f4092032f652c34ba66"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the evaluation of the best practices identified in the report required under paragraph (1); and</text> </clause><clause id="id02f3fc997e214b6a8765e7af2bc56cfe"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the results of the demonstration projects required under paragraph (2).</text>
							</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1f3ccaf0978c4310b611f20e1f4f510c"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Study on the impact of reentry on certain communities</header>
 <paragraph id="id2280867b02f54aba9517b6b55fb0280d"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General, in consultation with the Administrative Office of the United States Courts, shall submit to the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives a report on the impact of reentry of prisoners on communities in which a disproportionate number of individuals reside upon release from incarceration.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ide5dea8ed8d05421bbfd54a62b746fa8e"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report required under paragraph (1) shall analyze the impact of reentry of individuals released from both State and Federal correctional systems as well as State and Federal juvenile justice systems, and shall include—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id384f692474cc46f688962cbcac15f539"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an assessment of the reentry burdens borne by local communities;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idda963758309b4e05a0650df7fe844513"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a review of the resources available in such communities to support successful reentry, including resources provided by State, local, and Federal governments, the extent to which those resources are used effectively; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3c96880b1c004f29b9ea33bf517f8d7a"><enum>(C)</enum><text>recommendations to strengthen the resources in such communities available to support successful reentry and to lessen the burden placed on such communities by the need to support reentry.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id58f62d985545425b874db40546a95471"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Facilitating reentry assistance to veterans</header>
 <paragraph id="id0161952d9d0841619593ea2394d705d9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 2 months after the date of the commencement of a prisoner’s sentence pursuant to section 3585(a) of title 18, United States Code, the Director of the Bureau of Prisons shall notify the Secretary of Veterans Affairs if the prisoner’s presentence report, prepared pursuant to section 3552 of title 18, United States Code, indicates that the prisoner has previously served in the Armed Forces of the United States or if the prisoner has so notified the Bureau of Prisons.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id530e53de51ac4201b262609717bbd83a"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Post-commencement notice</header><text>If the prisoner informs the Bureau of Prisons of the prisoner’s prior service in the Armed Forces of the United States after the commencement of the prisoner’s sentence, the Director of the Bureau of Prisons shall notify the Secretary of Veterans Affairs not later than 2 months after the date on which the prisoner provides such notice.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id90ae04d1c7db4657a75e4129f5665841"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Contents of notice</header><text>The notice provided by the Director of the Bureau of Prisons to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs under this subsection shall include the identity of the prisoner, the facility in which the prisoner is located, the prisoner’s offense of conviction, and the length of the prisoner’s sentence.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idb6cb531bd9fe4b38853812adfe3ed2b1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Access to va</header><text>The Bureau of Prisons shall provide the Department of Veterans Affairs with reasonable access to any prisoner who has previously served in the Armed Forces of the United States for purposes of facilitating that prisoner’s reentry.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id584f1324e7d5439c9711f6877bfa5858"><enum>209.</enum><header>Parole for juveniles</header>
 <subsection id="idd53215a4cdc84addb49c60d357b55486"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/403">Chapter 403</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/5032">section 5032</external-xref> the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idA484793899C447F1BDDD9EB29136F534" style="USC">
						<section id="id41F10947EE7F4FCEBFB1AF394040BD41"><enum>5032A.</enum><header>Modification of an imposed term of imprisonment for violations of law committed prior to age 18</header>
 <subsection id="id91ecf2596e44487ea725affa1e618a76"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a court may reduce a term of imprisonment imposed upon a defendant convicted as an adult for an offense committed and completed before the defendant attained 18 years of age if—</text>
 <paragraph id="id4255bf5cbc464aa58ebd6f716e31a927"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the defendant has served 20 years in prison for the offense; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id13a14b8dba444396bd024d8763cd6b33"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the court finds, after considering the factors set forth in subsection (c), that the defendant is not a danger to the safety of any person or the community and that the interests of justice warrant a sentence modification.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1286b89e753b4b4283c44efb10970c33"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Supervised release</header><text>Any defendant whose sentence is reduced pursuant to subsection (a) shall be ordered to serve a period of supervised release of not less than 5 years following release from imprisonment. The conditions of supervised release and any modification or revocation of the term of supervise release shall be in accordance with section 3583.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id728a7d4b01ef408dac18024f2b4d0f60"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Factors and information To be considered in determining whether To modify a term of imprisonment</header><text>The court, in determining whether to reduce a term of imprisonment pursuant to subsection (a), shall consider—</text>
 <paragraph id="id70256f41e528428ead457e8b4e00a2e2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the factors described in section 3553(a), including the nature of the offense and the history and characteristics of the defendant;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id95a61d4989574afeb93dbd069c2a4da1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the age of the defendant at the time of the offense;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id1e9076dabd9647d6818097a75b989358"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a report and recommendation of the Bureau of Prisons, including information on whether the defendant has substantially complied with the rules of each institution to which the defendant has been confined and whether the defendant has completed any educational, vocational, or other prison program, where available;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id27c3bfe2eef24f61b92e83a0f1981ada"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a report and recommendation of the United States attorney for any district in which an offense for which the defendant is imprisoned was prosecuted;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id9869064f6bdd4550867c191b1a911352"><enum>(5)</enum><text>whether the defendant has demonstrated maturity, rehabilitation, and a fitness to reenter society sufficient to justify a sentence reduction;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ide8ee22db5f8546f9855bc1cb220512ae"><enum>(6)</enum><text>any statement, which may be presented orally or otherwise, by any victim of an offense for which the defendant is imprisoned or by a family member of the victim if the victim is deceased;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id6aaf2e48eeda472681dfeea7e99d783a"><enum>(7)</enum><text>any report of physical, mental, or psychiatric examination of the defendant conducted by a licensed health care professional;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id3074e5ca92ed497aa2d0c25cc59c21c0"><enum>(8)</enum><text>the family and community circumstances of the defendant at the time of the offense, including any history of abuse, trauma, or involvement in the child welfare system;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id09c61b95850646399dc30b5b44a111ef"><enum>(9)</enum><text>the extent of the role of the defendant in the offense and whether, and to what extent, an adult was involved in the offense;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id6291fb6f3c844e1fb382829342f93e93"><enum>(10)</enum><text>the diminished culpability of juveniles as compared to that of adults, and the hallmark features of youth, including immaturity, impetuosity, and failure to appreciate risks and consequences, which counsel against sentencing them to the otherwise applicable term of imprisonment; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id8cc4ba75fd544bb79656a357f0c7536a"><enum>(11)</enum><text>any other information the court determines relevant to the decision of the court.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idf1650f444b3f4b56b3b70625bc0bbd79"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitation on applications pursuant to this section</header> <paragraph id="idb16801eec2364b299890773cf23e74c5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Second application</header><text>Not earlier than 5 years after the date on which an order entered by a court on an initial application under this section becomes final, a court shall entertain a second application by the same defendant under this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id18798ab992fa45cd8d451966c7405031"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Final application</header><text>Not earlier than 5 years after the date on which an order entered by a court on a second application under paragraph (1) becomes final, a court shall entertain a final application by the same defendant under this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id8d1fea14ee604ba5bcd3af236b827ab0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>A court may not entertain an application filed after an application filed under paragraph (2) by the same defendant.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id64a888997dc74d0e946369fec51e4e33"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Procedures</header>
 <paragraph id="id8943c102e30248879cf86ff3c72f1572"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>The Bureau of Prisons shall provide written notice of this section to—</text> <subparagraph id="idb84e7adb34264e8398d50108c0218bc7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any defendant who has served 19 years in prison for an offense committed and completed prior to the defendant's 18th birthday for which the defendant was convicted as an adult; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf6807b5c47864061905659dd9b2d8a49"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the sentencing court, the United States attorney, and the Federal Public Defender or Executive Director of the Community Defender Organization for the judicial district in which the sentence described in subparagraph (A) was imposed.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id7b916f88497e4a75a85024baddb73152"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Crime victims rights</header><text>Upon receiving noticed under paragraph (1), the United States attorney shall provide any notifications required under section 3771.</text>
								</paragraph><paragraph id="idbe223d9b31814a13943ec9c5cd987db4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Application</header>
 <subparagraph id="id47cd0bfc38ef4642b2175d5dcc9801cd"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An application for a sentence reduction under this section shall be filed as a motion to reduce the sentence of the defendant and may include affidavits or other written material.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0788eeb2c1f7462889425506628ee191"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>A motion to reduce a sentence under this section shall be filed with the sentencing court and a copy shall be served on the United States attorney for the judicial district in which the sentence was imposed.</text>
									</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id8652eedb5c0743d3919e79492499cee2"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Expanding the record; hearing</header>
 <subparagraph id="id739de86a4b604c3e96cbafd78fdd7457"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Expanding the record</header><text>After the filing of a motion to reduce a sentence under this section, the court may direct the parties to expand the record by submitting additional written materials relating to the motion.</text>
									</subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4b3ef9d8b1784b5f895c878e26e4178d"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Hearing</header>
 <clause id="id47122b0dda0d4080ba2f59e3b42f2719"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The court shall conduct a hearing on the motion, at which the defendant and counsel for the defendant shall be given the opportunity to be heard.</text>
 </clause><clause id="iddcbe6af55761441498430ab421f4e14b"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Evidence</header><text>In a hearing under this section, the court may allow for parties to present evidence.</text> </clause><clause id="id2e1f1d10459045bc8be92537448def10"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Defendant’s presence</header><text>At a hearing under this section, the defendant shall be present unless the defendant waives the right to be present. The requirement under this clause may be satisfied by the defendant appearing by video teleconference.</text>
 </clause><clause id="id42c1082a445f4ba2bd82167e92bd576c"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Counsel</header><text>A defendant who is unable to obtain counsel is entitled to have counsel appointed to represent the defendant for proceedings under this section, including any appeal, unless the defendant waives the right to counsel.</text>
 </clause><clause id="id65ad93dc6c1949a9b7f4aed90a324399"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>The court shall state in open court, and file in writing, the reasons for granting or denying a motion under this section.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2ddae48509d3463e9acc0f57d8cd2b1d"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Appeal</header><text>The Government or the defendant may file a notice of appeal in the district court for review of a final order under this section. The time limit for filing such appeal shall be governed by rule 4(a) of the Federal Rules of Appellate Procedure.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id2a5471472270411ba0320933611e06e0"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Educational and rehabilitative programs</header><text>A defendant who is convicted and sentenced as an adult for an offense committed and completed before the defendant attained 18 years of age may not be deprived of any educational, training, or rehabilitative program that is otherwise available to the general prison population.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="id76c05a95458f4da3a79b7d164871da7d"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of sections</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/403">chapter 403</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/5032">section 5032</external-xref> the following:</text>
					<quoted-block id="idc0ae621c-2af8-4eaf-9a37-3f28463452fa" style="OLC"><toc><toc-entry level="section">5032A. Modification of an imposed term of imprisonment for violations of law committed prior to age
			  18.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb6ffeb5a021c41f6a785a6afeb516656"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to any conviction entered before, on, or after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="id4220392EC9F54C85870927817BCE88B3"><enum>210.</enum><header>Compassionate release initiative</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 231(g) of the Second Chance Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/17541">42 U.S.C. 17541(g)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="id4DCEA7070C894A0FB4D1EAEA15A3DC9B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)(B), by inserting <quote>, upon written request from either the Bureau of Prisons or an eligible aging offender</quote> after <quote>to home detention</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id78D028F556D043C288088976EFB4CD48"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>and shall be carried out during fiscal years 2009 and 2010</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id0A553A82C9BB45AB8A5753F4C1EE83C2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (5)(A)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idDC68DC57A35C4856B56F2B61189F2455"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in clause (i), by striking <quote>65 years</quote> and inserting <quote>60 years</quote>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4F58CD8FCA9542A39140B4E398B345CF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in clause (ii)—</text>
 <clause id="id04E074B00BFD4F349C3D48C8A6A74FF9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>the greater of 10 years or</quote>; and</text> </clause><clause id="idDE3E823E3A2B4714A6F0E95B2E6C1FC8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>75 percent</quote> and inserting <quote><fraction>2/3</fraction></quote>;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE99E0042DC954A318A5B94F803E057A9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in clause (vi), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idFEEF2D73C6654332B6805B96A6C56C4C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in clause (vii), by striking the period at the and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE00CC2593BC8489F805F8E96F63D3F1C"><enum>(E)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id156B80CAD3D842BAA01A6C7C05A0229A" style="OLC"> <clause id="id2440F9FBDF8C4F9E8A4F6D2B23AEF4DC"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>who—</text>
 <subclause id="id85A076E95788450181F0F8F8E7455671"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is receiving or in medical need of care at a nursing home, intermediate care facility, or assisted living facility, as those terms are defined in section 232 of the National Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1715w">12 U.S.C. 1715w</external-xref>); or</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id691AE88AB0A44AE498BF19D5A181B21C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>has been diagnosed with a terminal illness.</text></subclause></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subparagraph></paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf4523b8c8bdb422d907527c0f6544028" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>211.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Juvenile sealing and expungement</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id75A791B7FBF54B96A3ECCEDC9C196B45"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Purpose</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The purpose of this section is to—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5c29a0d0a97345dc9eb31542f628777b"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">protect children and adults against damage stemming from their juvenile acts and subsequent juvenile delinquency records, including law enforcement, arrest, and court records; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1547074aefd148c7b76004cdb54779c2"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prevent the unauthorized use or disclosure of confidential juvenile delinquency records and any potential employment, financial, psychological, or other harm that would result from such unauthorized use or disclosure.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc9a5f61acc3f45d9bde93bca81b43dcd"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 5031 of title 18, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id699EA615D14644C2B33B7C400899E7A4" style="USC"> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id91E1FA802E3146DDB42E5ED26E099196" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>5031.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this chapter—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB45395C935914B5DA3AECE5BA860D844"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>adjudication</term> means a determination by a judge that a person committed an act of juvenile delinquency;</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7D4632756E1B475AB1BA079A468F58CC"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>conviction</term> means a judgment or disposition in criminal court against a person following a finding of guilt by a judge or jury;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id417E03BBFB56480B8A3DC65177BC91C3"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>destroy</term> means to render a file unreadable, whether paper, electronic, or otherwise stored, by shredding, pulverizing, pulping, incinerating, overwriting, reformatting the media, or other means;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2C54BA56737241119F5FFAFB4582CF33"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>expunge</term> means to destroy a record and obliterate the name of the person to whom the record pertains from each official index or public record;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB7E32AD5ED4B4C25A886421C821820F5"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>expungement hearing</term> means a hearing held under section 5044(b)(2)(B);</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idEF95765E931547DAACAE74B867371DA6"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>expungement petition</term> means a petition for expungement filed under section 5044(b);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id55316469C843482B836EB5C1A17147BA"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>juvenile</term> means—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF68E99C7D64B422381A679237FDDC996"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">except as provided in subparagraph (B), a person who has not attained the age of 18; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4E0F5337E0DF47AE980BA14FC08C7CBD"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for the purpose of proceedings and disposition under this chapter for an alleged act of juvenile delinquency, a person who has not attained the age of 21;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id93AC268B103A4124BBC63AED69C3EC12"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>juvenile delinquency</term> means the violation of a law of the United States committed by a person before attaining the age of 18 which would have been a crime if committed by an adult, or a violation by such a person of section 922(x);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id14BE005C661D4616A23F2A127F0E4E7A"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>juvenile nonviolent offense</term> means—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idD103D52F47C14DACA0B69B933CA63ECB"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of an arrest or an adjudication that is dismissed or finds the juvenile to be not delinquent, an act of juvenile delinquency that is not—</text>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1021ACB3E0A44848823D8ED533FAB3CF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a criminal homicide, forcible rape or any other sex offense (as defined in section 111 of the Sex Offender Registration and Notification Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/16911">42 U.S.C. 16911</external-xref>)), kidnapping, aggravated assault, robbery, burglary of an occupied structure, arson, or a drug trafficking crime in which a firearm was used; or</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB3A36862B63A4049ADE8682E90DAD061"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a Federal crime of terrorism (as defined in section 2332b(g)); and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9FDF98F5984D4E31A818E9DB0B5E0007"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of an adjudication that finds the juvenile to be delinquent, an act of juvenile delinquency that is not—</text>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB0E9A9C4171D4F848D4E0B8A7E7C6C61"><enum>(i)</enum><text>described in clause (i) or (ii) of subparagraph (A); or</text> </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id23CF58F56CD3440FB8177BAD344DFD3D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a misdemeanor crime of domestic violence (as defined in section 921(a)(33));</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0A8E9DAB0FDA46F8A1C4BCB6131BEF82"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>juvenile record</term>—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3376423C827B4DE0B117A6DD45B57ABB"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means a record maintained by a court, the probation system, a law enforcement agency, or any other government agency, of the juvenile delinquency proceedings of a person;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7B992FA58C0C4FED922AE47828FB412D"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id364E172567C54C6F91DE4340B98132CE"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a juvenile legal file, including a formal document such as a petition, notice, motion, legal memorandum, order, or decree;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id233FC83658A446538CB36E0C9B07A994"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a social record, including—</text> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3A0CAF8C928E4EB68F14F783383D0FF4"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a record of a probation officer;</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id029163018C644A9284EC11EE834202E9"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a record of any government agency that keeps records relating to juvenile delinquency;</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9DE51D5BA3674CA1A6AD47E4122C0477"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a medical record;</text> </subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF6CCC87C96604298A69B620959AD68A3"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a psychiatric or psychological record;</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB1082576AFCB4AE2A3D006D5AD1294F1"><enum>(V)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a birth certificate;</text> </subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idBBBE13656CD144EEBFC0F2A54A0166C9"><enum>(VI)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an education record, including an individualized education plan;</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idC184D19883234A88B1DCC3568E5B6EA8"><enum>(VII)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a detention record;</text> </subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1EED135BB8EB42499191382F0BC5C11A"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">demographic information that identifies a juvenile or the family of a juvenile; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB89F4A78CF574191B4971F38D5BD42B6"><enum>(IX)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other record that includes personally identifiable information that may be associated with a juvenile delinquency proceeding, an act of juvenile delinquency, or an alleged act of juvenile delinquency; and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id523278C4DABB49F1B37DC8766799543B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a law enforcement record, including a photograph or a State criminal justice information system record; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9600FCC9D6714CF3AAA2AA7212749AEB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>does not include—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB2AFE00346984B859A6D5287561C1CB6"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">fingerprints; or</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idA1150DFBA07E46D9827B457033383E67"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a DNA sample;</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idCC4CF2D4412149DA831234E17C1E2F62"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>petitioner</term> means a person who files an expungement petition or a sealing petition;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF34E592F383E4DD5ADD9658562B9C801"><enum>(12)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>seal</term> means—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idAB6484D36C964D85A3D7BE46DB4DB76A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to close a record from public viewing so that the record cannot be examined except as otherwise provided under section 5043; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9977F7A37E4E49DDA91DB394A56CDB3F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to physically seal the record shut and label the record <quote>SEALED</quote> or, in the case of an electronic record, the substantive equivalent;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id36A63486DE504986B597D5FC1EEEFA2B"><enum>(13)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>sealing hearing</term> means a hearing held under section 3632(b)(2)(B); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id28F474665E8C4C8784C0750E1D073096"><enum>(14)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>sealing petition</term> means a petition for a sealing order filed under section 5043(b).</text></paragraph></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd90525f0993b4e4ab42877f6502fd765"><enum>(c)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Confidentiality</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 5038 of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0cafa6b0a71841ccab4d12e0e894d5c6"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (a), in the flush text following paragraph (6), by inserting after <quote>bonding,</quote> the following: <quote>participation in an educational system,</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id444c10948b0842a2ade80daa4a67b38e"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (b), by striking <quote>District courts exercising jurisdiction over any juvenile</quote> and inserting the following: <quote>Not later than 7 days after the date on which a district court exercises jurisdiction over a juvenile, the district court</quote>.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1810A5C717E44FF2B3BF319E9E65FF69"><enum>(d)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Sealing; expungement</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id028137FAD34D4C878DFE0F6DD16B0E25"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/403">Chapter 403</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idAF78BC68A7B74AB7B8E3730A914B6251" style="USC"> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc625ba2dd18d4d38a8d34f5701498e65" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>5043.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Sealing</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id589aeebfd6a945ac8c4cafc0bbd31024"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Automatic sealing of nonviolent offenses</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id79892B6271504B828F6C0D9DC06FE8A1"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Three years after the date on which a person who is adjudicated delinquent under this chapter for a juvenile nonviolent offense completes every term of probation, official detention, or juvenile delinquent supervision ordered by the court with respect to the offense, the court shall order the sealing of each juvenile record or portion thereof that relates to the offense if the person—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id94FD7304B2F74FE889FE5C0863F4CDED"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has not been convicted of a crime or adjudicated delinquent for an act of juvenile delinquency since the date of the disposition; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0F54871946234F3096672B9A7BDF726D"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is not engaged in active criminal court proceedings or juvenile delinquency proceedings.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5A3C02BAF6654AD5A7C3B2B29E5DAE78"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Automatic nature of sealing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The order of sealing under paragraph (1) shall require no action by the person whose juvenile records are to be sealed.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3169117C1E48441AA1AD26126127B96E"><enum>(3)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notice of automatic sealing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A court that orders the sealing of a juvenile record of a person under paragraph (1) shall, in writing, inform the person of the sealing and the benefits of sealing the record.</text>
									</paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3d07812dc2fc4001a145d9eff6dbda86"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Petitioning for early sealing of nonviolent offenses</header>
									<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7391FFBCFCC049DFA92954A3DB813671"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Right to file sealing petition</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7A02C7D31F5F44B581A6A8EAC8CC42F1"><enum>(A)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the 3-year period beginning on the date on which a person who is adjudicated delinquent under this chapter for a juvenile nonviolent offense completes every term of probation, official detention, or juvenile delinquent supervision ordered by the court with respect to the offense, the person may petition the court to seal the juvenile records that relate to the offense unless the person—</text>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id723A9448ADB447A8AAE4560A06BCCBFF"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has been convicted of a crime or adjudicated delinquent for an act of juvenile delinquency since the date of the disposition; or</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8E192A2E209D43DDAF9B1AF21CC0CECB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is engaged in active criminal court proceedings or juvenile delinquency proceedings.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idC1852579B6BA4FF8B10E2C156DEFC110"><enum>(B)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notice of opportunity to file petition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a person is adjudicated delinquent for a juvenile nonviolent offense, the court in which the person is adjudicated delinquent shall, in writing, inform the person of the potential eligibility of the person to file a sealing petition with respect to the offense upon completing every term of probation, official detention, or juvenile delinquent supervision ordered by the court with respect to the offense, and the necessary procedures for filing the sealing petition—</text>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id177C9ED8197444FD9D3530859B2342B9"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">on the date on which the individual is adjudicated delinquent; and</text> </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8419F344006E4C4DB6B1A0B42C61496F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">on the date on which the individual has completed every term of probation, official detention, or juvenile delinquent supervision ordered by the court with respect to the offense.</text>
											</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idCDC9071883C94EF689E13E77CDFFB757"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Procedures</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3FEB0FB35F304976827B0E5C3E202E69"><enum>(A)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notification to prosecutor</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a person files a sealing petition with respect to a juvenile nonviolent offense, the court in which the petition is filed shall provide notice of the petition—</text>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id87D2B1FDD8F34D438CEBB8827AB09C5B"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to the Attorney General; and</text> </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id70A098A3CA024422955D2BD3532F7E15"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">upon the request of the petitioner, to any other individual that the petitioner determines may testify as to—</text>
 <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id074F269AF50F4D5CA8336C406D1B2F4B"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the conduct of the petitioner since the date of the offense; or</text> </subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1A7C6E866D9944A281182198F17ADA14"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the reasons that the sealing order should be entered.</text>
												</subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id76389B744EBD4A989855D576424B0BD6"><enum>(B)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Hearing</header>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3DD78246D9924378A6FC25AAA358BC11"><enum>(i)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a person files a sealing petition, the court shall—</text> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7D726DD37A354F6EB04DF60E27BDF6DD"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">except as provided in clause (iii), conduct a hearing in accordance with clause (ii); and</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0BE77BD3D86648DFB02BD984525F8A3A"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">determine whether to enter a sealing order for the person in accordance with subparagraph (C).</text>
												</subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idCBEB1CCAE90642B7A9631201272FF5A8"><enum>(ii)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Opportunity to testify and offer evidence</header>
 <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7A6176AB510C48E59626CD1B6F03758F"><enum>(I)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Petitioner</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The petitioner may testify or offer evidence at the sealing hearing in support of sealing.</text> </subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id76514453B03D4FC6B1FF6E2CEAD668E0"><enum>(II)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Prosecutor</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General may send a representative to testify or offer evidence at the sealing hearing in support of or against sealing.</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1CBE20AAD18E4CAE896A095DC0CE3D54"><enum>(III)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Other individuals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual who receives notice under subparagraph (A)(ii) may testify or offer evidence at the sealing hearing as to the issues described in subclauses (I) and (II) of that subparagraph.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5FF3986724E348CCAEAA81D86F038971"><enum>(iii)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Waiver of hearing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the petitioner and the Attorney General so agree, the court shall make a determination under subparagraph (C) without a hearing.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idEF2A596D82454579B4121548DD33EE5D"><enum>(C)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Basis for decision</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The court shall determine whether to grant the sealing petition after considering—</text>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id742EA3383B024528ACD1B65FC4228D25"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the sealing petition and any documents in the possession of the court;</text> </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3E90721D06AA42D6868CA0D11FE16299"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">all the evidence and testimony presented at the sealing hearing, if such a hearing is conducted;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7ae3b610163741aaa9a9b9f27c314c8e"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the best interests of the petitioner;</text> </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id051feaa3890d424aba44f09eca18aeba"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the age of the petitioner during his or her contact with the court or any law enforcement agency;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida9eed07f61374dafb8fc03a048b8ac97"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the nature of the juvenile nonviolent offense;</text> </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6d9fa94ada2047bf823c7ebcfe25f6a9"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the disposition of the case;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id60eaf5e9fdf34a19942cf5c289718e30"><enum>(vii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the manner in which the petitioner participated in any court-ordered rehabilitative programming or supervised services;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id117833959c63452d9bde0f71f926bcb7"><enum>(viii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the length of the time period during which the petitioner has been without contact with any court or law enforcement agency;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id30856e4cec29477880aa25d9a3323dec"><enum>(ix)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether the petitioner has had any criminal or juvenile delinquency involvement since the disposition of the juvenile delinquency proceeding; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id261bbf751e8f499f8b5f42306213e674"><enum>(x)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the adverse consequences the petitioner may suffer if the petition is not granted.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id27FF86BC060945CC8CB7F0DA00FC746C"><enum>(D)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Waiting period after denial</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the court denies a sealing petition, the petitioner may not file a new sealing petition with respect to the same juvenile nonviolent offense until the date that is 2 years after the date of the denial.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0FED24DED1434C22BC2149994F9F4774"><enum>(E)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Universal form</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts shall create a universal form, available over the Internet and in paper form, that an individual may use to file a sealing petition.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5DCF5933570747BB843F41FED30498DD"><enum>(F)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">No fee for indigent petitioners</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the court determines that the petitioner is indigent, there shall be no cost for filing a sealing petition.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idCCF79D69F0594D5EB9832415EB506577"><enum>(G)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Reporting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this section, and each year thereafter, the Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts shall issue a public report that—</text>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id19247EE1CD7C4AAB9CE686B520C4627E"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">describes—</text> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2DC77BDAB41446CBB975170565D89049"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of sealing petitions granted and denied under this subsection; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id59EC24AB0BDA4659AB4BC4F715D3D218"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of instances in which the Attorney General supported or opposed a sealing petition;</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id79BFC9A33BFC4FA9B897EBF8E486A958"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes any supporting data that the Director determines relevant and that does not name any petitioner; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id92995fed27fc40f2adc660a570d73166"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">disaggregates all relevant data by race, ethnicity, gender, and the nature of the offense.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9359BAC0481D4A1D848F55188F81AEC4"><enum>(H)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Public defender eligibility</header> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id42D47BD2AE174545AC03FD82E7F9D292"><enum>(i)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Petitioners under age 18</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The district court shall appoint counsel in accordance with the plan of the district court in operation under section 3006A to represent a petitioner for purposes of this subsection if the petitioner is less than 18 years of age.</text>
											</clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idED00D16C85214ED2A4144261FCC9B87E"><enum>(ii)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Petitioners age 18 and older</header>
 <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id23DD56F69C0E4B8DAC155C5FDF7C62BA"><enum>(I)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Discretion of court</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a petitioner who is not less than 18 years of age, the district court may, in its discretion, appoint counsel in accordance with the plan of the district court in operation under section 3006A to represent the petitioner for purposes of this subsection.</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id79802B22BBB44D93A9D538C127125AEE"><enum>(II)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Considerations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In determining whether to appoint counsel under subclause (I), the court shall consider—</text>
 <item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idBA4AB6B9DFE847919C91CEA1F7AC7A4D"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the anticipated complexity of the sealing hearing, including the number and type of witnesses called to advocate against the sealing of the records of the petitioner; and</text>
 </item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idEEADB0866FEB46CBAFA37E7E165E416D"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the potential for adverse testimony by a victim or a representative of the Attorney General.</text>
													</item></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddbf37100e72b4aea935b4fe5401ce878"><enum>(c)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Effect of sealing order</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idD3971180426146BC8510EDABF2C24978"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Protection from perjury laws</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in paragraph (4)(C)(i), if a court orders the sealing of a juvenile record of a person under subsection (a) or (b) with respect to a juvenile nonviolent offense, the person shall not be held under any provision of law to be guilty of perjury, false swearing, or making a false statement by reason of the person's failure to recite or acknowledge the offense and any arrest, juvenile delinquency proceeding, adjudication, or other result of such proceeding relating to the offense in response to an inquiry made of the person for any purpose.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id53005bbd046e439cbdad3b117fc97889"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Verification of sealing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a court orders the sealing of a juvenile record under subsection (a) or (b) with respect to a juvenile nonviolent offense, the court shall—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1ADE0CE337834433A79E1AFDF70CB1FD"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">send a copy of the sealing order to each entity or person known to the court that possesses a record relating to the offense, including each—</text>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB01BC4E3B15E4563BAE26F6663ABEC55"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">law enforcement agency; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7C403DF6D4B1435397B90B65342629C6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">public or private correctional or detention facility;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE9A0B83686AA4EA6940DBDB83C0BAF59"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the sealing order, require each entity or person described in subparagraph (A) to—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB8017ED835AA4A56A3444E37EC5E1AA5"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">seal the record; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id921721FEFB9B4C50B367B0810426D5E6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submit a written certification to the court, under penalty of perjury, that the entity or person has sealed each paper and electronic copy of the record;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idFF52CBB00CBC42D989581FDFA18C79A0"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">seal each paper and electronic copy of the record in the possession of the court; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id239D3F2513934FD9A5F7830C240B9FB4"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">after receiving a written certification from each entity or person under subparagraph (B)(ii), notify the petitioner that each entity or person described in subparagraph (A) has sealed each paper and electronic copy of the record.</text>
										</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id725f91e5cc614031bf6a029e54908ce5"><enum>(3)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Law enforcement access to sealed records</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id760EB0DC56104B35B8959F497A0DC6A7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), a law enforcement agency may access a sealed juvenile record in the possession of the agency or another law enforcement agency solely—</text>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2CEFECDF0D4A421B8F5A4AA4D1210513"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to determine whether the person who is the subject of the record is a nonviolent offender eligible for a first-time-offender diversion program;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idAB5FEC721F464384B61125AC2A7E86C5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for investigatory or prosecutorial purposes within the juvenile justice system; or</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5DDC7AB4712B458E899F236A37881A8D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for a background check that relates to—</text> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idC24D35F3A0E044C2AD514F432DB4DC3D"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">law enforcement employment; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id39A5A760D21744989F32AA1BD8DF1CD1"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any position that a Federal agency designates as a—</text> <item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB6F4CDF14C8C47F5BAEAF7B83CA03493"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">national security position; or</text>
 </item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0B30358375FD4DD893FEBCAC9AD457F5"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">high-risk, public trust position.</text> </item></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id359E47C93ED947E9A94E2D79A7C23E7C"><enum>(B)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Transition period</header><text>During the 1-year period beginning on the date on which a court orders the sealing of a juvenile record under this section, a law enforcement agency may, for law enforcement purposes, access the record if it is in the possession of the agency or another law enforcement agency.</text>
										</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3b563ec477c54408bee86e96ec44a770"><enum>(4)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Prohibition on disclosure</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9D0CDFE2702141CAB7AEF075403B1E7A"><enum>(A)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subparagraph (C), it shall be unlawful to intentionally make or attempt to make an unauthorized disclosure of any information from a sealed juvenile record in violation of this section.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id56D7C42E3AAD4A08BDEDE5B044823048"><enum>(B)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Penalty</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any person who violates subparagraph (A) shall be fined under this title, imprisoned for not more than 1 year, or both.</text>
										</subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE8F1C465E2E64943891AF316692BE0A7"><enum>(C)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Exceptions</header>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE8D34F0706CB47C39660A2F569A99C98"><enum>(i)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Background checks</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a background check for law enforcement employment or for any employment that requires a government security clearance—</text>
 <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id345708F7E45E4EA7B794BB79F7CB3AAA"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a person who is the subject of a juvenile record sealed under this section shall disclose the contents of the record; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id102490A46B674AD5A0EB4805E50F210D"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a law enforcement agency that possesses a juvenile record sealed under this section—</text> <item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id784FB64DC5224D538C79A440ACBAE597"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may disclose the contents of the record; and</text>
 </item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id58A85E8A4BDD4F98B9344D99DBFFCC81"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>if the agency obtains or is subject to a court order authorizing disclosure of the record, may disclose the record.</text>
 </item></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id00FC9E80167943FFB5A090BDC81CC926"><enum>(ii)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Disclosure to Armed Forces</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person, including a law enforcement agency that possesses a juvenile record sealed under this section, may disclose information from a juvenile record sealed under this section to the Secretaries of the military departments (or the Secretary of Homeland Security with respect to the Coast Guard when it is not operating as a service in the Navy) for the purpose of vetting an enlistment or commission, or with regard to any member of the Armed Forces.</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id920F78F633374C1B998EE0254750299F"><enum>(iii)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Criminal and juvenile proceedings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A prosecutor may disclose information from a juvenile record sealed under this section if the information pertains to a potential witness in a Federal or State—</text>
 <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id975ADDA6AA01476A8E06921EE0662F0D"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">criminal proceeding; or</text> </subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id560233F6E1A24A849DC488E6DB455E6D"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">juvenile delinquency proceeding.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idEE163A3286934625824F69A0CC09FAC0"><enum>(iv)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Authorization for person to disclose own record</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person who is the subject of a juvenile record sealed under this section may choose to disclose the record.</text>
											</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6255C6FE587C40748998B27EB37B7510"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitation relating to subsequent incidents</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id15117CFCA5B24480AE712491C3A3E986"><enum>(1)</enum><header>After filing and before petition granted</header><text>If, after the date on which a person files a sealing petition with respect to a juvenile offense and before the court determines whether to grant the petition, the person is convicted of a crime, adjudicated delinquent for an act of juvenile delinquency, or engaged in active criminal court proceedings or juvenile delinquency proceedings, the court shall deny the petition.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idA21B4622129B4D44A508242C799ED026"><enum>(2)</enum><header>After petition granted</header><text>If, on or after the date on which a court orders the sealing of a juvenile record of a person under subsection (b), the person is convicted of a crime, adjudicated delinquent for an act of juvenile delinquency, or engaged in active criminal court proceedings or juvenile delinquency proceedings—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idA281F498C78D4743903DE90DD700917A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the court shall—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF5874AD9239B4290AB2D00F0A2A1DC1D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>vacate the order; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id175D1F64BB5F496AA8039EF53E8626DA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>notify the person who is the subject of the juvenile record, and each entity or person described in subsection (c)(2)(A), that the order has been vacated; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id20C96EDDF109462B87B19AB51B8F94B9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the record shall no longer be sealed.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id237BA4B3FDED49E1BE50E19D09D21FCE"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Inclusion of State juvenile delinquency adjudications and proceedings</header><text>For purposes of subparagraphs (A) and (B) of subsection (a)(1), clauses (i) and (ii) of subsection (b)(1)(A), and paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (d), the term <term>juvenile delinquency</term> includes the violation of a law of a State committed by a person before attaining the age of 18 which would have been a crime if committed by an adult.</text>
								</subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd312c473c516423499f8d0fe0396791c" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>5044.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Expungement</header>
								<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide5b8646ca85b46a79e2dbbf40cf11f54"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Automatic expungement of certain records</header>
									<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF31D499599334AFDAC90A35E8F7F205A"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Attorney General motion</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7D206451208D4DCD9C1A43216B0EDA3A"><enum>(A)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nonviolent offenses committed before a person turned 15</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a person is adjudicated delinquent under this chapter for a juvenile nonviolent offense committed before the person attained 15 years of age, on the date on which the person attains 18 years of age, the Attorney General shall file a motion in the district court of the United States in which the person was adjudicated delinquent requesting that each juvenile record of the person that relates to the offense be expunged.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf7f9d7cd5de54a729a3f99027c77c458"><enum>(B)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Arrests</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a juvenile is arrested for a juvenile nonviolent offense for which a juvenile delinquency proceeding is not instituted under this chapter, and for which the United States does not proceed against the juvenile as an adult in a district court of the United States, the Attorney General shall file a motion in the district court of the United States that would have had jurisdiction of the proceeding requesting that each juvenile record relating to the arrest be expunged.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9CA89CECA6D144B2BED51AA9D52BB051"><enum>(C)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Expungement order</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon the filing of a motion in a district court of the United States with respect to a juvenile nonviolent offense under subparagraph (A) or an arrest for a juvenile nonviolent offense under subparagraph (B), the court shall grant the motion and order that each juvenile record relating to the offense or arrest, as applicable, be expunged.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0A5F9CE789214DAB82419128C4304E57"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Dismissed cases</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a district court of the United States dismisses an information with respect to a juvenile under this chapter or finds a juvenile not to be delinquent in a juvenile delinquency proceeding under this chapter, the court shall concurrently order that each juvenile record relating to the applicable proceeding be expunged.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id913BD32E9F0C48BB8F0EBE82F1410A51"><enum>(3)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Automatic nature of expungement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An order of expungement under paragraph (1)(C) or (2) shall not require any action by the person whose records are to be expunged.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idCC51997A9BD14606AAA6E379332ED0E9"><enum>(4)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notice of automatic expungement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A court that orders the expungement of a juvenile record of a person under paragraph (1)(C) or (2) shall, in writing, inform the person of the expungement and the benefits of expunging the record.</text>
									</paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id685651E2B2A34FA094B2021A0B469DE5"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Petitioning for expungement of nonviolent offenses</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idEF705AC6061A4BB7A13AB3BE4CD706D0"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person who is adjudicated delinquent under this chapter for a juvenile nonviolent offense committed on or after the date on which the person attained 15 years of age may petition the court in which the proceeding took place to order the expungement of the juvenile record that relates to the offense unless the person—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idD7190878F40D484C9AA5B4A10DBF9B20"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has been convicted of a crime or adjudicated delinquent for an act of juvenile delinquency since the date of the disposition;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6D1F0520D59B44A3BF5C9D22D259EA40"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is engaged in active criminal court proceedings or juvenile delinquency proceedings; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8A9012D6D33A46E0A4E7994AD6DD6F96"><enum>(C)</enum><text>has had not less than 2 adjudications of delinquency previously expunged under this section.</text>
										</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF7BD036133E048FBBE64CD9613B2C1E5"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Procedures</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF47FD6E4BB4E414FABE2A91ECBF4E935"><enum>(A)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notification of prosecutor and victims</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a person files an expungement petition with respect to a juvenile nonviolent offense, the court in which the petition is filed shall provide notice of the petition—</text>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB0D0530F3B2D4B7B81D8DB288F7009FB"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to the Attorney General; and</text> </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0F1AFA99544C4C2080A272610A51454A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">upon the request of the petitioner, to any other individual that the petitioner determines may testify as to—</text>
 <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id81F1724A0A344C37AE513C6A0460E29C"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the conduct of the petitioner since the date of the offense; or</text> </subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4EDD65F415B542B9A9895EE73933984C"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the reasons that the expungement order should be entered.</text>
												</subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id85D09C28360348EAB6C066C9C0F85317"><enum>(B)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Hearing</header>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0D7FC1C4C7954C4899693C91FC1242EF"><enum>(i)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a person files an expungement petition, the court shall—</text>
 <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB64CDBEFD5534B2EBC9C94712A0F8635"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">except as provided in clause (iii), conduct a hearing in accordance with clause (ii); and</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id16A67501DE8A43499DE0EA3AEBA06FF4"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">determine whether to enter an expungement order for the person in accordance with subparagraph (C).</text>
												</subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF8A5BD515408497D82410DE0E62392CA"><enum>(ii)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Opportunity to testify and offer evidence</header>
 <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id07A87852133549298D3259093B2ED323"><enum>(I)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Petitioner</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The petitioner may testify or offer evidence at the expungement hearing in support of expungement.</text> </subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id854FFC7F41264DC59986C1CDA1601C17"><enum>(II)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Prosecutor</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General may send a representative to testify or offer evidence at the expungement hearing in support of or against expungement.</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idA47EE71451FD49AEA061E4352B73B962"><enum>(III)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Other individuals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual who receives notice under subparagraph (A)(ii) may testify or offer evidence at the expungement hearing as to the issues described in subclauses (I) and (II) of that subparagraph.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id23E15B7C46D84A1DBF86D43407871007"><enum>(C)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Basis for decision</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The court shall determine whether to grant an expungement petition after considering—</text>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id83CD78853FEC4FE8BCF4773058B75A4F"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the petition and any documents in the possession of the court;</text> </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id74542222501148668E2CE7D2B9BF692B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">all the evidence and testimony presented at the expungement hearing, if such a hearing is conducted;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB1AE15C3582E429DB029BC74E2C32791"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the best interests of the petitioner;</text> </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id420622CA9303444AA4B852D757246C60"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the age of the petitioner during his or her contact with the court or any law enforcement agency;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF74904B8CC3441C8BE05A680FD6DE22D"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the nature of the juvenile nonviolent offense;</text> </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id233A73C18CB143969C67F35E68427451"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the disposition of the case;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id292E1DCF69B7482A93E8D5E20258F1F6"><enum>(vii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the manner in which the petitioner participated in any court-ordered rehabilitative programming or supervised services;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id817D5F0920394803A3FEF87F8A0B4352"><enum>(viii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the length of the time period during which the petitioner has been without contact with any court or any law enforcement agency;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1E6075FF6AB94C3FB7E1DA3ACC22D065"><enum>(ix)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether the petitioner has had any criminal or juvenile delinquency involvement since the disposition of the juvenile delinquency proceeding; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9F86891FA1F849F395060A824E684D81"><enum>(x)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the adverse consequences the petitioner may suffer if the petition is not granted.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id38C6070727904B6DA0BE2EB416373A57"><enum>(D)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Waiting period after denial</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the court denies an expungement petition, the petitioner may not file a new expungement petition with respect to the same offense until the date that is 2 years after the date of the denial.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE1F9DCF62BD04067ACA647D4FFF18D1C"><enum>(E)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Universal form</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts shall create a universal form, available over the Internet and in paper form, that an individual may use to file an expungement petition.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9CB7B76643114BF58B2CE5F862CA4DA2"><enum>(F)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">No fee for indigent petitioners</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the court determines that the petitioner is indigent, there shall be no cost for filing an expungement petition.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6E613EDB6B034C16B1DBFE3148D7D64C"><enum>(G)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Reporting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this section, and each year thereafter, the Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts shall issue a public report that—</text>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8B21674A90214F31939B13891CC8CB9F"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">describes—</text> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6F4D9C880E9940D8A70F70FD730C9178"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of expungement petitions granted and denied under this subsection; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1A01EA48FE8D4D9DBD107460DB28C80D"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of instances in which the Attorney General supported or opposed an expungement petition;</text> </subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id97E58D0BDC0142C38E9D6C4D9F2FE18B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes any supporting data that the Director determines relevant and that does not name any petitioner; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id86BEDFEBAF2E4AD6B895046706A5EEFC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">disaggregates all relevant data by race, ethnicity, gender, and the nature of the offense.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id08EC85F66CF74DBDB440CB945498F536"><enum>(H)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Public defender eligibility</header> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id096B6204F3FE490D984165B3FF8242EF"><enum>(i)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Petitioners under age 18</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The district court shall appoint counsel in accordance with the plan of the district court in operation under section 3006A to represent a petitioner for purposes of this subsection if the petitioner is less than 18 years of age.</text>
											</clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idAD63A5E9B403424ABFCB18C8BE530F87"><enum>(ii)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Petitioners age 18 and older</header>
 <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id649CD6137733410FA92EBE92B225CE43"><enum>(I)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Discretion of court</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a petitioner who is not less than 18 years of age, the district court may, in its discretion, appoint counsel in accordance with the plan of the district court in operation under section 3006A to represent the petitioner for purposes of this subsection.</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id90A177B5EF914D44BE519CEB754E54CB"><enum>(II)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Considerations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In determining whether to appoint counsel under subclause (I), the court shall consider—</text>
 <item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id63157A2570EA4D4DA2E837354F198FBA"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the anticipated complexity of the expungement hearing, including the number and type of witnesses called to advocate against the expungement of the records of the petitioner; and</text>
 </item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id17BBD92A6871480E9A6504C6195F22B0"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the potential for adverse testimony by a victim or a representative of the Attorney General.</text>
													</item></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id23A0706819634069AF527C64CA3D6FFF"><enum>(c)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Effect of expunged juvenile record</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idA65CFA47E7E740BE874B40742785AC68"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Protection from perjury laws</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in paragraph (4)(C), if a court orders the expungement of a juvenile record of a person under subsection (a) or (b) with respect to a juvenile nonviolent offense, the person shall not be held under any provision of law to be guilty of perjury, false swearing, or making a false statement by reason of the person's failure to recite or acknowledge the offense and any arrest, juvenile delinquency proceeding, adjudication, or other result of such proceeding relating to the offense in response to an inquiry made of the person for any purpose.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5c7b91fce6ef46c8ad30a4f9e9fec330"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Verification of expungement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a court orders the expungement of a juvenile record under subsection (a) or (b) with respect to a juvenile nonviolent offense, the court shall—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id88DF0662541B42879889876FBBE7E62F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">send a copy of the expungement order to each entity or person known to the court that possesses a record relating to the offense, including each—</text>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id43CAD462535642B8A6B6EE185119EA45"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">law enforcement agency; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0B7A416A354E4170BA2F8B803E1CB4CC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">public or private correctional or detention facility;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id00EFE1BDC6334450B1C37F6CB5B16DDA"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the expungement order—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idD4F03CF6E4FA420EAB156BE531A9004E"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">require each entity or person described in subparagraph (A) to—</text>
 <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id97D30EA24D0F41FD976D9B4B69795D2C"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">seal the record for 1 year and, during that 1-year period, apply paragraphs (3) and (4) of section 5043(c) with respect to the record;</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8E7FBF3158224A5DA3B67952327B3D1D"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">on the date that is 1 year after the date of the order, destroy the record unless a subsequent incident described in subsection (d)(2) occurs; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idBF3DB09E06B14CAB81ABCB6EBCAD3EC2"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submit a written certification to the court, under penalty of perjury, that the entity or person has destroyed each paper and electronic copy of the record; and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idD81379BB99884918BE1362D9B2828748"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>explain that if a subsequent incident described in subsection (d)(2) occurs, the order shall be vacated and the record shall no longer be sealed;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idC28BD23BE1804CB0B1CDA59354D5B727"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">on the date that is 1 year after the date of the order, destroy each paper and electronic copy of the record in the possession of the court unless a subsequent incident described in subsection (d)(2) occurs; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idAAA17C1762104512B0B22C8B0A775C8A"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">after receiving a written certification from each entity or person under subparagraph (B)(i)(III), notify the petitioner that each entity or person described in subparagraph (A) has destroyed each paper and electronic copy of the record.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3102e050e4744da8a1680506dc8652f9"><enum>(3)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Reply to inquiries</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On and after the date that is 1 year after the date on which a court orders the expungement of a juvenile record of a person under this section, in the case of an inquiry relating to the juvenile record, the court, each law enforcement officer, any agency that provided treatment or rehabilitation services to the person, and the person (except as provided in paragraph (5)) shall reply to the inquiry that no such juvenile record exists.</text>
									</paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5a7ca71691754124b18c75579e27181d"><enum>(4)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Civil actions</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0441FE492CD54CC197FD1B80EE2A4BBE"><enum>(A)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On and after the date on which a court orders the expungement of a juvenile record of a person under this section, if the person brings an action against a law enforcement agency that arrested, or participated in the arrest of, the person for the offense to which the record relates, or against the State or political subdivision of a State of which the law enforcement agency is an agency, in which the contents of the record are relevant to the resolution of the issues presented in the action, there shall be a rebuttable presumption that the defendant has a complete defense to the action.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id80B9CF2E1329441893C9849A438323F4"><enum>(B)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Showing by plaintiff</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In an action described in subparagraph (A), the plaintiff may rebut the presumption of a complete defense by showing that the contents of the expunged record would not prevent the defendant from being held liable.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2DF20889B1F443A494AB9F8DF0E9E16B"><enum>(C)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Duty to testify as to existence of record</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The court in which an action described in subparagraph (A) is filed may require the plaintiff to state under oath whether the plaintiff had a juvenile record and whether the record was expunged.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2C2D866A2BE548679D5742E228E1D59C"><enum>(D)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Proof of existence of juvenile record</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the plaintiff in an action described in subparagraph (A) denies the existence of a juvenile record, the defendant may prove the existence of the record in any manner compatible with the applicable laws of evidence.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5C0BC2D3267E433C86557C2D57234B49"><enum>(5)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Criminal and juvenile proceedings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On and after the date that is 1 year after the date on which a court orders the expungement of a juvenile record under this section, a prosecutor may disclose underlying information from the juvenile record if the information—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1D8BE5E66F6E469E977FA543ABB85EA4"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is derived from a source other than the juvenile record; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id108BE1E830FA46A08FD52BBEF4AA1322"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">pertains to a potential witness in a Federal or State—</text>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3CE818A14A224438A26F87F943A9A3FC"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">criminal proceeding; or</text> </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8C2A44E588894F56928C4804C91D9C34"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">juvenile delinquency proceeding.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0068AEB804584D0D905D2B51744D6260"><enum>(6)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Authorization for person to disclose own record</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person who is the subject of a juvenile record expunged under this section may choose to disclose the record.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4675287528364DD2A2F238A4176A2D8E"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Treatment as sealed record during transition period</header><text>During the 1-year period beginning on the date on which a court orders the expungement of a juvenile record under this section, paragraphs (3) and (4) of section 5043(c) shall apply with respect to the record as if the record had been sealed under that section.</text>
									</paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idD9BC18E04A8D4C0A9B10EEC54741D0A0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitation relating to subsequent incidents</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2DC619EA90D0451FA209860BF3C3FCD9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>After filing and before petition granted</header><text>If, after the date on which a person files an expungement petition with respect to a juvenile offense and before the court determines whether to grant the petition, the person is convicted of a crime, adjudicated delinquent for an act of juvenile delinquency, or engaged in active criminal court proceedings or juvenile delinquency proceedings, the court shall deny the petition.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id97FB7AB4B8654F69B844FDF82C14E6B5"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">After petition granted</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If, on or after the date on which a court orders the expungement of a juvenile record of a person under subsection (b), the person is convicted of a crime, adjudicated delinquent for an act of juvenile delinquency, or engaged in active criminal court proceedings or juvenile delinquency proceedings—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idDC9ED272FAE3463FA7BC3254549553B8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the court that ordered the expungement shall—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id37D4342E831A4F0A94905911D5636C62"><enum>(i)</enum><text>vacate the order; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id781F13F335A54A96A741C882B4E94F5E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>notify the person who is the subject of the juvenile record, and each entity or person described in subsection (c)(2)(A), that the order has been vacated; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3285073BDB2449A791E0CF2F7BE5177B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the record shall no longer be sealed.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id543C3517E73449DBB95DCC742EE8DBC7"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Inclusion of State juvenile delinquency adjudications and proceedings</header><text>For purposes of subparagraphs (A) and (B) of subsection (b)(1) and paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (d), the term <term>juvenile delinquency</term> includes the violation of a law of a State committed by a person before attaining the age of 18 which would have been a crime if committed by an adult.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id10DB430CB84142F9923ED21FBDB81165"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Technical and conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/403">chapter 403</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1EC65ADB5D09481398646D7EFD117646" style="OLC"><toc><toc-entry bold="off" idref="idc625ba2dd18d4d38a8d34f5701498e65" level="section">5043. Sealing.</toc-entry><toc-entry bold="off" idref="idd312c473c516423499f8d0fe0396791c" level="section">5044. Expungement.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE93CF29A64564267A4A02C6602EFA934"><enum>(3)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Applicability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Sections 5043 and 5044 of title 18, United States Code, as added by paragraph (1), shall apply with respect to a juvenile nonviolent offense (as defined in section 5031 of such title, as amended by subsection (b)) that is committed or alleged to have been committed before, on, or after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id754F30601DF74557B2FC7245B1B08A95"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in the amendments made by this section shall be construed to authorize the sealing or expungement of a record of a criminal conviction of a juvenile who was proceeded against as an adult in a district court of the United States.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="idd22ff1ce4ee14b5b807cd87ffe80d7f6"><enum>212.</enum><header>Juvenile solitary confinement</header>
 <subsection id="idefc552f35db0428cb441498ddc1e2888"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/403">Chapter 403</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, as amended by section 211, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaad687e37fcf4036adb35a378c6ad6be" style="USC">
						<section id="id9f6ca46799b04c5185c36c8a9398322c" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>5045.</enum><header>Juvenile solitary confinement</header>
 <subsection id="idbba641aec64b437890c9af714303c4b3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text> <paragraph id="id399c2bbeba5947139756b4350a8721d8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>covered juvenile</term> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idd2dd971cd3744b4a80a596e9ccb94ba3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a juvenile who—</text> <clause id="id2d9b5de8212d41b1a17efcf6c6c5a292"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is being proceeded against under this chapter for an alleged act of juvenile delinquency; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="idff96f6117b0b476993fcbef826cf8f0a"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has been adjudicated delinquent under this chapter; or</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id11b3157ca0e24a86a65db8914ff748d4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a juvenile who is being proceeded against as an adult in a district court of the United States for an alleged criminal offense;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide353ac2f274947d5ae537134c65a1c01"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>juvenile facility</term> means any facility where covered juveniles are—</text> <subparagraph id="id9c40a59aff0f4dd1a856b9e3fb04825c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>committed pursuant to an adjudication of delinquency under this chapter; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcae9266d440a4b6896388524a62ed9de"><enum>(B)</enum><text>detained prior to disposition or conviction; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idb0265979e67d47e3aed6fa4212c8d56b"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>room confinement</term> means the involuntary placement of a covered juvenile alone in a cell, room, or other area for any reason.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id754e084ebc2942e1b49d74eeb22fe4f9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition on room confinement in juvenile facilities</header>
 <paragraph id="id2b5c6ebfdde844dd9b7a645bd922b8d7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The use of room confinement at a juvenile facility for discipline, punishment, retaliation, or any reason other than as a temporary response to a covered juvenile’s behavior that poses a serious and immediate risk of physical harm to any individual, including the covered juvenile, is prohibited.</text>
								</paragraph><paragraph id="idd26d02e82ea84342a87070309ebe2694"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Juveniles posing risk of harm</header>
									<subparagraph id="id83b3e6346f2e4a679037ba0ddf9d24b5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Requirement to use least restrictive techniques</header>
 <clause id="ide494681b5055431f84813133aabe3591"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Before a staff member of a juvenile facility places a covered juvenile in room confinement, the staff member shall attempt to use less restrictive techniques, including—</text>
 <subclause id="id6b081ca06d2a49f2a4adbbd9b314b6d2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>talking with the covered juvenile in an attempt to de-escalate the situation; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="id53f7b1f2e0fa4cb7a58252b8a67dfddf"><enum>(II)</enum><text>permitting a qualified mental health professional to talk to the covered juvenile.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="ide14179f2037c429a953dd6014e4dc59f"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Explanation</header><text>If, after attempting to use less restrictive techniques as required under clause (i), a staff member of a juvenile facility decides to place a covered juvenile in room confinement, the staff member shall first—</text>
 <subclause id="id202af7e997964b45a23b19e2d016588b"><enum>(I)</enum><text>explain to the covered juvenile the reasons for the room confinement; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="id920a583041cd41f485e9acced0434c64"><enum>(II)</enum><text>inform the covered juvenile that release from room confinement will occur—</text>
 <item id="idca48dfc6dc7f45fc9a856bac2d1b5d7f"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>immediately when the covered juvenile regains self-control, as described in subparagraph (B)(i); or</text> </item><item id="ide1ade516bfe64221848a813bcfe892fd"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>not later than after the expiration of the time period described in subclause (I) or (II) of subparagraph (B)(ii), as applicable.</text>
 </item></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id62b047b0228e40da934dc8e23563638e"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Maximum period of confinement</header><text>If a covered juvenile is placed in room confinement because the covered juvenile poses a serious and immediate risk of physical harm to himself or herself, or to others, the covered juvenile shall be released—</text>
 <clause id="idd3d2b9cd6f8b49359b78c502e8cb754b"><enum>(i)</enum><text>immediately when the covered juvenile has sufficiently gained control so as to no longer engage in behavior that threatens serious and immediate risk of physical harm to himself or herself, or to others; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="id57938e527f574838b3921d030eb50b85"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if a covered juvenile does not sufficiently gain control as described in clause (i), not later than—</text>
 <subclause id="id2828cd6c700243fbbc9fe03b2005aa23"><enum>(I)</enum><text>3 hours after being placed in room confinement, in the case of a covered juvenile who poses a serious and immediate risk of physical harm to others; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id1eb1262a034f436aa5ab87be787a1e30"><enum>(II)</enum><text>30 minutes after being placed in room confinement, in the case of a covered juvenile who poses a serious and immediate risk of physical harm only to himself or herself.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5fc325d59ad14d2c89d0644b6fc6a799"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Risk of harm after maximum period of confinement</header><text>If, after the applicable maximum period of confinement under subclause (I) or (II) of subparagraph (B)(ii) has expired, a covered juvenile continues to pose a serious and immediate risk of physical harm described in that subclause—</text>
 <clause id="id93c3000fcfac40a5ab23cfca22c67441"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the covered juvenile shall be transferred to another juvenile facility or internal location where services can be provided to the covered juvenile without relying on room confinement; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="id4a14dbaa7ccc49f1bbf6367dabc25738"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if a qualified mental health professional believes the level of crisis service needed is not currently available, a staff member of the juvenile facility shall initiate a referral to a location that can meet the needs of the covered juvenile.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0bcb9c95e4c04c02bcfae5e357bf1ebc"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Spirit and purpose</header><text>The use of consecutive periods of room confinement to evade the spirit and purpose of this subsection shall be prohibited.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="id9bbda88c41ce4a83b970c33d2943679c"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/403">chapter 403</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, as amended by section 211, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block id="ida138c7e7-91e1-4417-b9ff-99dc0c8716f8" style="OLC"><toc><toc-entry idref="id9f6ca46799b04c5185c36c8a9398322c" level="section">5045. Juvenile solitary confinement.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</subsection></section><section id="id2835f8c17d2246909313eee422804cc2"><enum>213.</enum><header>Ensuring accuracy of Federal criminal records</header>
 <subsection id="id30d6f305e41b46c289ce14dc015b6994"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 534 of title 28, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc4eace206cc2468492f69e0448e35ec3" style="OLC"> <subsection id="id4d691b9476c24a74ad01b77088a3b319"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Ensuring accuracy of federal criminal records</header> <paragraph id="idabc6af8ce589458384e8176dd30cd41f"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id3fb22c7f54f646778cf2266e691dfc03"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the term <term>applicant</term> means the individual to whom a record sought to be exchanged pertains;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd2c1874b74154264971a198e0c9914db"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the term <term>incomplete</term>, with respect to a record, means the record—</text>
 <clause id="id561289e8b4d341818170047d875420a3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>indicates that an individual was arrested but does not describe the offense for which the individual was arrested; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="idf40b4b2f9a7d48d9b2030a505277bff8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>indicates that an individual was arrested or criminal proceedings were instituted against an individual but does not include the final disposition of the arrest or of the proceedings if a final disposition has been reached;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id408db810753040809e5f5152d134917e"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the term <term>record</term> means a record or other information collected under this section that relates to—</text> <clause id="idbbde2fc29222465e92db36e02f1d9cce"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an arrest by a Federal law enforcement officer; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="id58e4dfeae7364b1091d6e49ef3c1dcbe"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a Federal criminal proceeding;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb95cca7f51bd49b487fa669646446ca7"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the term <term>reporting jurisdiction</term> means any person or entity that provides a record to the Attorney General under this section; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3f9155e9e88e4944977295b2e7c2a88b"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the term <term>requesting entity</term>—</text> <clause id="id7a2943c2e2074d30a617c70845c0a05f"><enum>(i)</enum><text>means a person or entity that seeks the exchange of a record for civil purposes that include employment, housing, credit, or any other type of application; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id981ba1feb89a4b05ac81bd8da59442f6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>does not include a law enforcement or intelligence agency that seeks the exchange of a record for—</text> <subclause id="id72ca081c128f4011a5ae9ff15a400397"><enum>(I)</enum><text>investigative purposes; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id491a30ba3fbf4765b53004a22fd92348"><enum>(II)</enum><text>purposes relating to law enforcement employment.</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9d06662a422a40579030e72c2dc29569"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Incomplete or inaccurate records</header><text>The Attorney General shall establish and enforce procedures to ensure the prompt release of accurate records exchanged for employment-related purposes through the records system created under this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="iddf8b1917029045a8be82aa4386d0b2e7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Required procedures</header><text>The procedures established under paragraph (2) shall include the following:</text> <subparagraph id="id2170c9c51751402392286a5322499a28"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Inaccurate record or information</header><text>If the Attorney General determines that a record is inaccurate, the Attorney General shall promptly correct the record, including by making deletions to the record if appropriate.</text>
								</subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6319d103363b426994cd9bffcaa83119"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Incomplete record</header>
 <clause id="id06116eb585114739a7daca9b3f407b2f"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the Attorney General determines that a record is incomplete or cannot be verified, the Attorney General—</text>
 <subclause id="idf48e28b9c387409c9f9868125c00a3a9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>shall attempt to complete or verify the record; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="id969695aab71243738afb395acfe004cb"><enum>(II)</enum><text>if unable to complete or verify the record, may promptly make any changes or deletions to the record.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="id0c06633a3d9c44869d91c65a13b38175"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Lack of disposition of arrest</header><text>For purposes of this subparagraph, an incomplete record includes a record that indicates there was an arrest and does not include the disposition of the arrest.</text>
 </clause><clause id="idc8b6bf55fa8147dca464a16b8e8b5cfc"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Obtaining disposition of arrest</header><text>If the Attorney General determines that a record is an incomplete record described in clause (ii), the Attorney General shall, not later than 10 days after the date on which the requesting entity requests the exchange and before the exchange is made, obtain the disposition (if any) of the arrest.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id75675db1971f43bfad8f6ff97f9d6d38"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Notification of reporting jurisdiction</header><text>The Attorney General shall notify each appropriate reporting jurisdiction of any action taken under subparagraph (A) or (B).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7a13515894f646afbf14634241a92e9d"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Opportunity to review records by applicant</header><text>In connection with an exchange of a record under this section, the Attorney General shall—</text> <clause id="id0b9d7bfbe96f4884973609335557344c"><enum>(i)</enum><text>notify the applicant that the applicant can obtain a copy of the record as described in clause (ii) if the applicant demonstrates a reasonable basis for the applicant’s review of the record;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idc27f4c36ca9246a886ab51768d51e198"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provide to the applicant an opportunity, upon request and in accordance with clause (i), to—</text> <subclause id="id9ab50ba2ef9a4bd7a9a0357b6f9aa46a"><enum>(I)</enum><text>obtain a copy of the record; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idb727f7ec140c4254af95892faf644025"><enum>(II)</enum><text>challenge the accuracy and completeness of the record;</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="id9ca2feb866d44062a61af7bb7a1ee3ee"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>promptly notify the requesting entity of any such challenge;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idcbd765b39bf744199ec5aecfcd58922d"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>not later than 30 days after the date on which the challenge is made, complete an investigation of the challenge;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idfd2ba2607e3142849b409a95697277e0"><enum>(v)</enum><text>provide to the applicant the specific findings and results of that investigation;</text> </clause><clause id="ida221c71b020d45edb4d2e60e7fc09b60"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>promptly make any changes or deletions to the records required as a result of the challenge; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idd93e4243470047b894a55b0e7266e421"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>report those changes to the requesting entity.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddd7b3b34bed640d8ac577aa4fc6e6cc7"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Certain exchanges prohibited</header> <clause id="id2e37eab5e7c3404396793433d397b56d"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An exchange shall not include any record—</text>
 <subclause id="id89b4cfe58908408ea79f1dc2a212d0f9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>except as provided in clause (ii), about an arrest more than 2 years old as of the date of the request for the exchange, that does not also include a disposition (if any) of that arrest;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id5f1313180f384fe98f5c08a41308ff86"><enum>(II)</enum><text>relating to an adult or juvenile nonserious offense of the sort described in section 20.32(b) of title 28, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on July 1, 2009; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="iddb31b6a8c5f24bd78aae30f2958cf101"><enum>(III)</enum><text>to the extent the record is not clearly an arrest or a disposition of an arrest.</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="id21225ada5e0f45eea018ba96242dacea"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Applicants for sensitive positions</header><text>The prohibition under clause (i)(I) shall not apply in the case of a background check that relates to—</text>
 <subclause id="id37c6e06ca708470fa7ad3ccec2fe3f5d"><enum>(I)</enum><text>law enforcement employment; or</text> </subclause><subclause id="id630c9dec7aa44da98da72862fd2dc01f"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any position that a Federal agency designates as a—</text>
 <item id="idcaf7c23d5ee1440984922a7bd3275a8a"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>national security position; or</text> </item><item id="idce5597ee32fd4e3ca95c842f82833734"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>high-risk, public trust position.</text>
 </item></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id449c20da6c7e49c498b157a5ba76240d"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Fees</header><text>The Attorney General may collect a reasonable fee for an exchange of records for employment-related purposes through the records system created under this section to defray the costs associated with exchanges for those purposes, including any costs associated with the investigation of inaccurate or incomplete records.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="ide887a6ac4acc4781887fd362d1d57cd8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Regulations on reasonable procedures</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall issue regulations to carry out section 534(g) of title 28, United States Code, as added by subsection (a).</text>
				</subsection><subsection id="ide2db219831f64b71bcc9d888e99e503a"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header>
 <paragraph id="idb8b925cb78064055bfbea14e287748ad"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>record</term> has the meaning given the term in subsection (g) of section 534 of title 28, United States Code, as added by subsection (a).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id10efa5e56457412db5bbbbee05e1747c"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report required</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall submit to Congress a report on the implementation of subsection (g) of section 534 of title 28, United States Code, as added by subsection (a), that includes—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id1b2a9a62492b46bf97440b4170698b9a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of exchanges of records for employment-related purposes made with entities in each State through the records system created under such section 534;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfc902ced10e240f7990b92c7666fbf33"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any prolonged failure of a Federal agency to comply with a request by the Attorney General for information about dispositions of arrests; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide9c68cbd5fda4cada1d235fda198bd95"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the numbers of successful and unsuccessful challenges to the accuracy and completeness of records, organized by the Federal agency from which each record originated.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></title></legis-body>
</bill>


