<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S2070 IS: Gender Advancement in Pay Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-09-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2070</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150922">September 22, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S340">Ms. Ayotte</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to provide more effective remedies to victims of
			 discrimination in the payment of wages on the basis of sex, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HE8DA87774A974135AC37494B074BB5B1" style="OLC">
 <section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB2DEF33A4CA448C6907BE96333A3C88A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Gender Advancement in Pay Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>GAP Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idA692FD58E42D43A9BD965D6F93578DE7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Enhanced prohibition on wage discrimination</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 6(d) of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/206">29 U.S.C. 206(d)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="id03F06187991D421A9FEA8D79434D276A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id858499A860574F5B96323D3F08B733B6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in clause (iii), by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9EC00936B450455C8109DBCEFF0254AF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating clause (iv) as clause (vi);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD03B7072B6F3400C898BD2C220CF6418"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting before clause (vi), as redesignated by subparagraph (B) of this paragraph, the following: <quote>(iv) a differential based on expertise; (v) a shift differential; or</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD4524D32410B4F52A023CE54CD4BAD9E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in clause (vi), as redesignated by subparagraph (B) of this paragraph, by striking <quote>any other factor other than sex</quote> and inserting <quote>a business-related factor other than sex, including but not limited to education, training, or experience</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id7C66AAC09D5442D38AED6429D09CDDED"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (4) as paragraph (5); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id650CBFEA34E7489BAAFCAC89CDD89C96"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (3) the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0297207D064D439288002661A1984D87" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="id8652741A20F944BEA72195ADF0A5A8AC" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>If a charge is filed by or on behalf of an employee for a violation of title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000e">42 U.S.C. 2000e et seq.</external-xref>), and an action is brought by or on behalf of the employee for a violation of this subsection, with respect to the same practice, or if an action is brought before the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission by or on behalf of the employee for a violation of this subsection, the statute of limitations for the action involved under section 6 of the Portal-to-Portal Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/255">29 U.S.C. 255</external-xref>) shall be tolled until the earlier of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id69B9739E0B6E4BA8B3035256D20054CA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the date on which the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission or the Attorney General brings an action or provides notification to the employee with respect to the charge under section 706(f)(1) of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000e-5">42 U.S.C. 2000e–5(f)(1)</external-xref>); or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF521F7F853A84E0285150C0D718789F8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the date that is 270 days after the date on which such charge is filed.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></section><section id="H8516C5469FEE4D9F8F5E0B58E9B653D0"><enum>3.</enum><header>Nonretaliation provision</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 15 of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/215">29 U.S.C. 215</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HE295212230534A4FA6DEC65771C3DB0A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(3), by striking <quote>employee has filed</quote> and all that follows and inserting</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HBCAE2EB44C694DE0B096AFF11CF6CF26" style="OLC">
 <text>employee—</text><subparagraph id="H240B8FDFE2C04D57B7C3592A02378EE3"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has made a charge or filed any complaint or instituted or caused to be instituted any investigation, proceeding, hearing, or action under or related to this Act, including an investigation conducted by the employer, or has testified or is planning to testify or has assisted or participated in any manner in any such investigation, proceeding, hearing, or action, or has served or is planning to serve on an industry committee; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9F14CC66A69240C1B39B074605D7CABF"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has inquired about, discussed, or disclosed the wages of the employee or another employee, or has declined to discuss or disclose the wages of the employee;</text>
					</subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;
				and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC5046635716540EFAAA5F2BAF724D769"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6E924E5794F64BBAA5D489C798A5F63E" style="traditional">
 <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H847638761F97495E9C7568216A7586E7"><enum>(c)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id86398FA576CE46A5A24E12EB6DE93588"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (a)(3)(B) shall not apply to an instance in which an employee who has access to the wage information of other employees as a part of such employee’s essential job functions discloses the wages of any of such other employees to an individual who does not otherwise have access to such information, unless such disclosure is in response to a charge or complaint or in furtherance of an investigation, proceeding, hearing, or action under or related to section 6(d), including an investigation conducted by the employer.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idFABA44AB615E4C9CA66778DB30728170" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Subsection (a)(3)(B) shall not apply to an instance in which an employee engages in an inquiry, discussion, or disclosure that is prohibited by the terms and conditions of a provision, applicable to the employee, of—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0E35B180A4A44CC49C11C98105367924"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a confidential settlement;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id893059108E004B38BE76C50228F9B2C1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a severance agreement;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7AFA37FB4E4C4209A05B5953BAF8C088"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a noncompete, nondisclosure, or nondisparagement clause of an agreement; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB9CAC3ADD87C44C1996A5154583C98B9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any post-employment agreement similar to an agreement described in subparagraph (A) or (B), or a clause described in subparagraph (C).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4A5753F20B3C45DAB5FCDCD8E4FF1F80" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any employer who requires an employee to sign a contract or waiver (other than a provision described in paragraph (2)) that would prohibit the employee from disclosing information about the employee's wages shall be considered to have committed an unlawful act under subsection (a)(3)(B).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id527DB99DCF034DD9AA5E4C47AFEE863F" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to limit the rights of an employee provided under any other provision of law.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></section><section id="id5513c6f3048b4a4e9459a2cdfa2f0960"><enum>4.</enum><header>Civil penalty</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 16(e) of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/216">29 U.S.C. 216(e)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="id1ed3fcd067c147fdb19ffcb8c2e728a8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id133eb335ca8d453c813213a3c6b2f1b6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(2)</quote> and inserting <quote>(2)(A)</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD2520A5EB6F943E0B56A61D3A1405F11"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide625a8891a91475582102316c76b214a" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="id0408f1b54a77465990cf10bffc83b18a" indent="up2"><enum>(B)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idC58605C134A44304A81C4AB4D525F3A9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Any person who willfully violates section 6(d) shall be subject to—</text> <subclause id="idAD917566D58242BF90CC67D6ED3795BA" indent="up1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a civil penalty in an amount described in clause (ii) for each employee affected (less the amount of any penalty the person has paid under State law for the wage differential involved); and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id63E071D5153549A6AF965A9BDE4867DB" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any penalty that may apply under subparagraph (A).</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="idA2B427CEF7E14FB2B6836EDA553D3E46" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The amount referred to in clause (i)(I) shall be—</text> <subclause id="idABB575C79FAA441B9F37C15E218D25BA"><enum>(I)</enum><text>for an employer with not more than 100 employees, the lesser of the amount of the liquidated damages available under subsection (b) or (c), or $2,500;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idF80AAAA35E4E468582E0820D284EE2D7"><enum>(II)</enum><text>for an employer with not less than 101 and not more than 200 employees, the lesser of the amount of the liquidated damages available under subsection (b) or (c), or $5,000;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id5A8E0C446A7449E7B094D91CACA04637"><enum>(III)</enum><text>for an employer with not less than 201 and not more than 500 employees, the lesser of the amount of the liquidated damages available under subsection (b) or (c), or $10,000; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id31D46E896C2E408384F17D8F222E6B68"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>for an employer with not less than 501 employees, the lesser of the amount of the liquidated damages available under subsection (b) or (c), or $15,000.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id44518A23667F4B0EA8BB422048CD3B86"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), in the first sentence, by striking <quote>this subsection</quote> and inserting ‘‘this subsection (other than paragraph (2)(B)); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idF361968EDF2C4954AB63B1AC48200A19"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (5)—</text> <subparagraph id="id4388C998523C434E85C7CD01AC2560E4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the first sentence, by striking <quote>violations of section 12</quote> and inserting <quote>violations of section 6(d) or section 12</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB2F6C8653792485A9141A17EAAE2F44D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after the first sentence the following: <quote>Civil penalties collected for violations of section 6(d) shall be deposited in the account created under section 5(d) of the GAP Act.</quote>.</text>
				</subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="id3CC29890CB114A468A26B5FC934FD150"><enum>5.</enum><header>Study on high-wage, high-demand occupations and equivalent pay</header>
 <subsection id="idE58C8D4904884674A5604FF84D0ECF82"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Joint Study</header><text>Using funds from the account created under subsection (d), the Secretary of Labor, together with the Secretary of Education, shall conduct a multistate study, through a grant to a nonprofit research institution, that includes strategies to increase the participation of women in—</text>
 <paragraph id="id82DCB04D236646B39BAD440D2AEE15C3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>high-wage, high-demand occupations; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idC384EA4C772641898279D8D1D16014D1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>industries in which women are underrepresented.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idCD81BEC18E5E482F8A855B7CBFEB7E4E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Comptroller General Study</header><text>Using funds from the account created under subsection (d), the Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a multistate study to develop strategies described in subsection (a).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id8ABCE462F9A342038DBDDCD8F364033E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reports</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act—</text> <paragraph id="idD0C962E64CD245F0B31ADE762C1388BF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Secretary of Labor and the Secretary of Education shall submit to Congress a report containing—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idEA2CFCE91FAE478981C9B54C3C86B7B6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a statement of the findings and conclusions of the study under subsection (a); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id16895D4CE3CC4E12AF1745655CCB7764"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any recommendations the Secretary of Labor and the Secretary of Education consider appropriate based on their conclusions;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id51D12E491C954F668F6F2C4D43C1AD15"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Comptroller General shall submit to Congress a report containing—</text> <subparagraph id="id30392B5ABEC6408FB96BA3D6367CF28C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a statement of the findings and conclusions of the study under subsection (b); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id231CC1F33CE94B2DB2E77070D22633B9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any recommendations the Comptroller General considers appropriate based on its conclusions; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idD22DA8F2B50848DCB209C9A3CBD691D0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Secretary of Labor, the Secretary of Education, and the Comptroller General shall make available to the public the reports described in this subsection.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id7D0F163002F0440A8E9598EE950BFB4B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Accounts</header>
 <paragraph id="idF4C026BAD5784D37ABC193B496C6360B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Labor shall create an account to manage the funds required to conduct the studies under subsections (a) and (b) and to complete the reports under subsection (c). The account shall contain the civil penalties collected under section 16(e)(2) of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/216">29 U.S.C. 216(e)(2)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idAF7F50F92EC2454BB79FEC92EC28C916"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Withdrawal of funds</header><text>The Secretary of Labor is authorized to withdraw funds from the account created under subsection (d) to carry out the joint study under subsection (a).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id73A9FCADD6A34D34AE0759EEFF1389A4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Transfer of funds</header><text>At the request of the Comptroller General, the Secretary of Labor shall transfer to the Comptroller General the funds required to carry out the study under subsection (b).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3407A00109D04DB898E94CF18D145D46"><enum>6.</enum><header>Small Business
			 Assistance</header>
			<subsection id="H776F4F08443A435D8D2354FC26B23D23"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Effective
 date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act and the amendments made by this Act shall take effect on the date that is 6 months after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HEA0F16E89A4B4A01BAB990A4AB4A1ED9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical
 assistance materials</header><text>The Secretary of Labor and the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission shall jointly develop technical assistance materials to assist small businesses in complying with the requirements of this Act and the amendments made by this Act.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HDC4EAF99E55D431E92E67D3CF01E7768"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Small
 Businesses</header><text>A small business shall be exempt from the provisions of this Act, and the amendments made by this Act, to the same extent that such business is exempt from the requirements of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 pursuant to clauses (i) and (ii) of section 3(s)(1)(A) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/203">29 U.S.C. 203(s)(1)(A)</external-xref>).</text>
			</subsection></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA2D86D4FFC954F7599CEA30A4E98B039"><enum>7.</enum><header>Rule of
 Construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act, or in any amendment made by this Act, shall affect the obligation of employers and employees to fully comply with all applicable immigration laws, including any penalties, fines, or other sanctions.</text></section></legis-body></bill>


