<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1719 IS: Recognize, Assist, Include, Support, and Engage Family Caregivers Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 1719</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150708">July 8, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S252">Ms. Collins</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S354">Ms. Baldwin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S340">Ms. Ayotte</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S182">Ms. Mikulski</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To provide for the establishment and maintenance of a National Family Caregiving Strategy, and for
			 other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Recognize, Assist, Include, Support, and Engage Family Caregivers Act of 2015</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>RAISE Family Caregivers Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </section><section id="idB364F1759AE1480C9972C5C28BAA2A51"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="idE9CD91E8359840DCA8A28D9D23AEF71A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Advisory Council</header><text>The term <term>Advisory Council</term> means the Family Caregiving Advisory Council convened under section 4.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idEF9D48375A854A71A5575D4F4D45FD7C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Family caregiver</header><text>The term <term>family caregiver</term> means a relative, partner, friend, or neighbor who has a significant relationship with, and who provides a broad range of assistance for, a person with a chronic or other health condition, disability, or functional limitation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id7B78495FC33C46A2BD42F0645B48B971"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idA398A4DD54534930B84450797D8ECBCD"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Strategy</header><text>The term <term>Strategy</term> means the National Family Caregiving Strategy established, maintained, and updated under section 3.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="id52DCCE35212D4B4E81B89644077E087E"><enum>3.</enum><header>National Family Caregiving Strategy</header>
 <subsection id="id0EBAE92B432340F6BB491101B17364F8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the heads of other appropriate Federal agencies, shall develop, maintain, and periodically update a National Family Caregiving Strategy.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idF668C2BF7CCF4EE38026F5C473113871"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The Strategy shall identify specific actions that Federal, State, and local governments, communities, health care, long-term services and supports and other providers, employers, and others can take to recognize and support family caregivers in a culturally competent manner, including with respect to the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="id04FEA006A1914DDA937CBF4E4F09FB11"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Promoting greater adoption of person- and family-centered care in all health and long-term services and supports settings, with the person receiving services and supports and the family caregiver (as appropriate) at the center of care teams.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id11160A6244F047E394F08AD6E4BC077C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Assessment and service planning (including care transitions and coordination) involving family caregivers and care recipients.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idD3005078F072420597E28D4BFE2A4D6A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Training and other supports.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id7F92AB315FC441569CEAA1B9C11CC07D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Information, education, referral, and care coordination, including hospice, palliative care, and advance planning services.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id26052C91E1EA4F6394B8B7A60FAB5DFC"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Respite options.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id6E835BD7F5F746BB8F0D5877B4673057"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Financial security.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id2C64B2380C994980B23C3E52FD61B2EC"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Workplace policies and supports that allow family caregivers to remain in the workforce.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id298D55DD79C24B8286D01DCE3448D1C4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Responsibilities of the Secretary</header><text>The Secretary, in carrying out this section, shall be responsible for the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="id743907B8840A481B8A4DE20A2E97C056"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Collecting and making publically available information, including evidence-based or promising practices and innovative models (both domestically and internationally) regarding the provision of care by family caregivers or support for family caregivers.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idD02D6DA33221410F92A198751B2E96D9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Coordinating Federal Government programs and activities to recognize and support family caregivers while ensuring maximum effectiveness and avoiding unnecessary duplication.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id35C5487AF14D45DDA15FF520126693EA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Providing technical assistance, such as best practices and information sharing, to State or local efforts, as appropriate, to support family caregivers.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idBD228B0095DF441E8A1D688DAA546A17"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Addressing disparities in recognizing and supporting family caregivers and meeting the needs of the diverse family caregiving population.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idDEDE71911F734B7D84110C90CB838B33"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Assessing all Federal programs regarding family caregivers, including with respect to funding levels.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idAC178853D1C34370882E38285E8D4E0B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Initial strategy; updates</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text> <paragraph id="id4FF21723E71443FFA26483CBA3FAE1D5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, develop, publish, and submit to Congress the initial Strategy incorporating the items addressed in the Advisory Council's report in section 4(d)(2) and other priority actions for recognizing and supporting family caregivers; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id9ECCD366CA364767B639EC7D61E46EEE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not less than annually, update, republish, and submit to Congress the Strategy, taking into account the most recent annual report submitted under section 4(d)(1)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idC16FE329FEDE40EF9D28C5258A234A20"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to reflect new developments, challenges, opportunities, and solutions; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5776229D04AC4D3D931766475BDD8657"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to assess progress in implementation of the Strategy and, based on the results of such assessment, recommend priority actions for such implementation.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idD8995059B8FB4AD8997BA3CCC4DE3CBB"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Process for public input</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a process for public input to inform the development of, and updates to, the Strategy, including a process for the public to submit recommendations to the Advisory Council and an opportunity for public comment on the proposed Strategy.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idD339984392D64344938D367E29B01073"><enum>(f)</enum><header>No preemption</header><text>Nothing in this Act preempts any authority of a State or local government to recognize or support family caregivers.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="id9FA864FD9AD94B21AB979ECFB02841DD"><enum>4.</enum><header>Family Caregiving Advisory Council</header>
 <subsection id="id1521E643AAE84E5797F4CC63A201C099"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Convening</header><text>The Secretary shall convene a Family Caregiving Advisory Council to provide advice to the Secretary on recognizing and supporting family caregivers.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="idD3E2C880C5954F24AE0B42EB5294285A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership</header>
 <paragraph id="id5CD4E6474B374A158D9C05275D2DEFE2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The members of the Advisory Council shall consist of—</text> <subparagraph id="id186E09F14474478BABE923B0B5C5221A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Federal members under paragraph (2); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE557CFBB1C934112BEA7AA4B184E80BB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the appointed members under paragraph (3).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id004BCFF4CD614480A836142B1ADC2FD1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federal members</header><text>The Federal members of the Advisory Council shall consist of the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="id9C9E964F82C04F0194FFA8F38A7B6E1B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Administrator of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (or the Administrator's designee).</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id516276D3428A496F89E7E3B8CBA6F9FA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Administrator of the Administration for Community Living (or the Administrator's designee who has experience in both aging and disability).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC986803D01C64160AEA94273938953D1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Assistant Secretary for the Administration for Children and Families (or the Assistant Secretary's designee).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id726D5BF4DDDB41D9B5141041F8D0D9F2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs (or the Secretary's designee).</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id55512B9EA48648D0A360164E4780EF12"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The Secretary of Labor (or the Secretary's designee).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8EDE52803A09415B91921622AECD0F24"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The Secretary of the Treasury (or the Secretary's designee).</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC60058B17886490485E369A3F1B58764"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The National Coordinator for Health Information Technology (or the National Coordinator's designee).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC95FB570F9EE4F17BDFAFCF9661AE032"><enum>(H)</enum><text>The heads of other Federal departments or agencies (or their designees), as appointed by the President or the Chair of the Advisory Council.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idEBD3062D4B954D7489E44B1D9E36FFE4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Appointed members</header><text>In addition to the Federal members under paragraph (2), the Secretary shall appoint not more than 15 members of the Advisory Council who are not representatives of Federal departments or agencies and who shall include at least one representative of each of the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="idA11876909B3F4C86932EC1D31F2A960A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Family caregivers.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9761D1F1BE1745C8A44064D620CFF862"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Older adults with long-term services and supports needs, including older adults facing disparities.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1A5C56203678420FB21EFB392698C44C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Individuals with disabilities.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5679B20074244BB59C155F5DC1A36CF9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Advocates for family caregivers, older adults with long-term services and supports needs, and individuals with disabilities.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id22C14554D3464AE6B6D9232F7DEB3954"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Health care and social service providers.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idCE93D73F9BF3437F97820D3B2F56F688"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Long-term services and supports providers.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3BE0261ED601402CA82E5F904E1F81E4"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Employers.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF32A7DFFF5084ED69CAB501364821EFC"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Direct care workers or advocates for such workers.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idFC528302EE5D48A8A0C38BF7B0203959"><enum>(I)</enum><text>State and local officials.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idDA7AEF70755D42E0885586DBB57144CE"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Accreditation bodies.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5B8A9888FCF340DFA1670D888B42C394"><enum>(K)</enum><text>Relevant industries.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id85F97F43A4104A51928F251BA426B59E"><enum>(L)</enum><text>Veterans.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1749B9B1FF514C19B2840F5420E6F853"><enum>(M)</enum><text>As appropriate, other experts in family caregiving.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idABD4FE75ECA340B9AA4A7410CB0AEDBE"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Diverse representation</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that the membership of the Advisory Council reflects the diversity of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idDA7ACA70AF0C4ABCBA0F9C0273E845AA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the overall population; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id22A661F275674AF780DE539013606A48"><enum>(B)</enum><text>family caregivers.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idF87633BF83404194806617D016DFD372"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text>The Advisory Council shall meet quarterly. Meetings of the Advisory Council shall be open to the public.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="id160AA9EF0F824DB4BEAA2249D31DFA56"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Advisory Council annual reports</header>
 <paragraph id="id2E9812CA05A7417088BE64E9B5684A8E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 15 months after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Advisory Council shall submit to the Secretary and Congress a report concerning the development, maintenance, and updating of the Strategy and the implementation thereof, including a description of the outcomes of the recommendations and priorities under paragraph (2), as appropriate. Such report shall be made publically available by the Advisory Council.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idABA25085ADE64709821E67500284AA5F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Initial report</header><text>The Advisory Council's initial report under paragraph (1) shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="id7B4832AA79E44C298CD0127D4749FF78"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an inventory and assessment of all federally funded efforts to recognize and support family caregivers and the outcomes of such efforts, including analyses of the extent to which federally funded efforts are reaching family caregivers and gaps in such efforts;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6EFEAA90E3A2418DBACCB91D8EE76FEC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>recommendations for priority actions—</text> <clause id="id93A8C82BE20847F49DB5EDE73433B304"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to improve and better coordinate programs; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id5768051CE5DC4D0BB372A81B24359625"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to deliver services based on the performance, mission, and purpose of a program while eliminating redundancies and ensuring the needs of family caregivers are met;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9D7205811CB643AC9CCEEC85CCAEEEBB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>recommendations to reduce the financial impact and other challenges of caregiving on family caregivers; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7FFA5C5BB88D4C2F85F4048F51DBFD26"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an evaluation of how family caregiving impacts the Medicare program, and Medicaid program, and other Federal programs.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id5A252E34AC5C46E3B63505ED329F37E0"><enum>5.</enum><header>Sharing of data</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The heads of Federal departments and agencies, as appropriate, shall share with the Secretary any data that is—</text>
 <paragraph id="id6B6F27E647BA473AB635A5D48B7004FF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>maintained by the respective department or agency; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id0C41321677C742D6A16D38F754E76EA6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>needed by the Secretary to prepare the initial and updated Strategies under section 3(d).</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="id420AC8A501AE41A3BAED7B1C283CE2D9"><enum>6.</enum><header>Sunset provision</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The authority and obligations established by this Act shall terminate on December 31, 2030.</text></section></legis-body> </bill> 

