<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1285 IS: Coal with Carbon Capture and Sequestration Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 1285</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150511">May 11, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S360">Ms. Heitkamp</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S338">Mr. Manchin</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To authorize the Secretary of Energy to enter into contracts to provide certain price stabilization
			 support relating to electric generation units that use coal-based
			 generation technology.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
 <section id="id395EE4BD82CE4DBFA0755A6C09756E81" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Coal with Carbon Capture and Sequestration Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="id2f0bd14895174cf381efb06898d7386e"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text>
 <paragraph id="idf795be11efd240768b11b83a454aef4f"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the high cost of installing and using technology to capture carbon dioxide from coal-fueled electric generating units can be mitigated by providing certainty, for a limited period of time, with respect to revenues from the sale of captured carbon dioxide;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idc7ddfc66ccfc426db345411036c2b87a"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the volatility of crude oil prices that determine the price paid for carbon dioxide creates uncertain market prices for carbon dioxide that is purchased and used to recover crude oil or for other beneficial purposes;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id0bbc41e7c08042d6a0fd4cfb852769cf"><enum>(3)</enum><text>assistance to stabilize the price received for carbon dioxide captured during the use of coal provides a degree of certainty to debt providers and investors with respect to the revenues to be received from the sale of carbon dioxide; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id24f8d6ca35ff4f3e85601136ebba18f8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>creating added certainty that captured carbon dioxide would receive a certain, agreed upon price for a limited period of time would help to ensure that carbon capture and storage technology would be developed and used.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="id745B2DB00550401CB657AA33489AEC17"><enum>3.</enum><header>Contracting authority of the Secretary</header>
 <subsection id="id82517F9D753749DB92F02CDF3BB628D2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition of electric generation unit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>electric generation unit</term> means an electric generation unit that uses coal-based generation technology.</text> </subsection><subsection id="idb0774ae11b994957a8e3bfd3c243298d"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contracting authority</header><text>Beginning on the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Energy may enter into binding contracts on behalf of the Federal Government, the duration of which shall not exceed 25 years, with qualified parties to provide price stabilization support for electricity generated at an electric generation unit or carbon dioxide captured from an electric generation unit and sold to a purchaser for—</text>
 <paragraph id="id8656A4DDB58040EE9B84A7FB77C4CAB5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the recovery of crude oil; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idAF935A1440B347F68636592C059CF3FF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>other purposes for which a commercial market exists.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


