<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1660 IS: To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to modify and make permanent bonus depreciation.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-06-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1660</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150624">June 24, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S260">Mr. Roberts</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S305">Mr. Isakson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S342">Mr. Blunt</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S351">Mr. Toomey</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to modify and make permanent bonus depreciation.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H7AD02115CBDA44A9814116068420FC8F" style="OLC">
		<section id="HC254B35ADF5E4E25B7EFDF5522F93491" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Bonus depreciation modified and made permanent</header>
			<subsection id="H5AC944420720497FB4C8360E4C734774"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Made permanent; applicable to qualified improvement property</header>
 <paragraph id="HB425BE83121A415A92ED9A50D7969DB0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/168">Section 168(k)(2)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block id="H537ADA5FE24A49E68E86F4F344775050" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H57559245F2C24011A85079233CE7FB08"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualified property</header><text>For purposes of this subsection—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HBDB4C017AE81432BBE6B9593AFC18370"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <quote>qualified property</quote> means property—</text> <clause id="H246F8F0D3B8241A48574D61B80B0EBA1"><enum>(i)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H486C7F67AA3D4256B2D8143AF3965B4D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to which this section applies which has a recovery period of 20 years or less,</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H7811E2AFA1E74BBCA0CA3135E2BBDF96" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>which is computer software (as defined in section 167(f)(1)(B)) for which a deduction is allowable under section 167(a) without regard to this subsection,</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HB7EBE272037D4284808DD17C6C8626F6" indent="up1"><enum>(III)</enum><text>which is water utility property, or</text> </subclause><subclause id="HF4D777403CC04F71A8282D25BA95E4A0" indent="up1"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>which is qualified improvement property, and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HAB18C6AA65F24A9CB6B8C9675A0FBC88"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the original use of which commences with the taxpayer.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H31B3E77D134A46BBBF690428DC44F728"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception for alternative depreciation property</header><text>The term <quote>qualified property</quote> shall not include any property to which the alternative depreciation system under subsection (g) applies, determined—</text>
 <clause id="H712D2B6D92DA4175B8520CA57C3E9927"><enum>(i)</enum><text>without regard to paragraph (7) of subsection (g) (relating to election to have system apply), and</text> </clause><clause id="H80B9156966044084864EB8C79EDFD098"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>after application of section 280F(b) (relating to listed property with limited business use).</text>
								</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H434EF52DE7DD488CBEC1135A18BEE60A"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Special rules</header>
 <clause id="H68BF1CC53F944274B9B53013438A0745"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Sale-leasebacks</header><text>For purposes of clause (ii) and subparagraph (A)(ii), if property is—</text> <subclause id="H1B66336356B6467EBB29926264F8DFC1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>originally placed in service by a person, and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H66C26EB26B9F4CEFA8276F7308979E6E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>sold and leased back by such person within 3 months after the date such property was originally placed in service,</text>
									</subclause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="clause">such property shall be treated as originally placed in service not earlier than the date on which
 such property is used under the leaseback referred to in subclause (II).</continuation-text></clause><clause id="H0498D16D100A4188B6B59918AA8D89E6"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Syndication</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A)(ii), if—</text> <subclause id="H0BA2FF220FAD4E70AAADC20E3BC2FF09"><enum>(I)</enum><text>property is originally placed in service by the lessor of such property,</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HB06181EC05F94A9AA0F0066FB5E906CC"><enum>(II)</enum><text>such property is sold by such lessor or any subsequent purchaser within 3 months after the date such property was originally placed in service (or, in the case of multiple units of property subject to the same lease, within 3 months after the date the final unit is placed in service, so long as the period between the time the first unit is placed in service and the time the last unit is placed in service does not exceed 12 months), and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H795F64FD008546B2A3A4DF523C38A391"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the user of such property after the last sale during such 3-month period remains the same as when such property was originally placed in service,</text>
									</subclause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="clause">such property shall be treated as originally placed in service not earlier than the date of such
 last sale.</continuation-text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8937EB2333644199B138EAF48736C4B7"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Coordination with section 280F</header><text>For purposes of section 280F—</text> <clause id="HDD9EF615BC06426D944107E03A681A1F"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Automobiles</header><text>In the case of a passenger automobile (as defined in section 280F(d)(5)) which is qualified property, the Secretary shall increase the limitation under section 280F(a)(1)(A)(i) by $8,000.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB4499D3FDBED440A891C832DEFE93370"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Listed property</header><text>The deduction allowable under paragraph (1) shall be taken into account in computing any recapture amount under section 280F(b)(2).</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1DCE999C954941BEA3167C0A751DDC91"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Inflation adjustment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any taxable year beginning in a calendar year after 2015, the $8,000 amount in clause (i) shall be increased by an amount equal to—</text>
 <subclause id="H4FFFC85E0D70410FA0F3F3860660F8FA"><enum>(I)</enum><text>such dollar amount, multiplied by</text> </subclause><subclause id="H2ECF83C8D04147EAABC2E60EC9BC5E00"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the automobile price inflation adjustment determined under section 280F(d)(7)(B)(i) for the calendar year in which such taxable year begins by substituting <quote>2014</quote> for <quote>1987</quote> in subclause (II) thereof.</text>
									</subclause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="clause">If any increase under the preceding sentence is not a multiple of $100, such increase shall be
 rounded to the nearest multiple of $100.</continuation-text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD888A0970BA7459AB5630A0E52FECFBE"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Deduction allowed in computing minimum tax</header><text>For purposes of determining alternative minimum taxable income under section 55, the deduction under section 167 for qualified property shall be determined without regard to any adjustment under section 56.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1825EC2FB54442878D02B4FACB2FEE88"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualified improvement property</header><text>Section 168(k)(3) of such Code is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H20F2BA11EEA046E9BE11ECEC0D4E7423" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HB1794BF2E4E24E43BF845A5EF81AF1C1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Qualified improvement property</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H36871271BED647AD8D02E230E134420B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <quote>qualified improvement property</quote> means any improvement to an interior portion of a building which is nonresidential real property if such improvement is placed in service after the date such building was first placed in service.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H704E82984DDE48E6B10E3A91F7D1F199"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Certain improvements not included</header><text>Such term shall not include any improvement for which the expenditure is attributable to—</text> <clause id="H17FAEDD808524010B4A09548B6D55B40"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the enlargement of the building,</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6C5002825A554C44BB2AD70D700AECB9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any elevator or escalator, or</text> </clause><clause id="HFF1BB7FF89BD489092550AF554ED460F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the internal structural framework of the building.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7382281542344C9789CDDE02A3B544D4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Expansion of Election To Accelerate AMT Credits in Lieu of Bonus Depreciation</header><text>Section 168(k)(4) of such Code is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block id="HE35A84807FEC4EA4A8E3E02AC98DEE64" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HAB27115FC557432899E5F12C5672DDB5"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Election to accelerate amt credits in lieu of bonus depreciation</header> <subparagraph id="H73AA132F8AE94C8687765B06F7D03922"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If a corporation elects to have this paragraph apply for any taxable year—</text>
 <clause id="H15FC0C72DCF44D28BFAA5B581893F01D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>paragraphs (1) and (2)(D) shall not apply to any qualified property placed in service during such taxable year,</text>
 </clause><clause id="H02CD927FD3D446768435A436802F408D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the applicable depreciation method used under this section with respect to such property shall be the straight line method, and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC48729B2AA084E4287002D5EF216CA00"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the limitation imposed by section 53(c) for such taxable year shall be increased by the bonus depreciation amount which is determined for such taxable year under subparagraph (B).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H015B64EA857046F78CBCB113E85C5B52"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Bonus depreciation amount</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph—</text> <clause id="HF0B2CB9400784F96945C5973216E9A99"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The bonus depreciation amount for any taxable year is an amount equal to 20 percent of the excess (if any) of—</text>
 <subclause id="H615AC2C05D9F4835A4381A71C2B255D2"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the aggregate amount of depreciation which would be allowed under this section for qualified property placed in service by the taxpayer during such taxable year if paragraph (1) applied to all such property (and, in the case of any such property which is a passenger automobile (as defined in section 280F(d)(5)), if paragraph (2)(D) applied to such automobile), over</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HD21D7B9BF3604F4DB21D4959DE8A22F9"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the aggregate amount of depreciation which would be allowed under this section for qualified property placed in service by the taxpayer during such taxable year if paragraphs (1) and (2)(D) did not apply to any such property.</text>
								</subclause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="clause">The aggregate amounts determined under subclauses (I) and (II) shall be determined without regard
			 to any election made under subparagraph (A) or subsection (b)(2)(D),
 (b)(3)(D), or (g)(7).</continuation-text></clause><clause id="H97AC6CDB1C334F83B4C950667118B1E3"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The bonus depreciation amount for any taxable year shall not exceed the lesser of—</text> <subclause id="HC79A9FECAB2C431C89459A8B9FFE3D7C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>50 percent of the minimum tax credit under section 53(b) for the first taxable year ending after December 31, 2014, or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H668306EACFA24B27B1A22D2905041620"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the minimum tax credit under section 53(b) for such taxable year determined by taking into account only the adjusted net minimum tax for taxable years ending before January 1, 2015 (determined by treating credits as allowed on a first-in, first-out basis).</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H398A39178CD44BD8B68B16033C412C2A"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Aggregation rule</header><text>All corporations which are treated as a single employer under section 52(a) shall be treated—</text> <subclause id="H90907022574347ECAACEA5A101F4E99C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>as 1 taxpayer for purposes of this paragraph, and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H4DF75343AAA146C285444F7574A8E48C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>as having elected the application of this paragraph if any such corporation so elects.</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEA53F5535A71427A82A6528881AC325D"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Credit refundable</header><text>For purposes of section 6401(b), the aggregate increase in the credits allowable under part IV of subchapter A for any taxable year resulting from the application of this paragraph shall be treated as allowed under subpart C of such part (and not any other subpart).</text>
						</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF7E8B426374436D947A5B528564367C"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Other rules</header>
 <clause id="HF71A3C84987241A5A03906E30DF33101"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Election</header><text>Any election under this paragraph may be revoked only with the consent of the Secretary.</text> </clause><clause id="H12488C5AC46748828F9F6D3D9131B9D8"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Partnerships with electing partners</header><text>In the case of a corporation which is a partner in a partnership and which makes an election under subparagraph (A) for the taxable year, for purposes of determining such corporation’s distributive share of partnership items under section 702 for such taxable year—</text>
 <subclause id="HACC2C53E59814EF8BECD88F12C300D04"><enum>(I)</enum><text>paragraphs (1) and (2)(D) shall not apply to any qualified property placed in service during such taxable year, and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H41844D1C73CC4E33BA88EA96C01CD4A5"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the applicable depreciation method used under this section with respect to such property shall be the straight line method.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H4E7E1AB697C344F08847C428241DC858"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Certain partnerships</header><text>In the case of a partnership in which more than 50 percent of the capital and profits interests are owned (directly or indirectly) at all times during the taxable year by 1 corporation (or by corporations treated as 1 taxpayer under subparagraph (B)(iii)), each partner shall compute its bonus depreciation amount under clause (i) of subparagraph (B) by taking into account its distributive share of the amounts determined by the partnership under subclauses (I) and (II) of such clause for the taxable year of the partnership ending with or within the taxable year of the partner.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H776F804320DC403EA35C56390EC36856"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Special rules for certain plants bearing fruits and nuts</header><text>Section 168(k) of such Code is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H9BAB6007435449AB9E0557173ED5AC63"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (5), and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H070B9439404D4541B2A2C00D2372B8CD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (4) the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE7F183747884401DB24E7327F6755360" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H03FB8D18A34E4B398463C67759C52CF1"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Special rules for certain plants bearing fruits and nuts</header> <subparagraph id="HF5CA8EDCA15A4656BB66489982D2204E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any specified plant which is planted, or is grafted to a plant that has already been planted, by the taxpayer in the ordinary course of the taxpayer’s farming business (as defined in section 263A(e)(4)) during a taxable year for which the taxpayer has elected the application of this paragraph—</text>
 <clause id="H411F7471109C48CCAEE6938FB5553F0E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a depreciation deduction equal to 50 percent of the adjusted basis of such specified plant shall be allowed under section 167(a) for the taxable year in which such specified plant is so planted or grafted, and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC8253300FF2245248FB2F61852536C8E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the adjusted basis of such specified plant shall be reduced by the amount of such deduction.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1DA5AE4725E4432AB2C82EBD770EA0F3"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Specified plant</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the term <quote>specified plant</quote> means—</text>
 <clause id="HC4CD0BBA5443405490D198E6A260658A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any tree or vine which bears fruits or nuts, and</text> </clause><clause id="HC07906FEFF594D1D8CA529602ACE5434"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any other plant which will have more than one yield of fruits or nuts and which generally has a period of more than 2 years from the time of planting or grafting to the time at which such plant begins bearing fruits or nuts.</text>
 </clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">Such term shall not include any property which is planted or grafted outside of the United States.</continuation-text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3D25D684389A4860A7296B7BFBCC38DD"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Election revocable only with consent</header><text>An election under this paragraph may be revoked only with the consent of the Secretary.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAECD4855246E414ABE7FFCCE27B88CD7"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Additional depreciation may be claimed only once</header><text>If this paragraph applies to any specified plant, such specified plant shall not be treated as qualified property in the taxable year in which placed in service.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC4EB3E9FDEDA4B2794B5D0F2E3DC653D"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Deduction allowed in computing minimum tax</header><text>Rules similar to the rules of paragraph (2)(E) shall apply for purposes of this paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0952BD6FD7864DFB9A68F6C9B5060F16"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header> <paragraph id="H498A89970DCD4F1DB8D22954A42A1606"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Section 168(e)(6) of such Code is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H17D05539C895472C96E64BE762E29127"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (A) and (B) as subparagraphs (D) and (E), respectively,</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5F68A3647EB044FA993A84CA8C891EC3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking all that precedes subparagraph (D) (as so redesignated) and inserting the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDFA9E27E4AA94768AFE9EF4274E49CA7" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="HFFB344DE573D4465B2405AEDEA3920D2"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Qualified leasehold improvement property</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection—</text> <subparagraph id="HCE2E12EBDEAF4718AA690DF5352E4FE0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>qualified leasehold improvement property</quote> means any improvement to an interior portion of a building which is nonresidential real property if—</text>
 <clause id="H8DEBD33628EB4371934B6B0F6214DC72"><enum>(i)</enum><text>such improvement is made under or pursuant to a lease (as defined in subsection (h)(7))—</text> <subclause id="HEAB368F595BF44D5954726ECED3C6EA3"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by the lessee (or any sublessee) of such portion, or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H8D60749357AF4B669139B0DE0F977CD6"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by the lessor of such portion,</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H780C11BD63F44A34B7D7651997D9CD42"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>such portion is to be occupied exclusively by the lessee (or any sublessee) of such portion, and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HFCA6EF5F5B094D6B8A2D4CB765D47189"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>such improvement is placed in service more than 3 years after the date the building was first placed in service.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H182593F393B34400ABFDA1A36B4C30B9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Certain improvements not included</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such term shall not include any improvement for which the expenditure is attributable to—</text> <clause id="H6CB4A19CB0D24C80A03C5FAEBC31DADB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the enlargement of the building,</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD36347B815FF4CAF93404C19773A54F4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any elevator or escalator,</text> </clause><clause id="H3EFFCDF3F80E428CAFD8774B3BA53C32"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any structural component benefitting a common area, or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HDAAA6B515F134689B5A056FEE0064ECE"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the internal structural framework of the building.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H125EEC9DF2574D5B9A1796734295A172"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Definitions and special rules</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph—</text>
 <clause id="H1AB3EE4C6F2B487386A46B37C61B3FF2"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Commitment to lease treated as lease</header><text>A commitment to enter into a lease shall be treated as a lease, and the parties to such commitment shall be treated as lessor and lessee, respectively.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC5B47723466A446CA4C3C167FB1850DA"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Related persons</header><text>A lease between related persons shall not be considered a lease. For purposes of the preceding sentence, the term <quote>related persons</quote> means—</text>
 <subclause id="H258F79F8D6B84E41B1F9A8F0F33A349D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>members of an affiliated group (as defined in section 1504), and</text> </subclause><subclause id="H6978091980C84182854972B2ABBA51DA"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">persons having a relationship described in subsection (b) of section 267; except that, for purposes of this clause, the phrase <quote>80 percent or more</quote> shall be substituted for the phrase <quote>more than 50 percent</quote> each place it appears in such subsection.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>, and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD61650ACF0D3464A950EA53606E58799"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking <quote>subparagraph (A)</quote> in subparagraph (E) (as so redesignated) and inserting <quote>subparagraph (D)</quote>.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H987DF314AF344597A43B50F28C4AC44C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Section 168(e)(7)(B) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>qualified leasehold improvement property</quote> and inserting <quote>qualified improvement property</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5615AFE027D64103BEA90C6363436913"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Section 168(e)(8) of such Code is amended by striking subparagraph (D).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H35D8EDEFA9494F3986E2F43DF6988FEC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Section 168(k) of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA7904CC9FD83410DB62D390F7DE59F2B" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H483F72DDBAEC48CDB199C55BE6B25201"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Election out</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a taxpayer makes an election under this paragraph with respect to any class of property for any taxable year, paragraphs (1) and (2)(D) shall not apply to any qualified property in such class placed in service during such taxable year. An election under this paragraph may be revoked only with the consent of the Secretary.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3B255CF41CD6495C89539F825135FDA8"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Section 168(l)(3) of such Code is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H6AE15689034B4DC29F58CD5F11DCB434"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>section 168(k)</quote> in subparagraph (A) and inserting <quote>subsection (k)</quote>, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6D8CADCE418F48B1A54CEDA8F3D43A14"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>section 168(k)(2)(D)(i)</quote> in subparagraph (B) and inserting <quote>subsection (k)(2)(B)</quote>.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H87278D5124E94CB88486BCB81532F015"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Section 168(l)(4) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>subparagraph (E) of section 168(k)(2)</quote> and all that follows and inserting <quote>subsection (k)(2)(C) shall apply.</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB417B0F0920C4605B3AADBDF256DA2ED"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Section 168(l)(5) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>section 168(k)(2)(G)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (k)(2)(E)</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7A122902E5274F179848AED9FBDE4812"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Section 263A(c) of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H746EF1432D144CC5901A1CFD2CD66CC1" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="HD8A734A59269431E8F06AFE20677B381"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Coordination with section <enum-in-header>168(k)(5)</enum-in-header></header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section shall not apply to any amount allowed as a deduction by reason of section 168(k)(5) (relating to special rules for certain plants bearing fruits and nuts).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3E5DC857D1084D2FB761F6C4A05784BD"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Section 460(c)(6)(B) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>which—</quote> and all that follows and inserting <quote>which has a recovery period of 7 years or less.</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7BBDEB1C45F64CCC804F5B72FF6F5003"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 168(k) of such Code is amended by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">acquired after December 31, 2007, and before January 1, 2014</header-in-text></quote> in the heading thereof.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF55DF66E96DB479D9FAE76F68DBB5E98"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective dates</header>
 <paragraph id="H0A130325A07A4854A11090257AC8EB73"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, the amendments made by this subsection shall apply to property placed in service after December 31, 2014, in taxable years ending after such date.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HAE9C70F2A36244ACB9484FB33B9B5BD8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Expansion of election to accelerate amt credits in lieu of bonus depreciation</header>
 <subparagraph id="H1010AB14758B45A09BEA6F187479DFD8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (b) shall apply to taxable years ending after December 31, 2014.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H74D01062DF314F17ACBDCE5DDE28317B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Transitional rule</header><text>In the case of any taxable year beginning before January 1, 2015, and ending after December 31, 2014, the limitation under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/168">section 168(k)(4)(B)(ii)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (as amended by this section) shall be the sum of—</text>
 <clause id="H6E9A91F3A2C2434BBD3AE047EDB95BB4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the product of—</text> <subclause id="HE7E3C2E9C6C3484E9C679CAD38FF6F2C"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the maximum increase amount (within the meaning of section 168(k)(4)(C)(iii) of such Code, as in effect before the amendments made by this section), multiplied by</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HB21286A55CF24BF7B6FC70D66D88A4CD"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a fraction the numerator of which is the number of days in the taxable year before January 1, 2015, and the denominator of which is the number of days in the taxable year, plus</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H3BC4E7B3B31A4F38AB480957C17BC285"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the product of—</text> <subclause id="HE56DF80C2D8745169492713438712377"><enum>(I)</enum><text>such limitation (determined without regard to this subparagraph), multiplied by</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H5E4AC420383D4FEBB0C4E30AAC278C9E"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a fraction the numerator of which is the number of days in the taxable year after December 31, 2014, and the denominator of which is the number of days in the taxable year.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2A5EA54A165449D3974F10B029BE8AF6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Special rules for certain plants bearing fruits and nuts</header><text>The amendments made by subsection (c) (other than paragraph (1) thereof) shall apply to specified plants (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/168">section 168(k)(5)(B)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended by this section) planted or grafted after December 31, 2014.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" id="H375EAF5DEA7A426B8C76F192BEE5D792"><enum>2.</enum><header>Budgetary effects</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The budgetary effects of this Act shall not be entered on either PAYGO scorecard maintained pursuant to section 4(d) of the Statutory Pay-As-You-Go Act of 2010.</text></section></legis-body></bill>


