<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S278 IS: Citizen Empowerment Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 278</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150128">January 28, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S342">Mr. Blunt</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S287">Mr. Cornyn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S357">Mrs. Fischer</cosponsor> and <cosponsor name-id="S260">Mr. Roberts</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend title 5, United States Code, to establish certain procedures for conducting in-person or
			 telephonic interactions by executive branch employees with individuals,
 and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HDFE8DC1D8C9C44AFB63C624BA00F8B1B" style="OLC"><section id="H17D299EE8D704349AA8D0348D5C860B4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Citizen Empowerment Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HFA18CDD417AC4AE2B32F33F583E3E18C" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Amendments</header><subsection id="H0DE7AB7D95E84F41895B24F02464E9CF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Part III of title 5, United States Code, is amended by inserting after chapter 79 the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7D0EDC45C2084EC8B46A1B11C1B7475B" style="USC"><chapter id="HEE4F16F6515442E9AA583998285E6BD9"><enum>79A<?LEXA-Enum 79A?></enum><header>Services to
				members of the public</header><toc container-level="chapter-container" idref="HEE4F16F6515442E9AA583998285E6BD9" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration"><toc-entry idref="HC5E6ED9DFA2640A7AA0A1EA0AF29F71D" level="section">Sec.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HC5E6ED9DFA2640A7AA0A1EA0AF29F71D" level="section">7921. Procedures for in-person and telephonic interactions
				  conducted by executive branch employees.</toc-entry></toc><section id="HC5E6ED9DFA2640A7AA0A1EA0AF29F71D" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>7921.</enum><header>Procedures for
				in-person and telephonic interactions conducted by executive branch
 employees</header><subsection id="H45296A4982074F5EA14986F6A6B33C4D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text><paragraph commented="no" id="H9FBA02223B7542D980EB47E644F21A3F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>covered interaction</term> means an in-person or telephonic interview, audit, investigation, inspection, or other official interaction between an employee of an Executive agency and another individual relating to a possible or alleged violation of any Federal statute or regulation that could result in the imposition of a fine, forfeiture of property, civil monetary penalty, or criminal penalty against, or the collection of an unpaid tax, fine, or penalty from, the individual or a business owned or operated by the individual;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id5F03E54DE3B842AFBD48B21803F25E7E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>State</term> means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, and any commonwealth, territory, or possession of the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HC34E6D594D6A409297DFD8F688C5F73E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>telephonic</term> means by telephone or other similar electronic device.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE9322B32240743199C79EA822CE856AD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Recording of
				enforcement actions</header><paragraph id="HF306302761904316BBBD122102D75B2F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Recording by
 individuals</header><text>Any employee of an Executive agency who is conducting a covered interaction with an individual shall allow the individual to make an audio recording of the covered interaction at the individual’s own expense and with the individual’s own equipment.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H974CCC5C6BE8416E8D98C8A708590B71"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Recording by
 Federal employees</header><text>Any employee of an Executive agency that is conducting a covered interaction may record that interaction if the employee—</text><subparagraph id="HCAB0125616164A9F855A9F15D126084D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>informs the individual of the recording prior to or at the initiation of the interaction; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H491D417A2D124B4284DA66D0E822745E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>upon request of the individual, provides the individual with a transcript or copy of the recording, but only if the individual provides reimbursement for the cost of the transcription and reproduction of the transcript or copy.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDD137CAD4AFC4F848888EC134A7F6B39"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Explanations of
				rights</header><paragraph id="HE4CB2128800A4964AAF10215807D456E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>Any employee of an Executive agency shall, before or at an initial covered interaction, provide to the individual a verbal or written notice of the individual’s rights under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HC2F3B39C6D414C24A19C10DF9E5C76ED"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Separate
 notifications for separate violations</header><text>Paragraph (1) shall not, for purposes of any covered interaction, be considered satisfied based on a notification previously given if that previous notification was given in the case of a possible or alleged violation separate from the possible or alleged violation at hand.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H81F3F9EEF3CD4C19AFC9777550C98F86"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Application to
 official representative or those holding power of attorney</header><text>Any person who is permitted to represent, before an Executive agency described in subsection (b)(1), an individual permitted to make an audio recording under that subsection of a covered interaction conducted by an employee of that Executive agency—</text><paragraph id="HB6A31526C8F14CD9B3C2F116475CB5B0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall be permitted—</text><subparagraph id="H36FE529564314415983109BA421D0466"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to make an audio recording under subsection (b)(1) as if the person were the individual; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBABEAE2B573F4864B0AB42E251211149"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to receive a transcript or copy of an audio recording under subsection (b)(2) as if the person were the individual;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB5C333092BFD42BF90C0D38836FEE901"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall receive the same notice as that which is required to be provided to the individual under subsection (c); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1809FCDC0B064CD898C1C5D810210F67"><enum>(3)</enum><text>with respect to an audio recording (as referred to in paragraph (1)(A)) and a transcript or copy of a recording (as referred to in paragraph (1)(B)), shall have the same rights as described in subsection (e).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H344785E6B81344F1AE99C8803D282BF2"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Property of
 audio recording</header><text>Any audio recording or transcript of an audio recording made by an individual under subsection (b)(1) or provided to an individual under subsection (b)(2)(B) shall be the property of the individual.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1DBAECEB99074D949A1C328131A9BAEF"><enum>(f)</enum><header>No cause of
 action</header><text>This section does not create any express or implied private right of action.</text></subsection><subsection id="HBE70D1A6A3B6480286CC13F26F15D4B6"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><paragraph id="H6FD214587370491AA818D6D5944BA6E4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Classified
 information, public safety, criminal investigation</header><text>This section shall not apply to any covered interaction that is likely to include the discussion of—</text><subparagraph id="HFBF94B4E65464381AFB2B118BACE8167"><enum>(A)</enum><text>classified material;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4C6E9874B09442218AD843DC0690C87D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>information that, if released publicly, would endanger public safety; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2F0AFD1CFCAF4774B4FCA95A8361022D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>information that, if released publicly, would endanger an ongoing criminal investigation conducted by a Federal law enforcement officer (as defined in section 2 of the Law Enforcement Congressional Badge of Bravery Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/15231">42 U.S.C. 15231</external-xref>)) who is employed by a Federal law enforcement agency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7A709134A1D5475B8FD85A79AC2BB0D5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Determination by
 employees</header><text>An employee of an Executive agency who determines that an exception under paragraph (1) applies to a covered interaction or series of covered interactions shall provide written notification of the determination to any person who would otherwise be permitted to make an audio recording of the interaction or interactions under subsection (b)(1) or (d).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCF8D3DEFC8574A19A2787DC57059A08A"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Prior
 law</header><text>For the purposes set forth in paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (b), this section supersedes section 2511(2)(d) of title 18 and any provision of Federal or State law insofar as such section or provision relates to the recording of an interaction that is a covered interaction.</text></subsection><subsection id="HDDAB02572E2747B293271448F9C6A76B"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Disciplinary
 action</header><text>An employee of an Executive agency who violates this section shall be subject to appropriate disciplinary action in accordance with otherwise applicable provisions of law.</text></subsection></section></chapter><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HF413E966708149CFBF51B07BD433E8C8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical
 amendment</header><text>The analysis for part III of title 5, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to chapter 79 the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6B87D9864BA44889A59B90020D29996E" style="USC"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><multi-column-toc-entry level="chapter"><toc-enum>79A.</toc-enum><level-header level="chapter">Services
				  to members of the
				  public</level-header><target>7921</target></multi-column-toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


