<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1297 IS: U.S. Commercial Space Launch Competitiveness Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 1297</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150512">May 12, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S355">Mr. Cruz</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S282">Mr. Nelson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S380">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S350">Mr. Rubio</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S377">Mr. Gardner</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To update the Commercial Space Launch Act by amending title 51, United States Code, to promote
			 competitiveness of the U.S. commercial space sector, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="id53E389FF31C64ADB928C8CF4680A44E2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>U.S. Commercial Space Launch Competitiveness Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </section><section id="idDA1A8BFAD3F146BBBE76E837C5881BE7"><enum>2.</enum><header>References to title 51, United States Code</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Except as otherwise expressly provided, wherever in this Act an amendment or repeal is expressed in terms of an amendment to, or repeal of, a section or other provision, the reference shall be considered to be made to a section or other provision of title 51, United States Code.</text>
		</section><section id="idB9CC645B3E1E4BFA8466D3FD617B4DCB"><enum>3.</enum><header>Liability insurance and financial responsibility requirements</header>
 <subsection id="id7B140474913A407397EB1924D93BC30A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that it is in the public interest to update the methodology used to calculate the maximum probable loss from claims under section 50914 of title 51, United States Code, with a validated risk profile approach in order to consistently compute valid and reasonable maximum probable loss values.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idDB772CB3B7F74027861C3E6DE34C9A58"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than September 30, 2015, the Secretary of Transportation, in consultation with the commercial space sector and insurance providers, shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="idB33D7BF723074F52AC74B0D7F8C42453"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">evaluate and, if necessary, develop a plan to update the methodology used to calculate the maximum probable loss from claims under section 50914 of title 51, United States Code;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idDFBFA8688E1A4543B397F0ADE190A487"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in evaluating or developing a plan under paragraph (1)—</text> <subparagraph id="id9AE4A1A49A364CEF9900AB17B1687C6E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ensure that the Federal Government is not exposed to greater costs than intended and that launch companies are not required to purchase more insurance coverage than necessary; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id826483C3F80240F0AF90A815E0E61057"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consider the impact of the cost to both the industry and the Government of implementing an updated methodology; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id7E21A43AF5064823BFA47D1F73F648E4"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submit the evaluation, and any plan, to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id3E6A9643AACC49B1AD71D773AC3005E7"><enum>4.</enum><header>Launch liability extension</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 50915(f) is amended by striking <quote>December 31, 2016</quote> and inserting <quote>December 31, 2020</quote>.</text> </section><section id="id7560F197BA934C65875142CCF7163D14"><enum>5.</enum><header>Commercial space launch licensing and experimental permits</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 50906 is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="idEC8531DA8848464A8BEA17A57C6C1503"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (d), by striking <quote>launched or reentered</quote> and inserting <quote>launched or reentered under that permit</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idE60A784C8A9346C09733DE6304B1F258"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by amending subsection (d)(1) to read as follows:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id570931E78FB5429D8529A17B331E3552" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="id92F9A9C27C194226851C522AFC2FAA59"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">research and development to test design concepts, equipment, or operating techniques;</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph id="idC14A9A4053814F11A3D1C848FEB01C6E"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (d)(3) by striking <quote>prior to obtaining a license</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idBC7274ACD1B24A6CA49D9F5E84496248"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (e)(1) by striking <quote>suborbital rocket design</quote> and inserting <quote>suborbital rocket or suborbital rocket design</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idC6467654C01B4322AE1E41CF9F529438"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by amending subsection (g) to read as follows:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id20C92DBE3CA84D84B626D9DBE84BCE6A" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="idEFB630AF3C564614902F3B80AE854AB8"><enum>(g)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may issue a permit under this section notwithstanding any license issued under this chapter. The issuance of a license under this chapter may not invalidate a permit issued under this section.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></section><section id="id893B8536464949CC8BD1404FFAD4ABFB"><enum>6.</enum><header>Licensing report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation shall submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives a report on approaches for streamlining the licensing and permitting process of launch vehicles, reentry vehicles, or components of launch or reentry vehicles, to enable non-launch flight operations related to space transportation. The report shall include approaches to improve efficiency, reduce unnecessary costs, resolve inconsistencies, remove duplication, and minimize unwarranted constraints.</text>
		</section><section id="id36E983DECCA24DAFA753AAFE0BED88B8"><enum>7.</enum><header>Space authority</header>
 <subsection id="idC2835580D085415692C3CA3FB8132E04"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy, in consultation with the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Transportation, the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, the heads of other relevant Federal agencies, and the commercial space sector, shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="idB9427069460B47A8900EC193F82FB146"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assess current, and proposed near-term, commercial non-governmental activities conducted in space;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id03467D460EB443B69D61229B681AA0BB"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify appropriate oversight authorities for the activities described in paragraph (1);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id3648528B8FAA455C91E2CE79253234B2"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommend an oversight approach that would prioritize safety, utilize existing authorities, minimize burdens, promote the U.S. commercial space sector, and meet the United States obligations under international treaties; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id81C53786590742AA96CA6F7B1CEB4AD4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives a report on the assessment and recommended approaches.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="id3A0B96334D4949DC841B106F2FE51AD0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Nothing in this section shall apply to the activities of the ISS national laboratory as described in section 504 of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration Authorization Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18354">42 U.S.C. 18354</external-xref>), including any research or development projects utilizing the ISS national laboratory.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="idEC5889AAFF664819BF76B0C0DF2A2763"><enum>8.</enum><header>Space surveillance and situational awareness data</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation in concurrence with the Secretary of Defense shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="id68BFC06E5ABB462ABABAD54DC87B86C3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in consultation with the heads of other relevant Federal agencies, study the feasibility of processing and releasing safety-related space situational awareness data and information to any entity consistent with national security interests and public safety obligations of the United States; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idFB9CA0BCBF8F4314ADC93BDBDFBBAB49"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submit a report on the feasibility study to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="idC62208189FB141BEAA30B6A991123051"><enum>9.</enum><header>Extension of certain safety regulation requirements</header>
 <subsection id="id0C82CC93BF3B47CDA6DF037281247091"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Extension of certain safety regulation requirements</header><text>Section 50905(c)(3) is amended by striking <quote>Beginning on October 1, 2015</quote> and inserting <quote>Beginning on October 1, 2020</quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="idF2EACEC7BA2D4B4FAF45459FEC74EDAE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Construction</header><text>Section 50905(c) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id905E1C5E95004281BBF15C97BD668696" style="OLC">
 <paragraph commented="no" id="idFE6F0D24BDC74E19BA80EC4EA9A5F500"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to limit the authority of the Secretary to discuss potential regulatory approaches with the commercial space sector, including observations, findings, and recommendations from the Commercial Space Transportation Advisory Committee, prior to the issuance of a notice of proposed rulemaking.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="id00A9399D2B8646B0AE029543278DB9A4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 270 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation, in consultation with the commercial space sector, including the Commercial Space Transportation Advisory Committee, shall submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives a report specifying key industry metrics that might indicate readiness of the commercial space sector and the Department of Transportation to transition to a regulatory approach under section 50905(c)(3) of title 51, United States Code, that considers space flight participant, government astronaut, and crew safety.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="id3431704697DB44DC93B6A72E5F57F567"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Biennial report</header><text>Beginning on December 31, 2016, and biennially thereafter, the Secretary of Transportation, in consultation and coordination with the commercial space sector, including the Commercial Space Transportation Advisory Committee, shall submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives a report that identifies the activities, described in subsections (c) and (d) of section 50905 of title 51, United States Code, most appropriate for regulatory action, if any, and a proposed transition plan for such regulations.</text>
			</subsection></section><section commented="no" id="id5A85157EE2594A1D861805C8CDBE3F17"><enum>10.</enum><header>Industry voluntary consensus standards</header>
 <subsection id="id9E73248936E743FB9A2E906E83BCC88F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Industry voluntary consensus standards</header><text>Section 50905(c), as amended in section 9 of this Act, is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idAE4216111CF34A088BCAC3DAD10D92B6" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="id252DBDB6F9D84F9BA42796A97265B41C"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The Secretary shall continue to work with the commercial space sector, including the Commercial Space Transportation Advisory Committee, to facilitate the development of voluntary consensus standards based on recommended best practices to improve the safety of crew, government astronauts, and space flight participants as the commercial space sector continues to mature.</text>
					</paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="idB79BBA9DA049451180FE4BE4DB2B272A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Biennial report</header><text>Beginning on December 31, 2016, and biennially thereafter, the Secretary of Transportation, in consultation and coordination with the commercial space sector, including the Commercial Space Transportation Advisory Committee, shall submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives a report detailing progress on the development of industry voluntary consensus standards under section 50905(c)(6) of title 51, United States Code.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="S1" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>11.</enum><header>Government astronauts</header>
 <subsection id="idC737A975A3E74B22A27088F386BF9DB1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings and purpose</header><text>Section 50901(15) is amended by inserting <quote>, government astronauts,</quote> after <quote>crew</quote> each place it appears.</text> </subsection><subsection id="id61ACA4BE4052460DB8652457B0656B96"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definition of government astronaut</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 50902 is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="id5285090CC39348BE84769C7BE408D006"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (4) through (22) as paragraphs (7) through (25), respectively; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id6C15A0313B6149DBA6009AF11C4835D9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (3) the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3912512B62AF4DAD9F36847E158C56B4" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="idD561A51949254261BBEC2514B6D3F738"><enum>(4)</enum><text><term>government astronaut</term> means an individual who—</text> <subparagraph id="idA5C99C07D7B74E989359D2D33D49C22A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is either—</text>
 <clause id="id492DE780059F4A6FB14525C4841AB944"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an employee of the United States Government, including the uniformed services, engaged in the performance of a Federal function under authority of law or an Executive act; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="idE11A5E466AC3425EAFD597DC26D603E0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an international partner astronaut;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idEB46FE912ADC42D894389BDB51825EF6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is identified by the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1E1B97EB1E6A4023BB98B672FB497690"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is carried within a launch vehicle or reentry vehicle; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id321E84C66EDE4E36B27FC9CBCF0F1093"><enum>(D)</enum><text>may perform or may not perform activities directly relating to the launch, reentry, or other operation of the launch vehicle or reentry vehicle.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9A27C03E8B72483D88D8257F94D49272"><enum>(5)</enum><text><term>international partner astronaut</term> means an individual designated under Article 11 of the International Space Station Intergovernmental Agreement, by a partner to that agreement other than the United States, as qualified to serve as an International Space Station crew member.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id926DF3E7C25E47B29780D0C8233FE7F0"><enum>(6)</enum><text><term>International Space Station Intergovernmental Agreement</term> means the Agreement Concerning Cooperation on the International Space Station, signed at Washington January 29, 1998 (TIAS 12927).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="idF2716FD166574A778FBBC7CF7FA52B9A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definition of launch</header><text>Paragraph (7) of section 50902, as redesignated, is amended by striking <quote>and any payload, crew, or space flight participant</quote> and inserting <quote>and any payload or human being</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="idA78186FD76C74ED88191F299A692CB86"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definition of launch services</header><text>Paragraph (9) of section 50902, as redesignated, is amended by striking <quote>payload, crew (including crew training), or space flight participant</quote> and inserting <quote>payload, crew (including crew training), government astronaut, or space flight participant</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="id29265FF4F5AD49BD8E276AF852AB6FDA"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definition of reenter and reentry</header><text>Paragraph (16) of section 50902, as redesignated, is amended by striking <quote>and its payload, crew, or space flight participants, if any,</quote> and inserting <quote>and its payload or human beings, if any,</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="idC1BF49898B5E46E59F36AB4F879E4312"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definition of reentry services</header><text>Paragraph (17) of section 50902, as redesignated, is amended by striking <quote>payload, crew (including crew training), or space flight participant, if any,</quote> and inserting <quote>payload, crew (including crew training), government astronaut, or space flight participant, if any,</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idE57965A706094194B800046FB1C223C9"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definition of space flight participant</header><text>Paragraph (20) of section 50902, as redesignated, is amended to read as follows:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB692F51CA0E74D89AD1AA66A09A14686" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="idE30873CBF8204D6FAA29767942807246"><enum>(20)</enum><text><term>space flight participant</term> means an individual, who is not crew or a government astronaut, carried within a launch vehicle or reentry vehicle.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="id212F0095CCBF4057AB0D77F586DAC17F"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Definition of third party</header><text>Paragraph (24)(E) of section 50902, as redesignated, is amended by inserting <quote>, government astronauts,</quote> after <quote>crew</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id0F043CF93FD443BE938ED0DC1F382E7D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Restrictions on launches, operations, and reentries; single license or permit</header><text>Section 50904(d) is amended by striking <quote>activities involving crew or space flight participants</quote> and inserting <quote>activities involving crew, government astronauts, or space flight participants</quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="id268E7E3C7648449FA4C149105E8F3697"><enum>(j)</enum><header>License applications and requirements; applications</header><text>Section 50905 is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="id62BFEE8131004656BB2D330AE99FEBC9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(2), by striking <quote>crews and space flight participants</quote> and inserting <quote>crew, government astronauts, and space flight participants</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id66D4B54FA58047CDB51C2BA47E2C87FB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(2)(D), by striking <quote>crew or space flight participants</quote> and inserting <quote>crew, government astronauts, or space flight participants</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id9FABA2FDD97C4F9091C1BC0E5B4E4A1B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idAECAB23AA9D047FEB10AC0385954D199"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>crew and space flight participants</quote> and inserting <quote>crew, government astronauts, and space flight participants</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2B87638D2B184641AC64719AD7F7C25A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>to crew or space flight participants</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>to crew, government astronauts, or space flight participants</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id58C0E11851AB41FE93DE51CBA9E7AD82"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Monitoring activities</header><text>Section 50907(a) is amended by striking <quote>crew or space flight participant training</quote> and inserting <quote>crew, government astronaut, or space flight participant training</quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="id138F2745B2F44313A8F941113BB7BFDF"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Additional suspensions</header><text>Section 50908(d)(1) is amended by striking <quote>to crew or space flight participants</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>to any human being</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id078D6FC74A8B43A7A585CFB1B7362C68"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Enforcement and penalty</header><text>Section 50917(b)(1)(D)(i) is amended by striking <quote>crew or space flight participant training site,</quote> and inserting <quote>crew, government astronaut, or space flight participant training site,</quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="idAC8799F7FE50476EB0BD0DC0EA49FFCB"><enum>(n)</enum><header>Relationship to other executive agencies, laws, and international obligations; nonapplication</header><text>Section 50919(g) is amended to read as follows:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id46FF573BAEF14F13ACAAB56E3D29730F" style="OLC">
					<subsection commented="no" id="id4E008C78ACB445C6A4E8623764FDA970"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Nonapplication</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="id93C9CFDD4E4748688C59B6207B7DB7DC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>This chapter does not apply to—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="idF99D62B0CE884F70BCD50616100ACB0E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a launch, reentry, operation of a launch vehicle or reentry vehicle, operation of a launch site or reentry site, or other space activity the Government carries out for the Government; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="idAF197F7AA2A848A9AA248D4D52DEE14B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>planning or policies related to the launch, reentry, operation, or activity under subparagraph (A).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id4A1FAEE2D5144357909A19B8944F0D50"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>The following activities are not space activities the Government carries out for the Government under paragraph (1):</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="id46A6E3AE53D54F6B85A43D5F1783ACA6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A government astronaut being carried within a launch vehicle or reentry vehicle under this chapter.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id730DE503408B47A0A0159AACAF84E31D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A government astronaut performing activities directly relating to the launch, reentry, or other operation of the launch vehicle or reentry vehicle under this chapter.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="idABB150BC683544649FB7D9935DB39F9B"><enum>(o)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this Act, or the amendments made by this Act, may be construed to modify or affect any law relating to astronauts.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="id897FDFCA94DE4CA3A7D9C406D20BE078"><enum>12.</enum><header>Streamline commercial space launch activities</header>
 <subsection id="id458E590A90A646BBA33756477A21898F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that eliminating duplicative requirements and approvals for commercial launch and reentry operations will promote and encourage the development of the commercial space sector.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idB5BBCAA5577341DBA461DFD5F8CB3B0B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reaffirmation of policy</header><text>Congress reaffirms that the Secretary of Transportation, in overseeing and coordinating commercial launch and reentry operations, should—</text>
 <paragraph id="id69DB0CAF274B4667BD623EA3539E7920"><enum>(1)</enum><text>promote commercial space launches and reentries by the private sector;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idA8B414AB52824F039FFDB3248D8460CC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>facilitate Government, State, and private sector involvement in enhancing U.S. launch sites and facilities;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id2DAB5B8E7BB74BD9AB06DB29669A1299"><enum>(3)</enum><text>protect public health and safety, safety of property, national security interests, and foreign policy interests of the United States; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id3602BEE70B5E45178592C6942DD8649F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>consult with the head of another executive agency, including the Secretary of Defense or the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, as necessary to provide consistent application of licensing requirements under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/51/509">chapter 509</external-xref> of title 51, United States Code.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id2AB9BF1F8C984CBDB53A772E0DBA41BC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Requirements</header>
 <paragraph id="id738F79A3EFA549B1BF08779243A8E255"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Transportation under section 50918 of title 51, United States Code, and subject to section 50905(b)(2)(C) of that title, shall consult with the Secretary of Defense, the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, and the heads of other executive agencies, as appropriate—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idA0F41FC8121B48298C3FB99DCABA3F66"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to identify all requirements that are imposed to protect the public health and safety, safety of property, national security interests, and foreign policy interests of the United States relevant to any commercial launch of a launch vehicle or commercial reentry of a reentry vehicle; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2BA65A3D2EBA4EEA8C6198B91D8C80EC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to evaluate the requirements identified in subparagraph (A) and, in coordination with the licensee or transferee and the heads of the relevant executive agencies—</text>
 <clause id="id5F4BA24E07694982A081C24DB70E12F6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>determine whether the satisfaction of a requirement of one agency could result in the satisfaction of a requirement of another agency; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id252126702CB6445EBE688C0E90FF76A6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>resolve any inconsistencies and remove any outmoded or duplicative requirements or approvals of the Federal Government relevant to any commercial launch of a launch vehicle or commercial reentry of a reentry vehicle.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id162A8AC2A46743BD9CFF949A9CBB5443"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reports</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter until the Secretary of Transportation determines no outmoded or duplicative requirements or approvals of the Federal Government exist, the Secretary of Transportation, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense, the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, the commercial space sector, and the heads of other executive agencies, as appropriate, shall submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate, the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives, and the congressional defense committees a report that includes the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="id8ACB70BAC7CF4C3AA2A14864CA231D2C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A description of the process for the application for and approval of a permit or license under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/51/509">chapter 509</external-xref> of title 51, United States Code, for the commercial launch of a launch vehicle or commercial reentry of a reentry vehicle, including the identification of—</text>
 <clause id="id9B15750E4B0244D39451E084F124F6C4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any unique requirements for operating on a United States Government launch site, reentry site, or launch property; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id636B61894BD743EFBF684836BD0488B5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any inconsistent, outmoded, or duplicative requirements or approvals.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2D7A23DCAC6047BFA167694120746D51"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A description of current efforts, if any, to coordinate and work across executive agencies to define interagency processes and procedures for sharing information, avoiding duplication of effort, and resolving common agency requirements.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1BD6EBEC25594A2885A556E026201829"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Recommendations for legislation that may further—</text> <clause id="id6ADE46ADB1CB40EEBE9AB3304DB77C91"><enum>(i)</enum><text>streamline requirements in order to improve efficiency, reduce unnecessary costs, resolve inconsistencies, remove duplication, and minimize unwarranted constraints; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id848BB86EB5404555BCB7C3B0C830DDF3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>consolidate or modify requirements across affected agencies into a single application set that satisfies the requirements identified in paragraph (1)(A).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id680AC02DD38046B2B5C8FCAC8EE06200"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this subsection—</text> <subparagraph id="id63FD93B9D80E48D5B64568E8C9FD7EE6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any applicable definitions set forth in section 50902 of title 51, United States Code, shall apply;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id75ABC72AAA084EF3954C7D5BE9CB6831"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the terms <term>launch</term>, <term>reenter</term>, and <term>reentry</term> include landing of a launch vehicle or reentry vehicle; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD29F1A42D353403F94AE14BCC3E59F1E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the terms <term>United States Government launch site</term> and <term>United States Government reentry site</term> include any necessary facility, at that location, that is commercially operated on United States Government property.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="iddd3edd42-bfef-4682-8b3e-c263319a2398"><enum>13.</enum><header>Operation and
			 utilization of the ISS</header>
			<subsection id="id386c6285-683b-4928-8d97-af958337b8bb"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of
 Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that—</text> <paragraph id="id99b3645b-5609-419d-ae77-7dcc24d6aa42"><enum>(1)</enum><text>maximum utilization of partnerships, scientific research, commercial applications, and exploration test bed capabilities of the ISS is essential to ensuring the greatest return on investments made by the United States and its international partners in the development, assembly, and operations of that unique facility; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id30432733-0d0a-43d4-8ceb-0ce3181250a9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>every effort should be made to ensure that decisions regarding the service life of the ISS are based on the station's projected capability to continue providing effective and productive research and exploration test bed capabilities.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="id6c002ab7-2ae9-4ab0-aff1-332e5ad54ae2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Continuation of the
			 International Space Station</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="idB6FAD42A1D22445A8B4CAC6DD50FD254"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 501 of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration Authorization Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18351">42 U.S.C. 18351</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="idDCE24345F96D48B39C11ECEA9A74076D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">through 2020</header-in-text></quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="idF764300213CD41E181C0D504D43F247A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>through at least 2020</quote> and inserting <quote>through at least 2024</quote>.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idC2ABFFDD85F14709B72E347C4919A538"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Maintenance of the United States segment and assurance of continued operations of the International
 Space Station</header><text>Section 503 of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration Authorization Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18353">42 U.S.C. 18353</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="id2401694B6B80437CB5FACB08B2B4DF77"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>through at least September 30, 2020</quote> and inserting <quote>through at least September 30, 2024</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id59FE11D56A434DD98CE894644BA6435C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(1), by striking <quote>In carrying out subsection (a), the Administrator</quote> and inserting <quote>The Administrator</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id9B90BFADED894CD29BC3D82727D01169"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Research capacity allocation and integration of research payloads</header><text>Section 504(d) of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration Authorization Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18354">42 U.S.C. 18354(d)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>September 30, 2020</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>at least September 30, 2024</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id8DC215BEDD6B4CDF95669DB82337C280"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Maintaining use through at least 2024</header><text>Section 70907 is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF6F5131A5C2E4C41BE1848B51A29CA8D" style="USC"> <section commented="no" id="idEE39D390A0954A0A861C0AB8BE438B54"><enum>70907.</enum><header>Maintaining use through at least 2024</header> <subsection commented="no" id="id529A967E852343AB994A5B1322E217D5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Policy</header><text>The Administrator shall take all necessary steps to ensure that the International Space Station remains a viable and productive facility capable of potential United States utilization through at least September 30, 2024.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="idCA8231F80B574D46801C1D072D530A07"><enum>(b)</enum><header>NASA actions</header><text>In furtherance of the policy under subsection (a), the Administrator shall ensure, to the extent practicable, that the International Space Station, as a designated national laboratory—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="id36CE1A554F3E4A199B779A77672C7E65"><enum>(1)</enum><text>remains viable as an element of overall exploration and partnership strategies and approaches;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id9720B8FAE4C242E8BF5431E2F1C49161"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is considered for use by all NASA mission directorates, as appropriate, for technically appropriate scientific data gathering or technology risk reduction demonstrations; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id071C6A30E3094F1D836023F37481B489"><enum>(3)</enum><text>remains an effective, functional vehicle providing research and test bed capabilities for the United States through at least September 30, 2024.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idCAAC7F430D10463B968AFC10F417C73A"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendments</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="idCC7FE1040B6D4E75972FCCD52F677603"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Table of contents of 2010 Act</header><text>The item relating to section 501 in the table of contents in section 1(b) of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration Authorization Act of 2010 (124 Stat. 2806) is amended by striking <quote>through 2020</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id523FD42F191D49C6B10101E3226E934D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Table of contents of chapter 709</header><text>The table of contents for chapter 709 is amended by amending the item relating to section 70907 to read as follows:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idBEDA241E3B0E4093B27A1ED3106C2D5F" style="OLC"><toc><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">70907. Maintaining use through at least 2024.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


