<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S2184 RS: Foreign Aid Transparency and Accountability Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-10-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><calendar>Calendar No. 295</calendar><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2184</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20151020">October 20, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S350">Mr. Rubio</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S308">Mr. Cardin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S305">Mr. Isakson</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSFR00" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><action stage="Reported-in-Senate"><action-date>November 17, 2015</action-date><action-desc>Reported by <sponsor name-id="S310">Mr. Corker</sponsor>, with an amendment</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To direct the President to establish guidelines for United States foreign development and economic
			 assistance programs, and for other purposes. </official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HD93836E1B9DA478CABDCE361E44E9542" style="OLC">
 <section changed="deleted" committee-id="SSFR00" id="HD3AC31CC2F914DE4B622D8B69E74EFED" reported-display-style="strikethrough" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Foreign Aid Transparency and Accountability Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section changed="deleted" committee-id="SSFR00" id="H553A781DD32B4497B0C90B055427D6BB" reported-display-style="strikethrough"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
 <paragraph id="HE45E875CDCD44B24A4088198B1D04A86"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H7065D3C9A1374D0C81B2353644D8FCA8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate</committee-name>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5040EA3D69BB40FC9CD62F5739515FCB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSAP00">Committee on Appropriations of the Senate</committee-name>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB5E6B5502E104331A2FCB1103006132C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives</committee-name>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDC59E994FE624B9E95CD2B2A455F401A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives</committee-name>.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA0F92AD146124D728A37E60C8FB9326B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>evaluation</term> means, with respect to a United States foreign development and economic assistance program, the systematic collection and analysis of information about the characteristics and outcomes of the program, including projects conducted under such program, as a basis for—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id3A65FF371BA64DEBBD771C22A5F5968C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">making judgments and evaluations regarding the program;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF93C98FE020C4C4DAA2B32B83C16E128"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improving program effectiveness; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id75490C26F88F4C9C918E8914D6D2D68F"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">informing decisions about current and future programming.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HFC4AB9F9898346EAA68F5457857D71F5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>United States foreign development and economic assistance</header><text>The term <term>United States foreign development and economic assistance</term> means assistance provided primarily for the purposes of foreign development and economic support, including assistance authorized under—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H860C287FD5AE44A4B06BE202C41D6EE6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>part I of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2151">22 U.S.C. 2151 et seq.</external-xref>), except for—</text> <clause commented="no" id="H86D7DD6811944139921922C7B5D07A43"><enum>(i)</enum><text>title IV of chapter 2 of such part (relating to the Overseas Private Investment Corporation);</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H8323F2815DF649CEA0B9169516CE37A7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>chapter 3 of such part (relating to International Organizations and Programs); and</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="HD0D8CAA5AB80402C96F7A5B7315BCC7A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>chapter 8 of such part (relating to International Narcotics Control);</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HD9E2D5344C5646459D7B0E7F17F78C4B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>chapter 4 of part II of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2346">22 U.S.C. 2346 et seq.</external-xref>; relating to Economic Support Fund);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H89DB984EFBB148029433224A2FADCA31"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Millennium Challenge Act of 2003 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7701">22 U.S.C. 7701 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD6E4A91D9412498CB773F21ABEE36615"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Food for Peace Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1721">7 U.S.C. 1721 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
				</subparagraph></paragraph></section><section changed="deleted" committee-id="SSFR00" id="H5E10F0B0107342BCA818977645049F75" reported-display-style="strikethrough"><enum>3.</enum><header>Guidelines for United States foreign development and economic assistance programs</header>
 <subsection id="H03689C4403EF4379A6252FB3597BE2B0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The purposes of this section are—</text> <paragraph id="id6B6DE46E45B349488346D9B6AE2D5BAC"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to evaluate the performance of United States foreign development and economic assistance and its contribution to the policies, strategies, projects, program goals, and priorities undertaken by the Federal Government;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id38E3A63DE13B4D1EA0B7BFF12CD7EEB4"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to foster and promote innovative programs to improve effectiveness; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idFD955C32E1A448A7A8B8D3E5261FF5F2"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to coordinate the monitoring and evaluation processes of Federal departments and agencies that administer United States foreign development and economic assistance.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H72D98F6EF8294D729E313B6BD366FB47"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment of guidelines</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall set forth guidelines, according to best practices of monitoring and evaluation studies and analyses, for the establishment of measurable goals, performance metrics, and monitoring and evaluation plans that can be applied with reasonable consistency to United States foreign development and economic assistance.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H617ABDE563B24CE3AF8970DED8DC40CE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Objectives of guidelines</header>
 <paragraph id="HD023EE2622764ECBA5E2F972CA3889F6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The guidelines established pursuant to subsection (b) shall provide direction to Federal departments and agencies that administer United States foreign development and economic assistance on—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id5E29E2E4C20C47DCB08C4C30D67038EF"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">monitoring the use of resources;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6B88A7FC150E493CBC0698EFA74EA6BD"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">evaluating the outcomes and impacts of United States foreign development and economic assistance projects and programs; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA58B7E3B1AD5499A8F82F83107C9CB5D"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">applying the findings and conclusions of such evaluations to proposed project and program design.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF93ECD2175C64C7BBBBD17C693F16B0C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Objectives</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The guidelines established pursuant to subsection (b) shall require Federal departments and agencies that administer United States foreign development and economic assistance—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H4A4147BBCAA94053AE36D6A0B38D657C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to establish annual monitoring and evaluation agendas and objectives to plan and manage the process of monitoring, evaluating, analyzing progress, and applying learning toward achieving results;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HE9552E34A4A74FB69A0EA2D9C7E41A16"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to develop specific project monitoring and evaluation plans, including measurable goals and performance metrics, and to identify the resources necessary to conduct such evaluations, which should be covered by program costs, during project design;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H98483702C32B472894263DF656DA81F6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to apply rigorous monitoring and evaluation methodologies to such programs, including through the use of impact evaluations, ex-post evaluations, or other methods as appropriate, that clearly define program logic, inputs, outputs, intermediate outcomes, and end outcomes;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H6C680727F73D479FAEBA89172A2AB29A"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to disseminate guidelines for the development and implementation of monitoring and evaluation programs to all personnel, especially in the field, who are responsible for the design, implementation, and management of United States foreign development and economic assistance programs;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H64BBB5632E0B42D8A640803C1614DA50"><enum>(E)</enum><text>to establish methodologies for the collection of data, including baseline data to serve as a reference point against which progress can be measured;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H42807E95082648A4A008D7AE424FD8CD"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to evaluate, at least once in their lifetime, all programs whose dollar value equals or exceeds the median program size for the relevant office or bureau or an equivalent calculation to ensure the majority of program resources are evaluated;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC14C3426C0D94AFA824C3C2E6A5BD014"><enum>(G)</enum><text>to conduct impact evaluations on all pilot programs before replicating wherever possible, or provide a written justification for not conducting an impact evaluation where such an evaluation was deemed inappropriate or impossible;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAFE5A25075734C4C85DEA2749A2E8AC3"><enum>(H)</enum><text>to develop a clearinghouse capacity for the collection and dissemination of knowledge and lessons learned that serve as benchmarks to guide future programs for United States development professionals, implementing partners, the donor community, and aid recipient governments, and as a repository of knowledge on lessons learned;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1D7E57D219FC4B19BDE0D11A913E54B6"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to internally distribute evaluation reports;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFDB960FE217443C7B04B318F4EB43074"><enum>(J)</enum><text>to develop a summary of each evaluation, including a description of the evaluation methodology and key findings and recommendations made in the evaluation within 90 days after the completion of the evaluation;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8044DA6F7B54409AA3402EC99E8D4D21"><enum>(K)</enum><text>to undertake collaborative partnerships and coordinate efforts with the academic community, implementing partners, and national and international institutions that have expertise in program monitoring, evaluation, and analysis when such partnerships provide needed expertise or significantly improve the evaluation and analysis;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA0361FBB6EB842709F5833A689D65EF9"><enum>(L)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to ensure verifiable, valid, credible, precise, reliable, and timely data are available to monitoring and evaluation personnel to permit the objective evaluation of the effectiveness of United States foreign development and economic assistance programs, including an assessment of assumptions and limitations in such evaluations; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H86B128CCB36946E7BC5A2FDA4C359795"><enum>(M)</enum><text>to ensure that standards of professional evaluation organizations for monitoring and evaluation efforts are employed, including ensuring the integrity and independence of evaluations, permitting and encouraging the exercise of professional judgment, and providing for quality control and assurance in the monitoring and evaluation process.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H897120F13134417196F545EAD0B599FD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>President’s report</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees that contains a detailed description of the guidelines established pursuant to subsection (b). The report shall be submitted in unclassified form, but it may contain a classified annex.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H3DF9BCF0EA82420281E6991BAC2776CF"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Comptroller General’s report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date on which the report required under subsection (d) is submitted to Congress, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H7227E33220284326BB186B69AE3A5829"><enum>(1)</enum><text>analyzes the guidelines established pursuant to subsection (b); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE728C11053364E80956F0F4A7EAE3130"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provides a side-by-side comparison of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id83BE94D6EB7849579FA334DF26D09EB9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the President’s budget request for that fiscal year of every operational unit that carries out United States foreign development and economic assistance; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id054AA7C2E5AB4AD9948AD476CC8B65BD"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the performance of such units during the most recently completed fiscal year.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section changed="deleted" committee-id="SSFR00" id="HC74DB47DAA1C4F6A8D890F4728E02344" reported-display-style="strikethrough"><enum>4.</enum><header>Information on United States foreign development and economic assistance programs</header>
			<subsection id="H94CC4B7D571545A7A9B70C3FD2BD9609"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Publication of information</header>
 <paragraph id="H6A9D3C97376147E7A81A9AF8FE9DB62C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Update of existing website</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall update the Department of State’s website, <quote>ForeignAssistance.gov</quote>, to make publicly available comprehensive, timely, and comparable information on United States foreign development and economic assistance programs, including all information required under subsection (b) that is available to the Secretary of State.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H725E345CD93841119ED3EFE103E68ED6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Information sharing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, and quarterly thereafter, the head of each Federal department or agency that administers United States foreign development and economic assistance shall provide the Secretary of State with comprehensive information about the United States foreign development and economic assistance programs carried out by such department or agency.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAF807E24266541A699F8FB9929D20A4E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Updates to website</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, and quarterly thereafter, the Secretary of State shall publish, on the <quote>ForeignAssistance.gov</quote> website or through a successor online publication, the information provided under subsection (b).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF6774A1963344E99ACC7867B379BD7FD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Matters To be included</header>
 <paragraph id="H98DEFC84DAA0496583149895007A309B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The information described in subsection (a)—</text> <subparagraph id="idB6ECEA46747C4C11B3A7E33DB0A81F9E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall be published on a detailed award-by-award and country-by-country basis; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF74DB90D13894F4E99D4BC296B5589F5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if assistance is provided on a regional level, shall be published on an award-by-award and region-by-region basis.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAFA90CCBB63F4F15BAEC0CB5C1178944"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Types of information</header>
 <subparagraph id="HD0A32B074403454C881C8507943ED43A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To ensure the transparency, accountability, and effectiveness of United States foreign development and economic assistance programs, the information described in subsection (a) shall include—</text>
 <clause id="idF1D0556949F94E978121CECFE980D998"><enum>(i)</enum><text>all regional, country, and sector assistance strategies, annual budget documents, congressional budget justifications, obligations, expenditures, evaluations and summaries of evaluations in accordance with section 3(c)(2)(J); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idA18BF2707F9D45F9968A2CF6C2B49909"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>basic descriptive summaries for United States foreign development and economic assistance programs and awards under such programs.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB29BF2BA14F04BEEB6728C26F1EB36D6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>Each type of information described in subparagraph (A) shall be published or updated on the appropriate website not later than 90 days after the date on which the information is issued.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H804E29449DA140428E345EC84252C6D3"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this paragraph may be construed to require a Federal department or agency that administers United States foreign development and economic assistance to provide any information that does not relate to, or is not otherwise required by, the United States foreign development and economic assistance programs carried out by such department or agency.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDD81E74B57B94649872D00694542C928"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report in lieu of inclusion</header>
 <subparagraph id="HD4E9C9F7F699433993C4DDE52AAAD177"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Health or security of implementing partners</header><text>If the head of a Federal department or agency makes a determination that the inclusion of a required item of information online would jeopardize the health or security of an implementing partner or program beneficiary or would require the release of proprietary information of an implementing partner or program beneficiary, the head of the Federal department or agency shall provide such determination in writing to the appropriate congressional committees, including the basis for such determination and shall—</text>
 <clause id="H5C32C7CE06D44C6D8B7BD18D392E7BBD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>provide a briefing to the appropriate congressional committees on such information; or</text> </clause><clause id="H409719C19F754FB493673CF36B14EE66"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>submit such information to the appropriate congressional committees in a written report.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB9C74CBAD3DB4ABBA2286ECC7D1B1448"><enum>(B)</enum><header>National interests of the united states</header><text>If the Secretary of State makes a determination that the inclusion of a required item of information online would be detrimental to the national interests of the United States, the Secretary of State shall—</text>
 <clause id="id5E809614E8CF4729B72DE0F5A663FD55"><enum>(i)</enum><text>provide such determination, including the basis for such determination, in writing to the appropriate congressional committees; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE3B21D35779E455A8FA45B3D33126DFF"><enum>(ii)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idA9235F3900714BD3B62E41AF52C5723C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>provide a briefing on such information to the appropriate congressional committees; or</text> </subclause><subclause changed="deleted" committee-id="SSFR00" id="id883D335B416B4AD085E9EB28B6BCCCF0" indent="up1" reported-display-style="strikethrough"><enum>(II)</enum><text>submit the item of information in a written report to the appropriate congressional committees.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7E0535E7961040049E235FDE1FDB3197"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Form</header><text>Any briefing or item of information provided under this paragraph may be provided in classified form, as appropriate.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H63410768D63F49FAB07D3BDCBC99B034"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Failure to comply</header><text>If a Federal department or agency fails to comply with the requirements under paragraph (1) or (2), subsection (a), or subsection (c), with respect to providing information described in subsection (a), and the information is not subject to a determination under subparagraph (A) or (B) of paragraph (3) not to make the information publicly available, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, in consultation with the head of such department or agency, not later than September 1, 2016, shall submit a consolidated report to the appropriate congressional committees that includes, with respect to each required item of information not made publicly available—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H1AFFCC89B3064D3CB66EFDB4622B5DAB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a detailed explanation of the failure of not making such information publicly available; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF02CD6C1C12E4E3BA99E8813169B94EF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of the department’s or agency’s plan and timeline for—</text>
 <clause id="id59BD5028C16449358CBD95A23BF64333"><enum>(i)</enum><text>immediately making such information publicly available; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id2E49C4880F0149A89E32B237337BE5EB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ensuring that such failures do not take place in subsequent years.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6AA6A65130554865BC89462C0FE15799"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Scope of information</header><text>The online publication required under subsection (a) shall, at a minimum—</text> <paragraph id="H7CE3262456FF4C508C01093FEAE350BF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in each of the fiscal years 2016 through 2019, provide the information required under subsection (b) for fiscal years 2012 through the current fiscal year; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB3E966B8367B493C866179F30C019CDF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for fiscal year 2020 and each fiscal year thereafter, provide the information required under subsection (b) for the immediately preceding 5 fiscal years in a fully searchable form.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
	<legis-body display-enacting-clause="no-display-enacting-clause" style="OLC">
 <section changed="added" committee-id="SSFR00" id="id3d231b90-b93b-4666-981b-2fdbb4435709" reported-display-style="italic" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Foreign Aid Transparency and Accountability Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section changed="added" committee-id="SSFR00" id="id9332b496-9fef-4560-a31a-fcb0aafe1d2f" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
 <paragraph id="id87df54dd-8e3f-4560-bfed-119a95b6bcb3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="id4b0c74c6-e826-47a6-a674-8a89ee447b79"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate</committee-name>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf2bb8ba3-76b5-4353-8260-fdcab5b923bf"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSAP00">Committee on Appropriations of the Senate</committee-name>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf7fd6b94-0c4c-4f15-9e75-31288daa92dd"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives</committee-name>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd4af478b-1539-4ffe-8b4c-a26b428219cc"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives</committee-name>.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id4a2459ed-9040-461d-ba63-0ae93b7e152f"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>evaluation</term> means, with respect to a United States foreign development and economic assistance program, the systematic collection and analysis of information about the characteristics and outcomes of the program, including projects conducted under such program, as a basis for—</text>
 <subparagraph id="ida67f37d8-e2c8-46aa-8c15-db33d75464a2"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">making judgments and evaluations regarding the program;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4965f51b-bfe8-42aa-a4dc-e291e04a198c"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improving program effectiveness; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb6089b5f-09cf-4908-af61-fe88bba1c8ae"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">informing decisions about current and future programming.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id9e929c8c-ae76-446d-9cac-33bf60bd3fa3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>United States foreign development and economic assistance</header><text>The term <term>United States foreign development and economic assistance</term> means assistance provided primarily for the purposes of foreign development and economic support, including assistance authorized under—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="id4cf9f0f2-0f8a-4e26-9b31-9fa9d52e1ce3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>part I of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2151">22 U.S.C. 2151 et seq.</external-xref>), except for—</text> <clause commented="no" id="id956fa878-2d2e-4370-81b0-86b1b4d2809b"><enum>(i)</enum><text>title IV of chapter 2 of such part (relating to the Overseas Private Investment Corporation);</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="id7f3d109d-47ff-49f8-9734-dc3506bee856"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>chapter 3 of such part (relating to International Organizations and Programs); and</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="ida2ca6169-212d-4d9f-a88e-b90c4f330a88"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>chapter 8 of such part (relating to International Narcotics Control);</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id0d1058e6-5a35-4bb5-9e3c-ea0bb3b4c38b"><enum>(B)</enum><text>chapter 4 of part II of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2346">22 U.S.C. 2346 et seq.</external-xref>; relating to Economic Support Fund);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id85dcc8e6-ab91-45cb-a5ad-cac30b26dd46"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Millennium Challenge Act of 2003 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7701">22 U.S.C. 7701 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3362fd29-d049-4071-b3a2-12a9e2a87b23"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Food for Peace Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1721">7 U.S.C. 1721 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
				</subparagraph></paragraph></section><section changed="added" committee-id="SSFR00" id="id7fa83a60-8e93-46b8-8cee-2952f2b4b69b" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>3.</enum><header>Guidelines for United States foreign development and economic assistance programs</header>
 <subsection id="id2152bd83-077b-45a9-9a81-f090498f0cd3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The purposes of this section are—</text> <paragraph id="idd4cb3ace-c6a7-4cdd-a928-0971de862de8"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to evaluate the performance of United States foreign development and economic assistance and its contribution to the policies, strategies, projects, program goals, and priorities undertaken by the Federal Government;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id582f9c61-a768-4c27-8983-f2792ef27b6b"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to foster and promote innovative programs to improve effectiveness; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id56e96d00-bf2e-4b57-89b0-124b66ff34cb"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to coordinate the monitoring and evaluation processes of Federal departments and agencies that administer United States foreign development and economic assistance.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0d89c852-459e-482b-b15f-4f3d5cb38b34"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment of guidelines</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall set forth guidelines, according to best practices of monitoring and evaluation studies and analyses, for the establishment of measurable goals, performance metrics, and monitoring and evaluation plans that can be applied with reasonable consistency to United States foreign development and economic assistance.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="id590dea59-a9f7-4c29-9fb3-97a4f321b069"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Objectives of guidelines</header>
 <paragraph id="id9881d153-448c-48f8-89d9-2ce128bd6ebf"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The guidelines established pursuant to subsection (b) shall provide direction to Federal departments and agencies that administer United States foreign development and economic assistance on—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id36dd0a55-40db-49e6-9d73-be2b765e46b6"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">monitoring the use of resources;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id09751b4d-dfc5-498a-a2f1-acb484bed34d"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">evaluating the outcomes and impacts of United States foreign development and economic assistance projects and programs; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id369f897b-ca8f-464d-8c7b-ee39905bb5cb"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">applying the findings and conclusions of such evaluations to proposed project and program design.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idf225c75e-1359-4cba-a85d-483530da53f4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Objectives</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The guidelines established pursuant to subsection (b) shall provide direction to Federal departments and agencies that administer United States foreign development and economic assistance on how—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id8f9b6034-ba87-4dc6-b12e-360529741d1a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to establish annual monitoring and evaluation agendas and objectives to plan and manage the process of monitoring, evaluating, analyzing progress, and applying learning toward achieving results;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="ide54c151a-b74d-4b58-b83e-6df974ab7a17"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to develop specific project monitoring and evaluation plans, including measurable goals and performance metrics, and to identify the resources necessary to conduct such evaluations, which should be covered by program costs, during project design;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id95196d17-d29b-4e64-a0d8-d2db8101b536"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to apply rigorous monitoring and evaluation methodologies to such programs, including through the use of impact evaluations, ex-post evaluations, or other methods as appropriate, that clearly define program logic, inputs, outputs, intermediate outcomes, and end outcomes;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id8af06dd8-b42d-4d47-bde3-d8cf90549c6b"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to disseminate guidelines for the development and implementation of monitoring and evaluation programs to all personnel, especially in the field, who are responsible for the design, implementation, and management of United States foreign development and economic assistance programs;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id80607d64-60fe-483b-997a-e8f025000363"><enum>(E)</enum><text>to establish methodologies for the collection of data, including baseline data to serve as a reference point against which progress can be measured;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf434b028-3234-41de-a504-36fc613c3834"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to evaluate, at least once in their lifetime, all programs whose dollar value equals or exceeds the median program size for the relevant office or bureau or an equivalent calculation to ensure the majority of program resources are evaluated;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6ef881e5-030f-4b62-94a5-ca3a12daa7c8"><enum>(G)</enum><text>to conduct impact evaluations on all pilot programs before replicating wherever possible, or provide a written justification for not conducting an impact evaluation where such an evaluation was deemed inappropriate or impossible;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2c96960e-fa08-41b3-8c2e-cbf8d97230bf"><enum>(H)</enum><text>to develop a clearinghouse capacity for the collection and dissemination of knowledge and lessons learned that serve as benchmarks to guide future programs for United States development professionals, implementing partners, the donor community, and aid recipient governments, and as a repository of knowledge on lessons learned;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbe65152f-e6d5-42da-b9fc-5ca33cb65ba2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to internally distribute evaluation reports;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfe4565f4d52d424ba8111c77113046dd"><enum>(J)</enum><text>to publicly report each evaluation, including an executive summary, a description of the evaluation methodology, key findings, appropriate context, including quantitative and qualitative data when available, and recommendations made in the evaluation within 90 days after the completion of the evaluation;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1b6abb0d-739e-4033-8853-8b0e0b87b5d5"><enum>(K)</enum><text>to undertake collaborative partnerships and coordinate efforts with the academic community, implementing partners, and national and international institutions that have expertise in program monitoring, evaluation, and analysis when such partnerships provide needed expertise or significantly improve the evaluation and analysis;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf6cc510c-36cb-48ba-86c3-6f2d35f58ca3"><enum>(L)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to ensure verifiable, valid, credible, precise, reliable, and timely data are available to monitoring and evaluation personnel to permit the objective evaluation of the effectiveness of United States foreign development and economic assistance programs, including an assessment of assumptions and limitations in such evaluations; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id325e3600-7375-4a6b-a8ab-c61ce491641b"><enum>(M)</enum><text>to ensure that standards of professional evaluation organizations for monitoring and evaluation efforts are employed, including ensuring the integrity and independence of evaluations, permitting and encouraging the exercise of professional judgment, and providing for quality control and assurance in the monitoring and evaluation process.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id225e12e9-7641-4f7f-9559-07cc348fbf3f"><enum>(d)</enum><header>President’s report</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees that contains a detailed description of the guidelines established pursuant to subsection (b). The report shall be submitted in unclassified form, but it may contain a classified annex.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id0f2ba56b-8b6e-430c-8018-8f0dba8d7ec5"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Comptroller General’s report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date on which the report required under subsection (d) is submitted to Congress, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees that—</text>
 <paragraph id="id44a9ed00-0253-40ca-adbf-86aa2d48020e"><enum>(1)</enum><text>analyzes the guidelines established pursuant to subsection (b); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id233399cc-f1ca-4c1d-bf10-2662671dfd34"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provides a side-by-side comparison of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id4a7bddd7-2145-468b-8da4-d8637ea8eb84"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the President’s budget request for that fiscal year of every operational unit that carries out United States foreign development and economic assistance; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd0e13ab0-2018-4a7d-b990-21eee83a13a4"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the performance of such units during the most recently completed fiscal year.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section changed="added" committee-id="SSFR00" id="id6098969c-46bc-4e4a-9eb5-08563ed4fc7f" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>4.</enum><header>Information on United States foreign development and economic assistance programs</header>
			<subsection id="idb5c7b69c-ace8-4f61-b9de-eb05dca186ad"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Publication of information</header>
 <paragraph id="id88193d28-76ea-4654-b60f-28015bba2aed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Update of existing website</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall update the Department of State’s website, <quote>ForeignAssistance.gov</quote>, to make publicly available comprehensive, timely, and comparable information on United States foreign development and economic assistance programs, including all information required under subsection (b) that is available to the Secretary of State.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id2f7b6e59-bf71-4fb4-bd7d-0d81b08d6a0d"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Information sharing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, and quarterly thereafter, the head of each Federal department or agency that administers United States foreign development and economic assistance shall provide the Secretary of State with comprehensive information about the United States foreign development and economic assistance programs carried out by such department or agency.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id20f85541-9bc5-4e5e-a58b-e0742ead60c5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Updates to website</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, and quarterly thereafter, the Secretary of State shall publish, on the <quote>ForeignAssistance.gov</quote> website or through a successor online publication, the information provided under subsection (b).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ide6590064-217c-48a3-87ce-a2faf898bc20"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Matters To be included</header>
 <paragraph id="id3da84ebe-908e-4400-be0d-40922a750846"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The information described in subsection (a)—</text> <subparagraph id="id139de08f-5423-42d3-b90a-778e9420bdf0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall be published on a detailed award-by-award and country-by-country basis; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id60541602-c170-4177-86cd-3a35840c87ad"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if assistance is provided on a regional level, shall be published on an award-by-award and region-by-region basis.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id79843860-8358-4e23-8871-051a63e368f6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Types of information</header>
 <subparagraph id="ida8010c26-ebc9-497a-a490-84aa96c339ef"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To ensure the transparency, accountability, and effectiveness of United States foreign development and economic assistance programs, the information described in subsection (a) shall include—</text>
 <clause id="iddae33b84d8fe4d8c88380e5d93467935"><enum>(i)</enum><text>links to all regional, country, and sector assistance strategies, annual budget documents, congressional budget justifications, and evaluations in accordance with section 3(c)(2)(J);</text>
 </clause><clause id="id8ccc32235eb64f45b7c892785d99a0a7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>basic descriptive summaries for United States foreign development and economic assistance programs and awards under such programs; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id9f59fada07434f799961c82a150f5a57"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>obligations and expenditures.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf2132519-b92f-493f-86d6-986e32d58588"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>Each type of information described in subparagraph (A) shall be published or updated on the appropriate website not later than 90 days after the date on which the information is issued.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0ddea966-145c-4bd8-bcbe-3a8be82fecdb"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this paragraph may be construed to require a Federal department or agency that administers United States foreign development and economic assistance to provide any information that does not relate to, or is not otherwise required by, the United States foreign development and economic assistance programs carried out by such department or agency.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id38ae5f6e-6173-4f6e-97eb-7c3e7aa1903b"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report in lieu of inclusion</header>
 <subparagraph id="idf1e21dc4-62ee-4116-9dc1-e032e26ad0ec"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Health or security of implementing partners</header><text>If the head of a Federal department or agency, in consultation with the Secretary of State, makes a determination that the inclusion of a required item of information online would jeopardize the health or security of an implementing partner or program beneficiary or would require the release of proprietary information of an implementing partner or program beneficiary, the head of the Federal department or agency shall provide such determination in writing to the appropriate congressional committees, including the basis for such determination and shall—</text>
 <clause id="id1308f5a2-04e8-4e95-887d-bf2229acc03d"><enum>(i)</enum><text>provide a briefing to the appropriate congressional committees on such information; or</text> </clause><clause id="idfe5de556-dabc-4f4f-9cb2-617f80341a50"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>submit such information to the appropriate congressional committees in a written report.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ideb804f4a-856d-4d2a-b5d7-1853747792dc"><enum>(B)</enum><header>National interests of the United States</header><text>If the Secretary of State makes a determination that the inclusion of a required item of information online would be detrimental to the national interests of the United States, the Secretary of State shall—</text>
 <clause id="idba72d977-bcc0-484f-ab09-1e5bb2bdf721"><enum>(i)</enum><text>provide such determination, including the basis for such determination, in writing to the appropriate congressional committees; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id8a53b90c-bc7f-4dc9-9583-be046950de74"><enum>(ii)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="ida9039233-12da-4c32-89e7-2c44ab2ad73e"><enum>(I)</enum><text>provide a briefing on such information to the appropriate congressional committees; or</text> </subclause><subclause changed="added" committee-id="SSFR00" id="ide97d909f-b4a5-4982-814e-4157fb197572" indent="up1" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>(II)</enum><text>submit the item of information in a written report to the appropriate congressional committees.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9e84770a-1067-405a-a050-7727173852e5"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Form</header><text>Any briefing or item of information provided under this paragraph may be provided in classified form, as appropriate.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id99c58fbd-5984-4757-b015-59a3c4a85f02"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Failure to comply</header><text>If a Federal department or agency fails to comply with the requirements under paragraph (1) or (2), subsection (a), or subsection (c), with respect to providing information described in subsection (a), and the information is not subject to a determination under subparagraph (A) or (B) of paragraph (3) not to make the information publicly available, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, in consultation with the head of such department or agency, not later than September 1, 2016, shall submit a consolidated report to the appropriate congressional committees that includes, with respect to each required item of information not made publicly available—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idb3a07484-3b85-4b17-bbc0-84eb6de0f438"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a detailed explanation of the reason for not making such information publicly available; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id578411da-ee03-4dfa-80a7-38435679ba83"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of the department’s or agency’s plan and timeline for—</text>
 <clause id="id34ae7324-a033-447b-ae9f-89a641c9e2a3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>immediately making such information publicly available; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="ida2c13ad7-ed84-4db8-a805-7e339942d676"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ensuring that such information is made publicly available in subsequent years.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idf411a99b-2383-43a3-ae82-21fa30dce43d"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Scope of information</header><text>The online publication required under subsection (a) shall, at a minimum—</text> <paragraph id="id0f15ae57-bf4d-49d3-bfd1-873acf0bcbb0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in each of the fiscal years 2016 through 2019, provide the information required under subsection (b) for fiscal years 2012 through the current fiscal year; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idd5e70bad-4cb1-4489-a653-ba9dedd535d2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for fiscal year 2020 and each fiscal year thereafter, provide the information required under subsection (b) for the immediately preceding 5 fiscal years in a fully searchable form.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id8e11a897c06c4f4fada6b3015c370780"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that the Secretary of State and the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development should coordinate the consolidation of processes and data collection and presentation for the Department of State’s website, <quote>ForeignAssistance.gov</quote>, and the United States Agency for International Development’s website, <quote>Explorer.USAID.gov</quote>, to the extent that is possible to maximize efficiencies, no later than the end of fiscal year 2018.</text></subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement><action-date>November 17, 2015</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment</action-desc></endorsement></bill>


