<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1836 IS: Defund Planned Parenthood Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1836</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150722">July 22, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S378">Mr. Lankford</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To provide for a moratorium on Federal funding to Planned Parenthood Federation of America, Inc.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H21A10D3581E54A54946EC4A8CF7DD9EC" style="OLC">
 <section id="H6D4F01ABEB274E8C98642BCF2E84BBFD" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Defund Planned Parenthood Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H0B193A5341674C5996B03CFFA25B888D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Moratorium on Federal funding to Planned Parenthood Federation of America, Inc</header> <subsection id="H8C374E8E97754690A859EA52C215FC00"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the one-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, subject to subsection (b), no funds authorized or appropriated by Federal law may be made available for any purpose to Planned Parenthood Federation of America, Inc., or any affiliate or clinic of Planned Parenthood Federation of America, Inc., unless such entities certify that Planned Parenthood Federation of America affiliates and clinics will not perform, and will not provide any funds to any other entity that performs, an abortion during such period.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idBDB407293BBD46858FFD2A48DC52DBB4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Subsection (a) shall not apply to an abortion—</text> <paragraph id="H3A57FF2671114CA0BCE0DD6E85C7E717"><enum>(1)</enum><text>if the pregnancy is the result of an act of rape or incest; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1E8159009A98482C9DFB0EEA1DFD8749"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the case where a woman suffers from a physical disorder, physical injury, or physical illness that would, as certified by a physician, place the woman in danger of death unless an abortion is performed, including a life-endangering physical condition caused by or arising from the pregnancy itself.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEBE4D6546FFE48898026D3B6D9B151D7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Repayment</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services and the Secretary of Agriculture shall seek repayment of any Federal assistance received by Planned Parenthood Federation of America, Inc., or any affiliate or clinic of Planned Parenthood Federation of America, Inc., if it violates the terms of the certification required by subsection (a) during the period specified in subsection (a).</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


