<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S888 IS: Promoting Regional Energy Partnerships for Advancing Resilient Energy Systems Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 888</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150326">March 26, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S353">Mr. Schatz</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S359">Mr. Heinrich</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To promote Federal-State partnerships for developing regional energy strategies and plans to
			 mitigate risks in changing energy systems, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body>
 <section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Promoting Regional Energy Partnerships for Advancing Resilient Energy Systems Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PREPARE Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </section><section id="idBB3DD92B9A7048A1931B2E27D4F17F96"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text> <paragraph id="id4b647bdb771b449287faad1f32b10d30"><enum>(1)</enum><text>energy systems in the United States are in a period of significant change;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id1f408b93be6e4bf7918923b2f54c91e1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>aging infrastructure, new technologies, increasing complexity, and growing threats are posing new challenges to energy systems and their resilience;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idcfeff7f1636f46fd81b6214d0f185e56"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the interconnected nature of energy systems means regional energy strategies and plans will be more effective at preparing for challenges and mitigating risks;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id35AD57697D2242D4A5B92FA8BB2374B6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>States have distinct needs and unique energy, environmental, and economic goals and will play a critical role in developing and implementing regional energy strategies and plans;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idDFAFBF4B4DBA4D728C8D93831B164B65"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the views and participation of a broad range of stakeholders in the development and implementation of regional energy strategies and plans is needed for success; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id3D07CAA59B6B445D948EDE697259B49A"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the Federal Government, in the role of a long-term strategic energy partner, can effectively—</text> <subparagraph id="idF9197A7F357944B38B5BCC8F5DCF12C8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>establish strategic alliances with States;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id72E419A4471948E3AD678A2D6AF49846"><enum>(B)</enum><text>convene stakeholders;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idCF4DBD66F7B842199E6A1F473B0A33BC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>facilitate the process of developing regional energy strategies and plans; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC0E41C5FE4F14B838DCC0AF7840E8D5E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>provide technical assistance and support in implementation.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="idA125C32169634764A69E7423D29ADEF9"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
 <paragraph id="id556B6E3AA3F244489A2F7A3BDCE337BE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Cooperative agreement</header><text>The term <term>cooperative agreement</term> has the meaning given the term in sections 6302 and 6305 of title 31, United States Code.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id04B31B2092854CC5AF7002371E9C7F1C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretaries</header><text>The term <term>Secretaries</term> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idB5F3A69C78B042E8B5E48371AA28C444"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary of Energy, acting through the Assistant Secretary of the Office of Electricity Delivery and Energy Reliability in consultation with the Assistant Secretary of Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy, the Assistant Secretary of Fossil Energy, and the Director of the Office of Nuclear Energy, Science, and Technology Programs; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3F2B8D8FB39440DDA73D23A23CCAC4D3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Assistant Secretary for Land and Minerals Management in consultation with the Director of the Bureau of Land Management, the Director of the Bureau of Ocean Energy Management, the Assistant Secretary for Indian Affairs, and the Assistant Secretary for Fish and Wildlife and Parks.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID914346B62C5D497EA7E427F09091F8FA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="ID1AA0C8024B5B488EA17F81A36FBC1821"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a State;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID792A8B98FE9C42679797E3F1D68FC25F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the District of Columbia;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID28D43A31F3264D79A65D4436F400AF2F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID4912258B462B4AAD8DC29F5610699D3D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any other territory or possession of the United States.</text>
				</subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="ida00a99ae2d9242db97590235f6140c84"><enum>4.</enum><header>Regional energy partnerships</header>
 <subsection id="id35B976F87D4D4468A1E5C8B8DDCE8226"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretaries shall provide assistance in accordance with this section for the purpose of developing energy strategies and plans that help harmonize and promote national, regional, and State energy goals, including goals for advancing resilient energy systems to mitigate risks and prepare for emerging energy challenges.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idad7292e4ad7e4cac8f672807ffd8eae3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text>The Secretaries may provide such technical assistance to States, political subdivisions of States, substate regional organizations (including organizations that cross State boundaries), multistate regional organizations, Indian tribes, and nonprofit organizations as the Secretaries determine appropriate to promote—</text>
 <paragraph id="ide71f308f38cd4bb4b765fc843f77ca55"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the development and improvement of regional energy strategies, where appropriate, and plans that sustain and promote energy system modernization across the United States;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id21929dece61a40ae80223add3738205c"><enum>(2)</enum><text>investment in energy infrastructure, technological capacity, innovation, and workforce development to keep pace with the changing energy ecosystem;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id1c00bcf8a37248a7b3d0ae582a601a72"><enum>(3)</enum><text>structural transformation of the financial, regulatory, legal, and institutional systems that govern energy planning, production, and delivery within States and regions; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id1f1e471b167348f480d4f7c2d27a01df"><enum>(4)</enum><text>public-private partnerships for the implementation of regional energy strategies and plans.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idfa678bf9ebf14c32901bdb06e7db0cb6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Cooperative agreements</header> <paragraph id="id22df19013bd04531a3d40133edea664a"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretaries may enter into cooperative agreements with one or more States and Indian tribes, on a regional basis, to develop and implement strategies and plans to address the energy challenges of States, Indian tribes, and regions.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id74dc24535c28427181145f9f48f7203c"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>A cooperative agreement entered into under this subsection shall include provisions covering or providing—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id420762fb99194835ac422c9ad86e3903"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the purpose and goals of the cooperative agreement, such as advancing energy efficiency, clean energy, fuel and supply diversity, energy system resiliency, economic development, or other goals to make measurable, significant progress toward specified metrics and objectives that are agreed to by the States or Indian tribes and the Secretaries;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfb25db34a1a14396b1c2b701921078f2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the roles and responsibilities of the States or Indian tribes and the Secretaries for various functions of the cooperative agreement, including outreach, communication, resources, and capabilities;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id28cdb7a6bfb1465a8fdeac2be7f373b3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a comprehensive framework for the development of energy strategies and plans for States, Indian tribes, or regions;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3b353c5a09c14a95abc8c6c1512013c0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>timeframes with associated metrics and objectives;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide54da127b98949ab96a514e596e39cf0"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a governance structure to resolve conflicts and facilitate decisionmaking consistent with underlying authorities; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id40c9784b071045c4842329def1702249"><enum>(F)</enum><text>other provisions determined necessary by the Secretaries, in consultation with the States or Indian tribes, to achieve the purposes described in paragraph (1).</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idbf45fc4ea53247a7ac324fce3deea93f"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Staff</header>
 <paragraph id="id20363b0b681e4abc932345d9a0e57989"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of the entering into a cooperative agreement under subsection (c), the Secretaries shall, as appropriate, assign or employ individuals who have expertise in the technical and regulatory issues relating to the cooperative agreement, including particular expertise in (as applicable)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id79036cdc1c114a7cbbacf5b333f81857"><enum>(A)</enum><text>energy systems integration;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7af92732b7f443168d7788a3dbc8d89f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>renewable energy and energy efficiency;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9a0a524fc5a3425faaec7ed376af9061"><enum>(C)</enum><text>innovative financing mechanisms;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idba8ea3efc81444acbf5f61674eef62c1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>utility regulatory policy;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id71e4a889faa84b1bb06e1fd422c03d41"><enum>(E)</enum><text>modeling and analysis;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id604740a5b33147269854327cac9aa92f"><enum>(F)</enum><text>facilitation and arbitration;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id696dd262667d4b37b45bb48912190363"><enum>(G)</enum><text>energy assurance and emergency preparedness; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id93139b27500148c7b1b5ee7145ba8e24"><enum>(H)</enum><text>cyber and physical security of energy systems.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id3b4ef5fa0a584a969610935fb2dc0b7e"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>Each individual assigned to carry out a cooperative agreement under paragraph (1) shall—</text> <subparagraph id="id753fc67bcf1a4d8d89c5ef7faa15e7a4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>report to a location in the applicable State, Indian tribe, or region not later than 90 days after the date of assignment;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3351549a841b4c7db51ef09e2e29db7e"><enum>(B)</enum><text>be responsible for issues and technical assistance relating to the cooperative agreement;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1eb8f4c79c584a268d00653fd7893366"><enum>(C)</enum><text>participate as part of the team of personnel working on developing and implementing the applicable regional energy strategy and plan; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id64288BC9DBE847B7A53FB51FF8F2C27C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>build capacity within the State, Indian tribe, or region to continue to implement the goals of this Act after the expiration of the cooperative agreement.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idc305778691964c059a8920b2e478036d"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Comprehensive framework</header><text>Under a cooperative agreement, a comprehensive framework shall be developed that identifies opportunities and actions across various energy sectors and cross-cutting issue areas, including—</text>
 <paragraph id="id5193a5e96ba449399b3682d3b6cdd2f9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>end-use efficiency;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idd9272daae4c648b2a261f18e63c17710"><enum>(2)</enum><text>energy supply, including electric generation and fuels;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ida5b273828e464616a82d15ebda1976f8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>energy storage and delivery;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id0d1739e97a4b4b1c9d0519b0687ca081"><enum>(4)</enum><text>transportation;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id4b17ec3da77f45698659adc6b22133a6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>technical integration, including standards and interdependencies;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idf0a70e04e01e4e1ca9a9a35726399ce9"><enum>(6)</enum><text>institutional structures;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id15820575099245ab85b73af66253d567"><enum>(7)</enum><text>regulatory policies;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idb9b5ef1faff84485a049d7d387ec0888"><enum>(8)</enum><text>financial incentives; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id90a37c3182224eef920dd9864da674d8"><enum>(9)</enum><text>market mechanisms.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id421fecee1d794f08aad20e7958be8686"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Awards</header> <paragraph id="ida2ac5cb4dc574efa8f4464f3dcc7a331"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text>
 <subparagraph id="id92D81C42290D49A0A8B26D31EDFF683D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Application group</header><text>The term <term>application group</term> means a group of States or Indian tribes that have—</text> <clause id="id3D6ED38CA92C4139A5A893146EAC0F5B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>entered into a cooperative agreement, on a regional basis, with the Secretaries under subsection (c); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idBB14B987A8B2404DA9B3F27A1C5D93CC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>submitted an application for an award under paragraph (2)(A).</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id983B0F1AF7DC49CB991901B17CB439A0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Partner State</header><text>The term <term>partner State</term> means a State or Indian tribe that is part of an application group.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id85B14E66C64640718653641D90483F16"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applications</header>
 <subparagraph id="idB7EE47ABAC7B4D0CA2488B99DC3D8EC9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B), an application group may apply to the Secretaries for awards under this subsection.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA39F005729254BD18648835E09C1EFD4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Individual States</header><text>An individual State or Indian tribe that has entered into a cooperative agreement with the Secretaries under subsection (c) may apply to the Secretaries for an award under this subsection if the State or Indian tribe demonstrates to the Secretaries the uniqueness of the energy challenges facing the State or Indian tribe.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idcd66e9decc7b40299c6a64ce731dd213"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Base amount</header><text>Subject to paragraph (4), the Secretaries shall provide 6 awards under this subsection, with a base amount of $20,000,000 for each award.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="id2a380f8623234fd7a4aad00e3ed09271"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Bonus amount for application groups</header>
 <subparagraph id="id0E8D0CA608424FD0AD28C2AE4878C6E2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B), the Secretaries shall increase the amount of an award provided under this subsection to an application group for a successful application under paragraph (2)(A) by the quotient obtained by dividing—</text>
 <clause id="id6FC7A222319B43C6A7F5E6A73DC0B9FE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the product obtained by multiplying—</text> <subclause id="id23D5DF8A94464A6DBE68EE0D395667AA"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the number of partner States in the application group; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idB0AD625BEB4648B0A07FDE33009234ED"><enum>(II)</enum><text>$100,000,000; by</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="idA986D44413C44BCABAC41C0FB49B6A50"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the total number of partner States of all successful applications under this subsection.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4c2d8d744c614e1f9be56001d8d0dcf3"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Maximum amount</header><text>The amount of a bonus determined under subparagraph (A) shall not exceed an amount that represents $5,000,000 for each partner State that is a member of the relevant application group.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id206a3f5788984eee918473d9b9f817c8"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>A State or Indian tribe shall not be part of more than 1 award under this subsection.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id52de2512cb6246c9a71011ba3f5a155d"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Selection criteria</header><text>In selecting applications for awards under this subsection, the Secretaries shall consider—</text>
 <subparagraph id="iddbd5818e2f124a1cadd6f2a5d4409553"><enum>(A)</enum><text>existing commitments from States or Indian tribes, such as memoranda of understanding;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4036f6194dae4e6f9c655e5419c1b37c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for States that are part of the contiguous 48 States, the number of contiguous States involved that cover a region;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idef853c0cc7f249f0948a26c7210df807"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the diversity of the regions represented by all applications;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id572b7c3b7ed24a0da57e7814d58962e5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the amount of cost-share or in-kind contributions from States or Indian tribes;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd883e43b002b40bdb56782fd7c0616e5"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the scope and focus of regional and State programs and strategies, with an emphasis on energy system resiliency and grid modernization, efficiency, and clean energy;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA04D3C8858E24BFBBB7F1EECA7ADC7AD"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a management and oversight plan to ensure that objectives are met;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id513f6899a22544ac86f071c78838c81d"><enum>(G)</enum><text>an outreach plan for the inclusion of stakeholders in the process for developing and implementing State or regional energy strategies and plans;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1edf153a05d84f2f886918c9f1b7cf3b"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the inclusion of tribal entities;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida5587d9fc8d1473aaa26b26ed3e604a8"><enum>(I)</enum><text>plans to fund and sustain activities identified in regional energy strategies and plans; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5347db84e6d44b9981b6d9449cb251a0"><enum>(J)</enum><text>the clarity of roles and responsibilities of each State and the Secretaries.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id50d949349a06426f95cf3c77e959d4f5"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Use of awards</header> <subparagraph id="id86B58AF693584177A2FA474D8D100620"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Awards provided under this subsection shall be used to achieve the purpose of this section, including by—</text>
 <clause id="idb639db1d434a4d7e9f2ecd66f0a6ddfc"><enum>(i)</enum><text>conducting technical analyses, resource studies, and energy system baselines;</text> </clause><clause id="id9341af8f9ccb4b0dbc4a120dde8cbab7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>convening and providing education to stakeholders on emerging energy issues;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id25b2f269022e42c7a5ed1ecf76a0fd39"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>building decision support and planning tools; and</text> </clause><clause id="idbf09114be09b4a8f9a86fc813b16ea18"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>improving communication between and participation of stakeholders.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf3f253b1813f49dfa1c25f50b4117f9e"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Awards provided under this subsection shall not be used for—</text> <clause id="idca71515127f243f9997846182a08bc87"><enum>(i)</enum><text>capitalization of green banks or loan guarantees; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="id3e4a08d7b0154c9b8e7ba98d28fa9da5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>building facilities or funding capital projects.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id4c246de5ab694558a903e957cc283365"><enum>5.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header> <subsection id="id6923cc382cef478e9d4fb838ee9ab884"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act $250,000,000, to remain available until expended.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id3f86aad321b743b582a23b4988997d17"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Allocation</header><text>Of the amount authorized to be appropriated under subsection (a)—</text> <paragraph id="id48545b6f4d904d5aae41957faf605ae3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$120,000,000 shall be used for the base amount of awards under section 4(f)(3);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idd38af973dfe04bdea9289c7914451de6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$100,000,000 shall be used for the bonus amount of awards under section 4(f)(4); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id65afa68a9daf4bab9d8534d04f42a5a3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>$30,000,000 shall be for the administration of this Act, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id8AFF80B33CC441BBBED68B9F43DC4829"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the assignment of staff under section 4(d); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id85294EC14B194BEE8CA64F06635673DB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if the Secretaries determine appropriate, the sharing of best practices from regional partnerships by parties to cooperative agreements entered into under this Act.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idb9539eb2a6444eb6850c3028cdcb09df"><enum>(c)</enum><header>State energy offices</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Funds provided to a State under this Act shall be provided to the office within the State that is responsible for developing the State energy plan for the State under part D of title III of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6321">42 U.S.C. 6321 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="id7702CC5D6E6C46EBB9902F87124F7177"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Maintenance of
 funding</header><text>The funding provided to States under this Act shall supplement (and not supplant) funding provided under part D of title III of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6321">42 U.S.C. 6321 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


