<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1687 IS: Offshore Reinsurance Tax Fairness Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-06-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1687</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150625">June 25, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to restrict the insurance business exception to passive
			 foreign investment company rules.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body>
 <section id="id7E876A725A0146B68AE9109E76C955F0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Offshore Reinsurance Tax Fairness Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H58AFC7F7C6014A6EBF3C8373B119D084" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Restriction on insurance business exception to passive foreign investment company rules</header> <subsection id="HE139E96D287D4A4C9B4D98E21F4AF788"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/1297">Section 1297(b)(2)(B)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended to read as follows:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFAE92EF2536E4332B1740BCE8EF5D47C" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H4C0E2B5DF9164BC3A4EE491A4669B4C6"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">derived in the active conduct of an insurance business by a qualifying insurance corporation (as defined in subsection (f)),</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD11037C8F5164E95BCA76BE982E0387C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Qualifying insurance corporation defined</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/1297">Section 1297</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idDAB963CDDE2B4C5794AE868227EE0C24" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="idBD760938E13148CA8B64B3764E004ACE"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Qualifying insurance corporation</header><text>For purposes of subsection (b)(2)(B)—</text> <paragraph id="idD585785AAC584847B1385F9F68510A01"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>qualifying insurance corporation</term> means, with respect to any taxable year, a foreign corporation—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H1B59034A0B614E9BBF9300A366D2E00E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>which would be subject to tax under subchapter L if such corporation were a domestic corporation, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB9CD43E5D5B74D00AAB4B0B9F378EF91"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the applicable insurance liabilities of which constitute more than 25 percent of its total assets, determined on the basis of such liabilities and assets as reported on the corporation’s applicable financial statement for the last year ending with or within the taxable year.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id8428DFE8F2D04AFDB5F8FF7B39CFFC0C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Alternative facts and circumstances test for certain corporations</header><text>If a corporation fails to qualify as a qualified insurance corporation under paragraph (1) solely because the percentage determined under paragraph (1)(B) is 25 percent or less, a United States person that owns stock in such corporation may elect to treat such stock as stock of a qualifying insurance corporation if—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id8A1A59CE94614AB0852ED81D31328139"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the percentage so determined for the corporation is at least 10 percent, and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0E1EC9F70F9540A9AE5785D733B991ED"><enum>(B)</enum><text>under regulations provided by the Secretary, based on the applicable facts and circumstances—</text>
 <clause id="idF7EB69063D36425F89687B6EF427EA3A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the corporation is predominantly engaged in an insurance business, and</text> </clause><clause id="id31187D1CE8C441C6918B18701CDD451A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>such failure is due solely to temporary circumstances involving such insurance business.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2332CD0961EF45FD8EB436BEB12F0AD7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Applicable insurance liabilities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection—</text> <subparagraph id="HAE59EF8FC9774FDE8441150EE2A2CD16"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>applicable insurance liabilities</term> means, with respect to any life or property and casualty insurance business—</text>
 <clause id="H42DAAA4C20094E9BB6ECA2B1F2F9E00F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>loss and loss adjustment expenses, and</text> </clause><clause id="HFB32F5AA635F4A69B3E4537E5CEF6116"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>reserves (other than deficiency, contingency, or unearned premium reserves) for life and health insurance risks and life and health insurance claims with respect to contracts providing coverage for mortality or morbidity risks.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id590568CADE46468BA0949B343B0C6DDE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitations on amount of liabilities</header><text>Any amount determined under clause (i) or (ii) of subparagraph (A) shall not exceed the lesser of such amount—</text>
 <clause id="id1531E5A4393F406F846D9DC4093FD22E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>as reported to the applicable insurance regulatory body in the applicable financial statement described in paragraph (4)(A) (or, if less, the amount required by applicable law or regulation), or</text>
 </clause><clause id="id8FA214BC362748D1A0D43E4C51CE425C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>as determined under regulations prescribed by the Secretary.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id78F8834F83304D8EB37E1CE7F977DEEF"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Other definitions and rules</header><text>For purposes of this subsection—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8DDBCDCCDDC24C1B8315B99BBC729827"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Applicable financial statement</header><text>The term <term>applicable financial statement</term> means a statement for financial reporting purposes which—</text> <clause id="H0E020ACD23684F1D9FF39C0FCA9AC0D6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is made on the basis of generally accepted accounting principles,</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9081EE098E8A4F0298C71A3B9F77ED4B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is made on the basis of international financial reporting standards, but only if there is no statement that meets the requirement of clause (i), or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H97D026A66DBB404D89B45F4663F164B8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>except as otherwise provided by the Secretary in regulations, is the annual statement which is required to be filed with the applicable insurance regulatory body, but only if there is no statement which meets the requirements of clause (i) or (ii).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idAF1BE0D3179F4CE99CFD082543AFEA2E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Applicable insurance regulatory body</header><text>The term <term>applicable insurance regulatory body</term> means, with respect to any insurance business, the entity established by law to license, authorize, or regulate such business and to which the statement described in subparagraph (A) is provided.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H44EE2C816CAB4D92908CEEDE8EB592AE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2015.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

