<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S923 IS: Healthy Relationships Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 923</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150414">April 14, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S293">Mr. Graham</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S299">Mr. Vitter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S303">Mr. Thune</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S365">Mr. Scott</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S261">Mr. Sessions</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S212">Mr. Coats</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To authorize the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Administrator of the
			 Health Resources and Services Administration, to award grants on a
			 competitive basis to public and private entities to provide qualified
			 sexual risk avoidance education to youth and their parents.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Healthy Relationships Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </section><section id="id3B835C340F2643DD8E4D1672AAA96F31"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sexual risk avoidance education</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part P of title III of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/280g">42 U.S.C. 280g et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idA8F2B83A07194261945368D649348104" style="OLC">
				<section id="id6CA0D27BEED54D9CBD6909E4A0AAA0B3"><enum>399V–6.</enum><header>Sexual risk avoidance education</header>
 <subsection id="id47CB59DCDACC44DA8002702D29A85E3C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, may award grants on a competitive basis to public and private entities to provide qualified sexual risk avoidance education to youth and their parents.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id386545B99E584B02BBCCC6BCB6C26DA1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Qualified Sexual Risk Avoidance Education</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under subsection (a), an entity shall submit an application to the Secretary describing a sexual risk avoidance education program that the entity would offer and that meets all of the following requirements:</text>
 <paragraph id="id0d4cebded21e4d91a61ae981bd0d15c5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The primary emphasis and context for each topic covered through the program shall be the unambiguous message that postponing sexual activity is the optimal sexual health behavior for youth.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id03C2447C185340D0B7C2DD53C04CF101"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The education shall be medically accurate.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idEA20AE38AF3741FCBFE199F647883E8D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The education shall use an evidence-based approach.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idDAAA26744E7547B8BFBD05D38170CA9C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The education shall be age appropriate.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id1A9ECA2A61274AD7820529E53D61AE34"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The education shall include thorough treatment of each of the following topics:</text>
 <subparagraph id="idd311897ffb8f49758cbb02f1e7c7faff"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The holistic individual and societal benefits associated with personal responsibility, success sequencing, self-regulation, goal-setting, healthy decisionmaking, and a focus on the future.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6ACB2809A57540A9848FB9B7B10785AE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The research-based advantage of reserving sexual activity for marriage, as associated with poverty prevention and optimal physical and emotional health for all youth, regardless of previous sexual experience.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idBC801CC64587436298F5C592B9DDB1B2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The skills needed to resist the pervasive sex-saturated culture that portrays teenage sexual activity as an expected norm, with few risks or negative consequences.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id66C5EE8403864202AE201F584662F401"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The foundational components of healthy relationships and their impact on the formation of healthy marriages and safe and stable families.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9143CD491E98426FB3162B739DDAE5CF"><enum>(E)</enum><text>How to avoid sexual coercion, dating violence, and risk behaviors, such as drugs, alcohol, and the misuse of social media.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idC0D09C88AE6745ED947DE801C9298725"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The education shall ensure that any information provided on contraception emphasizes the superior health benefits of sexual delay and does not exaggerate the effectiveness of contraception in preventing the physical and non-physical consequences of teen sexual activity.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id2a48450b42e145c6b90a103412bfa006"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding grants under subsection (a), the Secretary shall give priority to applicants proposing programs to provide qualified sexual risk avoidance education that—</text>
 <paragraph id="id5922e44f4b854cc887ef4de063aaa47f"><enum>(1)</enum><text>serves youth throughout the middle and high school grades; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idBF10BD56EC234D27BA172A8F2D08F7AC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>will promote parent-child communication regarding healthy sexual decisionmaking.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idda8ef511d59c45889fcb7f554721aa4e"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="id3d57efc2a732448693cf20288d9bba09"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>age appropriate</term> means appropriate for the general developmental and social maturity of the age group, as opposed to appropriate to the cognitive ability to understand a topic or the atypical development of a small segment of the targeted population.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idd4af579466f74ae8afcb02dd13b47f46"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>evidence-based approach</term> means an approach that—</text> <subparagraph id="id3f9f57e50173438f943f62a79e6aa59d"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has a clear theoretical framework integrating research findings with practical implementation relevant to the field;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idAAD7C9E8B4D041968AFAA2C27F8A09F6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>matches the needs and desired outcomes for the intended audience; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idEEB3AB442803469CAD898C2E94C1E833"><enum>(C)</enum><text>if effectively implemented, will demonstrate improved outcomes for the targeted population.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id4fa4d44e241047078edd8ecbaa9844de"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <term>medically accurate</term> means referenced to peer-reviewed research by medical, educational, scientific, governmental, or public health publications, organizations, or agencies.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id86413ee23c63423f8bfaf814dba298a8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The term <term>sexual risk avoidance</term> means voluntarily refraining from sexual activity.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id1b1e65c6485d4f4a879b3ff935411a2f"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The term <term>sexual activity</term> means genital contact or sexual stimulation for the purpose of arousal, including sexual intercourse.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idedbe325463bc472198fb2603a1f8a97c"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The term <term>success sequencing</term> means the progression of youth through a series of behavioral benchmarks that increases the youth's chances of avoiding poverty, in the following sequence: completing school, securing a job, and marrying before bearing children.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idf1fee0ca63594118a4cad71cad195fe0"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of Appropriations</header>
 <paragraph id="id79b4a64f8e9b4739ac7e90a6f78403fe"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated $110,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2016 through 2020 to carry out this section. Amounts authorized to be appropriated by the preceding sentence shall be derived exclusively from amounts in the Prevention and Public Health Fund established by section 4002 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300u-11">42 U.S.C. 300u–11</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id53B365C92CEE48239CC3ED5AC896953A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federal administrative costs</header><text>Of the amounts appropriated under paragraph (1) for a fiscal year—</text> <subparagraph id="idfe95c8cc6b6246949070be3cacf70bc2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not more than $1,000,000 may be used for Federal administrative costs; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB8F300A2315F44818A79F1C63F029A58"><enum>(B)</enum><text>of the amount used by the Secretary for administrative costs, at least 40 percent shall be used for training and technical assistance by qualified organizations—</text>
 <clause id="id97f1cf9901b041cca3e1684aca54309f"><enum>(i)</enum><text>whose sole focus is the development and advancement of sexual risk avoidance;</text> </clause><clause id="idFB5F5588E7AF4419ABA23738F548D8B4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>have expertise in theory-based sexual risk avoidance curriculum development and implementation;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id830D9D11D5B345519330782771914BF1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>have direct experience in developing sexual risk avoidance evaluation instruments; and</text> </clause><clause id="id618977BF9FE9455880C3B4FDFD50FC3B"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>can offer technical assistance and training on a wide range of topics relevant to the sexual risk avoidance field.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


