<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S94 IS: To prohibit the provision of Federal funds to State and local governments for payment of obligations, to prohibit the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System from financially assisting State and local governments, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 94</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150107">January 7, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S299">Mr. Vitter</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To prohibit the provision of Federal funds to State and local governments for payment of
			 obligations, to prohibit the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve
			 System from financially assisting State and local governments, and for
			 other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="id6DB85E49459A4BFD93AA0603A4732E54" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Prohibition on the use of
			 Federal funds to pay State and local obligations</header><subsection id="id2B3E640504E04CC595F7231A57BEA922"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no Federal funds may be used to purchase or guarantee obligations of, issue lines of credit to, or provide direct or indirect grants-and-aid to, any State government, municipal government, local government, or county government which, on or after January 26, 2011, has defaulted on its obligations, is at risk of defaulting, or is likely to default, absent such assistance from the United States Government.</text></subsection><subsection id="ID296be60133d94a539ec59e83736218f0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limit on Use of
 Borrowed Funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury shall not, directly or indirectly, use general fund revenues or funds borrowed pursuant to title 31, United States Code, to purchase or guarantee any asset or obligation of any State government, municipal government, local government, or county government, or otherwise to assist such government entity, if, on or after January 26, 2011, that State government, municipal government, or county government has defaulted on its obligations, is at risk of defaulting, or is likely to default, absent such assistance from the United States Government.</text></subsection><subsection id="idCC0D84C4A8CC418AB19149C9192CAA6A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Prohibition on
 Federal Reserve assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System shall not provide or extend to, or authorize with respect to, any State government, municipal government, local government, county government, or other entity that has taxing authority or bonding authority, any funds, loan guarantees, credits, or any other financial instrument or other authority, including the purchasing of the bonds of such State, municipality, locality, county, or other bonding authority, or to otherwise assist such government entity under any authority of the Board of Governors.</text></subsection><subsection id="IDcbc55ddddba9455986ede940c2d6dacb"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Subsections (a) through (c) shall not apply to Federal assistance provided in response to a natural disaster.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


