<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1616 IS: Saving Federal Dollars Through Better Use of Government Purchase and Travel Cards Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-06-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 1616</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150618">June 18, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S277">Mr. Carper</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S153">Mr. Grassley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S312">Mrs. McCaskill</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S345">Mr. Johnson</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To provide for the identification and prevention of improper payments and the identification of
			 strategic sourcing opportunities by reviewing and analyzing the use of
			 Federal agency charge cards.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Saving Federal Dollars Through Better Use of Government Purchase and Travel Cards Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </section><section id="id1C6B31B4715B497EA16C8A44EEC94A57"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="idD05ECF2832F84ADF8AAC3393F25E86D6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Strategic sourcing</header><text>The term <term>strategic sourcing</term> means analyzing and modifying a Federal agency’s spending patterns to better leverage its purchasing power, reduce costs, and improve overall performance.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idB8ED8C75918F48068F2A3977802B3264"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Improper payment</header><text>The term <term>improper payment</term> has the meaning given the term in section 2 of the Improper Payments Information Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/31/3321">31 U.S.C. 3321</external-xref> note).</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="id15ca99aa1bd5406aac5b3b5a2b5fd24f"><enum>3.</enum><header>Office of Federal Charge Card Analytics and Review</header>
 <subsection id="idc3aa1b3b7e4e41e1b2ca6f3d211ed42e"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Administrator of General Services shall establish an Office of Federal Charge Card Analytics and Review for improving the use and oversight of purchase and travel card transactions by Federal agencies and programs, including for the general purposes of—</text>
 <paragraph id="idfe5529e3266c4998a4ae1baf0922b5a5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identifying, preventing, and recovering improper payments (including fraud), and identifying and preventing other inappropriate use of purchase and travel cards that do not conform with Federal or agency purchase laws, policies, rules, or best practices; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id57afd90d4b1241ce952b7396c1b3dfff"><enum>(2)</enum><text>determining opportunities for strategic sourcing.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id967867b12bea42d3bceba8431a45e4de"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Office shall carry out the following duties:</text>
 <paragraph id="id1cc050ae8ae2492a98f9e25b71272229"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Interagency Review for Improper Payments and Strategic Sourcing</header><text>The review of purchase and travel card transaction data of all Federal agencies for the purposes described in subsection (a). The review shall include transactions for individual Federal agencies as well as across multiple Federal agencies and programs. Findings of potential improper payments (including fraud), opportunities for strategic sourcing, or issues of interest shall be communicated to the appropriate agency officials. The office may, as appropriate, use existing General Services Administration databases of purchase and travel card transaction for the interagency review. This analysis by the Office shall not end the requirement for individual agency oversight as described in the Government Charge Card Abuse Prevention Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/194">Public Law 112–194</external-xref>), but shall be considered as complementary and used in coordination with the individual agency.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idbb60297deb8f4255a8d5a1a56c3a6732"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Analytics library</header><text>The establishment of a library of analytics tools and data sources for use by all Federal agencies (including inspectors general) for the purposes described in subsection (a).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idf9cf9de906854ddf84da1c776625e84c"><enum>4.</enum><header>Guidance on improving information sharing to curb improper payments</header>
 <subsection id="id474f135c86a7412aa75a54f1ea1b1b87"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, in consultation with the Administrator of General Services and agency heads, and the interagency task force established under section 5, shall issue guidance on improving information sharing by government agencies (including inspectors general) for the purposes of section 3(a)(1).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id202de57ddad34be7b7df60637f0a5939"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The guidance issued under subsection (a) shall—</text> <paragraph id="id27b78add19804a70b62a4621b57c2b0f"><enum>(1)</enum><text>require relevant officials at Federal agencies to identify high-risk merchants and communicate that information to the appropriate level of administration within the agencies;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idc05080e6017c408bb56e11402487c945"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ensure that appropriate officials at Federal agencies review the reports issued by charge card-issuing contractors of potential fraudulent or otherwise inappropriate activity, including the suspension of purchase and travel card accounts, travel card activity outside of the official government travel location, transactions that occur with high risk merchant, and suspicious levels of cash withdrawals;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id1874128677ae418bb6084e28987fa8f6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provide for the appropriate sharing of information related to potential fraudulent transactions, fraud schemes, and high risk merchants with the Office of Federal Charge Card Analytics and Review established under section 3 and the appropriate officials in Federal agencies; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id08a656eee55c47908d6f8f84ab96e9fc"><enum>(4)</enum><text>other requirements determined appropriate by the Director for the purposes of carrying out this Act.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id2dc8830002214c93ab778f7ad64b2efe"><enum>5.</enum><header>Interagency task force</header>
 <subsection id="idc5bb9925bc2d43adbeaf2f5c800bec4a"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Administrator of General Services and the Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall establish and co-chair an interagency task force to develop and share best practices for the purposes described in section 3(a).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idfcf3efcfffe34418a9670c70defddf7a"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The best practices developed under subsection (a) shall—</text> <paragraph id="idf307f827ba004e71aca85488a2692b21"><enum>(1)</enum><text>cover rules, edits, and task order or contract modifications related to charge card-issuing contractors;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id5526cd3e65d84ea7b7889565cef7be9f"><enum>(2)</enum><text>include the review of purchase and travel card transaction data of all Federal agencies for the purpose of determining strategic sourcing opportunities; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id56533a1cf8934c9590bea4b07f8d1d2b"><enum>(3)</enum><text>include other best practices as determined by the Administrator and Director.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1da1ba063abb465d968315388c9c807c"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text>The interagency task force shall meet regularly as determined by the co-chairs, for a duration of three years, and include those agencies as described in section 2 of the Government Charge Card Abuse Prevention Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/194">Public Law 112–194</external-xref>) and others identified by the co-chairs.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="id28f4ee34d0274b36bbe88b6709dda90c"><enum>6.</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header>
 <subsection id="id9555da0ee79f4a6c87fb9479acc9b6f2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>General services administration report</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator for General Services shall submit a report to Congress on the implementation of this Act, including the metrics used in determining whether the analytic and investigatory efforts have reduced, or contributed to the reduction of, improper payments or improved strategic sourcing.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="iddc8f69ff8a854a219ef5c5b872553ea0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Agency reports</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the head of each Federal agency described in section 2 of the Government Charge Card Abuse Prevention Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/194">Public Law 112–194</external-xref>) shall submit a report to Congress on its activities to implement this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


