<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S2241 IS: Combat Heroin Epidemic and Backlog Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-11-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 2241</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151104">November 4, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To combat the heroin epidemic and drug sample backlogs.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Combat Heroin Epidemic and Backlog Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </section><section id="id6FB07A6C062C42CAA2D90E2BC6BE91BA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Confronting the use of heroin and associated drugs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3711">42 U.S.C. 3711 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB2C926F01B0E4BF58F04F3E9DD652A7C" style="OLC">
				<part id="id3A301DB87B104FA59AABE405DAEDC0FA" style="OLC"><enum>LL<?LEXA-Enum LL?></enum><header>Confronting the use of heroin and associated drugs</header>
					<section id="id139C160CCA5E45BE95F0239A08713FD1"><enum>3021.</enum><header>Authority to make grants to address public safety  and heroin distribution, sale, and use</header>
 <subsection id="id710111B335E047D3A0369C441E0822DD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of this section is to assist States and Indian tribes to—</text> <paragraph id="idbc8f4db7e928485da691aff268b3913b"><enum>(1)</enum><text>carry out programs to address the distribution, sale, and use of heroin, fentanyl, and associated synthetic drugs; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id8e5ee40ba8cb4e228bd90e2482f00af9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>improve the ability of State, tribal, and local government institutions to carry out such programs.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idb5d93d233a2141d3983410001ebec87d"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grant authorization</header><text>The Attorney General, through the Bureau of Justice Assistance, may make grants to States and Indian tribes to address the distribution, sale, and use of heroin, fentanyl, and associated synthetic drugs to enhance public safety.</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="id08f0e87b891247628c9a96181ef8d76b"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Grant projects To address distribution, sale, and use of heroin, fentanyl, and associated synthetic
 drugs</header><text>Grants made under subsection (b) may be used for programs, projects, and other activities to—</text> <paragraph id="id9f70ee258cad49288814de110bcdfb90"><enum>(1)</enum><text>reimburse State, local, or other forensic science laboratories to help address backlogs of untested samples of heroin, fentanyl, and associated synthetic drugs;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ida06ef55edb5d491c88f93b03b8d29628"><enum>(2)</enum><text>reimburse State, local, or other forensic science laboratories for procuring equipment, technology, or other support systems if the applicant for the grant demonstrates to the satisfaction of the Attorney General that expenditures for such purposes would result in improved efficiency of laboratory testing and help prevent future backlogs;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idf879dd3844874be2b648bbd3443d7d72"><enum>(3)</enum><text>reimburse State, tribal, and local law enforcement agencies for procuring field-testing equipment for use in the identification or detection of heroin, fentanyl, and associated synthetic drugs;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idA5AF15658FF74332923AAA60977D9F2C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>investigate, arrest, and prosecute individuals violating laws related to the distribution or sale of heroin, fentanyl, and associated synthetic drugs; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id753398654e68448a9249e7482fcac3d1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>support State, tribal, and local health department services deployed to address the use of heroin, fentanyl, and associated synthetic drugs.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idfbad4c53ad01470e95483292801f2a0d"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Not less than 60 percent of the amounts made available to carry out this section shall be awarded for the purposes under paragraph (1) or (2) of subsection (c).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id41422628294c4b2f8cc17c00f2ee6a39"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2017, 2018, and 2019.</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="id3daa59199249489ca133ac476c693ddd"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Allocation</header>
 <paragraph id="id097a4db11c2f4af8888d7f6ae8adb6c3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Population allocation</header><text>Seventy-five percent of the amount made available to carry out this section in a fiscal year shall be allocated to each State that meets the requirements of section 2802 so that each State shall receive an amount that bears the same ratio to the 75 percent of the total amount made available to carry out this section for that fiscal year as the population of the State bears to the population of all States.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="id8d8411d7c83f4e75a72325e25ce437b6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Discretionary allocation</header>
 <subparagraph id="id95DE5BAF8B994AD385F5ECF067109AB2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Twenty-five percent of the amount made available to carry out this section in a fiscal year shall be allocated pursuant to the Attorney General’s discretion for competitive awards to States and Indian tribes.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4F36B45BF33F4B4E89B84F897B7C9DA8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In making awards under subparagraph (A), the Attorney General shall consider—</text> <clause id="id16C8340D551E41729FE06F28B447CF1A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the average annual number of part 1 violent crimes reported by each State to the Federal Bureau of Investigation for the 3 most recent calendar years for which data is available; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id03E9971F43C94903B2AB2A54A08A6DB2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the existing resources and current needs of the potential grant recipient.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id57d1caa211e9470291e5389edcc00476"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Minimum requirement</header><text>Each State shall receive not less than 0.6 percent of the amount made available to carry out this section in each fiscal year.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="ID67B605490C944362B5EA01C81D208123"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Certain territories</header>
 <subparagraph id="id24CADB9388A94D98B4A8B176E808EB41"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of the allocation under this section, American Samoa and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands shall be considered as 1 State.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="IDC0B943FFBC3D4A5FA8A55E0E8AA94677"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Allocation amongst certain territories</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A), 67 percent of the amount allocated shall be allocated to American Samoa and 33 percent shall be allocated to the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></part><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


