<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S2008 IS: Transportation, Access, and Opportunity Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-08-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 2008</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150806">August 6, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To enhance transportation programs in order to achieve an interconnected transportation system
			 which connects people to jobs, schools, and other essential services
			 through a multimodal network, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Transportation, Access, and Opportunity Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="id1b918a08c86749318c35b01760cc46bd"><enum>2.</enum><header>Public involvement in plan development</header>
 <subsection id="idb625fd63b297445da9adc07db93bcce2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Section 134 amendment</header><text>Section 134(i) of title 23, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="id480af2e50ab447a18b62751ac383ad8b"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id13DD22FF232347C79BFF78940E0927A9" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="id240bef47320c401ca62ba6efbe9e8407"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Public involvement</header><text>A metropolitan planning organization shall offer interested parties, such as the interested parties described in paragraph (6), a reasonable opportunity to participate in the development and consideration of scenarios.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id1ac1f2e0b0e0442ebe6a25367d4069c3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (6)—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="idC00BDCD25B854821A996C3FDA60006AA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>comment on the transportation plan</quote> and inserting <quote>provide input during the development and implementation of the transportation plan</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="idCB29E98411584799B93B59211AA61FB8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)(ii), by striking <quote>comment on the contents of the transportation plan</quote> and inserting <quote>provide input during the development and implementation of the transportation plan</quote>.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ide17e19e62dde423dbb340293c12ad3ee"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Section 135 amendment</header><text>Section 135(f)(3)(A)(ii) of title 23, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>comment on the transportation plan</quote> and inserting <quote>provide input during the development and implementation of the transportation plan</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id32dc867d760c4463b6821da619e5768e"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Section 5303 amendment</header><text>Section 5303(i) of title 49, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="id764c3b96ec2242e195e0de268aeab445"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id98F4863CA683464AAF7637B2FD9432E0" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="id9840d8b39e944b669e736e658aa66f75"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Public involvement</header><text>A metropolitan planning organization shall offer interested parties, such as those described in paragraph (6), a reasonable opportunity to participate in the development and consideration of scenarios.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id1a26cf37dad242b58b81f3ca32900a98"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (6), by striking <quote>comment on the transportation plan</quote> and inserting <quote>provide input during the development and implementation of the transportation plan</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id2e4f8520095848a49bf27fcd3a77ead8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Section 5304 amendment</header><text>Section 5304(f)(3)(A)(ii) of title 49, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>comment on the proposed plan</quote> and inserting <quote>provide input during the development and implementation of the transportation plan</quote>.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="idf0e3af8656bc4362910acb3f95e52434"><enum>3.</enum><header>Connection to opportunities national goal and potential performance measure</header>
 <subsection id="id06d2b2f8b24c402ebec6510dc8914bae"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Transportation connections to opportunities</header><text>Section 150(b) of title 23, United States Codes, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="id937f208ff50e4002a9f0b3c9ea677889"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>highway infrastructure asset system</quote> and inserting <quote>infrastructure asset system under title 23</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id38252767ff8942aba09f0ee74388d864"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idACA560F5632E4954B4AFF8788736C929" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="idfcbed86712d34fb18efbc1ad17054f9e"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Multimodal connectivity</header><text>To achieve an interconnected transportation system which connects people to jobs, schools, and other essential services through a multimodal network.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idade6861bde694d93aeee8996ba6b4f6f"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment of performance measures</header><text>Section 150(c) of title 23, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="id8c9b1ce1cfbd41fea10e53e25f5d228a"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by inserting <quote>as listed in paragraphs (3), (4), (5), and (6)</quote> before the period at the end; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ide5f9a77ec1f44554a855ef06c881e817"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id42EF9D4B6BD34A6C957C43A224310F00" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="id4b053bb05dea4146a7b0d25c3f63f0e2"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Transportation connectivity</header><text>The Secretary may, in accordance with the framework established in sections 134 and 135 of this title, establish a Performance Measure to be used by metropolitan planning organizations to assess the degree to which the transportation system provides multimodal connections to economic opportunities, including job concentration areas, health care services, child care services, and education and workforce training services, particularly for disadvantaged populations.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id36a22dbb906240ab9d64dfe80870c5f2"><enum>4.</enum><header>Measuring transportation connectivity pilot activities</header>
 <subsection id="id9b089404876c4a52bb142d556a331223"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Title 23</header><text>Section 134 of title 23, United States Code, as amended by this Act, is further amended by inserting at the end, the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF1ACA6C3A0254347BAF297BAF30CE558" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="idA3D1F5F66C9B49A1B23ADD503E8F23A0"><enum>(r)</enum><header>Measuring transportation connections to opportunity</header>
 <paragraph id="idBC5A0861B3194B8CA5C643B02DABC375"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this subsection—</text> <subparagraph id="idBA99DADAD2B74A5B955876557A7E1352"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the term <term>covered metropolitan planning organization</term> means a metropolitan planning organization selected by the Secretary under paragraph (2)(B)(i).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8194B956DD314371A76DA28B60175ABF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the term <term>opportunity</term> means job concentration areas, schools, workforce training, child care services, and health care services;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE4406B7C267342E296770BA7F1D0A49D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the term <term>pilot location</term> means a location selected by the Secretary under paragraph (2)(B)(i);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idABE6E3D1DC264063A101B28B0974DA1B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the term <term>pilot program</term> means the Connection to Opportunity Pilot Program established under paragraph (2)(A); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id013608A0BE5540559242DA78AED6553A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the term <term>transportation-disadvantaged</term>, with respect to an individual or population, means any individual or population of individuals who—</text>
 <clause id="idE34576D862AA45D4B56CCD8898FD3E28"><enum>(i)</enum><text>face challenges in securing or accessing transportation due to age, disability, or income constraints, including lack of access to public transportation or a private vehicle; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="idCF642F9837B94AEF9E538C46D3433D83"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>are members of a protected class listed in section 601 of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d">42 U.S.C. 2000d</external-xref>).</text>
								</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id719C34910372489BB340C1DB2FE2C67B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Connection to Opportunity Pilot Program</header>
 <subparagraph id="id1FD8B45D49E54C8EB90427E2F16D5FA0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a pilot program, to be known as the <quote>Connection to Opportunity Pilot Program</quote>, under which not more than 10 metropolitan planning organizations shall each develop and deploy not less than 1 pilot project to improve multimodal connectivity and increase connections for transportation-disadvantaged individuals and neighborhoods with limited transportation options.</text>
							</subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD5BA2946AA1C4A88A413A044011B87D4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Pilot locations</header>
 <clause id="idEB425DAE857045648044133752CFA9F4"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall select not more than 10 metropolitan planning organizations, each of which is a metropolitan planning organization serving an urbanized area with a population of more than 200,000 individuals, which shall include—</text>
 <subclause id="id61CC4A34BF0D4CA78782D4441D68B402"><enum>(I)</enum><text>metropolitan planning organizations that can demonstrate previous successful use of performance measurements and performance-based planning efforts, which the Secretary shall designate as mentor grantees; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id3E17C314203145E6810DD8C9AD6076D8"><enum>(II)</enum><text>metropolitan planning organizations that have limited or no successful previous experience in performance measurements and performance-based planning efforts, which the Secretary shall designate as novice grantees.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="id8FC6129651584D889EFA9127ECE3D04B"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Varying population sizes</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that the metropolitan planning organizations selected under clause (i) serve urbanized areas with varying population sizes.</text>
								</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2B5C4BF126F141FC9142CD1CC603CE57"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Pilot program activities</header>
 <clause id="id007B90A96A52464DB5FCBEED3B9CBF66"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Transportation connectivity inventory</header><text>Not later than 6 months after the date on which the Secretary selects a pilot location and awards a grant under this subsection, and in consultation with appropriate States, transit agencies, and local governments, a covered metropolitan planning organization in the pilot location shall develop from existing data an inventory of transportation assets within the urbanized area served by the covered metropolitan planning organization, which shall describe—</text>
 <subclause id="idF342F7E3DAF7444CA72D72E17353AC72"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the condition and quality of service of key highway, transit, bicycle, pedestrian, and carshare facilities;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id5D8F97F95AF642FAB3E46AF0048B8F93"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the degree to which the facilities described in subclause (I) provide residents with connections to economic opportunities, including high job concentration areas, health care services, child care services, and education and workforce training services;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idC312164A2F094F85930EF5ADFAEC455F"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the identity and location of transportation-disadvantaged populations within the urbanized area and the disparity of services and facilities between those transportation-disadvantaged populations and non-transportation-disadvantaged populations; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id155E9D221ACC41A481A56FAB7620C45E"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>local challenges to multimodal connectivity, such as—</text> <item id="id5D8A745A148F43D49370BB12121B0E5C"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>zoning or land use issues;</text>
 </item><item id="id346869A0099B40EDB2AB53F5AE72ABE2"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>availability of affordable housing;</text>
 </item><item id="idBC17518DB655465F92D05CCAC5E3EC45"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>availability of accessible vehicles and accessible transportation facilities that meet the standards contained in sections 37.7 and 37.9, respectively, of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor thereto); and</text>
 </item><item id="id51C6857AB31543C5B01506A21F384492"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>barriers that obstruct access from residential areas to economic opportunities, such as—</text>
 <subitem id="id71D74866F36C4A4F9A7B09F7DB07D596"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>the amount of time it takes to reach economic opportunities;</text> </subitem><subitem id="id0145B23165314321AD57C5DA1B33ED8A"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>the average cost of commuting for transportation-disadvantaged populations compared to income levels; and</text>
 </subitem><subitem id="id12C6A8CE9B1642BF8B1B24212BE57348"><enum>(CC)</enum><text>the number of people served, by income level.</text> </subitem></item></subclause></clause><clause id="idA499C517F5574C7C98DBB8FB5F8EF15D"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Performance indicators</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date on which the Secretary selects a pilot location, a covered metropolitan planning organization in the pilot location shall apply the baseline data developed in the transportation connectivity inventory under clause (i) to adopt not less than 1 provisional indicator—</text>
 <subclause id="id0A7E45CED8D7490B9D34E52DF47D604B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to measure multimodal connectivity in the transportation system to economic opportunities, including measurements of multimodal connectivity improvements available to populations identified in clause (i)(III); and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id52CEBB33F2F44E639ECA92664D1F5493"><enum>(II)</enum><text>to appropriate to local assets and needs.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="id3A423A16B3C54CCB9229FF8437C8716A"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Data collection and reporting</header><text>A covered metropolitan planning organization in a pilot location shall—</text> <subclause id="idDE81C58C53524656A0C546A8A0D09B63"><enum>(I)</enum><text>collect baseline and annual performance data on multimodal transportation connectivity to opportunity; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id5879446333D24C18858BF12544BFCFDB"><enum>(II)</enum><text>submit the data described in subclause (I) to the Secretary for the duration of the pilot project.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="id65845B3D832A4BF4B049F93453845ED7"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Knowledge-sharing</header><text>A covered metropolitan planning organization designated as a mentor grantee under subparagraph (B)(i)(I) shall, to the extent feasible, engage in knowledge-sharing activities with novice grantees designated under subparagraph (B)(i)(II), which may include peer exchanges and technical assistance, as appropriate to the level of performance measurement capacity of the mentor grantee.</text>
 </clause><clause id="idD51FD5A2B027487DACC739C9CD1EBE31"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Project implementation</header><text>Notwithstanding section 120 of this title, a covered metropolitan planning organization may use funds remaining after the completion of the transportation connectivity inventory under clause (i), the adoption of provisional indicators under clause (ii), and related tracking activities to implement pilot projects within the urbanized area served by the covered metropolitan planning organization that are reasonably anticipated to address system gaps and improve performance according to the locally adopted provisional multimodal transportation connectivity measures.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ideda712097d414f7986a5105311c117c7"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The pilot program shall terminate on the date that is 3 years after the date on which the Secretary establishes the pilot program.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id48D8543381454D8B93550E722AA20B56"><enum>(3)</enum><header>National performance measure development activities</header>
 <subparagraph id="id5F9CAD2FFD7D44B0AF4648A37E267E33"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, using not more than $5,000,000 of the amount authorized to be appropriated under section 7(a) of the <short-title>Transportation, Access, and Opportunity Act of 2015</short-title>, shall—</text>
 <clause id="id4F79DDD41917407DA0D96946BE904828"><enum>(i)</enum><text>evaluate multimodal connectivity measures developed by covered metropolitan planning organizations in pilot locations; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id714FA6C6B29C4D9DBF8F09C80408D77C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>consider development of a national indicator to measure the multimodal connections to opportunities provided by the transportation network.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD33F77951E0A45CDBF94226074A093EB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Activities</header><text>To carry out the requirements under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall perform the following activities:</text>
 <clause id="idE337309476D84ADE87CE19CBDCF87EF8"><enum>(i)</enum><header>National technical assistance and peer exchange forums</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text> <subclause id="idAE2C2716BFD1464D80B2C50A9DEE2168"><enum>(I)</enum><text>support the measure development and data collection of covered metropolitan planning organizations in pilot locations through—</text>
 <item id="id0BE97D648DCF434E990E36AAF3D1D06A"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>technical assistance and peer exchanges; and</text>
 </item><item id="id36CEFC48A43D4030BCCA9E6DEEC89C2F"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>workshops with States, transit agencies, and covered metropolitan planning organizations to discuss pilot program findings; and</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause id="idE8374868E1804B75A8A0DA9B81AE05E7"><enum>(II)</enum><text>establish an online collaboration center for local jurisdictions to share ideas and challenges and document lessons learned.</text>
									</subclause></clause><clause id="idA6229681B6874ECA8B7775E4DE08C9C1"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Connection to Opportunity final report</header>
 <subclause id="idCE5A48ED9473432C8E28CD520F95B164"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date on which the pilot program terminates, the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, the Secretary of Commerce, and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, shall seek public comment on and submit to Congress a final report detailing the results of the pilot program.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id9940657F8923489CB63D114152B69330"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The final report submitted under subclause (I) shall include—</text> <item id="idEB0DD894718E4FBB9247B13C9F575E3D"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>recommendations on the establishment of 1 or more national multimodal connectivity measures;</text>
 </item><item id="idAC50D14315224ECB824E1CF68BE7C676"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the results of the efforts of covered metropolitan planning organizations to measure and improve multimodal connectivity;</text>
 </item><item id="id6050C7E8DDBA4D8A858395715313315D"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>the recommendations of the Secretary on the establishment of 1 or more national multimodal connectivity measures and the integration of those measures into the Federal transportation performance management framework in accordance with section 150 of this title; and</text>
 </item><item id="id73BCF8EBF1C5414795EE0F1D56F02732"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>an assessment of the impact of the pilot projects, including—</text> <subitem id="id66D13A284D4A4FE39283351C2A9E9DBE"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>social outcomes and economic impacts that may result from the pilot projects;</text>
 </subitem><subitem id="id9665F3C0F4FC4631A6FA66C193671D36"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>estimated savings to Federal, State, and local social service subsidy programs; and</text>
 </subitem><subitem id="idB8296B46A9D842BE98EEE22F50931D47"><enum>(CC)</enum><text>other costs avoided and new tax revenues attributable to increased connectivity.</text>
 </subitem></item></subclause></clause><clause id="id430440ABDE674457ACDC850DAE88D543"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Potential rulemaking</header><text>After the Secretary submits the final report to Congress under clause (ii), the Secretary, in consultation with State Departments of Transportation, metropolitan planning organizations, and other stakeholders, may promulgate a rulemaking that establishes performance measures and standards as described in section 150(c)(8) of this title.</text>
								</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="idf688c4b936e643bd965122353cf66951"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Chapter 53</header><text>Section 5303 of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idFD6C1C0475204CA7884FE68250196274" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="ide91daa0f32e24c668eb2e4e071781323"><enum>(r)</enum><header>Measuring transportation connections to opportunity</header>
 <paragraph id="idca0dcb0633984a36b6c0bc6227e33dec"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this subsection—</text> <subparagraph id="id4785c9a8b3554ff49677618da2986319"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the term <term>covered metropolitan planning organization</term> means a metropolitan planning organization selected by the Secretary under paragraph (2)(B)(i);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB25AAEAD4E814F239A0843E6689D0D11"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the term <term>opportunity</term> means job concentration areas, schools, workforce training, child care services, and health care services;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE312CAB4E27D495EA48653E525FDDC98"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the term <term>pilot location</term> means a location selected by the Secretary under paragraph (2)(B)(i);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6D14EDDEF339450184F3838DB80438BA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the term <term>pilot program</term> means the Connection to Opportunity Pilot Program established under paragraph (2)(A); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1f08bca35fa74fc09fd4a5e216166c1c"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the term <term>transportation-disadvantaged</term>, with respect to an individual or population, means any individual or population of individuals who—</text>
 <clause id="idABB4C8B254A44C8D9EDEFD4CA4BE33B1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>face challenges in securing or accessing transportation due to age, disability, or income constraints, including lack of access to public transportation or a private vehicle; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="idA0173AF7821441CF80938813DA0D5935"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>are members of a protected class listed in section 601 of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d">42 U.S.C. 2000d</external-xref>).</text>
								</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5D77F605C06F4927B416BE640A1EC7FD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Connection to Opportunity Pilot Program</header>
 <subparagraph id="idaf5060b7e29442f0983bc2bdae6c3d48"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a pilot program, to be known as the <quote>Connection to Opportunity Pilot Program</quote>, under which not more than 10 metropolitan planning organizations shall each develop and deploy not less than 1 pilot project to improve multimodal connectivity and increase connections for transportation-disadvantaged individuals and neighborhoods with limited transportation options.</text>
							</subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0bb9d17f24c64f349148f3373a51e2ca"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Pilot locations</header>
 <clause id="id5ADCAD7BA96E46A8817C5E2312382187"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall select not more than 10 metropolitan planning organizations, each of which is a metropolitan planning organization serving an urbanized area with a population of more than 200,000 individuals, which shall include—</text>
 <subclause id="idf1d67d37849a4343ac4c2a2c6f7313f9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>metropolitan planning organizations that can demonstrate previous successful use of performance measurements and performance-based planning efforts, which the Secretary shall designate as mentor grantees; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idfc93fe7c2b9e4a738b6eb200526e9694"><enum>(II)</enum><text>metropolitan planning organizations that have limited or no successful previous experience in performance measurements and performance-based planning efforts, which the Secretary shall designate as novice grantees.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="id4B269F4B839C41B89B9240DD6DE66B91"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Varying population sizes</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that the metropolitan planning organizations selected under clause (i) serve urbanized areas with varying population sizes.</text>
								</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf9891936a10e47c49bedb37e06586feb"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Pilot program activities</header>
 <clause id="id95ae8b5b296943b3b831022e2ce8183d"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Transportation connectivity inventory</header><text>Not later than 6 months after the date on which the Secretary selects a pilot location and awards a grant under this subsection, and in consultation with appropriate States, transit agencies, and local governments, a covered metropolitan planning organization in the pilot location shall develop from existing data an inventory of transportation assets within the urbanized area served by the covered metropolitan planning organization, which shall describe—</text>
 <subclause id="id21c51ca372bf4321ba81d9c0f4205d4b"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the condition and quality of service of key highway, transit, bicycle, pedestrian, and carshare facilities;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id38836d1f38574c20b3733dafd119db7e"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the degree to which the facilities described in subclause (I) provide residents with connections to economic opportunities, including high job concentration areas, health care services, childcare services, and education and workforce training services;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id6c106657f5dc479abd1e1f678b2f3ca4"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the identity and location of transportation-disadvantaged populations within the urbanized area and the disparity of services and facilities between those transportation-disadvantaged populations and non-transportation-disadvantaged populations; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idfd83b2c9c8614d0da1b94d354bc824a3"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>local challenges to multimodal connectivity, such as—</text> <item id="id8C8522A520874519B6B39FF2628A95D7"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>zoning or land use issues;</text>
 </item><item id="idC4D49A8A81414F8CBA84D6627D12F7C9"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>availability of affordable housing;</text>
 </item><item id="id3BC289EE965A405BBEAD279601D5D180"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>availability of accessible vehicles and accessible transportation facilities that meet the standards contained in sections 37.7 and 37.9, respectively, of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor thereto); and</text>
 </item><item id="id4B69A5DB201941C7AFFA4AAA0634E681"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>barriers that obstruct access from residential areas to economic opportunities, such as—</text>
 <subitem id="id4dee478ad99e414d897efe41b9ce2f54"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>the amount of time it takes to reach economic opportunities;</text> </subitem><subitem id="id7025a871eb704b5998dc9620e3572532"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>the average cost of commuting for transportation-disadvantaged populations compared to income levels; and</text>
 </subitem><subitem id="ide1136c9be42345a5a9665d76d95ce4c4"><enum>(CC)</enum><text>the number of people not adequately served, by income level.</text> </subitem></item></subclause></clause><clause id="idcd9e1e4d2e7b41b0808879cbd83544c4"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Performance indicators</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date on which the Secretary selects a pilot location, a covered metropolitan planning organization in the pilot location shall apply the baseline data developed in the transportation connectivity inventory under clause (i) to adopt not less than 1 provisional indicator—</text>
 <subclause id="id385B461CE707414AABAF5C1A1B424F4B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to measure multimodal connectivity in the transportation system to economic opportunities, including measurements of multimodal connectivity improvements available to populations identified in clause (i)(III); and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id3E6D0063E62D428AB5A124EC88D607E1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>appropriate to local assets and needs.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="id46295802115442f8b6bc54a930ee014d"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Data collection and reporting</header><text>A covered metropolitan planning organization in a pilot location shall—</text> <subclause id="id65904E6DCE174CB78E53CDDEEF58208B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>collect baseline and annual performance data on multimodal transportation connectivity to opportunity; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idC16D2D90F74A4D8F81165E82CAC31A73"><enum>(II)</enum><text>submit the data described in subclause (I) to the Secretary for the duration of the pilot project.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="id33121bfbf1e74858ad48a5901cb17a31"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Knowledge-sharing</header><text>A covered metropolitan planning organization designated as a mentor grantee under subparagraph (B)(i)(I) shall, to the extent feasible, engage in knowledge-sharing activities with novice grantees designated under subparagraph (B)(i)(II), which may include peer exchanges and technical assistance, as appropriate to the level of performance measurement capacity of the mentor grantee.</text>
 </clause><clause id="id40e8f65236924a78b32b43f0d912601b"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Project implementation</header><text>Notwithstanding section 120 of title 23, a covered metropolitan planning organization may use funds remaining after the completion of the transportation connectivity inventory under clause (i), the adoption of provisional indicators under clause (ii), and related tracking activities to implement pilot projects within the urbanized area served by the covered metropolitan planning organization that are reasonably anticipated to address system gaps and improve performance according to the locally adopted provisional multimodal transportation connectivity measures.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0B25228506434288A67FF2D8A9AE2100"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The pilot program shall terminate on the date that is 3 years after the date on which the Secretary establishes the pilot program.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide90fcaea7211412faca6d29e29394e22"><enum>(3)</enum><header>National performance measure development activities</header>
 <subparagraph id="id23EE1FE7DC0A4E0BB627ADCEBBD11650"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, using not more than $5,000,000 of the amount authorized to be appropriated under section 7(a) of the <short-title>Transportation, Access, and Opportunity Act of 2015</short-title>, shall—</text>
 <clause id="id02986935C68B4F6B8366435DE1B39F83"><enum>(i)</enum><text>evaluate multimodal connectivity measures developed by covered metropolitan planning organizations in pilot locations; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idDF5D3D303D3946CCBF0A1736983A73F1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>consider development of a national indicator to measure the multimodal connections to opportunities provided by the transportation network.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idFE1A3A4C6CAC4829947ACC9AF8152310"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Activities</header><text>To carry out the requirements under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall perform the following activities:</text>
 <clause id="id23248dcb7ed040d2891ab0ddfe9c8dda"><enum>(i)</enum><header>National technical assistance and peer exchange forums</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text> <subclause id="id2B9304B95CA441CBA28020C8CA1CC72D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>support the measure development and data collection of covered metropolitan planning organizations in pilot locations through—</text>
 <item id="id2A1BDEC3564E45289CE85C40910C2DFB"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>technical assistance and peer exchanges; and</text>
 </item><item id="idF3400019FA694E8FAB2A8CD191EE3276"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>workshops with States, transit agencies, and covered metropolitan planning organizations to discuss pilot program findings; and</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause id="id77DBFB3230A2434D9855EDAF6F59FB7B"><enum>(II)</enum><text>establish an online collaboration center for local jurisdictions to share ideas and challenges and document lessons learned.</text>
									</subclause></clause><clause id="ida2dc1e0577294f95b94eb66a8b27d6a9"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Connection to Opportunity final report</header>
 <subclause id="id89F3E1C8849842309A8D528569513ED9"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date on which the pilot program terminates, the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, the Secretary of Commerce, and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, shall seek public comment on and submit to Congress a final report detailing the results of the pilot program.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idE890B5A2E42A476394266C2B437C4C76"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The final report submitted under subclause (I) shall include—</text> <item id="idaec6f34b5512445491e5f855cc1b6219"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>recommendations on the establishment of 1 or more national multimodal connectivity measures;</text>
 </item><item id="id13D2F6114BC04F0DA2B145C1AACAAA7D"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the results of the efforts of covered metropolitan planning organizations to measure and improve multimodal connectivity;</text>
 </item><item id="id1f5d4d11999e407eae4bf37df6c88db9"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>the recommendations of the Secretary on the establishment of 1 or more national multimodal connectivity measures and the integration of those measures into the Federal transportation performance management framework in accordance with section 150 of title 23; and</text>
 </item><item id="id2e4671d6e98a4403a5a91816d563a7b0"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>an assessment of the impact of the pilot projects, including—</text> <subitem id="idFA99EF4E828545B3B2CF6177C404557E"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>social outcomes and economic impacts that may result from the pilot projects;</text>
 </subitem><subitem id="id6947883C942243F1A27FC885E7ABCA72"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>estimated savings to Federal, State, and local social service subsidy programs; and</text>
 </subitem><subitem id="idA1CF1FBC8E7A4161B4F2DC3CB1F78C96"><enum>(CC)</enum><text>other costs avoided and new tax revenues attributable to increased connectivity.</text>
 </subitem></item></subclause></clause><clause id="ida34cd8caf33940698f506092fbbed297"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Potential rulemaking</header><text>After the Secretary submits the final report to Congress under clause (ii), the Secretary, in consultation with State Departments of Transportation, metropolitan planning organizations, and other stakeholders, may promulgate a rulemaking that establishes performance measures and standards as described in section 150(c)(8) of title 23.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section id="id2cb3e310f54741b2b2960fe79f1c3b05"><enum>5.</enum><header>Performance Management Data Support Program</header>
 <subsection id="id6b7d5fefb6f242a1ba75f07ca1c52508"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Performance Management Data Support Program</header><text>Section 150 of title 23, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7593931DECAF40D283650EC571D5BD52" style="OLC"> <subsection id="id866a163a527a4a94ba3c0264600ac147"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Performance management data support</header><text>To assist metropolitan planning organizations, States, and the Department in carrying out performance management analyses, including the performance management requirements of this chapter, the Secretary shall create and maintain data sets and data analysis tools.</text>
					</subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="idf6d8dd2e1fb24a2d8f0974686c903b79"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Federal share</header><text>Section 120 of such title is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF5E42132C44B4CC790BEDFF8135ECAF9" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="id6eb4cbd29a224b28888970b680b7154a"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Performance Management Data Support Program</header><text>The Federal share payable on account of an activity under the performance management data support program under section 150(f) shall be 100 percent of the cost of the activity.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section id="id46786ca9303f4c9c805b450af59fa461"><enum>6.</enum><header>Multimodal accommodations</header>
 <subsection id="id934349fa99284c259ae646ff320c7c82"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Design standards</header><text>Section 109 of title 23, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="ide0109a9e509f4e5ba17ce78a43c93950"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id943ee80a7fae4caab368d6ce4bd979e5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text> <clause id="id34deae9cfc284c958f5b2d65dad11bc9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>may take into account</quote> and inserting <quote>shall take into account</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id2a9979ae70614b9b96564cfa76db01c3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (C) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF75EF3E0AFF043458BD82E8802138E5F" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="id29b1a560fc464417b928bad6f81b92da"><enum>(C)</enum><text>access and safety for users of all foreseeable modes of transportation.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idab362864be9746e9a415cdf4d7a8d359"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>may develop</quote> and inserting <quote>shall develop</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idef5d14b63e5442d2a151c507d745843b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (m), by striking <quote>and light motorcycles</quote> and inserting <quote>, safe, convenient, and continuous</quote> before <quote>alternate route</quote>.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id97e7bb52deac4e60af55e37c6e3d64d6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Transportation alternatives</header>
 <paragraph id="ide1d33077f0604030aeaefc1586bbbaae"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Federal share</header><text>Section 120 of title 23, United States Code, as amended by this Act, is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7925B65FEE204CC6A39EE2E3114FD5B5" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="id0243fbc6f7dc432787c00cd019addeed"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Transportation Alternatives Program</header><text>The Federal share requirements under this section applicable to the Transportation Alternatives Program under section 213 of this title may be met based on—</text>
 <paragraph id="id57b84ddcc75c4c0da66a994147732c6c"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an individual project or activity under that section; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="ide4399ba69aba4594b1ee1d3ddd07cd28"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a program of projects or activities approved under subsection (c)(6)(B) of that section.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id81834ef248f444eea325e597b8fdc3b9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reservation of funds</header><text>Section 213(a)(1) of title 23, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>of fiscal years 2013 and 2014</quote> and inserting <quote>fiscal year</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id9e18a197fc654e4c829d5a1606891756"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligible entities</header><text>Section 213(c)(4)(B) title 23, United States Code, is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id1cb732b7893e417cae937b6156bec658"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating clauses (vi) and (vii) as clauses (viii) and (ix); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcc8b99bd64eb437b834754c2ddc51e11"><enum>(B)</enum><text>inserting after clause (v) the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idBC5F98893E1C4DF08AB4B9248B8FDD96" style="OLC">
 <clause id="idee5c41246b514029995bdd015ee6e4d9"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>a nonprofit organization;</text> </clause><clause id="id9271a8d935394359b1fa019dc240bcfa"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>a metropolitan planning organization that is not developing the competitive process for funding;</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id124862ebf5824725a4aa1e163bb64288"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Program of projects</header><text>Section 213(c) of title 23, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id54B4142BE77A46A193934CCA85106A95" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="iddb5bd414d8774a55af82517f513670ed"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Program of projects</header><text>Funds may be obligated under this section for—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id4d21bd075c0d4cf8a6ac30daae17fef4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a project or activity eligible under subsection (b); or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id81c386f4a0a14dd48b44e0e35d4f1c43"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a program of projects or activities eligible under that subsection.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0a6a287b69134fa2983e1690e3cda102"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Administration</header>
 <subparagraph id="id4914443eac3c4c62ba840348c0808296"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Submission of project agreement</header><text>For each fiscal year, each State shall submit a project agreement that—</text> <clause id="ide1c7427485234d499fcd33d54b89f1d7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>certifies that the State will meet all the requirements of this section; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id64b250bec12d4e78b49e235407b97b36"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>notifies the Secretary of the amount of obligations needed to carry out the program under this section.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2096c555c7bc46b1991a5e1470c86a59"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Request for adjustments of amounts</header><text>Each State shall request from the Secretary such adjustments to the amount of obligations referred to in subparagraph (A)(ii) as the State determines to be necessary.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida2f947219e544acdac873be474285683"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Effect of approval by the Secretary</header><text>Approval by the Secretary of a project agreement under subparagraph (A) shall be deemed a contractual obligation of the United States to pay funds made available under this title.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idc5f70bcb6f7f48e48e9c8e77796fb134"><enum>7.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
 <subsection id="id080b2b0ac8174dd59ad9505dc5d7fea6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Connection to Opportunity Pilot Programs</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated $70,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2016 through 2019 to carry out the Connection to Opportunity Pilot Programs established under—</text>
 <paragraph id="id9CB46CAA906C479499B0849EE77636EF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>section 134(r) of title 23, United States Code (as added by section 4 of this Act); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idD5471DF94DE24A6FB51557D00707294A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>section 5303(r) of title 49, United States Code (as added by section 4 of this Act).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id256d97960635451f84df78b527422350"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Performance Management Data Support Programs</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2016 through 2019 to carry out the Performance Management Data Support Program under section 150(f) of title 23, United States Code, as added by section 5 of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


