<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1680 IS: National Multimodal Freight Policy and Investment Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-06-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 1680</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150625">June 25, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S275">Ms. Cantwell</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S229">Mrs. Murray</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To improve the condition and performance of the national multimodal freight network, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>National Multimodal Freight Policy and Investment Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="id6B856627D68742E2B70261D2D4BA62A4"><enum>2.</enum><header>National multimodal freight policy</header>
 <subsection id="id4BE16712BF964649B19FDF0B3C3CDF71"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Subtitle III of title 49, United States Code, is amended by inserting after chapter 53 the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id605F85A5BEA447F88DCE90F91F87DDD4" style="USC">
					<chapter id="idE4A22E55763445919577D49BD37772D5" style="OLC"><enum>54</enum><header>Freight</header>
 <section id="idE8449FA8A9F24059A18A0D481204C946"><enum>5401.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this chapter:</text> <paragraph id="id62CFA3E0375749BC974BE6D4F09FEC90"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Freight transportation modes</header><text>The term <term>freight transportation modes</term> means any mode of transportation that moves freight, including airports, highways, ports and waterways, rail, and pipeline.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idB3D2F9FAD52348358357B28424A12366"><enum>(2)</enum><header>National multimodal freight network</header><text>The term <term>national multimodal freight network</term> means the network established under section 5403.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idD46E9A342687400C88F69027911871D5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>National multimodal freight strategic plan</header><text>The term <term>national multimodal freight strategic plan</term> means the strategic plan developed under section 5404.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idC6A663AA37A94298A0CE1637D6E2DD2D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Transportation.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id40D11EA462284DA38E539B7E0AC437BE"><enum>(5)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means a State of the United States, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, the Northern Mariana Islands, Guam, American Samoa, and the Virgin Islands.</text>
							</paragraph></section><section id="idA1FC38E67F7A4996ABD85863375BC818"><enum>5402.</enum><header>National multimodal freight policy</header>
 <subsection id="id255199454D5F426A86D18CB2F0CCC99B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Policy</header><text>It is the policy of the United States to support investment in the condition and performance of the national multimodal freight network to ensure the United States maximizes its competitiveness in the global economy and achieves each goal described in subsection (b).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idB4FE0F2AB93C4010BC3635CEAC8A1A68"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Goals</header><text>The goals of the national multimodal freight policy are to enhance the economic competitiveness of the United States and improve quality of life—</text>
 <paragraph id="id379CBEA8129E4253ACEFDC3A866872E1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by increasing the overall productivity and connectivity of the national freight system;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id4B290303DB9744D19549F995E491BCD4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by improving the safety, security, and resiliency of freight transportation;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idACEC9F0A9B6C4A6ABB5D085A5FC09723"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by reducing the congestion of freight transportation;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id92E9D1C11EA3493B8BB6487717D4DE34"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by improving the reliability of freight transportation; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id18480B3B2F1B41D18CDC1F2E8F37EEAD"><enum>(5)</enum><text>by reducing, eliminating, or reversing adverse environmental and local community impacts of freight projects and freight movement in the United States.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id947B3B2E69814BD989C1E9FCBE109AC4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Strategy</header><text>The strategies that the United States may use to achieve the goals set forth in subsection (b) include—</text>
 <paragraph id="idF10DD236E6B444DDB9F767D03E785689"><enum>(1)</enum><text>dedicated funding to maintain and improve freight infrastructure facilities and operations;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id0911FE01F600476CB150BB4553954144"><enum>(2)</enum><text>appropriate safety, environmental, energy and other transportation policies;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id3F4A067C3CA24A2D9F4A2D67BFB839F9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>advanced technology and innovation;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id3C42DE8107B2402094BC47E7CBE26367"><enum>(4)</enum><text>workforce development; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id6CDD97B03473482EB344EEB8677D4D8B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>use of performance management.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id814CA895D12E43D699D6DCEECE64A7A4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definition of economic competitiveness</header><text>In this section, the term <term>economic competitiveness</term> means the ability of the economy to more efficiently move freight and people, produce goods, and deliver services, including—</text>
 <paragraph id="id6C2ACD8A62CC4B6681C51C995F0F91A4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>reductions in the travel time of freight and people;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id6154092CF2064679BA085631A83FB2E7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>reductions in the congestion caused by the movement of freight and people;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idD8B33DDE7D40496F8BEF145104597B37"><enum>(3)</enum><text>improvements to travel time reliability; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id22F0623462FA4CEEB6C58E8A67FE698F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>reductions in freight transportation costs due to congestion and insufficient infrastructure.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id65F1190145774519B7DD6B270894AE4C"><enum>5403.</enum><header>National multimodal freight network</header>
 <subsection id="id0DDD952EB2194A818FA2131027092665"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a national multimodal freight network in accordance with this section—</text>
 <paragraph id="id435FC33828694662A6E14E214A4395BD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to inform public and private planning;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id1E7EFDDD0E95422B83BF49CD0D872B80"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to assist in the prioritization of Federal investment;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id58DA526274C845F88F515007C9DFDE83"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to direct the use of Federal resources under section 5404;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id2115F87527D14D6D8F189E5683FBC2A0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to assess and support Federal investments to achieve the national multimodal freight policy goals described in section 5402(b); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id505AC254200540CEB231A61985389253"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to help States define and prioritize local community impacts of freight movement.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id66FF909A3E8B4A7B8B8909FB129732C2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Network components</header><text>The national multimodal freight network shall consist of all connectors, corridors, and facilities in all freight transportation modes that are the most critical to the current and future movement of freight to achieve the national multimodal freight policy goals described in section 5402(b).</text>
							</subsection><subsection id="id19F8B219FBCE4365B165249DE19E2795"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Designation of the national multimodal freight network</header>
 <paragraph id="idE1EA314C87174A0EB37D9989F0810F9C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial designation</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of the <short-title>National Multimodal Freight Policy and Investment Act</short-title>, the Secretary shall designate a national multimodal freight network—</text> <subparagraph id="idEE8D47E74F694DC7A2FE56B14A4D4C16"><enum>(A)</enum><text>using measurable data, including measurable data provided by States, to assess the significance of freight movement, including consideration of points of origin, destination, and linking components of domestic and international supply chains;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id774B4354B3F74EA9973BE9BFA3F9D847"><enum>(B)</enum><text>improving network and intermodal connectivity; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idAFC676C7CDAD44E8B98B05701CE07DD5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>reflecting input from stakeholders, including multimodal freight system users, transport providers, metropolitan planning organizations, local governments, seaports, airports, railroads, and States, through a public process to identify critical freight facilities and corridors that are vital to achieve the national multimodal freight policy goals described in section 5402(b).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id7A2FDDBD362441919D9F710262ED79B3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Redesignation</header><text>Beginning 5 years after the date of the initial designation of the national multimodal freight network under paragraph (1), and every 5 years thereafter, using the designation factors described in paragraph (3), the Secretary shall redesignate the national multimodal freight network.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idAE0D3706D2DE4F789AA87341066EF455"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Factors</header><text>In designating or redesignating the national multimodal freight network, the Secretary shall consider—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idD7B04D4059F347D9A35ADA3DC4B1E933"><enum>(A)</enum><text>origins and destinations of freight movement within, to, and from the United States;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idBD11E67189164C47AC947EF487FFDACF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>volume of freight, including value and tonnage;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE77203E477234F549B23185B5723B721"><enum>(C)</enum><text>population centers;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD8E29C86E79842B692579392C7958E50"><enum>(D)</enum><text>border crossings, airports, and seaports;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id502460C8E647407193E94BAC01FAFD7B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>economic factors;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idDF72571479754B198E367242E1299548"><enum>(F)</enum><text>freight chokepoints and other impediments contributing to significant measurable congestion, delay in freight movement, or inefficient modal connections;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id793AF458B65940DA820DC7A652051902"><enum>(G)</enum><text>facilities of future freight importance based on input from stakeholders and analysis of projections for future growth and changes to the national freight system;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id88A2CE311E5B4CF49E5D74270C032CCF"><enum>(H)</enum><text>impacts on all freight transportation modes and modes that share significant freight infrastructure;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8C81D326929C4D569B4CECBB5FED6E79"><enum>(I)</enum><text>elements and transportation corridors identified by a multi-State coalition, State, State advisory committee, or metropolitan planning organization using national or local data as having critical freight importance to the region; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id926CE2905AB34F01A46D0C3B378DAC9F"><enum>(J)</enum><text>intermodal connectors, major distribution centers, inland intermodal facilities, and first- and last-mile facilities.</text>
									</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idD3D80B19A164447DB56E4BDA01E8E30D"><enum>5404.</enum><header>National multimodal freight strategic plan</header>
 <subsection id="id650E35DD9E754848B47C969C84BF59D0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Initial development</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of the <short-title>National Multimodal Freight Policy and Investment Act</short-title>, the Secretary, in consultation with State departments of transportation, metropolitan planning organizations, local governments, and other appropriate public and private freight transportation stakeholders, shall develop, maintain, and post on the Department of Transportation public website a national multimodal freight strategic plan.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id3D3A244836DA4E5A8A4FDBCA312EF808"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The initial and each revised national multimodal freight strategic plan shall include—</text> <paragraph id="idE17CAB27EC524BED841C5554D757BE00"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an assessment of the current condition and performance of the national multimodal freight network, and the ability of the network to meet the policy and goals described in section 5402;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idD33567290A4441A4BEA19511E86BDB53"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an assessment of statutory, regulatory, technological, institutional, financial, and other barriers to improved freight transportation performance, including opportunities for overcoming the barriers;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idBF2296404EDE471EBA852FD721CE9336"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an analysis of emerging and long-term projected trends in economic and national trade policies, public health, workforce availability, and environmental conditions that will impact the performance, needs, safety, and uses of the national transportation system to move freight;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id97D496616BE14BEBB6F24965A4398868"><enum>(4)</enum><text>an identification of freight chokepoints on the national multimodal freight network that create significant freight congestion problems, based on a quantitative methodology developed by the Secretary and using the analysis under paragraph (3);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id8E0C53E332E448F2B1B5642EABC72A6E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>an identification of major international and domestic trade gateways and corridors that connect major population centers and ports of entry;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id6258D3D885944F1ABA6CA6BD65D9AD4E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>a projection of current and forecasted traffic and freight volumes on the gateways and corridors identified under paragraph (5);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id20EF93AFDDFA41E99B11B13BB302476C"><enum>(7)</enum><text>an identification of major agricultural and energy rural production areas and other major inland freight generators;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id06DC96D40FBC4055AFDF95DA6BC59BB9"><enum>(8)</enum><text>an identification of the gateways and corridors that connect the major inland freight generators identified in paragraph (7) to ports of entry;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id82818FE89A6140F0AE85D29B4A21609E"><enum>(9)</enum><text>the best practices for improving the operational and safety performance of the national multimodal freight network;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id93A152519A9C44EF837B84006FFF9EA0"><enum>(10)</enum><text>the best practices to reduce, minimize, and mitigate the environmental and other impacts of freight movement on communities;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idC4D7AA49AB974A4DABD77A294B3A8961"><enum>(11)</enum><text>a process for addressing multistate projects and encouraging jurisdictions to collaborate;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idD5475C2112494115BF1152065A4F1187"><enum>(12)</enum><text>strategies to improve freight intermodal connectivity, including bulk transloading facilities;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id744D3C4A26664867938CD5F973DF1854"><enum>(13)</enum><text>the development of more consistent and accurate data to measure freight movement domestically and internationally; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id3C863F2F1FDC409DADC8A74BDC49189F"><enum>(14)</enum><text>the identification of federally designated strategic defense ports and nearby freight chokepoints that create significant congestion which could hamper the flow of military equipment and personnel to those ports.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id13458B02253E455FB8EF778610372AA0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Updates</header>
 <paragraph id="idC839460C678A42AAA922143ADD0C8623"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 5 years after the date the initial national multimodal freight strategic plan under subsection (a) is complete, and every 10 years thereafter, the Secretary shall update and repost on the Department of Transportation public website a revised national multimodal freight strategic plan.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id8385B151D5C54EAC8C93BAE1E88E4DC4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Major international and domestic trade gateways and corridors</header><text>The identification of major international and domestic trade gateways and corridors that connect major population centers and ports of entry under subsection (b)(5) shall be updated, as appropriate, in each revised national multimodal freight strategic plan.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id5285C5B4F41B41F2AD7FF41B81A523F5"><enum>5405.</enum><header>National multimodal freight advisory committee</header>
 <subsection id="idB13D927E1BA94143B28AC3636A07312C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish a national multimodal freight advisory committee in the Department of Transportation consisting of a balanced cross-section of public and private freight stakeholders representative of all freight transportation modes, including—</text>
 <paragraph id="id2F89080A7E5C44CB867B5866953D2F27"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">airports, highways, ports and waterways, rail, and pipeline;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id4BB923915EB7400E962A64EBCDF0A634"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shippers;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id7875066E835D43C1AA2218790BDFC81C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>carriers;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idD5D0AF8185BA4C4E841108C6041A30B6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>freight-related associations;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id29DBB602EC8A4BA28708FAE6D3B06538"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the freight industry workforce;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id1CD184B2AA814565A482742D569B1E3E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>State departments of transportation;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id56D8CCD987C14A3C9E0FBF87F0C2465F"><enum>(7)</enum><text>local governments;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id67C56D2362C6418C975E4FBB04EB86ED"><enum>(8)</enum><text>metropolitan planning organizations;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idF2620C26B5054FA992CBAFE3301DD9BE"><enum>(9)</enum><text>regional or local transportation authorities, such as port authorities;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id244A000F1AB843FE8952A5DBFEC26238"><enum>(10)</enum><text>freight safety organizations; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id452DE360C72B4D9082AE6D02A03011E2"><enum>(11)</enum><text>university research centers.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idDF8B03F0E67348039EA92A09516D5307"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The purpose of the committee is to help promote a safe, economically efficient, and environmentally sustainable national freight system.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id34C19111AD434D0890B5055C33109F74"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The committee, in consultation with State departments of transportation and metropolitan planning organizations, shall provide advice and recommendations to the Secretary on matters related to freight transportation in the United States, including—</text>
 <paragraph id="id6BD264DC7DC7478CAC5546CC14E2758D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the implementation of freight transportation requirements;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id16E64B90863D4447B1384DC12CF85CCF"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the establishment of a national multimodal freight network under section 5403;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id5234A4F0F4484200A450771A5C450977"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the development of the national multimodal freight strategic plan under section 5404;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idF3DE5333ABDF41F797D081DBF8C1ECD2"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the development of measures of conditions and performance in freight transportation;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id7ED93E033E79498D8B8921CEFA3234EB"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the development of freight transportation investment, data, and planning tools; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id3D0CB5F9B8A640A4981A44398666148E"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommendations for Federal legislation.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idF38EA9EFE4714247AD8680F7A3025B82"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Qualifications</header><text>Each member of the committee shall have qualifications sufficient to represent the interests of the member's specific stakeholder group, such as—</text>
 <paragraph id="id42523B6A713642E1972DE868C9B69C4F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>general business and financial experience;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id684C993C150D4BD3ACB93188E2F36D6A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>experience or qualifications in the areas of freight transportation and logistics;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id350717112AD149659FB94F800A1D025B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>experience in transportation planning, safety, technology, or workforce issues;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idC8D2B374D6F54B2A9280C446800DCF1F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>experience representing employees of the freight industry;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idEAB8820CDBD04B0CBD70FA77A363565C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>experience representing State or local governments or metropolitan planning organizations in transportation-related issues; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id4B4744B8CA1B41B6B51518650C76BFC8"><enum>(6)</enum><text>experience in trade economics relating to freight flows.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="id7ABD92BD7EA84A8E9FCA8BA4E1DC28A8"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Support staff, information, and services</header><text>The Secretary shall provide support staff for the committee. On request of the committee, the Secretary shall provide information, administrative services, and supplies that the Secretary considers necessary for the committee to carry out its duties.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="id782C32DE2AC646B2AE1E58BAB2D774E4"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Nonapplication of FACA</header><text>Section 14 of the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 App. U.S.C.) does not apply to the committee.</text> </subsection></section><section id="id6758CFB56C824C36ADDE16A4F08CB800"><enum>5406.</enum><header>State freight plans</header> <subsection id="id7D0EEE28557448C0883DE506500EE204"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each State that receives a grant under this chapter shall develop a freight plan that provides a comprehensive plan for the immediate and long-range planning activities and investments of the State with respect to freight.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id4A278B5DAF974A84A4705E1736898376"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Each State freight plan shall include—</text> <paragraph id="id786C9A07A84648E4A5440BE603F99000"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an identification of significant freight system trends, needs, and issues with respect to the State and each neighboring State with which high levels of trade occurs or logistical dependence exists;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id90FBA73A0FAA44AC926715DC2795802B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of the freight policies, strategies, and performance measures that will guide the freight-related transportation investment decisions of the State to achieve a reasonable balance in freight transportation modes;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id7D132C58D9FC4EE1AEB4EC68D0879C4B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a description of how the plan will improve the ability of the State to meet the goals of the national multimodal freight policy described in section 5402(b) and any relevant State multimodal freight policy;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id45CBDDB2BFF645D8A635A6ADB76BF0E8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>evidence that the State will consider innovative technologies and operational strategies, including intelligent transportation systems, that improve the safety and efficiency of freight movement and provide multimodal transportation systems integration for information sharing;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idDCE62666B8E64DA9A74CCF65AC57878A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in the case of routes on public infrastructure on which heavy vehicles travel (including mining, agricultural, energy cargo or equipment, and timber vehicles) or other conditions exist that are projected to substantially deteriorate the condition of those routes, a description of improvements that may be required to reduce or impede the deterioration, including the use of alternate freight transportation modes;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id6D2F8DFC104647BB923F4504A12909D0"><enum>(6)</enum><text>an inventory of facilities and corridors with freight mobility or accessibility issues, such freight chokepoints, within the State, and a description of the strategies the State will employ to address those freight mobility or accessibility issues;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id81805CE8D8694A179A0C9F986CAD3D63"><enum>(7)</enum><text>consideration of any significant congestion or delay caused by freight movements and any strategies to mitigate that congestion or delay; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idFF894DDD964E4E549495CAAA8FFE6845"><enum>(8)</enum><text>a priority freight investment plan that includes a list of priority projects, a methodology to prioritize future projects, and an explanation of how those investments achieve the goals of the national multimodal freight policy described in section 5402(b) and any relevant State multimodal freight policy.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id62A8812AF05E407789230F4D33A3C444"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Relationship to statewide strategic long-Range transportation plan</header>
 <paragraph id="id014D6557457747358232BB3413014E28"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A State may develop its State freight plan with, and incorporate the plan into, its statewide strategic long-range transportation plan. The State freight plan may be separate from the long-range transportation plan, but shall be consistent with the long-range transportation plan. The State freight plan shall be consistent with the State rail plan under section 22702 for that State.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id91CADBCF962F48D294E2513D87117319"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Fiscal constraints</header><text>The priority freight investment plan of a State freight plan under subsection (b)(8) shall include a project, or an identified phase of a project, only if funding for completion of the project can reasonably be anticipated to be available for the project within the time period identified in the priority freight investment plan.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id21FABC3E3FC44579A3E2367538EBCFCA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Planning period</header><text>Each State freight plan shall address a 10-year forecast period.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idE659D89DDE8243519240B731EA86161E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Updates</header> <subparagraph id="idE6A9A02DB45B4EF1B08C723DFB998AD1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A State shall update its State freight plan as frequently as the State determines necessary, but not less frequently than once every 10 years.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA7955764055D4B6C90059AF62AFFA8FD"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Priority freight investment plan</header><text>A State shall update its priority freight investment plan as frequently as the State determines necessary, but at least once every 5 years.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idA0161A34EE5345F18AB51D07A40A721D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>Each State shall consult with applicable Federal, State, and local agencies relevant to land use and programming processes when developing a State freight plan under this section, including the State's freight advisory committee under section 5407.</text>
							</subsection></section><section id="LEXA-Repairid8717D60C6A6849B887806A0F1ED18C7D"><enum>5407.</enum><header>State freight advisory committees</header>
 <subsection id="id2BCA9E800C4E4DEBAAE5C04A1A3A3563"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>As a condition of, and prior to, receiving a grant under this chapter, a State shall establish and maintain a freight advisory committee consisting of a balanced cross-section of public and private freight stakeholders representative of all freight transportation modes, including—</text>
 <paragraph id="id8992CFAC234B4BE3A1A4F3CED38943DE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>as applicable, airports, highways, ports and waterways, rail, and pipeline;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idB9FCF1102ACA43A18AD6EBEA4105133C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shippers;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id4F0A068A701E40478F495772DD85C07C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>carriers;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idF9DAAE891DD74A46B47DE01A1DCF0FE7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>freight-related associations;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id0697027BAA694770BFA50C561885C843"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the freight industry workforce;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idD49CCD3D204A4DAC96B3E0947C555963"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the State department of transportation;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id57F5D7056C8B4749A711983674EECD76"><enum>(7)</enum><text>local governments;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id0922FA37FC3343AC8A9044504C67919C"><enum>(8)</enum><text>metropolitan planning organizations;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id574018210854418892462F958C66D523"><enum>(9)</enum><text>local transportation authorities, such as port authorities;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id93E14B643FFE4EC9B91DF5C253839E63"><enum>(10)</enum><text>freight safety organizations; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idA5E2FADD4E21498D8D9071A0CAA35552"><enum>(11)</enum><text>university research centers.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id21E086E623564C85B80ECEAB152791F8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Qualifications</header><text>Each member of the advisory committee shall have qualifications sufficient to represent the interests of the member's specific stakeholder group, such as—</text>
 <paragraph id="id3C4952E2EC9E4541AA04ED1E0AA3CE31"><enum>(1)</enum><text>general business and financial experience;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id7D29F2BD32F94578ADBB5320AEF3FBE0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>experience or qualifications in the areas of freight transportation and logistics;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id8DF2E75A6139411493D00D8C85821584"><enum>(3)</enum><text>experience in transportation planning, safety, or workforce issues;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id6D2FD7CAA9DF4910846EA14AE2183AC1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>experience representing employees of the freight industry;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id248265B0048D40F99CD4936EDD9F8D72"><enum>(5)</enum><text>experience representing State or local governments, or metropolitan planning organizations in transportation-related issues; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id7714AC9D4F9049DA95665C68CE4136A3"><enum>(6)</enum><text>experience in trade economics relating to freight flows.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id40452319853F437798426E81CCF0E629"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>A freight advisory committee of a State described in subsection (a) shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="id25173E0DA4B14592AC8786875A6FAAD3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>advise the State on freight-related priorities, issues, projects, and funding needs;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idB32E0DD80BA64813ACAE2CCF9EA7FC5E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>serve as a forum for discussion for State transportation decisions affecting freight movement;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idB9480E677D6C4562B2362FEB8F6787C6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>communicate and coordinate regional priorities with other freight-related organizations;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idE782821C4066441F801F1F408D4E3B86"><enum>(4)</enum><text>promote the sharing of information between the private and public sectors on freight issues; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idA12721ABBDC9492D9046E5197A249249"><enum>(5)</enum><text>participate in the development of the State freight plan under section 5406, including advising on the development of a priority freight investment plan under subsection (b)(8) of that section.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="LEXA-RepairidE0900BABA18840499C27C48A675A0673"><enum>5408.</enum><header>Conditions and performance reports</header>
 <subsection id="idD4C5B020276E4C4495C47B8A6BACA2CB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of the <short-title>National Multimodal Freight Policy and Investment Act</short-title>, and biennially thereafter, the Secretary shall prepare and submit to Congress a report that describes the conditions and performance of the national multimodal freight network.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id8C44DDDE430B4F319118BFD5F2B3D952"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report shall contain, at a minimum, the following—</text> <paragraph id="id632AF9D854B64E6491B6B1A2446B833A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an assessment of the ability, including the current performance, of the national multimodal freight network to make significant progress toward and achieve the policy and goals described in section 5402; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idA274357C975A4727B980905B8AD0F038"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of impediments to improving the conditions and performance of the national multimodal freight network.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id67F74575B85E484BA42F4CF007D92AC6"><enum>5409.</enum><header>Transportation investment data and planning tools</header>
 <subsection id="id64135D207B5B40B89D12490C2B38261E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of <short-title>National Multimodal Freight Policy and Investment Act</short-title>, the Secretary shall begin to develop new tools, and improve existing tools, to support an outcome-oriented, performance-based approach by Federal, State, local, and private decisionmakers when evaluating proposed freight-related and other transportation projects, including—</text>
 <paragraph id="idB495AE0C16724080B7D5FFE8AD9522E5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>methodologies for systematic analysis of benefits and costs on a national, regional, and local basis;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id7041F0C5D8A6423E94BCB6482C4B289D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>tools for ensuring that the evaluation of freight-related and other transportation projects would consider safety, economic competitiveness, environmental sustainability, innovation, and system condition in the project selection process;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id23B5BFE9AF41401C9941B596CB76905A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>improved methods for data collection and trend analysis;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id8DD28586F1E849D59B5BEC22683EA415"><enum>(4)</enum><text>freight forecasting models; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id8E9DED6788764DA3BF4EC63FF33E82F8"><enum>(5)</enum><text>other tools to assist in effective freight transportation planning.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id652BCFA3141E44A3B6191B7DD0B6F00F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Freight data</header><text>In support of the tools described in subsection (a), and to support a broad range of evaluation methods to assist Federal, State, local, and private decisionmakers in making transportation investment decisions, the Secretary shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="id06B6CD80F4464AF785630E65626381CA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>direct the collection of appropriate freight data and supply chain data, including more consistent and accurate data to measure the condition and performance of the national multimodal freight network; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id09A2A09379CF46989EE07AC0E7F4BA58"><enum>(2)</enum><text>consider any improvements to existing freight data collection, including the Commodity Flow Survey and Freight Analysis Framework, that could reduce identified freight data deficiencies and improve forecasts of freight transportation demand, both domestic and international.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1C828D9F65704D28B3F4F01607AE13C6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>The Secretary shall consult with Federal, State, and other public and private freight transportation stakeholders to develop, improve, and implement the tools described in subsection (a) and collect the freight data and supply chain data described in subsection (b).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id90A5BE1F2B6B4D69834DF15FAD7EEF32"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Multimodal freight performance measures</header><text>The Secretary shall establish freight performance measures to develop a framework for assessing the demand, efficiency, condition, safety, and investment in the national multimodal freight network.</text>
							</subsection></section><section id="id86A15B546A1042FDB691AA7E1EBDBDEC"><enum>5410.</enum><header>Freight investment grant program</header>
 <subsection id="id7F770994FBB74C97AE6B41C0ECFD0012"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="id7C8270F6E8C54300A3E5921AAADFDFB7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible applicant</header><text>The term <term>eligible applicant</term> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id7577C60510284E6486ABDA31912FCBB0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a State;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id81AA063E2C494890AA05FD34F631B7A5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a political subdivision of a State;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idEF4C5EBBE83C4EACA82A964E4D6FB33F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a metropolitan planning organization;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id16F40692E7EB42E3BBECB488B2D80E78"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a regional or local transportation authority, including a port authority;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id705C01458E9E47588B763E2733933E35"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a tribal government or a consortium of tribal governments; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC513479EB5714D53B71D44DDE7B7DAC8"><enum>(F)</enum><text>2 or more of the entities described in subparagraphs (A) through (E).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idA961E4D33E4E47E0933CFA622EB85FA2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible project</header><text>The term <term>eligible project</term> means a capital investment in a project, or a project phase with independent utility, for—</text> <subparagraph id="id9836B77AD79741599EC75D299951FB85"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a transportation infrastructure facility; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id366CCE9B5A014989A8F6B4DCE9BC0A70"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an intelligent transportation system project primarily for freight benefit that reduces congestion or improves safety.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idF38E23B2C60B428E893FBD58B78BEAB4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Facility</header><text>The term <term>facility</term> includes—</text> <subparagraph id="id899D2CB76161483386A992059E1C08CC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a road facility;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id16D7F37F34E943BE8EEF448AA259729F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a rail facility;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC988285B75FF40E582780743B89852D8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a marine highway facility;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id69470572944E4F2285511C52DD3862C1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a maritime, land border, or inland port facility;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id733AC4B0A70847DEA9DE9048D5C9970B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a freight intermodal facility, including an intermodal facility serving a seaport, an intermodal or cargo access facility serving an airport, an intermodal facility serving a port on the inland waterways, a bulk intermodal/transload facility, or a road/rail intermodal facility; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB2B6CDBC473C4E3A88685208A63ED358"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a facility related to an international border crossing.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5C3A14401CF34E0E907961A7D27397AB"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Marine highway</header><text>The term <term>marine highway</term> means all of the marine transportation routes designated by the Secretary that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idF9F81B43C7D242FEBB318ED1002B59E8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>serve as extensions of the surface transportation system; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8C65205A8AEA4508AB6C7F8F7CDA714A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>promote short sea transportation.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idCE5FE9CDDA214B0B8EB37D358E42BFC9"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Transportation infrastructure facility</header><text>The term <term>transportation infrastructure facility</term> means a facility that is significantly used for the movement of freight.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idE18CA7B72373488C8A839240CF7238C3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary shall establish and implement a freight investment grant program in accordance with the policy, goals, and strategies described in section 5402.</text>
							</subsection><subsection id="id9FED28A42CB34F8DB1D41CB878CAA0CC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applications</header>
 <paragraph id="idD64AD9B3592243F3940A080394DC58CC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An eligible applicant shall submit to the Secretary an application in such form and in accordance with such requirements as the Secretary shall establish.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id497E0FF6F8E34145ACE3B5F93E2389CF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Groups of entities</header><text>A group described in subsection (a)(1)(F) shall submit an application through a lead applicant that qualifies under subparagraph (A), (B), (C), (D) or (E) of subsection (a)(1). Public-private partnerships are eligible if the lead applicant qualifies under subparagraph (A), (B), (C), (D), or (E) of subsection (a)(1).</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id9B8A27FBD087402DA14970542A0AC1FA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Criteria for selection</header>
 <text>The Secretary shall select eligible projects for funding based on the following criteria:</text>
 <paragraph id="id13017E1691D84DABB02F9E4EB8F53ECE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The eligible project will help achieve the goals and strategies described in section 5402.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id1DF9C4E9EB0D480DA8D41284BB9626C0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Funding committed by State and local governments and other public and private partners, along with the Federal funding requested, will be sufficient to complete the capital investment.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id4B96DF6B863C48E9AB25844211F3C071"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The extent to which the eligible project leverages Federal funds by securing commitments of State, local, tribal, or private funds in addition to the Federal funding requested under this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id032AF03D4E35473C86AC4EFDEAAE0319"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The likely benefits of the eligible project relative to its costs.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idE5F9AE765151419ABE5E63ECAD129257"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The extent to which the eligible project demonstrates the use of innovative technology, strategies, and practices or involves collaboration among States or political subdivisions.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id4FE6469B49B84D2985A0F744A7FCE076"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The likely effect of the eligible project to support the movement of freight internationally or to efficiently move freight and people interstate or intrastate.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id1C945CAE33E94C5E9A5C09C25BBF2681"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The eligible project's support of freight operations in a nationally significant place, as determined by the Secretary.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id96A85953AD5A4C55AAB6DCFED845C3FB"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The consistency of the eligible project with the national multimodal freight strategic plan developed under section 5404.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idD3E3D30BDCFB49138D60F93E14812B68"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Inclusion of the eligible project in a State freight plan under section 5406 or, if the State freight plan is not complete, a regional transportation plan.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id770E97B5B7324EECBFABC2BB022D3E49"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The extent to which the eligible project will reduce the adverse impacts of freight transportation on a local community.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idF0EB8C9694F84789B9C64CF63D72E7F6"><enum>(11)</enum><text>The ability of the eligible project to increase throughput and reduce congestion at freight chokepoints.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idC3199A9309714F2DA1EF79229AA7159E"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Federal share</header><text>The Federal share for a project funded under this section shall not exceed—</text> <paragraph id="idFEE157EF99C545109DD09DEFD313E1A4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>80 percent of the total capital cost of the eligible project; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id0EE1A30B18D64A9FBE5F0F5001BF0115"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$50,000,000.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5E73790B559E44CAA90993E8E6B50123"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Grant analysis</header><text>A grant agreement under this section between the Federal Government and a grantee shall specify that the grantee will collect data and report to the Secretary, at such times as the Secretary specifies, on—</text>
 <paragraph id="id2C50DC1EA25E484DA334D796FC0B9441"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the actual cost of constructing the eligible project;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id5D5F0B33D99F4F7BB3A6930C460B5C83"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the time required to complete and implement the eligible project;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id7842087059C5475F9E4EE7590205A296"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the level of usage of the transportation infrastructure facility built or improved by the eligible project;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id3714A86144264C2696F7E8A24EEAF419"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the benefits of the eligible project, measured in a way that is consistent with the benefits that were estimated in the application under subsection (c); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id8C1C9DBD8DCF4ADFA5131AE7FF295C5E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>any costs resulting from the eligible project in addition to the projected costs estimated in the application under subsection (c).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id007EA54A21704A049E88135FFAB24989"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Terms and conditions</header><text>The Secretary may require such additional terms and conditions of a grant under this section as the Secretary considers necessary.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id4AE94FE1C8B549E390052DD6B2E92F3C"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>For the purpose of administering a grant under this section, funds authorized for this section may be transferred within the Department of Transportation and administered in accordance with this title or title 23, as applicable, and any other laws applicable to the eligible project.</text>
							</subsection><subsection id="id8F2B99AB7EB44F3B98912EF66D71F33B"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Administrative and oversight costs</header>
 <paragraph id="idDE822A858AE64BABA4E0BDADF77478E7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may retain up to one-half of 1 percent of the amounts authorized for each fiscal year under this section for—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id2ED71175683148369B39E9FA81078930"><enum>(A)</enum><text>administration of the freight investment grant program; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0023AC0E684B4FBC86293C321B575C88"><enum>(B)</enum><text>oversight of eligible projects funded under this section.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idF2EAAAC6F9334011ABDADA4B50A84192"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administration expenses</header><text>In order to carry out the administration and oversight of grants under this section, the Secretary may transfer portions of the funds retained under this subsection to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idC636EFB372B947B192FA1A28F6EC1734"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Administrator of the Federal Highway Administration;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3A73B3CD0E4A4667A21832490495D32E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Administrator of the Federal Railroad Administration;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB19DBADB29CA4FE6A82F97CAE5750F26"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id829E3A97A1EC433FA63F1C184BC8DF21"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Administrator of the Federal Maritime Administration;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0BAD8E3163C544CDBD6405672DA29547"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Assistant Secretary for Research and Technology; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4C7FBC98BBB044DB90D8237A5CF35A75"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the Assistant Secretary of Freight Planning, Permitting, and Development.</text>
									</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id6A90C9668B8C47AB97FB7638A1E9E74C"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
 <paragraph id="id4D3833CB4EA2449B866F0FB85A14BB08"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section—</text> <subparagraph id="idDD46D92CA9A2481E881D17D8293E0142"><enum>(A)</enum><text>$2,000,000,000 for fiscal year 2016;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id63AE6F74768B4DD4BCE8E07F4A0C2318"><enum>(B)</enum><text>$2,000,000,000 for fiscal year 2017;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE5273A09522A41C69B0EE0E4B3C2602B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>$2,000,000,000 for fiscal year 2018;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2EEC716CC1BB4CBCB911D39A854DFEA6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>$2,000,000,000 for fiscal year 2019;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD4D62A62073F4FAEADDEFAF0AD94CEAC"><enum>(E)</enum><text>$2,000,000,000 for fiscal year 2020; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF363DE95267C4BDDBF9077B1FB4CD88D"><enum>(F)</enum><text>$2,000,000,000 for fiscal year 2021.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idD9E64194A7894234A3C5382A4C741105"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administration of funds</header><text>The funds appropriated for this program shall be available for obligation until expended.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection></section></chapter><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="id849266F05FB84E8CBCA17C7138AE3BAD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendments</header>
 <text>The table of contents for subtitle III of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding after the item relating to section 5340 the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF42AF73066544252AF01FE9BCDDC48EA" style="OLC"><toc><toc-entry bold="off" level="chapter">Chapter 54. Freight.</toc-entry><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">5401. Definitions.</toc-entry><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">5402. National multimodal freight policy.</toc-entry><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">5403. National multimodal freight network.</toc-entry><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">5404. National multimodal freight strategic plan.</toc-entry><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">5405. National multimodal freight advisory committee.</toc-entry><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">5406. State freight plans.</toc-entry><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">5407. State freight advisory committees.</toc-entry><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">5408. Conditions and performance reports.</toc-entry><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">5409. Transportation investment date and  planning tools.</toc-entry><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">5410. Freight investment grant program.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section id="id5D828FBBD7A24CFBA67B8D97A1C2680B"><enum>3.</enum><header>Office of freight planning, permitting, and development</header>
 <subsection id="idF9F591C8AB8740968549D6D1677F5090"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 102 of title 49, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="id81CE6BD3908C4BF891FF3F3E066E6B4D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating subsection (h) as subsection (i); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id764EE9220F384669A91927F93E739777"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting after subsection (g) the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idFFB99E4EEC7144AA8EB0551E7EE3E81B" style="OLC"> <subsection id="id7844B4C497BC47F49BA22B7FFEF917FE"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Office of freight planning, permitting, and development</header> <paragraph id="id13A7DD4EFD3C47B2BE3DD1F7F645CA3C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established, in the Office of the Secretary, an Office of Freight Planning, Permitting, and Development (referred to in this subsection as the <quote>Office</quote>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id634A6B6772F8416E8629B47A324C5C4D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Office shall—</text> <subparagraph id="id49C979DDA14D402DB72D1C77FE27C8A8"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">coordinate the investment of Federal funding to improve the efficiency of the national multimodal freight network (as defined in section 5401) to move freight in accordance with the policy, goals, and strategies described in section 5402;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8323A2345B24498D96E16CC6430F0D67"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for projects that involve multiple Federal agencies, designate a lead Federal agency or a modal administrator within the Department of Transportation—</text>
 <clause id="id92B84B5C42E14DEE9986FF1970BA5E3B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to serve as the primary point of contact; and</text> </clause><clause id="id22863C99AAEB49B9B503178F06536F08"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to actively monitor and identify the progress of the permitting process;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA3ECEFEF95CE4F3391D74497BDAEBE5E"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish a process to give priority consideration to the freight projects receiving freight investment grants under section 5410 when—</text>
 <clause id="idB19D3FA49CD5450B8A75A9C03CB65B80"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">coordinating and facilitating the permit review process; and</text> </clause><clause id="id15601F8F660846E0AA1433964C14FCE1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">advancing project delivery objectives if there is duplication of processes;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id21D16DD49C294914AC0EC2EFAA460928"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">facilitate communication among government, public, and private freight transportation stakeholders;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idDC902FACA5B64E3F8BF7E33EB64D8B99"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">support the Secretary in the development of the national multimodal freight strategic plan (as defined in section 5401);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id945531936ED542DC809DD0710F6B473A"><enum>(F)</enum><text>provide guidance or best practices on the development of the State freight plans under section 5406; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0ACD698C6F7B41CBA24A0F877260557E"><enum>(G)</enum><text>carry out other duties, as prescribed by the Secretary.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idC94DBB96491F4DFDA68497279EDEFAAD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Organization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Office shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id2A43410D1FE843A68BFFCAFE000BD8D7"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be headed by the Assistant Secretary of Freight Planning, Permitting, and Development;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA5AFB76C7572497DB08BAFAF40A6BDB5"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be structured out of existing resources and funding within the Department of Transportation, to the extent feasible; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1300F83333894CA5A2AFCBA5F8F180CA"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">serve to consolidate freight staffing from all modal administrations to improve collaboration between freight transportation modes (as defined in section 5401), especially in permitting oversight, and otherwise support the efficiency of the national multimodal freight network.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id9F1EC47228CA49CC8CD26B6DFD0DE7D2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendments</header>
 <paragraph id="idC1A139D5AC024BAB81232F740DC5F6BB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Assistant secretaries</header><text>Section 102(e)(1) of title 49, United States Code, is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="idFA79DAB9A33E46D9B44A6DBBD3F7E1B1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>5</quote> and inserting <quote>6</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA8F4D8BADB884403AEBE966466CEA06B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id015D0B5B306D48FA9E9817C2B4F123C7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (D) as subparagraph (E); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id59A1DC09D7E84C9784F6FEF7366C8CF1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (C) the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB87157F3B4F844D1A055D72C0092F857" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="id457D3F08E46B4CB0BB706B87EA73DEB5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an Assistant Secretary of Freight Planning, Permitting, and Development, who shall be appointed by the Secretary, with the approval of the President; and</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id66FCF06A32A44DC4B039F1BF487EFBF1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Executive schedule pay rates</header><text>Section 5316 of title 5, United States Code, is amended by inserting <quote>Assistant Secretary of Freight Planning, Permitting, and Development, Department of Transportation.</quote> after <quote>Assistant Secretary for Administration, Department of Transportation.</quote>.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id3A2FAEE0CB124B4E9025AEE719550977"><enum>4.</enum><header>Capital grants for shortline freight railroad state of good repair</header>
 <subsection id="id80135FBE716248DEA451C2C2A16C37FA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> <paragraph id="id84159F52190C403499CB7D5C372BB8F7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Capital project</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>capital project</term> means acquiring, constructing, improving, or inspecting shortline or regional railroad infrastructure, such as equipment, track and track structures, or a facility, including—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="idAE55946E2C9041308BDDFDA3B7F43ABC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>bringing that infrastructure to a state of good repair;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7F2E23BBEDCF4675B706A7360BE71741"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">bond costs and other costs relating to the issuance of bonds or other debt financing instruments;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0BD60FAEF1484DD4B174FB69ADEA280E"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">evaluating and assessing project implementation and outcomes;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9016BE44868443F6B72EAF4647D35FCA"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">expenses incidental to the activities described in subparagraph (C), including designing, engineering, location surveying, mapping, and environmental studies;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id388C938B5DAB4A90B4E42E91B8F79A18"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">installing, restoring, and rehabilitating track;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idEB72B64EC0D34A03976FF28889BA180C"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">preserving and acquiring rights-of-way;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idDA90849630E04EA6877D0DB5DE1DEED6"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">relocation assistance, including—</text> <clause id="idA2809731550F4261BCEA316ED6681CE7"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">acquiring replacement housing sites, and acquiring, constructing, relocating, and rehabilitating replacement housing; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="id7C9CE5174DDF4DD6A57D66B65BAEC04F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the lateral relocation of any portion of a rail line;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idDA902A3EC3C94563B25633509FD144E0"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">eliminating obstacles and relocating utilities;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3C01E5B562F849F7A76D9077D4282281"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">payments for the maintenance responsibility of rail trackage rights agreements;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id84B444B9DF66480A8FFDEE82FDDF3DC9"><enum>(J)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">mitigating adverse impacts on safety, motor vehicle traffic flow, quality of life, environment, or economic development;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9E33C7FBCAC64C5D8B42AF0D023D1508"><enum>(K)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">highway-rail grade crossing improvements, including the safety of and elimination of hazards at a highway-rail grade crossing;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3967ABD45BBE439688D5F6984555CA90"><enum>(L)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">communication and signalization improvements;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id334299B8CFDD4A708F2C4C32FDC3C17E"><enum>(M)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">subsidy and administrative costs of projects eligible for Federal credit assistance under the Railroad Revitalization and Regulatory Reform Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/45/801">45 U.S.C. 801 et seq.</external-xref>) for a capital project to improve shortline or regional railroad infrastructure;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idED6C620AB88D41FAA7E61CE55B95A4A6"><enum>(N)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improving or replacing locomotives operated by a shortline or regional railroad;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8B8990B29ED847618ECB096229AD7784"><enum>(O)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">on-dock or near-dock projects at seaports;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idDFF4EF127056485BBE22C98E562F311C"><enum>(P)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">resolving critical freight chokepoints and addressing capacity constraints; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id35628321C4004DCB96D263368459D790"><enum>(Q)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such other construction, improvement or inspection-related activities as determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9CA7B14CE4B048EBB7E8FD95D37D9F33"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible recipient</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible recipient</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="idEB6DF42C15D6492C847ED4F83071C1A6"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a State;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8103B1B98699404DA51A02756AF42D2C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a political subdivision of a State;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idBC53D0C4FDCB4366B5932BF4A6FEBC74"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a metropolitan planning organization;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id99AFC154A07F4BE990900772B5FB3550"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a regional or local transportation authority, including a port authority;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE006A5174A54453DBD76202D39D2F9A8"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a tribal government or a consortium of tribal governments;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF6E1DB083876403AB4FCB1321C283085"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a public entity responsible for providing rail freight transportation service;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD2DC8499D583484E867BCADD30D231B9"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">solely for the purpose of constructing a rail connection between a plant or facility and a rail carrier, a limited option freight shipper that owns or operates a plant or facility;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idDBCBB9B39EDB483FA1242DF032560A8F"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">2 or more of the entities described in subparagraphs (A) through (G); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2DC7F4930A6149739F601D3A902744B6"><enum>(I)</enum><text>if the capital project is a public-private partnership with 1 or more of the entities described in subparagraphs (A) through (H), a shortline or regional railroad or a holding company of a shortline or regional railroad.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id1DD1474C295042CB9789D4E9A2FE3322"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Railroad carrier</header><text>The term <term>railroad carrier</term> has the meaning given the term in section 20102 of title 49, United States Code.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id912F52DC842C409F9124ECB81D5C4AA3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Transportation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id0E5DD032B64A491B8D4CC0E955A02EC0"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Shortline or regional railroad</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>shortline or regional railroad</term> means a railroad carrier that has annual carrier operating revenues that meet the threshold amount for Class II carriers or Class III carriers, as determined by the Surface Transportation Board under section 1201.1–1 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, on which not less than 80 percent of the volume of rail traffic is freight traffic.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id1F8B6152805B4164A913C57B7FDF935D"><enum>(6)</enum><header>State of good repair</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>state of good repair</term> means a condition in which the existing physical assets, both individually and as a system, are functioning as designed within their useful lives and are sustained through regular maintenance and replacement programs.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idE1012402B31D42B4BAADF07774CF53CC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grants authorized</header>
 <paragraph id="id4C9A5AA583F344F6A51C2E7415147A92"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish a competitive grant program to provide financial assistance to eligible recipients for capital projects that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idB200B8E7AACE464D999ACDEC31C3F495"><enum>(A)</enum><text>help accomplish the goals of a State rail plan under section 22702 of title 49, United States Code, or, if a State freight plan under section 5406 of that title is complete, the goals of the State freight plan; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4C26EAAB046E4A83BC834CA161F75581"><enum>(B)</enum><text>either—</text> <clause id="id6CFE38C9D5CB4423934AB88D217BC207"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improve shortline or regional railroad infrastructure by improving the efficient and safe movement of freight; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="id6E18A387F0F04B7FAD43431C1431B474"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">mitigate the adverse impacts of shortline or regional railroad infrastructure or operations on a local community.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9D1EA14923204C858FD9CD049326C8A5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligibility and considerations for approval</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In determining whether to award a grant to an eligible recipient under this section, the Secretary shall consider the following, listed by priority:</text>
 <subparagraph id="id6BD70232D7794470B3CE7D771EDF987E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The extent to which a capital project—</text> <clause id="idD301664A6D3041D49CB00717E59BEE63"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">will contribute to the efficient movement of freight, including multimodal freight;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idB45CE7C0D299420C9EFC2EC631D9EA3B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">will benefit the efficient movement of freight at or accessing a port, or agricultural or manufacturing cluster;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id3864CFFF1FAC412B97737EE16A18004A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">will contribute to increasing the economic competitiveness and state of good repair of a shortline or regional railroad;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id759AED050A5B449DB4A3233475F47F16"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">will alleviate the impacts of a shortline or regional railroad’s operations on local communities, including impacts on safety, motor vehicle traffic flow, community quality of life, environment, or economic development;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idFA58A97E44AD44FA92BBEA87F6312234"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">will enhance safety;</text> </clause><clause id="idEA95F8B763504F4981477BCA99F7E3C1"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is not capable of being fully funded without Federal grant funding;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idB586A65A42894F759DA4C97081F5082F"><enum>(vii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">complies with the limitation relating to the allocation of grant funds set forth in subsection (c);</text>
 </clause><clause id="id2B84A637A64A40BC91E6C5214E599008"><enum>(viii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">will contribute to the equitable treatment of the various regions of the United States;</text> </clause><clause id="idC98D1F112D034357AAC19AE9EAA7C140"><enum>(ix)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes equitable participation from other beneficiaries in the project’s financing, including the extent to which the project will leverage financial contributions or commitments from private entities involved with the project in proportion to the expected benefits that accrue to such entities from the project;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id25B10DE0AEDB403CA06ECC016AD7E24E"><enum>(x)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is compatible with local land use, economic development, and transportation plans and objectives; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id78D614B7AD724F60AC777D95152BA867"><enum>(xi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">will increase the reliability and resilience of the Nation’s multimodal freight system.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id22E7FC019F1B414FAA0327745804BC2F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The past performance of the eligible recipient and other beneficiaries of the capital project in developing and delivering 1 or more capital projects.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id10DF6E8E2AB3482F994911DEC6688128"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such other factors as the Secretary considers relevant.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id37CEE84FF0C842058A9A406B57EA3DFD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Allocation limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not less than 50 percent of all grant funds awarded under this section out of funds appropriated for a fiscal year shall be provided to publicly owned shortline railroads.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="id97B78394AD5643058A63E4157A833E25"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Project cost sharing</header>
 <paragraph id="idE4BEB62A1D8C48E7B4D4A506C1AFC4BA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Basis</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall estimate the total cost of each eligible project based on—</text> <subparagraph id="idAE87400D89A24FA3996A90F40DDDBAF6"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">engineering studies;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id18AB74DE6C1849D7A4E4700F138E3F03"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">studies of economic feasibility;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC648A136E7D647038D5CABBC52D8AE63"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">environmental analyses; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC9DB9F0D86254F2BA9EB8F0512FDDAC3"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information on the expected use of the shortline or regional railroad infrastructure, such as equipment, track, track structure, or facility.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id227054F0F55946E180C8F8AF098BF3A0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federal share</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A Federal grant for an eligible project under this section may not exceed—</text> <subparagraph id="idF9269384AD374D9E81E44B391BA0D6E2"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">90 percent of the total capital cost of the eligible project; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8227D7B938364C999C7823FDE76012E3"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$6,000,000.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id2A1A34D888C249758C4A414E90678CCE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Non-Federal share</header> <subparagraph id="idB95D06A93E37498C8CE87CC11D6A9928"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible recipient shall pay, or arrange for the payment from non-Federal sources, including financing, not less than 10 percent of the shared costs of an eligible project that is funded in part by a grant awarded under this section.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idFA52695EA04A4FA7AFBE391235AF0609"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Forms of contributions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The shared costs under subparagraph (A) may be paid in cash or in-kind contributions.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC1515DC9F1E446E0ADE8B0B9A88207E2"><enum>(C)</enum><header>In-kind contributions</header> <clause id="id6761517E65B049C0B69A087AFB0D18A1"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The non-Federal in-kind contributions under subparagraph (B) may consist of—</text>
 <subclause id="idF7F7FF6A034A4CB7B8AC811E0A7651C9"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">real property;</text> </subclause><subclause id="id858B53B795EC43029A5D1A59DBEFAD40"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">tangible personal property;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id6E7D1B04C43246B5A9F14A7F7C35547E"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">services of employees of the eligible recipient or non-Federal source; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="id8062353963504A15B65F08710581B31F"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>payments made by an eligible recipient or other non-Federal source for costs incurred for the eligible project before the filing of an application for a grant under this section, and any in-kind contributions that were made for the project before the filing of the application, to the extent that such costs were incurred or in-kind contributions were made to comply with a legal requirement necessary to carry out the eligible project.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="id1B9DE7B5661A4B71B1FACFFFEE3A2C64"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Calculations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The value of an in-kind contribution under clause (i)(III) shall be calculated—</text> <subclause id="id5EDD1EE527A547199268C49A03C0DDC7"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by including the costs incurred by the eligible recipient or other non-Federal source for the pay and benefits of an employee described in clause (i)(III); and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id82C5750C7833401D96E12FA7C84D31D1"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by excluding any overhead or general administrative costs.</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idA2186CBA210840DAA9AB390BBF42A678"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reporting requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As part of the grant application process, each eligible recipient shall submit a description of the anticipated public and private benefits (as those terms are defined in section 22701 of title 49, United States Code) associated with the eligible project.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id1033DF24245F442DA9685F9ECDA855D8"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Agreements To Combine Amounts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Two or more eligible recipients may agree to combine any part of the amounts provided through grants for an eligible project under this section if—</text>
 <paragraph id="idB96BB3D9F9164318B4BE0D3FE574701C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the eligible project will benefit each eligible recipient entering into the agreement; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idE81C9BA4CA4042A785467CE4CCF6DF8B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the agreement does not violate any Federal law or any law of any State in which an eligible recipient is located.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id7783E289D4D5418CA731B8C23ED90668"><enum>(g)</enum><header>State cooperation</header><text>The Secretary shall encourage each shortline or regional railroad applicant for a grant under this section to utilize the expertise and assistance of 1 or more State transportation agencies in applying for and administering the grant. The Secretary shall encourage each applicable State transportation agency to provide its expertise and assistance to the shortline or regional railroad.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id236F2597B77B44EB9A035681578A4E57"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than July 1, 2016, the Secretary shall issue final regulations for implementing the grant program authorized under this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id2001649FF16643A18B992DF94B7E2870"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this section $50,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2016 through 2021.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="id7CA92E97EB78468ABF714A88EEE4A697"><enum>5.</enum><header>Capital grants for grade separation projects</header>
 <subsection id="id26A5F22FD1BA4BA78E9D9E0DA31AAC08"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> <paragraph id="idC6DFEC7137AD4BE79D94F8671235E7DA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible applicant</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible applicant</term> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id9DB9B77DBBFF4902BD5BEA8C8A2AC6EE"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a State;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id346959C2FC184D959E62FB073DD041F8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a political subdivision of a State;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2AABFCD1351A406DB92CB474522C0917"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a metropolitan planning organization;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idFA8C240C1D4046939C4A70CAE82BC990"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a regional or local transportation authority, including a port authority;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE1F73746B2594CBBB31E0360CB78418A"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a tribal government or a consortium of tribal governments; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC74D10365F0B40B8B6F75200B6A3114B"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">2 or more of the entities described in subparagraphs (A) through (E).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id51AEBB4EB81D43F1ABD5DA21F92CA11D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Highway-rail vertical grade separation project</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>highway-rail vertical grade separation project</term> means a project that separates the grade of a road-rail crossing to eliminate the conflict between those freight transportation modes.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id8FE2909C2C59402DB0D7CA642440DFD0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Host railroad</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>host railroad</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="idF84CF55337FA46B0B5B240416798C8FC"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a Class I railroad, Class II railroad, or Class III railroad (as defined in section 20102 of title 49, United States Code); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6745E19563D9459592111977F5BBE405"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the public or private owner of rail infrastructure over which a Class I railroad, Class II railroad, or Class III railroad operates.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id2FCD78EC452C4D498D27A013616F7E8A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Transportation.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id580E4B2A2FAC49AF88E34EA2AF715C1B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grants authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish a competitive capital grant program to provide financial assistance to eligible applicants for highway-rail vertical grade separation projects intended to reduce highway and rail congestion and improve safety.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idE8370D9681AE4BD19198C4BFC1158B35"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligible projects</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible applicant may apply for a grant under this section for the purpose of—</text> <paragraph id="id72C2EDA193C9404682957B7B39EEE16A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">constructing a highway-rail vertical grade separation project; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id1C5094727E744DF9BED38C3CFCF15C31"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">planning, preparing, or designing a project described in paragraph (1).</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id6DEE5BC304044AD8B557C3AC800411D8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Project selection criteria</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In determining whether to award a grant to an eligible applicant under this section, the Secretary shall consider the following factors, listed by priority:</text>
 <paragraph id="idD0D4783230C24793BFBC4F200909DBEF"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether the highway-rail vertical grade separation project will cost-effectively reduce national, regional, or local truck and rail freight network delays.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id80ED80D23AF24670A187A5492F64A734"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The extent to which the highway-rail vertical grade separation project includes equitable financial participation from other beneficiaries of the project, including the extent to which the project will leverage financial contributions or commitments from private entities involved with the project in proportion with or greater to the proportion of the expected benefits that accrue to such entities from the project.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idB1EF56A186E849569E9BD75B2C46FF68"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The truck freight and train volumes at the crossing.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id062CA3174A394E10B10756278C3B49A7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The traffic delays caused by trains traveling through the crossing.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id7F0FE0FDF08C4C57B5CAC79DC14A3776"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The history at the crossing of incidents with fatal or severe injuries.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id5672546BFCFF4EA69676789E8435AA64"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The safety hazards, including sightlines, along the crossing approaches.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id66EE583999884B7FA067D18630C4FFC6"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The angle of the tracks to the roadway.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idEEBA67956AE44BE799046C4F03A26623"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The highway-rail vertical grade separation project readiness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id80E535EFDDA148A4B9F6B95C6BF07B17"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The benefit to railroad operations as a result of the project.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id0CCFD935786C42B8B8B24F9EEBF34702"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Such other factors as the Secretary considers relevant.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id7DF884FD6E124A1EAA3E5140E1D1026B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reporting requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As part of the grant application process, each eligible applicant shall submit a description of the anticipated public and private benefits associated with the highway-rail vertical grade separation project. The eligible applicant shall describe the anticipated public and private benefits in consultation with the host railroad involved in the project.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="idB21315BB76B54DDCA920288BFDF5EC20"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Project cost sharing</header>
 <paragraph id="id528E8D65C3134798A9DDF27D3C1BED76"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Basis</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall estimate the total cost of each highway-rail vertical grade separation project based on—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id8E5239EBD8074996B4E20A16A55F04AF"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">engineering studies;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC8A80513AC4640F1A11A712E103490EB"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">studies of economic feasibility; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7F56FF35275C48B5A372F9BE22F4D2E6"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information on the expected use of equipment or facilities.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id421D5AC2D1004883BA1521EAB4506A5B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federal share</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A Federal grant for a highway-rail vertical grade separation project under this section may not exceed—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id40FBAB70D7AC4E9AAB707BE8CF764C66"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">60 percent of the total capital cost of the highway-rail vertical grade separation project; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0A14E2E0EE504F98B92CDB294C42F0C9"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$15,000,000.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idF48B81E5601040A197A5EB07AD321ECE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Non-Federal share</header>
 <subparagraph id="id50B77B6A070047DC9AC9D6F5295ED2C1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The eligible applicant shall pay, or arrange for the payment from non-Federal sources, including financing, not less than 40 percent of the shared costs of a highway-rail vertical grade separation project that is funded in part by a grant awarded under this section.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD94EA4B913794BB69717CDA94AD620E8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Forms of contributions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The costs required under subparagraph (A) may be paid in cash or in-kind contributions.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD56F71FB53174AAD8BBCEC9898691842"><enum>(C)</enum><header>In-kind contributions</header> <clause id="id1F912ECE8F584169A13F00648C4B2C54"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The non-Federal in-kind contributions under subparagraph (B) may consist of—</text>
 <subclause id="id70B2D3CF0AE24F29AFE4BB2D2136E18E"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">real property;</text> </subclause><subclause id="idFC76EF95505D472FBE7DDE0007F1D4BF"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">tangible personal property;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idFF220695358A4A8E9F7B3B9E4C06E2AD"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">services of employees of the eligible applicant or other non-Federal source; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="idC1A4CA586E044E25AA7FAC8D3660D676"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">payments made by the eligible applicant or other non-Federal source for costs incurred for the highway-rail vertical grade separation project before the filing of an application for a grant for the project under this section, and any in-kind contributions that were made for the project before the filing of the application, to the extent that such costs were incurred or in-kind contributions were made to comply with a legal requirement necessary to carry out the project.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="idA57FE1DD0EE64ACB802B6F2FCE7C56FD"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Contributions</header><text>The value of an in-kind contribution under clause (i)(III) shall be calculated—</text> <subclause id="id4FCFBB299ADD4163AA027256B7A05FC9"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by including the costs incurred by the eligible applicant or other non-Federal source for the pay and benefits of an employee described in clause (i)(III); and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id88672F8C997341A18215366B117622A2"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by excluding any overhead or general administrative costs.</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1E1663A3C8614B60AC626B9413D7E5CB"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Grant conditions</header><text>The Secretary shall require as a condition of making any grant under this section that a written agreement exist between an eligible applicant and a host railroad concerning construction, maintenance, railroad contribution, and such other factors as the Secretary considers relevant.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id5E2C93A602974DCB9EC4C6175642A3EB"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than July 1, 2016, the Secretary shall issue final regulations for implementing the grant program authorized under this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idFA5F97B92E5249B6A25E6B5EF521BE0E"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Guidance</header><text>The Secretary may update existing or issue new guidance to assist an eligible applicant in determining whether a highway-rail crossing should be grade separated, including by identifying relevant criteria that should be considered and evaluating the benefits and costs of grade separations compared to other safety approaches within a risk analysis framework.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id652251CDAC1E47BFAAED07B877A1309C"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this section $150,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2016 through 2021.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


