<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S2113 IS: Crowdsourcing and Citizen Science Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-09-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 2113</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150930">September 30, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S375">Mr. Daines</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To harness the expertise, ingenuity, and creativity of all people to contribute to innovation in
			 the United States and to help solve problems or
			 scientific questions by
			 encouraging and increasing the use of crowdsourcing and citizen science
			 methods within the Federal Government, as appropriate, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Crowdsourcing and Citizen Science Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </section><section id="id7b52e731e2f64fd59cc1d1f94862f394"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text> <paragraph id="id20629d3ec5f34a50b9cc2c4925a9ec7b"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the authority granted to Federal agencies under the America COMPETES Reauthorization Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/358">Public Law 111–358</external-xref>) to pursue the use of incentive prizes and challenges has yielded numerous benefits, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id010f8b232290440a85986c796f0449d9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>paying only for success;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide719b544ea2f42168935a788fd543b64"><enum>(B)</enum><text>establishing an ambitious goal without having to predict which team or approach is most likely to succeed;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4f73bcdf351f4810a197c8019984e033"><enum>(C)</enum><text>reaching out to individuals or a broader group of people to increase the number of minds tackling a problem;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idebcc3f8092064987a9981cf602e33924"><enum>(D)</enum><text>bringing out-of-discipline perspectives to bear; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id628a4b8dc54341e887f12ebde831c52e"><enum>(E)</enum><text>increasing cost-effectiveness to maximize the return on taxpayer dollars;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id82dd2923fa49494890d3b452604d2a69"><enum>(2)</enum><text>granting Federal agencies the direct, explicit authority to use crowdsourcing and citizen science will—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idE1897C8CF07B4D338430308C8386D391"><enum>(A)</enum><text>remove ambiguity about whether an agency can use these techniques;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6B8D117C4F954E8EA7A1B2BFF4F24D8B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>encourage its appropriate use to advance agency missions; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id287551A6605648A6813835E75F520EAB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>stimulate and facilitate broader public participation in the innovation process;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0a8600233a904dca8539daef30e1a0fc"><enum>(3)</enum><text>crowdsourcing projects have a number of unique benefits, including—</text> <subparagraph id="id5d2d2daa8b474ec8b90b0160b31679ac"><enum>(A)</enum><text>improving the delivery of government services with significantly lower Federal or other public resource investments or at time scales or distribution scales that might not otherwise be possible;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id13EFE164DE6044FCBBB773A424277FFA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>connecting citizens to the missions of Federal agencies by promoting a spirit of open government and volunteerism;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbfcb8a25557940ac98decb9ee275dff7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>providing the acquisition of data at a greater geographic extent and in locations with a greater density or frequency than otherwise reasonably obtainable using conventional methods; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb4fbc682c85a40c99ed62b0dd6236cd3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>enabling citizens to address community and research-based concerns by gathering, analyzing, and sharing data and information;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id49D4A648D4B44A61951D3155A9B774DF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>citizen science has additional benefits, including—</text> <subparagraph id="id26f8d75a5f4145b984cac7572413cb15"><enum>(A)</enum><text>advancing and accelerating scientific research through group discovery, the cocreation of knowledge, and the inclusion of diverse perspectives;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5cac1309e4524f749b55070f945c817d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>improving science literacy and providing skills needed to excel in science, technology, engineering, and math, thereby increasing American competitiveness;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd9cb461f09ba48bd8b3b846a8ecb1ced"><enum>(C)</enum><text>furthering science diplomacy through the worldwide collaboration between scientists and citizens; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF63AB584AFDE498B8BB627975C2FA6D8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>building trust and understanding between citizens and science and between citizens and scientists; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ida3e640efec774bcca2352250a1dbd66a"><enum>(5)</enum><text>since participants in crowdsourcing and citizen science projects participate in crowdsourcing or citizen science for a variety of reasons, Federal agencies should consider meaningful incentives to engage and retain participants depending on the range of motivations for potential participants, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id49ab1131b1004d828fc79cb5199061e5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>receiving attribution for their contributions to research;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc92708bf56ab43e786f4886035a7c1dd"><enum>(B)</enum><text>learning new skills and knowledge or educating others;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4e84a8544a7141a98728279b398d86b2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>connecting with new individuals or communities and building relationships; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id70a24eef3f2149098b86c7f265db3d62"><enum>(D)</enum><text>knowing that their work is helping to solve meaningful problems and contributing to broader scientific endeavors for the benefit of society.</text>
				</subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="id37592ac34545406d9fd16994649ee146"><enum>3.</enum><header>Crowdsourcing and citizen science</header>
 <subsection id="idcf5023b6847741138e910e358d0f70f1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="idf622c19d41ee4f0fa976a1a69d1adb01"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Citizen science</header><text>The term <term>citizen science</term> means a form of open collaboration in which individuals or organizations participate in the scientific process in various ways, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id036BB8B2E54E4A128CE25925B0758F30"><enum>(A)</enum><text>enabling the formulation of research questions;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0CC0CB78FA3A45C18EF866201375D01F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>creating and refining project design;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2581D761004F4CA8940C69BA26AEA78A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>conducting scientific experiments;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8EAAFC963B994BD18B4761B677C7E82F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>collecting and analyzing data;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id600B5F9EBBAF48A8B59488F91958D4EC"><enum>(E)</enum><text>interpreting the results of data;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id44D9D3CA59D14128A8A0EACBB7BA3874"><enum>(F)</enum><text>developing technologies and applications;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id05152821DAD1431899A8C9B2CF712FBA"><enum>(G)</enum><text>making discoveries; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id70AD48C90F57457E80582C0B3AC77387"><enum>(H)</enum><text>solving problems.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idf219896d6db444c5aa0756a9e112118e"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Crowdsourcing</header><text>The term <term>crowdsourcing</term> means a method to obtain needed services, ideas, or content by soliciting voluntary contributions from a group of individuals or organizations, especially from an online community.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id6aa630fd3336402fadf39a9f2f82cb49"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The term <term>Director</term> means the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id09cb44c032664365993105a73e84df2e"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Federal agency</header><text>The term <term>Federal agency</term>—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id1FDDF14F88F44B7BAA1ED4C4F45C0D45"><enum>(A)</enum><text>except as provided in subparagraph (B), means—</text> <clause id="id587065EE861546CF9A0D6056D8DCA2FE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any Executive agency (as defined in section 105 of title 5, United States Code); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id91D36FE240154D3D931F3AF1F76C34D0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any military department (as set forth in section 102 of such title); and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id696122B0D63D488999127CD15F3955CC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include any legislative branch agency.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0490F50CFF8D4321B1C57E48C6CA422D"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Participant</header><text>The term <term>participant</term> means any individual or other entity that has consented as a volunteer in a crowdsourcing or citizen science project under this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id3dd2ac5239eb4f518aff91ad956fd4c6"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Related entity</header><text>The term <term>related entity</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="idE3ED1EC6C4D14A42A7D8482392DDD58E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a Federal Government contractor or subcontractor, at any tier; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7A66E93ADD504CAEB2E59887B130E97E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a supplier, user, customer, cooperating party, grantee, investigator, fellow, or detailee of a Federal agency.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id6877e087e4314f778cf2700a4dab52a3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Crowdsourcing and citizen science authorized</header>
 <paragraph id="id1394087598BD46CC8F83D8FB47CDF945"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The head of each Federal agency, or the heads of multiple Federal agencies working cooperatively, may utilize crowdsourcing and citizen science approaches to conduct activities designed to advance the mission of the respective Federal agency or the joint mission of Federal agencies, as applicable.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idf908246a5da14aa78631f3bdb09c970c"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Voluntary services</header><text>Notwithstanding section 1342 of title 31, United States Code, the head of a Federal agency may accept, subject to regulations issued by the Office of Personnel Management, voluntary services from participants under this section if such services—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idf681b7528f80489c93b8843b283ad684"><enum>(A)</enum><text>are performed as a part of a crowdsourcing or citizen science project authorized under paragraph (1);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id335afae676a24ed88de60a7d8d1a0c13"><enum>(B)</enum><text>are not financially compensated for their time; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id66a12400e76f4266af76aca8a6c6ade5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>will not be used to displace any employee of the Federal Government.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idc8d42bcfe27f41208985a33c6411903a"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Participation</header>
 <paragraph id="id3b7c13fb107648f59ebcd0b55bf04b46"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Advertising</header><text>The head of each Federal agency engaged in a crowdsourcing or citizen science project under this section shall make public and promote such project to encourage broad participation of consenting participants.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="id8198908436C74B80A430C02ECD757D7D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consent, registration, and terms of use</header>
 <subparagraph id="id58BEB9798EEB458897D11E10140E1EFF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each Federal agency is authorized to determine the appropriate level of consent, registration, or acknowledgment of the terms of use that is required from participants in crowdsourcing or citizen science projects on a per-project basis.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF01FC417A2B64FD192848E8982FDFF41"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Disclosures</header><text>In seeking consent, conducting registration, or developing terms of use for a project under this subsection, a Federal agency shall disclose the privacy, intellectual property, data ownership, compensation, service, program, and other terms of use to the participant in a clear and reasonable manner.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id198AD1A7645A4DE3A3E8E16FBC5672D7"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Mode of consent</header><text>A Federal agency or Federal agencies, as applicable, may obtain consent electronically or in written form from participants to the volunteer service terms of a crowdsourcing or citizen science project authorized under this section.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id323c973005c745ba95786ac4327756bc"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Human subjects</header><text>Any crowdsourcing or citizen science project that involves research involving human subjects shall be subject to part 46 of title 28, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id2E6D468EE7824769ABD09ED13F657C2C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Data</header><text>Notwithstanding security and privacy protections, Federal agencies shall endeavor to make data collected through a crowdsourcing or citizen science project authorized under this section open and available, in machine readable formats, to the public. As part of the consent process, the Federal agency shall notify all participants—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id2A6BBDCC40B04C73852BCD99FBBBBF22"><enum>(A)</enum><text>of the expected uses of the data compiled through the project;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5A6BE5871C324948A2A2B52FDED1212E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if the Federal agency will retain ownership of such data;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE6A687A89C444474B0E9F1F2F5B1BFA7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>if and how the data and results from the project would be made available for public or third party use; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF56A568336EA4A708C631C1BC420B7A8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>if participants are authorized to publish such data.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5126df8503ff4086ab9ec5fd0af08620"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Technologies and applications</header><text>Notwithstanding the intellectual property rights of the Federal Government, Federal agencies shall endeavor to make technologies, applications, code, and derivations of such intellectual property developed through a crowdsourcing or citizen science project under this section open and available to the public.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idF8E812E4775F443FB3B022DF5D324EDF"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Liability</header><text>Each participant in a crowdsourcing or citizen science project under this section shall agree—</text> <subparagraph id="id327B39F844104A6ABD0296398C8EB6D5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to assume any and all risks associated with such participation; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0AAC37C903C94A0983A5ECF2F8892D3B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to waive all claims against the Federal Government and its related entities, except for claims based on willful misconduct, for any injury, death, damage, or loss of property, revenue, or profits (whether direct, indirect, or consequential) arising from participation in the project.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id097ffe1e4bab4bb4ad2f1ca1f4b8ad49"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Scientific integrity</header><text>Federal agencies coordinating citizen science projects shall make all practicable efforts that participants adhere to all relevant scientific integrity or other applicable ethics policies.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idf81be9ac88af4200b71956080f3e44b8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Multi-Sector partnerships</header><text>The head of each Federal agency engaged in crowdsourcing or citizen science under this section, or the heads of multiple Federal agencies working cooperatively, may enter into a contract or other agreement to share administrative duties for such activities with—</text>
 <paragraph id="idEBE2A30BB23B43D688F9AA2D1A777B54"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a for-profit or nonprofit private sector entity, including a private institution of higher education; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idA45E0D908CCB40D6BE4E899C4C126EF5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a State, tribal, local, or foreign government agency, including a public institution of higher education.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4311111de550438e9f2035fa518d89fe"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>In carrying out crowdsourcing and citizen science activities under this section, the head of a Federal agency, or the heads of multiple Federal agencies working cooperatively—</text>
 <paragraph id="ida508ad64e5d24e36a49c433f9924e02a"><enum>(1)</enum><text>may use funds appropriated by Congress;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id495b56096f40412cb925fc06684ba934"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may request and accept funds or in kind support for such activities from—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idAC0FA6FE612D486694FB1C1E2C0DEB5F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>other Federal agencies;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7387B2CD67BC4AD699117431D9A55CEC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for-profit or nonprofit private sector entities, including private institutions of higher education; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF185B40DD8494C6980A52701E1E6BB7C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>State, tribal, local, or foreign government agencies, including public institutions of higher education; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id641142c7988743f48e4daa975272e5ee"><enum>(3)</enum><text>may not give any special consideration to any entity described in paragraph (2) in return for such funds or in kind support.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4983d0d1bca947618e3007a357c015f8"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Facilitation</header>
 <paragraph id="idB5704676B3A748A193A11904AE5B52E8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>General services administration assistance</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the General Services Administration, in coordination with the Director, shall identify and develop relevant products and services to facilitate the use of crowdsourcing and citizen science activities under this section, including by specifying the appropriate contract vehicles and technology and organizational platforms to enhance the ability of Federal agencies to carry out the activities under this section to further the policy objectives of the Federal Government.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id80A4BD9CCDE14B6799220459C9122F32"><enum>(2)</enum><header>OSTP guidance</header><text>The heads of each Federal agency engaged in crowdsourcing or citizen science under this section is encouraged to consult any guidance provided by the Director.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idf37d9a8806994ae7a0b0cb4b4dd6f714"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Report</header>
 <paragraph id="id496325b770c345f58ea1afaaab30e0fe"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, and every 4 years thereafter, as a component of the report required under section 24(p) of the Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/3719">15 U.S.C. 3719(p)</external-xref>), the Director shall report on the activities carried out under this subsection.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id42447f3edc5f4ca9bee92b73fd9f3fa7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Information included</header><text>Each report required under paragraph (1) shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="id1595ac2703c3424296ce223d590d00c0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a summary of each crowdsourcing and citizen science project conducted by any Federal agency during the most recently completed 2 fiscal years (for the first report) or since the last report was submitted (for subsequent reports), including a description of the proposed goals of each crowdsourcing and citizen science project;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1a6b166c54ea4d97ab09471db39801ef"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the participation rates, submission levels, number of consents, or any other statistic that might be considered relevant in each crowdsourcing and citizen science project;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcdb28e49a8344ae3998cff96d52c435a"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a description of—</text> <clause id="idBBA1566753C647F1B0CF67F90D03DE51"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the resources (including personnel and funding) that were used in the execution of each crowdsourcing and citizen science project;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id2BD243D10EBA4FAB89DBC6CFDC73115B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the activities for which such resources were used; and</text> </clause><clause id="idC8A93778FA9F46F398C430281B296D18"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>how the obligations and expenditures relating to the project’s execution was allocated among the accounts of the Federal agency;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc41d71d60c91487e9b2f710795a86cdf"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a description of—</text> <clause id="idEDFEA18897B844B38CC4F2FD407199EA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the ways in which each crowdsourcing and citizen science project advanced the mission of the Federal agency;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idBF4D32DEE30E4EE5A75A51FD25FF79AA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the project’s results, including the publications, results, tools, products, or services that the project created;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id33ED0F65AF314342964176CF7B83AA2F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the general methods used to ensure data quality and make the data publicly available; and</text> </clause><clause id="id5464FDBCDDCD418EA0CDF1978DFF071B"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>any savings realized or costs incurred by the Federal Government, whether financial or human resources, as a result of using crowdsourcing or citizen science projects instead of Federal agency resources, as possible;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5bbf8231302e4ac4aea175ec76d3a321"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a summary of the main challenges and barriers that constrained the ability of Federal agencies to conduct crowdsourcing and citizen science projects, including—</text>
 <clause id="id7A44CA039AD34947B409E6E3E63C9A59"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any steps that were taken to address such challenges; and</text> </clause><clause id="id21060DDA26AB4E8EA67FBDDDAAE02FC2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>recommendations for future administrative or legislative action;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbbfd1f5f72de44a1b9475cf561a22564"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a summary of the use of crowdsourcing and citizen science methods by all Federal agencies since the submission of the last report, including interagency and multi-sector partnerships; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4d1c28453d7a4a7c8f3305ad8539ddb4"><enum>(G)</enum><text>any other information that the Director considers relevant.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id80b00592f1e844a8a7da3b1ddb50f8d7"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Savings provisions</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed—</text>
 <paragraph id="id2E6F492CB5584F498F47743D04F84BE7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to affect the authority to conduct crowdsourcing and citizen science authorized by any other provision of law; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id795016990F9C4A02B753B9E529248DF8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to displace Federal Government resources allocated to the Federal agencies that use crowdsourcing or citizen science authorized under this section to carry out a project.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


