<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1997 IS: Prepare, Ready, Equip, and Prevent Areas at Risk of Emergency Wildfires Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-08-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 1997</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150805">August 5, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S266">Mr. Crapo</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to provide for
			 wildfire mitigation grants and financial assistance in certain areas
			 affected by wildfires.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body style="OLC">
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Prepare, Ready, Equip, and Prevent Areas at Risk of Emergency Wildfires Act of 2015</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PREPARE Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="idD2622AA3F7BE494194642ABA05E9E9ED"><enum>2.</enum><header>Wildfire Mitigation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title II of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5131">42 U.S.C. 5131 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 203 the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6F6290055C7646F6BC961F426AB62C48" style="OLC">
				<section id="id233B7374F3854895A22CFCDD9744606A"><enum>203A.</enum><header>Wildfire Mitigation</header>
 <subsection id="id9619DC6F90954C9CB97DF78FD31E7893"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text> <paragraph id="id1AE00840B50B4317BC7EC27EF0EF17D0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id87F9B4AF1EC04193BA94E65037F87E33"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>community wildfire protection plan</term> has the meaning given the term in section 101 of the Healthy Forests Restoration Act of 2003 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/6511">16 U.S.C. 6511</external-xref>);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idDFD3A0DEAF34462AB115B50AEA491218"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>eligible recipient</term> means a State or an Indian tribal government;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id25B2FBC92F994A42BAB6915B2BB54E3C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the term <term>local multi-hazard mitigation plan</term> means a mitigation plan developed by a local government under section 322(b) that addresses wildfire mitigation;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id9F00ABD331424074BC272FE0D7A3977C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the term <term>State mitigation plan</term> means a mitigation plan developed by a State under section 322(c) that addresses wildfire mitigation; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id8F9388CF1D75410CADDD9BA6435ABD5D"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the term <term>tribal mitigation plan</term> means a mitigation plan developed by a tribal government under section 322(b) that addresses wildfire mitigation.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id295CF2D75F214016A474040FBA02AEE9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment of Wildfire Mitigation Grant Program</header><text>The President, acting through the Administrator, shall establish a pilot program to make grants to eligible recipients for wildfire mitigation.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id43728ABFB8174224BFB22D01C75C136C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of Funds</header><text>A grant under this section may be used by an eligible recipient—</text> <paragraph id="idDEF77C23CADD4D1D8E4F78E87D40AA14"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to reduce the hazardous fuel load by reducing the use of fuels that may contribute to catastrophic wildfires in high-risk areas;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id9BA0D5663CC34F89904E0DB24B6D4575"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to invest in personnel and organizations to conduct wildfire mitigation;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id337BDFB66B124583BBC97DCE3535BF39"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to invest in vehicles and other equipment to conduct wildfire mitigation;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id3F56B83452934E21ABB5874104C0B89D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to mitigate against damage from runoff into waterways and floods caused by erosion from wildfires;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idD4BA936B21CB4B9BA0B3A02948FC8C92"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to build essential community collaboration and outline the necessary groundwork systems in anticipation of future fires; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idB61A1925E1B2421CBC4C5D7A9720CD50"><enum>(6)</enum><text>at the discretion of the Governor of a State or the Chief Executive of an Indian tribal government, and in consultation with the Administrator, for any other wildfire mitigation activities in the State or area under the jurisdiction of the Indian tribal government, as applicable, unless otherwise prohibited by law.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id8F76C6A8992A46239208D2DF5BD7BE1E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Eligibility for Assistance</header>
						<paragraph id="idA898E9E01EE9440D90645CB9E091C83B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header>
 <subparagraph id="id891B249006034F809CC1BF9D3535B34A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>An eligible recipient shall be eligible for assistance under this section if the section 420 grant ratio for the eligible recipient is equal to or greater than 125 percent of the population ratio of the eligible recipient.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA608078FFF024A47887545D1464FAC06"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Ratios</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A)—</text> <clause id="id3F131A94BB714CE0A0A50E00C85DF812"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the section 420 grant ratio shall be equal to the quotient of—</text>
 <subclause id="idD3A10FAADB0B4728B4EBA2AA0853A3F8"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the number of declarations for a grant under section 420 received by the eligible recipient during the 10 years prior to the date on which an application for assistance is submitted under this section, divided by</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id2E50C05CCCD24C55B22F418A4C5357BC"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the total number of declarations for a grant under section 420 in the United States during the 10 years prior to the date on which an application for assistance is submitted under this section; and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="id0B2DD37AAAAB4468BD13AB1F4459C62C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the population ratio of the eligible recipient shall be equal to the quotient of—</text> <subclause id="idA66E5F20B8B9422ABF809DEF99287F0A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the population of the State or the area under the jurisdiction of the Indian tribal government, as applicable, based on the most recent data available from the Bureau of the Census on the date on which an application for assistance is submitted under this section, divided by</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id48AE811A93D9445FA1784A348155EEE5"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the population of the United States, based on the most recent data available from the Bureau of the Census on the date on which an application for assistance is submitted under this section.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id230A8F3A0AB44753A6D32532C0DA84AE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The President may waive the requirement of paragraph (1) if an eligible recipient—</text> <subparagraph id="idBF161879F2E2455F96159E6A0B2AE68D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>files a petition for waiver of the requirement of paragraph (1); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB8A41E7B42084B3CA71F067D7026C0C7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>demonstrates that significant environmental changes or shifts in forest health put the eligible recipient at an elevated risk for catastrophic wildfires, as determined by the President.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idE91E316CBABF452784BE4321768F6CEF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Local Assistance</header><text>The Governor of a State may award funds received under this section, to be used solely for the purposes set forth under subsection (c), to—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="idC80876AFEEA948C4BB95500444FD7AC1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any county or municipality in that State with a community wildfire protection plan or a local multi-hazard mitigation plan;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idAE402630AF7E447F91627A468530A30A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any Indian tribal government in that State with a tribal mitigation plan; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="idD20E887FEBCA4D5C97A7DBC00D762DB4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any other entity that is explicitly referenced in and central to, in the determination of the Governor, the design of a community wildfire protection plan or a local multi-hazard mitigation plan.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id725D707532564A65B14812850A9BB92E"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Criteria for Assistance</header><text>In determining whether to award a grant to an eligible recipient under this section, the President shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="id74DCCC4B27324199B32F04DBBB2DC0E5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>give preference to—</text> <subparagraph id="id27C5A88A1D9A4F08BB0DAD7B54236491"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an eligible recipient with a high level of need for assistance based on the best scientific data available;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id99860F2F7BBE4388AE3E9179282D5016"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an eligible recipient that previously received a grant under this section and effectively used the Federal funds for wildfire mitigation activities in the State or area under the jurisdiction of the Indian tribal government, as applicable, as determined by the President; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id27054DD01A154222A867E3F09B841F6C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>consider environmental conditions in a State or an area under the jurisdiction of an Indian tribal government, as applicable, including environmental changes, deteriorating forest health, and overall wildfire risk.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id7E725127C91543E1952760598D9D033A"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Application for Assistance</header>
 <paragraph id="idF3DCBCCB2E8D4A19A4A7C5E417502A5D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To request a grant under this section, an eligible recipient shall submit an application to the Administrator in such form, in such manner, and containing such information as the Administrator may reasonably require.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id6AD4E74175EA44C0B1D440053D99F77F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>In addition to any other requirements that may be specified by the Administrator, an eligible recipient submitting an application for a grant under this section shall demonstrate that—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="idA7AD07E0297541F38FB06ADBDFF8651B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of an eligible recipient that is a State—</text> <clause commented="no" id="id989151B14FC34598AFD4A1FF63111D78"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the State has a State mitigation plan;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="id78391BD6A454431FBDBCF6FD4CC5384A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the State shall provide matching non-Federal funds equal to not less than 25 percent of the amount of Federal funds made available under this subsection;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="idC1D0E3B063DD465AA1664344C3820503"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a county or municipality that may receive funds from the grant has a community wildfire protection plan or a local multi-hazard mitigation plan; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="id0616F06A5D534E9EA07B1CE5010F98F2"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>an Indian tribal government that may receive funds from the grant has a tribal mitigation plan; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="idE85EE5C948904BF5AA07132F9037822E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of an eligible recipient that is an Indian tribal government—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="idB157BE8F2D0C4BCD8F686D68672B9C1C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Indian tribal government has a tribal mitigation plan; and</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="id3A5E704A8C8B4552899CF6D750839901"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Indian tribal government shall—</text>
 <subclause commented="no" id="idDDF548DA3A4145BC8DF4BAA2BCC73496"><enum>(I)</enum><text>provide matching non-Federal funds equal to not less than 25 percent of the amount of Federal funds made available under this subsection; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="id4B2C0841CAFB430B94202CE5C6E082F9"><enum>(II)</enum><text>if the Indian tribal government is a small impoverished community, as defined in section 203(a), provide non-matching Federal funds equal to not less than 10 percent of the amount of Federal funds made available under this subsection.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0950C34FE8504254AEEF8889F05621E8"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of receipt of a grant under this section, the recipient shall submit to the Administrator a report, which shall be made publically available, on the use of funds made available under the grant.</text>
					</subsection><subsection id="id5B31F1556978493081A235EC7A9880BA"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Funding for Assistance</header>
 <paragraph id="id8A049C9E66664C00B2ACD12224D33CA8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Predisaster mitigation fund</header><text>Subject to the availability of funds in the National Predisaster Mitigation Fund established under section 203(i), the Administrator shall use not less than $20,000,000 and not more than $30,000,000 from unobligated amounts in the National Predisaster Mitigation Fund for each of fiscal years 2016 through 2021 in carrying out this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idAADEB45F0DB942A19E1A3987A8A5F3BB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to increase the amount of appropriations authorized for the Department of Homeland Security in any given fiscal year.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section><section id="id0CD0F26390434DF1B70645175E4C3069"><enum>3.</enum><header>Wildfire Mitigation Assistance</header>
 <subsection id="id3F4ACDB162FD43B2B9BC8FAF3B7E5B27"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text>Section 420 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5187">42 U.S.C. 5187</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="id69433A8FB00B42EAB1BA15E8903692E4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (d) as subsection (e); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idE55090F28BF64EE0A13A109471061EE1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (c) the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id066169228BB44FB78E1E7E8AFB93EB3D" style="OLC">
						<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id36F3EF1BC35F4A1F9424D7038C4A8B8C"><enum>(d)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Hazard mitigation assistance</header>
 <text>Whether or not a major disaster is declared, the President may provide hazard mitigation assistance in accordance with section 404 in any area affected by a fire for which assistance was provided under this section.</text>
						</subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1D151006BAFF4F9D8574D60723E57247"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming Amendments</header><text>The Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5121">42 U.S.C. 5121 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="id16A5CD3F4AE94896B24F673ED78199BD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 404(a) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5170c">42 U.S.C. 5170c(a)</external-xref>)—</text> <subparagraph id="idD9F786791B0147E291E368F4C18B47B0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting before the first period <term>, or any area in which assistance was provided under section 420</term>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9160503D32A24897B087E251F04CFF72"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the third sentence, by inserting <term>or event under section 420</term> after <term>major disaster</term> each place that term appears; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id4991FF54295243FE9FAD2493117058EB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 322 (e)(1) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5165">42 U.S.C. 5165(e)(1)</external-xref>), by inserting <term>or event under section 420</term> after <term>major disaster</term> each place that term appears.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id441C65F0A7424679B32CDD8978CBD0AF"><enum>4.</enum><header>Factors to consider for major disaster declaration</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall amend subsection (a) of section 206.48 of title 44, Code of Federal Regulations, to require the Federal Emergency Management Agency to consider, in evaluating a Governor's request for major disaster assistance under the Public Assistance Program, whether—</text>
 <paragraph id="id641C3D146B74457D9D950CF6F6B74085"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">post-fire flooding occurred within 5 years, and as a result, of a single wildfire event in the State; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id3F1D68224B824739BD525B67D8F02D90"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the State received fire management assistance under section 420 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5187">42 U.S.C. 5187</external-xref>) related to the major disaster for which the Governor is requesting assistance under the Public Assistance Program.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="id15872E96444846AAAD7529123A067B62"><enum>5.</enum><header>Post-fire funding guide</header>
 <subsection id="id98C0CDE6916743F49CD6EA6D3F192640"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Creation and distribution</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall create and make publically available a post-fire recovery funding and resource guide for local communities.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id63323CD7AF3244DFB663867D4E4D222F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Involvement by local leaders</header><text>The Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall create the guide under subsection (a) in collaboration with local leaders who have experienced wildfires in their communities and who understand the requirements for the use of Federal disaster funds.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id7F542F41C51B4421BBFFBEE6003CF39A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Updates</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall update the guide under subsection (a) as programs and resources change.</text></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


