<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S2109 IS: Directing Dollars to Disaster Relief Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-09-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 2109</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150930">September 30, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S345">Mr. Johnson</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To direct the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency to develop an integrated
			 plan to reduce administrative costs under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster
			 Relief and Emergency Assistance Act, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Directing Dollars to Disaster Relief Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </section><section id="id47d2ab5b49484e2f80a38f3e625ee6b6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act—</text> <paragraph id="id28466783530a4a50998e9e14cf8af2e7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>administrative cost</term> means a cost incurred by the Agency in support of the delivery of disaster assistance for a major disaster;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id16523F1608F649278B94C272139A9F3F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Agency;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id9e073071378a40db86644f90f4fc5ee6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>Agency</term> means the Federal Emergency Management Agency;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id704C5425C84340919C096A0BA62581A0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the term <term>direct administrative cost</term> means a cost incurred by a grantee or subgrantee of a program authorized by the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5121">42 U.S.C. 5121 et seq.</external-xref>) that can be identified separately and assigned to a specific project;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id4E20F9C24C0641008A4C1322CDFAACE9"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the term <term>hazard mitigation program</term> means the hazard mitigation grant program authorized under section 404 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5170c">42 U.S.C. 5170c</external-xref>);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idF92F26C226E4486391DD5060D69EDE34"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the term <term>individual assistance program</term> means the individual assistance grant program authorized under sections 408, 410, 415, 416, 426, and 502(a) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5174">42 U.S.C. 5174</external-xref>, 5177, 5182, 5183, 5189d, and 5192(a));</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id30F9DFDECC1943EDA850B439E0567D3D"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the term <term>major disaster</term> means a major disaster declared by the President under section 401 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5170">42 U.S.C. 5170</external-xref>);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id12B11B3856C9473F92D86E38E0196240"><enum>(8)</enum><text>the term <term>mission assignment</term> has the meaning given the term in section 641 of the Post-Katrina Emergency Management Reform Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/741">6 U.S.C. 741</external-xref>); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idF558075C501D429E808329B73F94DA1E"><enum>(9)</enum><text>the term <term>public assistance program</term> means the public assistance grant program authorized under sections 403(a)(3), 406, 418, 419, 428, and 502(a) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5170b">42 U.S.C. 5170b(a)(3)</external-xref>, 5172, 5185, 5186, 5189f, and 5192(a)).</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="id2B4C502627AD4AD69ED31282AE3B91DD"><enum>3.</enum><header>Integrated plan for administrative cost reduction</header>
 <subsection id="id071EF6CC61774AC8A44FAF5F52AB5422"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 365 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall—</text> <paragraph id="id5C97A4DF1EDE4BB8971190B00EEA7937"><enum>(1)</enum><text>develop and implement an integrated plan to control and reduce administrative costs for major disasters, which shall include—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id653941C9C62C4EE2BE6CD99F1EEBA77F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>steps the Agency will take to reduce administrative costs;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8D6C4DB6A901416586D4AD35E8C04CC7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>milestones needed for accomplishing the reduction of administrative costs;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2064C59C6CAE4BB89E345D8779EF0926"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the assignment of clear roles and responsibilities, including the designation of officials responsible for monitoring and measuring performance; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB99C1209749946E380B55CB6B184AA97"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a timetable for implementation;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id17A76B9E61D443FBAE31CDF54B24B3DD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>compare the costs and benefits of tracking the administrative cost data for major disasters by the public assistance, individual assistance, hazard mitigation, and mission assignment programs, and if feasible, track this information; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idE766E947DEE341F3B94484B7F1A7893E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>clarify Agency guidance and minimum documentation requirements for a direct administrative cost claimed by a grantee or subgrantee of a public assistance grant program.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id8BC8E76241D6494B8741EEFC43A76F6F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Congressional update</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall brief the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives on the plan required to be developed under subsection (a)(1).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id2BD288F215C148D38E7BB8430947A356"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Updates</header><text>If the Administrator modifies the plan or the timetable under subsection (a), the Administrator shall submit to Congress a report notifying Congress of the modification, which shall include the details of the modification.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="id795B87AF935F44E6B2238A7326FAB2BA"><enum>4.</enum><header>Limitations  for administrative costs</header>
 <subsection id="id78FF294DFDC240B38F7FE077A9D19020"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (b), of the total amount obligated for major disasters by the Agency from the Disaster Relief Fund for a fiscal year, the amount obligated for administrative costs shall not exceed the milestones set by the Agency in the plan developed under section 3(a)(1).</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="id56160DBDEEF2414D8CC798396E202E69"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Waiver</header>
 <paragraph id="id05E7FFA6D9584BC08D20B09DDA395E14"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator may waive a requirement described in subsection (a) if the Administrator—</text> <subparagraph id="idDC794ECEC3FF4C59AB447B37B9085A3B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has completed an assessment described in paragraph (3); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id576B59ED50C5423A9F129BB2E4CB9377"><enum>(B)</enum><text>submits to the appropriate committees of Congress a written explanation as to why the Agency exceeded the milestones set by the Agency in the plan developed under section 3(a)(1) for administrative costs of major disasters for the specified fiscal year.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idFA32C44890E848538F0EFFCC211F30A2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date on which the Administrator submits the written explanation to Congress under paragraph (1), the Administrator shall make the explanation publicly available on the website of the Agency.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id79A45B85D3B64AB1A34E76080D219E2F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Assessment</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the last day of a fiscal year, the Administrator shall conduct an assessment of the administrative costs of major disasters for the fiscal year in order to determine whether a waiver is needed under this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


