<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S714 IS: Frontline Mental Health Provider Training Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 714</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150311">March 11, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S356">Mr. Donnelly</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S343">Mr. Boozman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSVA00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To require the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to jointly conduct a
			 pilot program to assess the feasibility and advisability of expanding the
			 use by the Department of Defense and the Department of Veterans Affairs of
			 physician assistants specializing in psychiatric medicine, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Frontline Mental Health Provider Training Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id88B2DCDC14A1465DB584B5EF92686E80"><enum>2.</enum><header>Pilot program on expansion of use of physician assistants to provide mental health care to members
			 of the Armed Forces and veterans</header>
 <subsection id="id4c3897bcce364374a167c49082fe961d"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Pilot program</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (in this section referred to as the <quote>Secretaries</quote>) shall jointly commence the conduct of a pilot program to assess the feasibility and advisability of expanding the use by the Department of Defense and the Department of Veterans Affairs of physician assistants specializing in psychiatric medicine at medical facilities of the Department of Defense and the Department of Veterans Affairs in order to meet the increasing demand for mental health care providers at such facilities through the use of an 18-month psychiatry fellowship program for physician assistants.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="id0808e311d6a54ceca7ddf0a81539539a"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Locations</header>
 <paragraph id="id342F2D8C86DF4ED2BA018078301416EB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Department of Defense</header><text>The Secretary of Defense shall carry out the pilot program at not less than three military medical treatment facilities, of which—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id4B7A7EC83FBC4539B28341E00B7A3A8B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not less than one shall be a military medical treatment facility under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Army;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id48F41701C6D748B5A38ECDBF348BC370"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not less than one shall be a military medical treatment facility under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Navy; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8AA2BD4EF33D4DF0B9AA8554E3EC70AF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>not less than one shall be a military medical treatment facility under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Air Force.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idEEB688164FB14431B382723E22C7A7BD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Department of Veterans Affairs</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall carry out the pilot program at not less than three medical centers of the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4ba347fe81c34e54ae7ff9e9d8b4e8a0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligible individuals</header>
 <paragraph id="id139F29CD2BFC4453B757CE299A2EC927"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), an individual eligible for participation in the pilot program is an individual who—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id63f34b1c25c34cd9ba74f0c4c62f63a2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has successfully graduated with a masters degree in physician assistant studies from an accredited physician assistant program;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9a3eb297b59147089fb2d49c026aec39"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is certified by the National Commission on Certification of Physician Assistants;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id954A1F0DE92941EC8EA3BBE6CE0D6A77"><enum>(C)</enum><text>has a valid license, certification, and registration necessary to practice medicine; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2daa8fa770774c18b06c84c019d6d570"><enum>(D)</enum><text>does not have any pending challenge, investigation, revocation, restriction, disciplinary action, suspension, reprimand, probation, denial, or withdrawal with respect to any license, certification, or registration described in subparagraph (C).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id07EE5EC665CE4E5BA0631607F808E141"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Department of Defense</header><text>With respect to the conduct of the pilot program at a military medical treatment facility, an individual eligible for participation in the pilot program is an individual who—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id633EAC7ED04D44E3A7D8B160DEEBC368"><enum>(A)</enum><text>qualifies as an eligible individual under paragraph (1);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id21078e75cafd41d68c7ae0a93abd2575"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is a commissioned officer in the Armed Forces; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id74A2FCC8AE1E44E984B83C5BBB177246"><enum>(C)</enum><text>meets the requirements necessary to be deployed as such an officer throughout the world.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id20d795153a4540df8e2a2c6e8d0b1ddf"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Selection of individuals</header> <paragraph id="id1CA26EA7575D4D44B66249FA9DB5418B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each of the Secretaries shall select not less than 12 individuals described in subsection (c) to participate in the pilot program for each 18-month psychiatry fellowship program carried out under subsection (e).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idEA84068A89AD47F08F9AA16C575865A9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Distribution</header><text>Each of the Secretaries shall equally distribute the individuals selected under paragraph (1) among the locations at which the pilot program is to be carried out by such Secretary.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idAA69314A9BC54BA18F2D68C409866B3C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Psychiatry fellowship program</header>
 <paragraph id="idEFA5F6DBAE1E4F3F8501268493EE3887"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In carrying out the pilot program, the Secretaries shall establish an 18-month psychiatry fellowship program for physician assistants that meets the training model for acuity, mixture, and volume established for psychiatric residency programs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id1594d54ccc0e4f7baa751cc7eeac8145"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Training and education</header><text>The psychiatric fellowship program established under paragraph (1) shall provide to eligible individuals who are selected for the program the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="idB35A8FB8D67746D98078DFBE9940E312"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Training that is equivalent to training received during a psychiatric residency with respect to guidelines, objectives, and milestones.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idCBC01AD91F2641CB9929F02AFCB22504"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Education leading to a clinical doctorate of science in psychiatry that addresses the following:</text> <clause id="idECBB0B81A4D84E8C8D8C89067EA030CA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Inpatient care.</text>
 </clause><clause id="idE73B2DB3F72D48B9BAFE526EC5A23750"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Outpatient care.</text> </clause><clause id="id1FA4BDDB64FE496F925D2D83DED36A68"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Emergency psychiatry.</text>
 </clause><clause id="idB5D5411E8E92475CB7FDA9C7C0B70310"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Neurology, including child, adolescent, and geriatric neurology.</text> </clause><clause id="idA444E55B7DF14E9A9E22123DCCEBAD1B"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Pain management.</text>
 </clause><clause id="id4585FDADDF4C479B923ECB302E0E5075"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Addictive psychiatry.</text> </clause><clause id="idAEC1FC35A40E43909FB3EF9962720FDC"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>Psycho-pharmacology.</text>
 </clause><clause id="id458C8013F9C042CFB1701DFBC6EF6E2F"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>Traumatic brain injury.</text> </clause><clause id="id455C5FA5B9CF4834B519F27B5498D094"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>Clinical practice guidelines.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC09DF0F32E994E9699A2037E3512637F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Education that addresses the particular needs of rural and other underserved populations of members of the Armed Forces and veterans to ensure a particular approach to psychiatry that benefits those individuals.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id02ba0f9299854a15a3533b6642f50a83"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Use of other programs</header><text>In carrying out the psychiatric fellowship program under paragraph (1), the Secretaries shall use resources available to the Secretaries under existing graduate medical education programs of the Department of Defense and the Department of Veterans Affairs to the greatest extent possible.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idbec4dbf7728041fb9aaedbca1bed7780"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reports on pilot program</header>
				<paragraph id="idabc567f750154a769220caf89e7a854b"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial report</header>
 <subparagraph id="id87BD3C0B98284244B65A447B684D835A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than two years after the date on which the pilot program commences under subsection (a), the Secretaries shall jointly submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on the pilot program.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id70299A2FFC3341B09112FE07618D55C2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report required by subparagraph (A) shall include the following:</text> <clause id="id1b04d46853434a3b8467861c6c097d59"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A description of the implementation of the pilot program at each location of the pilot program, including a detailed description of the education and training provided under the pilot program at such location.</text>
 </clause><clause id="ida7667305784b47218b19a3639e546ca5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A description and explanation of differences, if any, in the implementation and performance of the pilot program among the locations of the pilot program.</text>
 </clause><clause id="id80acafa4ee2547f280148f9aab7eeddb"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>An assessment of the satisfaction of members of the Armed Forces and veterans with mental health care provided under the pilot program, including an assessment of the outcomes of such care.</text>
 </clause><clause id="id9655b3391e124d63852036aa6093cecf"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>An assessment of cost savings, if any, to the Federal Government resulting from the pilot program.</text> </clause><clause id="id6E83A71B41534F2C9CCEB9B88D09CA65"><enum>(v)</enum><text>A description of improvements, if any, to the access of members of the Armed Forces and veterans to mental health care resulting from the pilot program.</text>
 </clause><clause id="idb7a52673f6e3453fac12b764221b6af5"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>A description of recommendations, if any, of the Secretaries of alternative methods to improve the access of members of the Armed Forces and veterans to mental health care other than through the pilot program.</text>
 </clause><clause id="idf442fecaf70440ec98f56a860a8e7a6c"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>A recommendation as to the feasibility and advisability of extending or expanding the pilot program.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5d5d40b5e2c74f669f040c3892e9db58"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Final report</header><text>Not later than 90 days before the date on which the pilot program terminates under subsection (g), the Secretaries shall jointly submit to the appropriate committees of Congress an update to the report submitted under paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idacdd96051ce84871b4c4620dc4abf229"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of congress defined</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="id4a2bdccc6c74458aa0af59062c9d54c7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2ec240db4bf04032a4372d0f036ae979"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1cafc4349f85453b80dd693376e7a8c6"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The authority of the Secretaries to carry out the pilot program shall terminate upon the completion of two 18-month psychiatry fellowship programs conducted under subsection (e).</text></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


