<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1210 IS: Oil and Gas Production and Distribution Reform Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 1210</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150506">May 6, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S372">Mrs. Capito</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S373">Mr. Cassidy</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S360">Ms. Heitkamp</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To provide for the timely consideration of all licenses, permits, and approvals required under
			 Federal law with respect to oil and gas production and distribution. </official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Oil and Gas Production and Distribution Reform Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="id069F2996EA39496A92A3469FA1BF18CA"><enum>2.</enum><header>FERC process coordination with respect to regulatory approval of oil and gas projects</header>
			<subsection id="idFA2D03BBCB7D4ECA99498EC4AA7161C1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header>
 <text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="idA0B5B2023DA64F2C909F35F0C2E06447"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agency</header><text>The term <term>agency</term> means a Federal or State agency or unit of local government identified under subsection (b).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id85E815AB62554F1BB2F7A9A593D86395"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idDF6A636AE76047DB97C972359BFA1532"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Federal authorization</header> <subparagraph commented="no" id="id4D23B353D8F3497686D006FD5C9E6284"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>Federal authorization</term> means any authorization required under Federal law with respect to an application for authorization or a certificate of public convenience and necessity relating to oil and gas production and distribution.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id3B106B598AEF4E69BA369C4BEE078502"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text>The term <term>Federal authorization</term> includes any permits, special use authorizations, certifications, opinions, or other approvals as may be required under Federal law with respect to an application for authorization or a certificate of public convenience and necessity relating to oil and gas production and distribution.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0E2C8043DC5C4272A9113FAD40992442"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Identification</header><text>As soon as practicable after an application for Federal authorization is submitted, the Commission shall identify each Federal or State agency or unit of local government that may consider an aspect of that application.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="id0b934a0321fc4fdd82b236942ec3194a"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Invitation</header>
 <paragraph id="idd4b8dba20bdd42ad87f50afa41f1eebc"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission shall invite each agency identified under subsection (b) to cooperate or participate in the review process for the application.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id25c4b2e06e6e4a9c9b084fd7fa9d0a9e"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text>An invitation issued under paragraph (1) shall establish a deadline by which a response to the invitation shall be submitted, which may be extended by the Commission for good cause.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id09D927C5EC064EC58FE6876EE3269B32"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Deadline for Federal authorization</header><text>Each agency delegated the authority to review an aspect of the application under subsection (c)(1) shall make a final decision on the aspect of the Federal authorization under consideration by that agency by not later than 90 days after the date on which the Commission issues the final environmental document of the Commission, unless a different schedule is otherwise established by Federal law.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id43f34120b0234513b78b63b6fe6631ac"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Deference to Commission</header><text>In making a decision with respect to a Federal authorization, each agency shall give deference, to the maximum extent authorized by law, to the scope of environmental review that the Commission determines to be appropriate.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idc8f89e36b9d4414abdb37eb8f3eac20b"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Concurrent Reviews</header><text>Each agency considering an aspect of an application for Federal authorization shall—</text> <paragraph id="id91d44d7365014de09f703c61019645a0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>carry out the obligations of that agency under applicable law concurrently and in conjunction with the review required by the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>), unless doing so would impair the ability of the agency to conduct needed analysis or otherwise carry out those obligations;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idcff17417c44b4a529444a0c6c693c80c"><enum>(2)</enum><text>formulate and implement administrative, policy, and procedural mechanisms to enable the agency to complete the required Federal authorizations by the deadline described in subsection (d); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id74f5ccfc4e0e4f84b92e2fe9b725377d"><enum>(3)</enum><text>transmit to the Commission a statement—</text> <subparagraph id="idaa4f3cf0b2174889a5434f5d3150fee3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>acknowledging notice of the deadline under subsection (d); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1795e6449e4b4f4287adf11582a849ac"><enum>(B)</enum><text>describing the plan formulated under paragraph (2).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id805c7e7e629f481589d57f43870f8054"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Issue Identification and Resolution</header> <paragraph id="idcb4586d350194996bbcce7c2c8616ed9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Identification</header><text>Each agency considering an aspect of an application for Federal authorization shall identify, as soon as practicable, any issues of concern that may delay or prevent the agency from granting the authorization.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="id57192f515ae14171b30e7918def00256"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Issue Resolution Meeting</header>
 <subparagraph id="idb88b964e0eaa46a5874ac08e368c744a"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>On request of an agency or applicant, the Commission shall convene a meeting with the relevant agencies and the applicant to resolve any issues that may—</text>
 <clause id="ided94f527b96a4709ac2151ca73a9425e"><enum>(i)</enum><text>delay completion of the environmental review document; or</text> </clause><clause id="idda3412c5cf7c4f8b8951f79efcf0490b"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>result in the denial of any Federal authorization.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6b0c48900f1247309f884882096a9a72"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Meeting Date</header><text>A meeting requested under subparagraph (A) shall be held not later than 21 days after the date on which the Commission receives the request for the meeting, unless the Commission determines that there is good cause to extend the deadline.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id01aefe61ab0540b3b265f1b40ac43c2a"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Notification</header><text>On receipt of a request for a meeting under subparagraph (A), the Commission shall notify all relevant agencies of—</text>
 <clause id="idB13E93BF17744DE9BF3918B679CB1F33"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the request for the meeting;</text> </clause><clause id="idB373728069B84F98A26246DE9DF262DB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the nature of the issue to be resolved; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id91A6C00C150547C5BED78406F89BE753"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the date for the meeting.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id583b8454fa8e4fd09c70353c3fa53cf6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Elevation of Issue Resolution</header> <subparagraph id="id98BA339ADCB34999B4EED390D705892F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the issue is not resolved within 30 days after a meeting under this paragraph, the Commission shall forward for resolution the dispute to the heads of the relevant agencies.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idDF7EA5AC43F0401BA59784BB1E4819D1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusion</header><text>In the case of a failure to achieve resolution by a State agency or unit of local government, the Commission shall forward for resolution the dispute to the head of the Federal agency overseeing the delegated authority.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id68804F79CA86481B9CCD650959C2444E"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Failure To meet deadline</header><text>If an agency does not complete a proceeding for an approval that is required for a Federal authorization by the deadline described in subsection (d), the head of the relevant Federal agency (including, in the case of a failure by the State agency or unit of local government, the Federal agency overseeing the delegated authority) shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="id35AA8A88BA58484F836844A90A12B4E7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>notify Congress and the Commission of the failure; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id330DDF21BCCD4BA7B41A70484334F29F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>describe in that notification an implementation plan to ensure completion.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idb106d822dc54480c8298eac5405bdc4d"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Application Processing</header><text>The Commission may allow an applicant seeking Federal authorization to fund a third-party contractor or Commission staff to assist the Commission in reviewing the application.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="id6ddd94c1527a48478a04c1eb2887e474"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Accountability; transparency; efficiency</header>
 <paragraph id="idFE9561E6018242AC9A82CB63022E7124"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For applications requiring multiple Federal authorizations, the Commission, in consultation with any agency considering an aspect of the application, shall track and make available to the public on the website of the Commission information relating to the actions required to complete permitting, reviews, and other requirements.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idCD0E15FD02944BBCB5C76A3E7C3CD7B6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text>Information tracked under paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text> <subparagraph id="id51e81591a1ce4b3c9c3e17a76d12870a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The deadline described in subsection (d).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idee0f8badd1ae446fabad28b77a3a6976"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A list of all the actions required by each applicable agency to complete permitting, reviews, and other requirements necessary to obtain a final decision on the Federal authorization.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9feaf51b499d417fa7470480d6904aad"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The expected completion date for each action listed under subparagraph (B).</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide65a208aa11447d1a09d1c2c60e9f664"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A point of contact at the agency accountable for each action listed under subparagraph (B).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9008f57fcec34cd2b5a1124cb313d003"><enum>(E)</enum><text>In the event that an action is still pending as of the expected date of completion, a brief explanation of the reason for the delay.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


