<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1450 IS: Department of Veterans Affairs Emergency Medical Staffing Recruitment and Retention Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 1450</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150521">May 21, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSVA00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend title 38, United States Code, to allow the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to modify the
			 hours of employment of physicians and physician assistants employed on a
			 full-time basis by the Department of Veterans Affairs.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
 <section id="id0D7127D286804EB19436E117E5462C02" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Department of Veterans Affairs Emergency Medical Staffing Recruitment and Retention Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="idAC4ADDDFDA934CE18CC9285F97457C0D" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Modification of hours of employment for physicians and physician assistants employed by the Department of Veterans Affairs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 7423(a) of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="id5EDF0B81E2DE4770AD869EA7F63D7421"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(a) The hours</quote> and inserting <quote>(a)(1) Except as provided in paragraph (2), the hours</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id4CBC2D7F02A947CA929A34C92DA08382"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idC1C660413A6048CA868AE141A8B88DA5" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="id087D501AD2CE4C6FBA3C3FF0924FAD93" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Secretary may modify the hours of employment for a physician or physician assistant appointed in the Administration under any provision of this chapter on a full-time basis to be more than or less than 80 hours in a biweekly pay period if the total hours of employment for such employee in a calendar year does not exceed 2,080 hours.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body>
</bill>


