<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S2233 IS: To amend section 3716 of title 31, United States Code, to reestablish the period of limitations for claims of the United States that may be collected by garnishing payments received from the Government. </dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-11-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 2233</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151103">November 3, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S299">Mr. Vitter</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend section 3716 of title 31, United States Code, to reestablish the period of limitations for
			 claims of the United States that may be collected by garnishing payments
			 received from the Government. </official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="id7C40416EDDCB4D91B41B87F8E6BC56F0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Period of limitations for garnishment</header>
 <subsection id="id3B853BE458944C4ABC0BD613330E0650"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3716(e)(1) of title 31, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>no limitation on the period within which an offset may be initiated or taken pursuant to this section shall be effective</quote> and inserting <quote>this section shall not apply to a claim under this subchapter that has been outstanding for more than 10 years</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idF026F54E0F71457087D89E7A5480B606"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>The amendment made by this section shall apply to claims under subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/37">chapter 37</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code, arising before, on, or after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


