<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S523 IS: To coordinate the provision of energy retrofitting assistance to schools.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 523</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150212">February 12, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S252">Ms. Collins</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S327">Mr. Warner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S340">Ms. Ayotte</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To coordinate the provision of energy retrofitting assistance to schools.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="id3CDE1411636745AEA4980D0FA7DA6C2E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Coordination of energy retrofitting assistance for schools</header>
 <subsection id="id000c4eaa5cc64a4aa951d0e7845ab138"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="id995624D7715E41A6B5AE97DC310FFECE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>School</header><text>The term <term>school</term> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id52c9c7e410474595bd78b1911a7607fc"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an elementary school or secondary school (as defined in section 9101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>));</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idec1d3345b5134ff098b74184bc7c8e30"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an institution of higher education (as defined in section 102(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1002">20 U.S.C. 1002(a)</external-xref>);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd3ee7b4cbedf432db94e6800b1ba7410"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a school of the defense dependents' education system under the Defense Dependents' Education Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/921">20 U.S.C. 921 et seq.</external-xref>) or established under section 2164 of title 10, United States Code;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3e685fc40eb740bcb6a45551bea6e734"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a school operated by the Bureau of Indian Affairs;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida1507c7f424548d98de23afe7c2f25e2"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a tribally controlled school (as defined in section 5212 of the Tribally Controlled Schools Act of 1988 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/2511">25 U.S.C. 2511</external-xref>)); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2436a61558ed44ffa63118844ec9dd67"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a Tribal College or University (as defined in section 316(b) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1059c">20 U.S.C. 1059c(b)</external-xref>)).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idD623B05699CF4CD58F30189755B1F29B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Energy.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id647733762e2b40cfba2d5a6f142fe873"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Designation of lead agency</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Office of Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy, shall act as the lead Federal agency for coordinating and disseminating information on existing Federal programs and assistance that may be used to help initiate, develop, and finance energy efficiency, renewable energy, and energy retrofitting projects for schools.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id5c80573f3d024fd1a84976e26040675d"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>In carrying out coordination and outreach under subsection (b), the Secretary shall—</text> <paragraph id="id299815db88cc4b10a8dfb019ef571969"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in consultation and coordination with the appropriate Federal agencies, carry out a review of existing programs and financing mechanisms (including revolving loan funds and loan guarantees) available in or from the Department of Agriculture, the Department of Energy, the Department of Education, the Department of the Treasury, the Internal Revenue Service, the Environmental Protection Agency, and other appropriate Federal agencies with jurisdiction over energy financing and facilitation that are currently used or may be used to help initiate, develop, and finance energy efficiency, renewable energy, and energy retrofitting projects for schools;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id41d3556017e34d6f8920e0b1e45e9045"><enum>(2)</enum><text>establish a Federal cross-departmental collaborative coordination, education, and outreach effort to streamline communication and promote available Federal opportunities and assistance described in paragraph (1) for energy efficiency, renewable energy, and energy retrofitting projects that enables States, local educational agencies, and schools—</text>
 <subparagraph id="iddd152b2fcdcb4524a25dc1ff5d8ce644"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to use existing Federal opportunities more effectively; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9b72ea41b5444a6daaa00b0ea33884a6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to form partnerships with Governors, State energy programs, local educational, financial, and energy officials, State and local government officials, nonprofit organizations, and other appropriate entities to support the initiation of the projects;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1daa419469394a1e8fbc3cf3e1450764"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provide technical assistance for States, local educational agencies, and schools to help develop and finance energy efficiency, renewable energy, and energy retrofitting projects—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id9e54dbc225a34e669a1b86387b55b66d"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to increase the energy efficiency of buildings or facilities;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8aaef1601bfc41af90762fa46ea3ccfd"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to install systems that individually generate energy from renewable energy resources;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc5ae89b5583b4f37a9d9bc3f690be8bf"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to establish partnerships to leverage economies of scale and additional financing mechanisms available to larger clean energy initiatives; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3ec6393e9c9e436f8f5aa751128de89a"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to promote—</text> <clause id="idb7f66c380e54470d9b2bcaeddc060fb9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the maintenance of health, environmental quality, and safety in schools, including the ambient air quality, through energy efficiency, renewable energy, and energy retrofit projects; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id57353ea8acf3496c9b998295a27a3583"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the achievement of expected energy savings and renewable energy production through proper operations and maintenance practices;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id584fdccffe24497d9e664ac1135983c1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>develop and maintain a single online resource website with contact information for relevant technical assistance and support staff in the Office of Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy for States, local educational agencies, and schools to effectively access and use Federal opportunities and assistance described in paragraph (1) to develop energy efficiency, renewable energy, and energy retrofitting projects; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id30f06e8066ce4295b812cce258cfa4fa"><enum>(5)</enum><text>establish a process for recognition of schools that—</text> <subparagraph id="id85e59b8d995b4f37b436311bad86f5e3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>have successfully implemented energy efficiency, renewable energy, and energy retrofitting projects; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id896950171d7d4ca5a673b1880473a68a"><enum>(B)</enum><text>are willing to serve as resources for other local educational agencies and schools to assist initiation of similar efforts.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id23e7393cdaf244da867f6df49fd351b9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report describing the implementation of this section.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


