<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1710 IS: AmeriCorps School Turnaround Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 1710</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150707">July 7, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S307">Mr. Brown</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S309">Mr. Casey</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To authorize a grant-matching program that strengthens and accelerates interventions in the
			 lowest-performing elementary schools and secondary schools.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>AmeriCorps School Turnaround Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="id75112ac35aab4bbbb54943b52cb82ba4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings and purposes</header>
 <subsection id="id4332e1e8b93c4705bcf0152d5b947b95"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph id="id294506533d6049f8a5f356fc46ccdf52"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Students are most successful when they have personal, attentive support.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id697215731c604c7ab6575d24c9b298d4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Turning schools around requires collaboration among teachers, administrators, counselors, business leaders, the philanthropic sector, and community members.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idbcfe80aced954e35aaec0221db0b142d"><enum>(3)</enum><text>National service provides valuable support to elementary schools and secondary schools and has a record for improving student academic achievement.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idd7df5fc30f6d4e4898463c45908bfde3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of this Act are to—</text> <paragraph id="id8cea29884a7d4e7a9ff2edf7c50b1b38"><enum>(1)</enum><text>strengthen and accelerate interventions in the lowest-performing elementary schools and secondary schools;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idc449d94b86624df49290e57197604bd0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide financial support to eligible entities that serve low-performing schools;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idf24d62abaf8d402c966f3c9d1f7eb528"><enum>(3)</enum><text>significantly improve outcomes for students in persistently low-performing schools by—</text> <subparagraph id="idc2373ee6a0a548ba9e6d7f7778afb770"><enum>(A)</enum><text>providing opportunities for academic enrichment;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcb244a21ab22475e8c3f706799215c65"><enum>(B)</enum><text>extending learning time; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idaa9ac513a5944b15bdce5d9e0a4a690c"><enum>(C)</enum><text>providing individual support for students; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id2c60a5856fd74192a53d35080f4e41fa"><enum>(4)</enum><text>improve high school graduation rates and college readiness for the most disadvantaged students.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id39306246dbf448c7bc0699441c06d914"><enum>3.</enum><header>School turnaround program</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
 <paragraph id="id9c7752ebb0b647c88f5915a22b67c363"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Chief executive officer</header><text>The term <term>Chief Executive Officer</term> means the Chief Executive Officer of the Corporation for National and Community Service appointed under section 193 of the National and Community Service Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12651c">42 U.S.C. 12651c</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idE5CC89D4134247C999A45EF6FC67762B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="id8D20DF1599C14B9CA2EF3ECD54D459E2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an elementary school or secondary school; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id46CE3A972D0E43A5B15B5A2E250249A2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any of the following entities that serve low-performing schools:</text> <clause id="idD1BCC6799C4443358427811D7E598EF4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Public or private nonprofit organizations, including faith-based and other community organizations.</text>
 </clause><clause id="idCCA79B4CE5B1475B88BB2AA9EBA4C8C2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Local educational agencies.</text> </clause><clause id="id83EA056FEE8845A4B4EEE5B37442F5CB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Institutions of higher education.</text>
 </clause><clause id="id7C9636021F814F5C962E39F3601033FB"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Government entities within States.</text> </clause><clause id="idDDD6EBF987EB45829006160B28B82943"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Indian Tribes.</text>
 </clause><clause id="id02911AAF01164C068B37285D31DEB8C8"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Labor organizations.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id137bf042d8104643b9d99e6981ab0710"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Low-performing school</header><text>The term <term>low-performing school</term> means an elementary school or secondary school that is identified under section 1116 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6316">20 U.S.C. 6316</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id4B2F1D9FE54B414CBA2C1010731A2DC6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>National service participant</header><text>The term <term>national service participant</term> means an individual described under part III of the National and Community Service Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12591">42 U.S.C. 12591 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idBB1BAE1817AB424B836F487D87F3DA48"><enum>(5)</enum><header>School Turnaround Corps project</header><text>The term <term>School Turnaround Corps project</term> means a project carried out by an eligible entity that is a permissible use of funds for a grant under this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id19259a396ff6499994b3074a36e06a24"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Education.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="id7B07DC78BCD6443786CF209F85BE7FD2"><enum>4.</enum><header>Interagency agreement for school turnaround grants</header> <subsection id="idd608ac461ce0487cbfa7c56de8950f71"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Interagency agreement</header> <paragraph id="id21DA99D64BA9453C868BA19EEF62945C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In General</header><text>The Chief Executive Officer shall enter into an interagency agreement with the Secretary similar to an interagency agreement described in section 121(b)(1) of the National and Community Service Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12571">42 U.S.C. 12571(b)(1)</external-xref>) regarding the grant program described in section 5, except that funds appropriated under this Act may be used as if for the purposes for which funds may be provided through grants under section 121(a) of the National and Community Service Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12571">42 U.S.C. 12571(a)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id43D6FFD282164B28A2819348DA5835F1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Amendment to the NCSA</header><text>Section 121(b) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12571">42 U.S.C. 12571(b)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id115D123C00E74D40B9789CD44B99C05E" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="id37FE1BF374284A4E85D54F79F06E5A73"><enum>(6)</enum><header>School turnaround grant interagency agreement</header><text>Notwithstanding paragraph (1), the Corporation shall enter into an interagency agreement similar to an interagency agreement described in paragraph (1) with the Secretary of Education under this subsection regarding the school turnaround grant program described in section 5 of the <short-title>AmeriCorps School Turnaround Act of 2015</short-title>.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5CF0C63982044BB89A640763872BF0B9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Approved National Service Positions</header>
 <paragraph id="id0699E944B3A14C13993278574F4C42DC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Chief Executive Officer shall approve positions for School Turnaround Corps projects as approved national service positions in accordance with subtitle C of title I of the National and Community Service Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12571">42 U.S.C. 12571 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idE76AF459DC2E4EE9B78CC6E31821C9D9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Distribution of assistance and approved positions unaffected</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to affect the distribution of assistance or approved national service positions under section 129 of the National and Community Service Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12581">42 U.S.C. 12581</external-xref>).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idE0BAC1294A0B44A6AFE4EB24A6ABAC8E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Treatment of funds appropriated</header>
 <paragraph id="id591C3BABD5274C6DA8FBF455A3C736AA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>National service trust</header><text>For purposes of section 145(a)(1) of the National and Community Service Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12601">42 U.S.C. 12601(a)(1)</external-xref>), a portion of the funds appropriated under this Act, as determined by the Chief Executive Officer based on the number of participants selected for School Turnaround Corps projects, shall be treated as funds made available to carry out subtitle D of title I of the National and Community Service Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12601">42 U.S.C. 12601 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id650AE5C2F3DF4F5AB0EB31CC9E5E83AB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Investment of trust funds</header><text>For purposes of subsection (b) of section 145 of the National and Community Service Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12601">42 U.S.C. 12601</external-xref>), a portion of the funds appropriated under this Act, as determined by the Chief Executive Officer based on the number of participants selected for School Turnaround Corps projects, shall be treated as if appropriated to the Trust established under such section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idD764132946EB45148C062822AB967317"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reserve account</header><text>For purposes of section 149(b)(1)(B)(ii) of the National and Community Service Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12606">42 U.S.C. 12606(b)(1)(B)(ii)</external-xref>), a portion of the funds appropriated under this Act, as determined by the Chief Executive Officer based on the number of participants selected for School Turnaround Corps projects, shall be treated as funds appropriated for the fiscal year involved under section 501 of the National and Community Service Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12681">42 U.S.C. 12681</external-xref>) and made available to carry out subtitle C or D of title I of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12571">42 U.S.C. 12571 et seq.</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12601">42 U.S.C. 12601 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id5FC8566F8B0B408ABE28875861EF98D2"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Audits</header><text>For purposes of section 149(c) of the National and Community Service Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12606">42 U.S.C. 12606(c)</external-xref>), funds appropriated under this Act shall be treated as appropriated funds for approved national service positions.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idBB9F1F6824B34E5FA2EAD00335E5957F"><enum>5.</enum><header>School turnaround grant program</header>
 <subsection id="idB57B2334FE48471AAEBBB4D6B15AF6CA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text>From amounts made available under this Act after the reservation described in subsection (b), the Chief Executive Officer, in consultation with the Secretary, shall award grants, on a competitive basis, to eligible entities to enable such eligible entities—</text>
 <paragraph id="idC4E89FD492D54ADFA7ED6F6CC7F132FB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to improve the academic achievement of elementary school and secondary school students; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idC9175C83FFF24327B6293BCDC1243A6B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to select national service participants and engage such participants' in School Turnaround Corps projects.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idd846a4b5e11c47bcae4a9cf625dfcfc7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Amounts reserved</header><text>The Chief Executive Officer shall reserve not less than 1 percent, and not more than 2 percent, of the amount appropriated to carry out this Act for each fiscal year to award grants under this Act to Indian tribes and organizations serving tribal populations.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idC2741E7C404A4B49909310FA12F2F6FD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In making grants under this Act, the Chief Executive Officer, in consultation with the Secretary—</text>
 <paragraph id="idf3fa8483eb6f4cd2b261d18cf4cbd299"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall give priority to eligible entities that will serve significant populations of low-income students; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ida983ebe250d648a69dd0195787658a2e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may give priority to eligible entities that—</text> <subparagraph id="ide395fda1e9c849de9898156a5759740f"><enum>(A)</enum><text>are located in low-income communities;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8d2645658b754bd3ba149152f8256bb0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>will serve communities with significant populations of families with limited English proficiency;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb6b98218388b4690a733056b91953598"><enum>(C)</enum><text>will place national service participants in urban or rural areas; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id27293198175b4c4bbd96a5c3a997e844"><enum>(D)</enum><text>will increase the ability of educators to provide appropriate services and coordinate activities with State and local systems providing services under part B of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1411">20 U.S.C. 1411 et seq.</external-xref>) for children with developmental delays or disabilities, including such children in the child welfare system of the State.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id50d9e5a6b65a4af8a212d267be57b513"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Use of funds</header>
 <paragraph id="id16ccda28ca7a472f8d9903eb4fc529e9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An eligible entity that receives a grant under this section shall use the funds made available through the grant to carry out 1 or more of the activities described in paragraphs (2) through (6), and shall engage national service participants to carry out such activities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id9d4931eb5354450e92ad536a1da654b4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Increasing high-quality, individualized learning time</header><text>Improving the quality and frequency of individualized learning time provided to elementary school and secondary school students by providing individualized support, which may include increasing postsecondary education enrollment rates through postsecondary education preparation counseling assistance, including assistance with completing the Free Application for Federal Student Aid (FAFSA) and applications for institutions of higher education, and educating students and their families about financial literacy for postsecondary education.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idec6f5eea7dab48739cf3d613765345cd"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Out-of-school and extended learning programs</header><text>Increasing personalized, out-of-school and extended learning programs provided to elementary school and secondary school students by engaging national service participants to serve as—</text>
 <subparagraph id="ida1b2b548ebdc4454a50d8cb266a1756c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>tutors who provide individualized, academic support outside of the standard school day; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id62977155307c4dab805ea3c194159caa"><enum>(B)</enum><text>family resource mentors who connect the student, family, and school in an open conversation about the student’s academic situation.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ida98115c698404856849a87e91b3857f9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>College and career readiness and graduation coaches</header><text>The provision of individual graduation, postsecondary education, and career preparation guidance and assistance by college or career planing advisors.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id8B49F5E5815B4E5395FEABBB01293C8E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Schoolwide activities</header><text>Carrying out schoolwide activities, including—</text> <subparagraph id="idB1C8521111B0438DB8B5E85044B5848F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>establishing a school culture and environment that improves school safety, attendance, and discipline and addressing other non-academic factors that impact student achievement, such as students’ social, emotional, and health needs; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB9A034B548E94D0BBF45D980D2FB463B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>carrying out activities to increase graduation rates, such as early warning systems, credit-recovery programs, and re-engagement strategies.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id66024B3EFC164345A4AB2B6BBB98FF11"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Accelerating reading and mathematics knowledge and skills</header><text>The provision of activities to accelerate students’ acquisition of reading and mathematics knowledge and skills.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id54b2f8af4de04f59af780bda15556385"><enum>6.</enum><header>Annual report</header>
 <subsection id="id7fe71ee2013a46fe96c12707f5bc74ce"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As a condition on receipt of any funds for a program under this Act, each grantee shall agree to submit an annual report at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Chief Executive Officer, in consultation with the Secretary, may require.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="iddf8ec13f3d914763963344539edeb47c"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Content</header><text>At a minimum, each annual report under this subsection shall describe—</text> <paragraph id="ida8e1bb111ed94fc2934b1b78ad8618b4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the degree to which progress has been made toward meeting the annual benchmarks and long-term goals and objectives described in the grant recipient's application; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="iddd95025087014554b3c278267e38eb7e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>demographic data about low-performing schools, including the number of low-income and minority students, served in each program.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id6a651360c79546b3b90689a92937bc2e"><enum>7.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act $25,000,000 for fiscal year 2016, and such sums as may be necessary for each of the 5 succeeding fiscal years.</text>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


