<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S2311 IS: Bringing Postpartum Depression Out of the Shadows Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-11-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2311</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20151119">November 19, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S352">Mr. Heller</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S331">Mrs. Gillibrand</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S340">Ms. Ayotte</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Public Health Service Act to authorize the Secretary of Health and Human Services,
			 acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services
			 Administration, to make grants to States for screening and treatment for
			 maternal depression.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H8C04D697A00F45B982CF47A778D5A8F0" style="OLC">
 <section id="HDEAD1D6F303448519E2758FF93F4482B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Bringing Postpartum Depression Out of the Shadows Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HDAB2C37A755F499E960F3C0D09FEB648"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds as follows:</text>
 <paragraph id="H7A7EC21620324121947A96CD47B15DED"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Depression is a medical, physiologic illness, and not a sign of weakness or poor parenting.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HAA1F97FD686D4521A1E56AD85E472956"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Maternal depression includes major and minor depressive episodes that occur during pregnancy or in the first 12 months after delivery.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF2772D168E994CCBB10DDA1EC17FEE43"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An estimated 9 to 16 percent of new mothers experience postpartum depression.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4DCE05E461F34145A927B7DB8F87A7B1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Every year, more than 400,000 infants are born to mothers who have depression, which makes perinatal depression the most underdiagnosed obstetric complication in the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA8EA1B2DCA39407B8C76A4207C4D9AB2"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The consequences of maternal depression include poor bonding between mother and infant, which may have negative effects on cognitive development, social-emotional development, and behavior of the child.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H82ECBB9B04734F9387146F156E9A29A6"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Maternal suicide exceeds hemorrhage and hypertensive disorders as a cause of maternal mortality.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HDA928D8B373947A292501734D9147842"><enum>(7)</enum><text>About 90 percent of women who have maternal depression can be treated successfully with a combination of medication and counseling.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD22C7E0267004FBDA2AFB5D26DF906E6"><enum>(8)</enum><text>States and professional organizations are taking the lead in addressing this problem, through public awareness campaigns, resource collection, and even promoting phone consultations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H28A48E089044498BA5EE9A81BE32F30F"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Congress should provide resources to support State teams, and help them find innovative solutions to this problem.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="HF9171EA80E10445393C3981C80A978CF"><enum>3.</enum><header>Screening and treatment for maternal depression</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Public Health Service Act is amended by inserting after section 317L of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/247b-13">42 U.S.C. 247b–13</external-xref>) the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2AB77E97EFE847AA83AB1FCEF96DF344" style="OLC">
				<section id="H86704685F5A9493AB30E5E37FC42B8F7"><enum>317L–1.</enum><header>Screening and treatment for maternal depression</header>
 <subsection id="H977E6621C09943F0B88D7E1025762D3B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, may make grants to States to establish, expand, or maintain culturally competent programs for screening and treatment of women who are pregnant, or who have given birth within the preceding 12 months, for maternal depression.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6337659EC04747A7904D87631C7E5970"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Number</header><text>The Secretary shall make grants under this section to not fewer than 3 States.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H05040FB5FDE643EDB8A288BFFAAFE962"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header><text>To seek a grant under this section, a State shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require. At a minimum, any such application shall include explanations of—</text>
 <paragraph id="H1B1078E182B14474A03AF2EEE04C87E0"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how the State’s proposed program will increase the percentage of women screened and treated for maternal depression in one or more communities; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB9374A2997E44BDCA958C973695B946B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>how the State’s proposed program, if expanded, would lead to substantial increases in screening and treatment for maternal depression.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H780EC289966B4686B280BD51D3E7D383"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Priority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to States proposing to expand or enhance screening for maternal depression in primary care settings, including family medicine, general internal medicine, general pediatrics, preventive medicine, obstetrics and gynecology, and psychiatry.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HFA6164C876B346298D18711418C0C344"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The activities eligible for funding through a grant under subsection (a)—</text> <paragraph id="HECAFC82052D343FBB925E15D96C422D4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall include—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HC7AD89F093924FECB46A81608224694E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>providing appropriate training to health care providers; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4B72073ADAB6426FA5D4EE7878F73CE9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>providing relevant resources to health care providers, including information on maternal depression screening, treatment, and followup support, and linkages to community-based resources; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4558E7064C0E4F07A711EA932D85C47B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may include—</text> <subparagraph id="H9396D16AAC43464F80437C09C5D70CDC"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">enabling health care providers (including obstetrician-gynecologists, pediatricians, psychiatrists, mental health care providers, and adult primary care clinicians) to provide or receive real-time psychiatric consultation (in-person or remotely) to aid in the treatment of pregnant and postpartum women;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H46F35CB49ECE4A29B4F88BF2A631159E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>conducting a public awareness campaign;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H898FECE71F304CB3A0BF97A26DEE7666"><enum>(C)</enum><text>funding start-up costs for phone lines, websites, the collection and dissemination of information, and other relevant resources and services; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5BAE8B44CB3D4A94AA62E6D49010A492"><enum>(D)</enum><text>establishing linkages with and among community-based resources, including mental health resources, primary care resources, and support groups.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDB61C52D4B524130A1DC0D6271CAACA7"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>To carry out this section, there are authorized to be appropriated $5,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2016 through 2020.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill>


