<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S156 IS: Energy Consumers Relief Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 156</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150113">January 13, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S373">Mr. Cassidy</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S352">Mr. Heller</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEV00">Committee on Environment and Public Works</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To protect consumers by prohibiting the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency from
			 promulgating as final certain energy-related rules that are estimated to
			 cost more than $1,000,000,000 and will cause significant adverse effects
 to the economy.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H79E2C5073ECF4375999B6B6C6350AE6E" style="OLC"><section id="HBFDAD3E673D8448EB8E39454C4EF9F8D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Energy Consumers Relief Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H41083E3593044F6C94114A2703938AC7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph commented="no" id="HEB020F47366B44C3BFA0D32FEADDB015"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id9957CECE430E4616A1E11FDC3ABB8985"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Direct costs</header><text>The term <term>direct costs</term> has the meaning given the term in chapter 8 of the report of the Environmental Protection Agency entitled <quote>Guidelines for Preparing Economic Analyses</quote> and dated December 17, 2010.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD56C4D19FF754361AFC1AA4F82E0405D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Energy-related rule that is estimated to cost more than $1,000,000,000</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>energy-related rule that is estimated to cost more than $1,000,000,000</term> means a rule of the Environmental Protection Agency that—</text><subparagraph id="HF22D1B84C8B144B79F0C84C7B22AACDB"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">regulates any aspect of the production, supply, distribution, or use of energy or provides for such regulation by States or other governmental entities; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0CC28296E2FA47E091F8D33A3DDAFA22"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is estimated by the Administrator or the Director of the Office of Management and Budget to impose direct costs and indirect costs, in the aggregate, of more than $1,000,000,000.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9AA2ABE20E7F4909AD1E150CBB679F6C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Indirect costs</header><text>The term <term>indirect costs</term> has the meaning given the term in chapter 8 of the report of the Environmental Protection Agency entitled <quote>Guidelines for Preparing Economic Analyses</quote> and dated December 17, 2010.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE97BEBE7967145168D602421C9726890"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Rule</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>rule</term> has the meaning given to the term in section 551 of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1EAC6D2B47EF4CBDA1292AEC1932A6BF"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Energy.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H21356711F7C647F49B48A54D882B9231"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibition against finalizing certain energy-related rules that will cause significant adverse effects to the economy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Administrator may not promulgate as final an energy-related rule that is estimated to cost more than $1,000,000,000 if the Secretary determines under section 4(b)(3) that the rule will cause significant adverse effects to the economy.</text></section><section id="H5823D23DD5BE400B8234E032A5B8042B"><enum>4.</enum><header>Reports and determinations prior to promulgating as final certain energy-related rules</header><subsection id="idABE8AEAD83A741E297CDE26A526A76A0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Before promulgating as final any energy-related rule that is estimated to cost more than $1,000,000,000, the Administrator shall carry out the requirements of subsection (b).</text></subsection><subsection id="idE211D9911DBE4E6996D935D1222FBCA9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><paragraph id="HA2E447B03FB3475FA847969FD026878E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall submit to Congress and the Secretary a report containing—</text><subparagraph id="HD8C51E20375B4679887164BE6DC8FB4D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a copy of the rule;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFB76B1F330E34579ADC5F5C7C2DCB1CE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a concise general statement relating to the rule;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3728830DECF6483384F84207E36159A6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an estimate of the total costs of the rule, including the direct costs and indirect costs of the rule;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD79278CE80624EE995528CFF94490C8A"><enum>(D)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HABEE3B39B3784490B5BB0ACA284D757A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an estimate of the total benefits of the rule and when such benefits are expected to be realized;</text></clause><clause id="H7F368B8203554E8FA6A5409628C9430A" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a description of the modeling, the calculations, the assumptions, and the limitations due to uncertainty, speculation, or lack of information associated with the estimates under this subparagraph; and</text></clause><clause id="HC568F43FADD941999A153DC8CBBBA290" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a certification that all data and documents relied upon by the Environmental Protection Agency in developing the estimates—</text><subclause id="H230EEB685E904CFF9A37F064E12DE5FC"><enum>(I)</enum><text>have been preserved; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HF20A0FEC68EF4F58928321C664852D2B"><enum>(II)</enum><text>are available for review by the public on the Web site of the Environmental Protection Agency, except to the extent to which publication of the data and documents would constitute disclosure of confidential information in violation of applicable Federal law;</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H578D4FFB500345B2AE7FC7EB0D25D2EE"><enum>(E)</enum><text>an estimate of the increases in energy prices, including potential increases in gasoline or electricity prices for consumers, that may result from implementation or enforcement of the rule; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB0F3BE95927F430AA75E37BBFE0063CA"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a detailed description of the employment effects, including potential job losses and shifts in employment, that may result from implementation or enforcement of the rule.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCFF9FA21EB60459ABC691290AE90D367"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Initial determination on increases and impacts</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission and the Administrator of the Energy Information Administration, shall prepare an independent analysis to determine whether the rule will cause any—</text><subparagraph id="H2701300868014366A843666B80FC5C2D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>increase in energy prices for consumers, including low-income households, small businesses, and manufacturers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2AB2FCA4BD2F4615B11D49F43215E6AE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>impact on fuel diversity of the electricity generation portfolio of the United States or on national, regional, or local electric reliability;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H864381855E044B3BAF6C099E5B3A0E60"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">adverse effect on energy supply, distribution, or use due to the economic or technical infeasibility of implementing the rule; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3719BE34CD774A23B2D7105E96E3C344"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">other adverse effect on energy supply, distribution, or use, including a shortfall in supply and increased use of foreign supplies.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H99AD062AB9684426AC5E2DF256464081"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Subsequent determination on adverse effects to the economy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary determines under paragraph (2) that the rule will cause an increase, impact, or effect described in that paragraph, the Secretary, in consultation with the Administrator, the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of Labor, and the Administrator of the Small Business Administration, shall—</text><subparagraph id="H4A536A32DE254BB1A92FB637042A6F62"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">determine whether the rule will cause significant adverse effects to the economy, taking into consideration—</text><clause id="HEEEE720B12FB42C9BB130370AA049CED"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the costs and benefits of the rule and limitations in calculating the costs and benefits due to uncertainty, speculation, or lack of information; and</text></clause><clause id="H6A6C11BA9D9B4C5D9EB0EDB533A3A67C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the positive and negative impacts of the rule on economic indicators, including those related to gross domestic product, unemployment, wages, consumer prices, and business and manufacturing activity; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1C430B18B1104A18A293841A18E14A5F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>publish the results of the determination made under subparagraph (A) in the Federal Register.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H4CCCDAAB69454137AE92D8C3C29B20CB"><enum>5.</enum><header>Prohibition on use of social cost of carbon in analysis</header><subsection id="H932393322DDF446F9099C8F1BE9F2921"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition of social cost of carbon</header><text>In this section, the term <term>social cost of carbon</term> means—</text><paragraph id="idE8626FA894A44457B9E8C31EFA2C9549"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the social cost of carbon as described in the technical support document entitled <quote>Technical Support Document: Technical Update of the Social Cost of Carbon for Regulatory Impact Analysis Under Executive Order 12866</quote>, published by the Interagency Working Group on Social Cost of Carbon, United States Government, in May 2013 (or any successor or substantially related document); or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8E80B87EB689413D9ABB38B6A1BF0ADC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any other estimate of the monetized damages associated with an incremental increase in carbon dioxide emissions in a given year.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H522E441A767B4456AC35A0B42F1B0E7F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition on use of social cost of carbon in analysis</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law or any Executive order, the Administrator may not use the social cost of carbon to incorporate social benefits of reducing carbon dioxide emissions, or for any other reason, in any cost-benefit analysis relating to an energy-related rule that is estimated to cost more than $1,000,000,000 unless a Federal law is enacted authorizing the use.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


