<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1920 IS: Biennial Report on the Skills Gap Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-08-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 1920</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150804">August 4, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S356">Mr. Donnelly</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S352">Mr. Heller</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To require the Comptroller General of the United States to develop and submit to Congress a
			 biennial report
			 on the current state
			 of the skills gap in the United States, as of the date of
			 the report, that includes an analysis of the effectiveness of efforts to
			 close the skills gap and policy recommendations to improve such
			 efforts, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Biennial Report on the Skills Gap Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </section><section id="id6FF32D4090EF44BF955AF0B3A3C8B3F4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definition of skills gap</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <term>skills gap</term> means the difference or gap between the specific skills set of employees and the skills that are desired by employers in the workforce.</text>
		</section><section id="id82F54BC9DA5A455ABF9BB860D2D6B759"><enum>3.</enum><header>Biennial report</header>
 <subsection id="id2C6048E69081452CA01AB555E5223FED"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, and every other year thereafter, the Comptroller General of the United States shall develop and submit to Congress a report on the current state of the skills gap in the United States, as of the date of the report, that includes—</text>
 <paragraph id="id7DE7F1664A834BFA9F5710C7EA18E9E2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an analysis of the effectiveness of efforts to close the skills gap; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id41EC5CB0FD1E4A7897AD4D5C53B9DBB4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>policy recommendations to improve such efforts.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id9FCB1437FB494971955B54FB50A11464"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Content of report</header><text>Each report required under subsection (a) may include the following:</text> <paragraph id="id15A033E3D5174D86B892B4C01BBC4C57"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An analysis of employer participation in apprenticeships and on-the-job training in the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idBBF77AFCFC3B4C9D8B24D30226276562"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of the Registered Apprenticeship program of the Department of Labor (Act of August 16, 1937 (commonly known as the <quote>National Apprenticeship Act</quote>; 50 Stat. 664, chapter 663; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/50">29 U.S.C. 50 et seq.</external-xref>)) to determine if the program can be better utilized.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id48BADB52CFD1486ABAB2B2E5A81710BD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An analysis of the prevalence and portability of recognized postsecondary credentials, including industry-recognized credentials, that align with occupations that are in demand.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id74EDCC89FBDD446AAAB729E29D3FE636"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A comparison of policies and strategies addressing the current skills gap in the United States, as of the date of the report, with the policies and strategies employed by other large countries.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id107178FF45D74D65BF315F8190D4FAAA"><enum>(5)</enum><text>An analysis of the specific barriers preventing the United States workforce from acquiring the skills desired by United States employers, including an assessment of opportunities to reduce those barriers.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


