<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S131 IS: Fair And Immediate Release of Generic Drugs Act </dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 131</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150108">January 8, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S299">Mr. Vitter</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S332">Mr. Franken</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to ensure that valid generic drugs may enter the
			 market.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short
 title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fair And Immediate Release of Generic Drugs Act </short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>FAIR Generics Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="ID11c8c50a21c74d90849d012e200ec243"><enum>2.</enum><header>180-Day
			 exclusivity period amendments regarding first applicant status</header><subsection id="ID6330cbed4e2a4d69910df9758f1950aa"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Amendments to
			 Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act</header><paragraph id="IDbc6d731c151c43a88c1217124c6e7504"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>Section 505(j)(5)(B) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355">21 U.S.C. 355(j)(5)(B)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="id7189819659D84B4E825654171F2A4802"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in clause (iv)(II)—</text><clause id="id75184DCBDD8141FD9731CB9FA27B929E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking item (bb); and</text></clause><clause id="idDF4638148C314F7DAFB5222A16DF8E6B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by redesignating items (cc) and (dd) as items (bb) and (cc), respectively; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE1ADF87F66434238B999027300C82A34"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id062F1252272E409EABD43240FEBE52DC" style="OLC"><clause id="idFC020D43F9E24E30B1644B9D46E7DF1D" indent="up2"><enum>(v)</enum><header>First applicant
 defined</header><text>As used in this subsection, the term <term>first applicant</term> means an applicant—</text><subclause id="idAC05111366AF4C3CB46A2FBAF22FE08C"><enum>(I)</enum><item commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id511902278CDE4F2FA469536435C660E5"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>that, on the first day on which a substantially complete application containing a certification described in paragraph (2)(A)(vii)(IV) is submitted for approval of a drug, submits a substantially complete application that contains and lawfully maintains a certification described in paragraph (2)(A)(vii)(IV) for the drug; and</text></item><item id="idC1F279C52DA7419596F2E10BF86F5DC3" indent="up1"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>that has not entered into a disqualifying agreement described under clause (vii)(II); or</text></item></subclause><subclause id="id61033FA684994005B76A355D49F9DFEE"><enum>(II)</enum><item commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idF657711E907E4FEBB26A2B3E89DBE9E3"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>for the drug that is not described in subclause (I) and that, with respect to the applicant and drug, each requirement described in clause (vi) is satisfied; and</text></item><item id="id6A17EC58D89A4680B169EB6655A202C1" indent="up1"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>that has not entered into a disqualifying agreement described under clause (vii)(II).</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="id9C7D942107E74E23939E3F2AB9E76CBD" indent="up2"><enum>(vi)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>The requirements described in this clause are the following:</text><subclause id="id17C91423D5C7410B83FD8451EFCBCEB3"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The applicant described in clause (v)(II) submitted and lawfully maintains a certification described in paragraph (2)(A)(vii)(IV) or a statement described in paragraph (2)(A)(viii) for each unexpired patent for which a first applicant described in clause (v)(I) had submitted a certification described in paragraph (2)(A)(vii)(IV) on the first day on which a substantially complete application containing such a certification was submitted.</text></subclause><subclause id="id88EAA3A7E5CF4AD3B24BB5F47EE28C30"><enum>(II)</enum><text>With regard to each such unexpired patent for which the applicant described in clause (v)(II) submitted a certification described in paragraph (2)(A)(vii)(IV), no action for patent infringement was brought against such applicant within the 45-day period specified in paragraph (5)(B)(iii); or if an action was brought within such time period, such an action was withdrawn or dismissed by a court (including a district court) without a decision that the patent was valid and infringed; or if an action was brought within such time period and was not withdrawn or so dismissed, such applicant has obtained the decision of a court (including a district court) that the patent is invalid or not infringed (including any substantive determination that there is no cause of action for patent infringement or invalidity, and including a settlement order or consent decree signed and entered by the court stating that the patent is invalid or not infringed).</text></subclause><subclause id="id6C8EDF3813A54DFBBC0E0A6512B87EB9"><enum>(III)</enum><text>If an applicant described in clause (v)(I) has begun commercial marketing of such drug, the applicant described in clause (v)(II) does not begin commercial marketing of such drug until the date that is 30 days after the date on which the applicant described in clause (v)(I) began such commercial marketing.</text></subclause></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="IDc4a27ff356014a90822eaefdf619e67c"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming
 amendment</header><text>Section 505(j)(5)(D)(i)(IV) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355">21 U.S.C. 355(j)(5)(D)(i)(IV)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>The first applicant</quote> and inserting <quote>The first applicant, as defined in subparagraph (B)(v)(I),</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID7877ead9b43446278c9a46d5cbb98204"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>The amendments made by subsection (a) shall apply only with respect to an application filed under section 505(j) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355">21 U.S.C. 355(j)</external-xref>) to which the amendments made by section 1102(a) of the Medicare Prescription Drug, Improvement, and Modernization Act of 2003 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/108/173">Public Law 108–173</external-xref>) apply.</text></subsection></section><section id="IDaa05ca3397834cd18cc37eaa41730c75"><enum>3.</enum><header>180-Day
			 exclusivity period amendments regarding agreements to defer commercial
			 marketing</header><subsection id="IDa57973e12bf7408bb4e4ca2272a32c2f"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Amendments to
			 Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act</header><paragraph id="ID2b6f4468ee824d7d8d1f500bb607b062"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Limitations on
 agreements to defer commercial marketing date</header><text>Section 505(j)(5)(B) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355">21 U.S.C. 355(j)(5)(B)</external-xref>), as amended by section 2, is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4C3D872B8665425B8C7A3E91481B5062" style="OLC"><clause id="ID8a16b9ede9a54dfbaaef407fdd8bcb07" indent="up2"><enum>(vii)</enum><header>Agreement by first applicant to
				defer commercial marketing; limitation on acceleration of deferred
			 commercial
				marketing date</header><subclause id="id3BCBB59EA21A43BC92585341D54E464F"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Agreement to defer approval or
 commercial marketing date</header><text>An agreement described in this subclause is an agreement between a first applicant and the holder of the application for the listed drug or an owner of one or more of the patents as to which any applicant submitted a certification qualifying such applicant for the 180-day exclusivity period whereby that applicant agrees, directly or indirectly, (aa) not to seek an approval of its application that is made effective on the earliest possible date under this subparagraph, subparagraph (F) of this paragraph, section 505A, or section 527, (bb) not to begin the commercial marketing of its drug on the earliest possible date after receiving an approval of its application that is made effective under this subparagraph, subparagraph (F) of this paragraph, section 505A, or section 527, or (cc) to both items (aa) and (bb).</text></subclause><subclause id="id2100E98E2D8C4787B83D9027C112363A"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Agreement that disqualifies
 applicant from first applicant status</header><text>An agreement described in this subclause is an agreement between an applicant and the holder of the application for the listed drug or an owner of one or more of the patents as to which any applicant submitted a certification qualifying such applicant for the 180-day exclusivity period whereby that applicant agrees, directly or indirectly, not to seek an approval of its application or not to begin the commercial marketing of its drug until a date that is after the expiration of the 180-day exclusivity period awarded to another applicant with respect to such drug (without regard to whether such 180-day exclusivity period is awarded before or after the date of the agreement).</text></subclause></clause><clause id="idF68A0ED0F925446088097254CDE8F268" indent="up2"><enum>(viii)</enum><header>Limitation on
 acceleration</header><text>If an agreement described in clause (vii)(I) includes more than 1 possible date when an applicant may seek an approval of its application or begin the commercial marketing of its drug—</text><subclause id="id796AC24DE5064AE89C4452D890D9F9D0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the applicant may seek an approval of its application or begin such commercial marketing on the date that is the earlier of—</text><item id="id00286B1642FE4134BCF26D96F4ACD759"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the latest date set forth in the agreement on which that applicant can receive an approval that is made effective under this subparagraph, subparagraph (F) of this paragraph, section 505A, or section 527, or begin the commercial marketing of such drug, without regard to any other provision of such agreement pursuant to which the commercial marketing could begin on an earlier date; or</text></item><item id="id95ACCEA6874C4196BA5DFFD3F4BEB518"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>180 days after another first applicant begins commercial marketing of such drug; and</text></item></subclause><subclause id="id90E43F67E8E14ECE88A62341D3367419"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the latest date set forth in the agreement on which that applicant can receive an approval that is made effective under this subparagraph, subparagraph (F) of this paragraph, section 505A, or section 527, or begin the commercial marketing of such drug, without regard to any other provision of such agreement pursuant to which commercial marketing could begin on an earlier date, shall be the date used to determine whether an applicant is disqualified from first applicant status pursuant to clause (vii)(II).</text></subclause></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="ID274147e1bc1e4e829fb9ba5cbba0abfc"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notification of
 FDA</header><text>Section 505(j) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355">21 U.S.C. 355(j)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id92543B96C89246AA96E0FA28D7610EC9" style="OLC"><paragraph id="id258EF44DD8EC4556BAFD25E519E7C365" indent="up1"><enum>(11)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id8BA2581345A9494FAD6142F15879D519"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The holder of an abbreviated application under this subsection shall submit to the Secretary a notification that includes—</text><clause id="id97B739EBA40E4368A07CA39B43D263FB" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id6BC12AC1CD5540A098FA669F8DCF6A2E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the text of any agreement entered into by such holder described under paragraph (5)(B)(vii)(I); or</text></subclause><subclause id="id48EF35BC525A40DCA8E088C294D5A294" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>if such an agreement has not been reduced to text, a written detailed description of such agreement that is sufficient to disclose all the terms and conditions of the agreement; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id7810422424D24170B4BFEC0DF5F84D0E" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the text, or a written detailed description in the event of an agreement that has not been reduced to text, of any other agreements that are contingent upon, provide a contingent condition for, or are otherwise related to an agreement described in clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5C9D77465B32412C8F0B9F5F7479BE38" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The notification described under subparagraph (A) shall be submitted not later than 10 business days after execution of the agreement described in subparagraph (A)(i). Such notification is in addition to any notification required under section 1112 of the Medicare Prescription Drug, Improvement, and Modernization Act of 2003.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id05D23BC53A8D4FCE91C31B1B8BA03DC9" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Any information or documentary material filed with the Secretary pursuant to this paragraph shall be exempt from disclosure under section 552 of title 5, United States Code, and no such information or documentary material may be made public, except as may be relevant to any administrative or judicial action or proceeding. Nothing in this paragraph is intended to prevent disclosure to either body of the Congress or to any duly authorized committee or subcommittee of the Congress.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="IDd27f5d987fc5464eab7db22282cbb94c"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Prohibited
 acts</header><text>Section 301(e) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/331">21 U.S.C. 331(e)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>505 (i) or (k)</quote> and inserting <quote>505 (i), (j)(11), or (k)</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id16BEAD7F09334ACA9C246D678D72CBA6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Infringement of
 patent</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 271(e) of title 35, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1A4A441502CA4B5CB0C8588CFF4F54D9" style="OLC"><paragraph commented="no" id="id083C8BD9829A4876B838C909B072A884" indent="up1"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The exclusive remedy under this section for an infringement of a patent for which the Secretary of Health and Human Services has published information pursuant to subsection (b)(1) or (c)(2) of section 505 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act shall be an action brought under this subsection within the 45-day period described in subsection (j)(5)(B)(iii) or (c)(3)(C) of section 505 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="ID0ea03683aa68491d9b0e96bcf486d8b1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applicability</header><paragraph id="id969843E1653B4421917CDBDDEA094CA1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Limitations on
 acceleration of deferred commercial marketing date</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (a)(1) shall apply only with respect to—</text><subparagraph id="id8950AB1A3BF64B558BE86764F142AD6F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an application filed under section 505(j) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355">21 U.S.C. 355(j)</external-xref>) to which the amendments made by section 1102(a) of the Medicare Prescription Drug, Improvement, and Modernization Act of 2003 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/108/173">Public Law 108–173</external-xref>) apply; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="IDb86db9e1370c4c24908624d69993b4b8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an agreement described under section 505(j)(5)(B)(vii)(I) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (as added by subsection (a)(1)) executed after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID1712456ef18c4b7c8e9569acd5b2fa47"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notification of
 FDA</header><text>The amendments made by paragraphs (2) and (3) of subsection (a) shall apply only with respect to an agreement described under section 505(j)(5)(B)(vii)(I) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (as added by subsection (a)(1)) executed after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


