<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1614 IS: Court-Appointed Guardian Accountability and Senior Protection Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-06-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1614</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150618">June 18, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S287">Mr. Cornyn</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To provide for the inclusion of court-appointed guardianship improvement and oversight activities
			 under the Elder Justice Act of 2009.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short
 title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Court-Appointed Guardian Accountability and Senior Protection Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="id8BF671A901264995B3A265EDEBF556C6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Court-appointed
			 guardianship oversight activities under the Elder Justice Act of
 2009</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2042(c) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1397m-1">42 U.S.C. 1397m–1(c)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="id4EA2B8EBF9AF43A999204275DB8BC279"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by inserting <quote>(and, in the case of demonstration programs described in paragraph (2)(E), to the highest courts of States)</quote> after <quote>States</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idC0331A08A2C949E9A54F316901943B98"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (2)—</text> <subparagraph id="id0727312FC0024E39B36BF1DE4FB15793"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by inserting <quote>(and the highest courts of States, in the case of demonstration programs described in subparagraph (E))</quote> after <quote>local units of government</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id670DA265DDAF42A684B40604FFD98405"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (D), by striking <quote>or</quote> after the semicolon;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id42FD7ED5B8B1468D88DA7290CD503CC7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (E) as subparagraph (F); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9C978D202CFB4531A19DFDD0B0B9376E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (E), the following new subparagraph:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE7F9C06643774EE5BAC9DFEC4C885057" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="idBBCCEA9DDB114C3F9912EDF066A0E849"><enum>(E)</enum><text>subject to paragraph (3), programs to assess the fairness, effectiveness, timeliness, safety, integrity, and accessibility of adult guardianship and conservatorship proceedings, including the appointment and the monitoring of the performance of court-appointed guardians and conservators, and to implement changes deemed necessary as a result of the assessments such as mandating background checks for all potential guardians and conservators, and implementing systems to enable the annual accountings and other required conservatorship and guardianship filings to be completed, filed, and reviewed electronically in order to simplify the filing process for conservators and guardians and better enable courts to identify discrepancies and detect fraud and the exploitation of protected persons; or</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idA7F75BC2883A432EBDE1C57F74BB1380"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (3), (4), and (5) as paragraphs (4), (5), and (6), respectively;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idA4AD13050DCF4CF4AEE472E63971BC63"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (2), the following new paragraph:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id47049D0A5B6A42478DC7FCB09346E55B" style="OLC">
					<paragraph id="idED56C9368D594C5FB4B7B104F60FD4E1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Requirements
				for court-appointed guardianship oversight demonstration programs</header>
						<subparagraph id="id9E9CB61F79CE421196DFEB6427B8F6C2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Award of
 grants</header><text>Any grants the Secretary awards to the highest courts of States for demonstration programs described in paragraph (2)(E) shall be based on the recommendations of the Attorney General and the State Justice Institute<added-phrase reported-display-style="italic">, </added-phrase>as established by section 203 of the State Justice Institute Act of 1984 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/10702">42 U.S.C. 10702</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idDFE9DE60E1F245BC8BB66215520FA62D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Collaboration</header><text>The highest court of a State awarded a grant to conduct a demonstration program described in paragraph (2)(E) shall collaborate with the State Unit on Aging for the State and the Adult Protective Services agency for the State in conducting the demonstration program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idE06C2033CCEE4102B9428FFDE2254122"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in paragraph (4) (as redesignated by paragraph (3) of this section), by inserting <quote>(and, in the case of demonstration programs described in paragraph (2)(E), the highest court of a State)</quote> after <quote>a State</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id5ED355274F334ACB8241A0FA6AAB0E1F"><enum>(6)</enum><text>in paragraph (5) (as so redesignated), by inserting <quote>(or, in the case of demonstration programs described in paragraph (2)(E), the highest court of a State)</quote> after <quote>State</quote> each place it appears.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


