<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S770 IS: Escambia County Land Conveyance Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 770</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150318">March 18, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S350">Mr. Rubio</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To authorize Escambia County, Florida, to convey certain property that was formerly part of Santa
			 Rosa Island National Monument and that was conveyed to Escambia County
			 subject to restrictions on use and reconveyance.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HB4F21857B31D4B7FB9E5583047686169" style="OLC">
 <section id="idF477AF50BDD842ABBB8BF8C83F923E9F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Escambia County Land Conveyance Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="idB1EA8E701A934D53AE110608EBEF6634"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
 <paragraph id="id812E2DDD423B4370BAE7AD0350F21954"><enum>(1)</enum><header>County</header><text>The term <quote>County</quote> means Escambia County, Florida.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idED6C88528C9C4E1D870D36460567D711"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Non-Federal land</header><text>The term <quote>non-Federal land</quote> means the former Santa Rosa Island National Monument land in the State of Florida that was conveyed by the United States to the County under the Act of July 30, 1946 (60 Stat. 712, chapter 699), and by deed dated January 15, 1947.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="idB0E12553CAFE401DBF2956F4DCD16799"><enum>3.</enum><header>Reconveyance of non-Federal land</header>
 <subsection id="H2E157B03E55B48BB938FA4CD384B98F2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding the restrictions on conveyance in the Act of July 30, 1946 (60 Stat. 712, chapter 699) and the deed to the non-Federal land from the United States to the County dated January 15, 1947, and subject to subsection (c), the County may convey all right, title, and interest of the County in and to the non-Federal land or any portion of the non-Federal land, to any person or entity, without any restriction on conveyance or reconveyance imposed by the United States in that Act or deed.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id8D53D86541B84A4CA9F677B0695929B9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effect on leasehold interests</header><text>No person or entity holding a leasehold interest in the non-Federal as of the date of enactment of this Act shall be required to involuntarily accept a fee interest to the non-Federal land in place of the leasehold interest.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H1414C3B55FD344959DD25DD712A48CE2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Land within Santa Rosa County</header>
 <paragraph id="H7B22A250FB29406A9C94C0B3FAA073BE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The County may convey to Santa Rosa County, Florida, all right, title, and interest of the County in and to any portion of the non-Federal land that is within the jurisdictional boundaries of Santa Rosa County.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id7472DC5B55CB447F8B86A136CCF0186F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A conveyance under paragraph (1) shall—</text> <subparagraph id="idF9F910D52C6A41959694D827B06E84F6"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be absolute;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6AEA8F80C611458C80BF5331E47E916A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">terminate—</text> <clause id="id21398FCD15B1476B8FA7F0573BF07F8A"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any subjugation of Santa Rosa County to the County; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="idE7E7DB3281EA402EA05F85BB43A93078"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any regulation of Santa Rosa County by the County; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id452D6D9D2CE9466C82DBEFE88D19F03F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>be without consideration, except that the County may require Santa Rosa County, Florida, to pay the actual costs associated with the conveyance of the non-Federal land.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H923138D8CAFC45AEA39361D0D1CE5E4B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reconveyance</header><text>Santa Rosa County, Florida, or any other person to whom Santa Rosa County, Florida, reconveys the non-Federal land may reconvey the non-Federal land or any portion of the non-Federal land conveyed to Santa Rosa County, Florida, under paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA5655FB9C355474D934898884611C8D2"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Incorporation or annexation</header><text>The owners or leaseholders of non-Federal land conveyed under this subsection may pursue incorporation, annexation, or any other governmental status for the non-Federal land, if the owners or leaseholders comply with the legal conditions required for incorporation, annexation, or the other governmental status.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id370E5689DA744C3FAD07044AE4BD8E58"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Intent of congress</header><text>It is the intent of Congress that the conveyance under paragraph (1) shall be completed by the date that is 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA9949248F1D04697B3FEB9C0DAD6F8EA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Jurisdiction</header><text>The non-Federal land conveyed under this section shall be subject to the jurisdiction of the county or unit of local government in which the non-Federal land is located.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8570771A48C4493C925E439398FA73C8"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Proceeds</header><text>Any proceeds from the conveyance of non-Federal land by the County or Santa Rosa County, Florida (other than amounts paid for the direct and incidental costs associated with the conveyance) under this section shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="id36B9F02DF381431EA9C5167D76D6E56F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be considered windfall profits; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idE539784EF26B47B2BA8A6769DF2BBB88"><enum>(2)</enum><text>revert to the United States.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H039FBC75EAE3437F935C705C8F536CC6"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Preservation</header><text>The County and Santa Rosa County, Florida, shall preserve the areas of the non-Federal land conveyed under this section that, as of the date of enactment of this Act, are dedicated for conservation, preservation, public recreation access, and public parking, in accordance with resolutions adopted by the Board of County Commissioners of the County or Santa Rosa County, Florida, respectively.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idD0F7A003CFCB45148113BB81046DAD9A"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authority of counties</header><text>The County and Santa Rosa County, Florida—</text> <paragraph id="idB4C107AD54F34F50BA22A6A2193E9D43"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall not be subject to a deadline or requirement to make any conveyance or reconveyance of the non-Federal land authorized under this section; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id5A2109A3A74549FD91320701DD912484"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may establish terms for the conveyance or reconveyance of the non-Federal land authorized under this section, subject to this Act and applicable State law.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


