<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Placed-on-Calendar-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S754 PCS: Cybersecurity Information Sharing Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><calendar>Calendar No. 28</calendar><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 754</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150317">March 17, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S300">Mr. Burr</sponsor>, from the <committee-name committee-id="SLIN00">Select Committee on Intelligence</committee-name>, reported the following original bill; which was read twice and placed on the calendar</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To improve cybersecurity in the United States through enhanced sharing of information about
			 cybersecurity threats, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header>
 <subsection id="id3C8B63FB728A48D3AC39E76FFB1ECD27"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Cybersecurity Information Sharing Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id1fed1a87ac6f4a33bfae973e45ef5432"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents of this Act is as follows:</text><toc><toc-entry idref="S1" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="id9ad6c373f3fd44b3819b45b5a8b19688" level="section">Sec. 2. Definitions.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="ide272b572449646ad8add7175c744bf49" level="section">Sec. 3. Sharing of information by the Federal Government.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="idc220a261d0c34c7ea5df4103764ca4a6" level="section">Sec. 4. Authorizations for preventing, detecting, analyzing, and mitigating cybersecurity threats.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="id7aa014d8219640b0be5ba8486e0f5776" level="section">Sec. 5. Sharing of cyber threat indicators and defensive measures with the Federal Government.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="idc6842ed051194cfda77e2d250867c1f7" level="section">Sec. 6. Protection from liability.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="id17447f6b123447758c2de795a3e321f1" level="section">Sec. 7. Oversight of Government activities.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="id898778e8394a4fe4ad6887b0a43e323a" level="section">Sec. 8. Construction and preemption.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HC8808302347C" level="section">Sec. 9. Report on cybersecurity threats.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="idd1aad41644974051a07957b0cab75563" level="section">Sec. 10. Conforming amendments.</toc-entry></toc> </subsection></section><section id="id9ad6c373f3fd44b3819b45b5a8b19688"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
 <paragraph id="id7911fd65ce084ae385699ee0c08f6980"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agency</header><text>The term <term>agency</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3502 of title 44, United States Code.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id9b1a48cd17ba422f98aa745056575a58"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Antitrust laws</header><text>The term <term>antitrust laws</term>—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idc3da4df80b934190b5ee9de137e98984"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has the meaning given the term in section 1 of the Clayton Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/12">15 U.S.C. 12</external-xref>);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4fa842a0015f461fb591330c423aac91"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes section 5 of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/45">15 U.S.C. 45</external-xref>) to the extent that section 5 of that Act applies to unfair methods of competition; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id25203abac7d0401389183dac69df376d"><enum>(C)</enum><text>includes any State law that has the same intent and effect as the laws under subparagraphs (A) and (B).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id73d59805f1de41f2983959af41913db8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Appropriate Federal entities</header><text>The term <term>appropriate Federal entities</term> means the following:</text> <subparagraph id="idF2B782B5CA5444B18DB0BA1AA1D5EF0B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Department of Commerce.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id168A3396E35C401388D0E7DC6120A196"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Department of Defense.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB18405C9B6E64BEAB6C544ADCC279E57"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Department of Energy.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id722BF882414B4583B6C3936BB661A0FB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The Department of Homeland Security.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id63DD26950DE34A82A15FD96C6256EE19"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The Department of Justice.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id638639FC6F944B4AB1E96A2856B3826B"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The Department of the Treasury.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8905AE36D3BB4022B7C5D89803ED5818"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The Office of the Director of National Intelligence.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id6f2156fd7ef24e388e053ee6abb27400"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Cybersecurity purpose</header><text>The term <term>cybersecurity purpose</term> means the purpose of protecting an information system or information that is stored on, processed by, or transiting an information system from a cybersecurity threat or security vulnerability.</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="id49e2ceedee2b406085fd7419f68b9911"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Cybersecurity threat</header>
 <subparagraph id="id75183C81810A47BCBB1FA22846039F2F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the term <term>cybersecurity threat</term> means an action, not protected by the First Amendment to the Constitution of the United States, on or through an information system that may result in an unauthorized effort to adversely impact the security, availability, confidentiality, or integrity of an information system or information that is stored on, processed by, or transiting an information system.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id048A10E53E624CF28551B1402C687163"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text>The term <term>cybersecurity threat</term> does not include any action that solely involves a violation of a consumer term of service or a consumer licensing agreement.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0d3983bb450040588baa2b4c13f3f224"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Cyber threat indicator</header><text>The term <term>cyber threat indicator</term> means information that is necessary to describe or identify—</text> <subparagraph id="id9839151608aa4fcbb91b2080ae58c5b9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>malicious reconnaissance, including anomalous patterns of communications that appear to be transmitted for the purpose of gathering technical information related to a cybersecurity threat or security vulnerability;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idde6f1ae882a8414ca47c746997e96427"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a method of defeating a security control or exploitation of a security vulnerability;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id41f50ebb0ec048f3baef7497bd877901"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a security vulnerability, including anomalous activity that appears to indicate the existence of a security vulnerability;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc20c1bf328d84bf59b11c9c820f5152e"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a method of causing a user with legitimate access to an information system or information that is stored on, processed by, or transiting an information system to unwittingly enable the defeat of a security control or exploitation of a security vulnerability;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbde7ef0cbdf94756ac82b859bdb91c6f"><enum>(E)</enum><text>malicious cyber command and control;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfb338fdbf73540cb8e7ae602c8886422"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the actual or potential harm caused by an incident, including a description of the information exfiltrated as a result of a particular cybersecurity threat;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbc7c214c9a5f4630a5de4a6a7cca5814"><enum>(G)</enum><text>any other attribute of a cybersecurity threat, if disclosure of such attribute is not otherwise prohibited by law; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id29bfdc551bc543d5a4fd4c47dc352ed9"><enum>(H)</enum><text>any combination thereof.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1203198c8bc0424f800e4e47f0a91512"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Defensive measure</header> <subparagraph id="idE520C00A63F74C50B05F966818B84E31"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the term <term>defensive measure</term> means an action, device, procedure, signature, technique, or other measure applied to an information system or information that is stored on, processed by, or transiting an information system that detects, prevents, or mitigates a known or suspected cybersecurity threat or security vulnerability.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id16C68EFAC95D46509212D799EAA9431F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text>The term <term>defensive measure</term> does not include a measure that destroys, renders unusable, or substantially harms an information system or data on an information system not belonging to—</text>
 <clause id="idFC370EE17C19419C84F5A048BA6D4D9B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the private entity operating the measure; or</text> </clause><clause id="idD2315551DF8E4C659C8CAAEA1A7A76C4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>another entity or Federal entity that is authorized to provide consent and has provided consent to that private entity for operation of such measure.</text>
					</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id34eb4bd570ed4bb3ac5d3bdae53a5fdf"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Entity</header>
 <subparagraph id="id2866E0CAD376460D9A88810630760C50"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as otherwise provided in this paragraph, the term <term>entity</term> means any private entity, non-Federal government agency or department, or State, tribal, or local government (including a political subdivision, department, or component thereof).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3987878577f047da89256c30cd3d81a6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text>The term <term>entity</term> includes a government agency or department of the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, the Northern Mariana Islands, and any other territory or possession of the United States.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd52d556a0f2e44bb88afcc81bd90ce0f"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text>The term <term>entity</term> does not include a foreign power as defined in section 101 of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1801">50 U.S.C. 1801</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id275198b1338644fba3e7f3e1315f2f27"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Federal entity</header><text>The term <term>Federal entity</term> means a department or agency of the United States or any component of such department or agency.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id867ca89f79d444b69cbe8153a1a85ecc"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Information system</header><text>The term <term>information system</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="id06DF2B5CFAA54295B55238E4DA6EAB3B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has the meaning given the term in section 3502 of title 44, United States Code; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2D111ECF60B745F282D232B4C6986E74"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes industrial control systems, such as supervisory control and data acquisition systems, distributed control systems, and programmable logic controllers.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="iddf9a16b5e40e463ca138fd546ab928cb"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Local government</header><text>The term <term>local government</term> means any borough, city, county, parish, town, township, village, or other political subdivision of a State.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id255d0e47cba3478d89fee5757d0bb58d"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Malicious cyber command and control</header><text>The term <term>malicious cyber command and control</term> means a method for unauthorized remote identification of, access to, or use of, an information system or information that is stored on, processed by, or transiting an information system.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id11ed2a58b56446b09f35ecb40ca47bfb"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Malicious reconnaissance</header><text>The term <term>malicious reconnaissance</term> means a method for actively probing or passively monitoring an information system for the purpose of discerning security vulnerabilities of the information system, if such method is associated with a known or suspected cybersecurity threat.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idf67bb949fcb445aca2a003c831f0ce13"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Monitor</header><text>The term <term>monitor</term> means to acquire, identify, or scan, or to possess, information that is stored on, processed by, or transiting an information system.</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="id1c568a5fa8834920b74beda78edcf77f"><enum>(15)</enum><header>Private entity</header>
 <subparagraph id="id0E7F7023274F4BE9AD0AD2B964AEE9DC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as otherwise provided in this paragraph, the term <term>private entity</term> means any person or private group, organization, proprietorship, partnership, trust, cooperative, corporation, or other commercial or nonprofit entity, including an officer, employee, or agent thereof.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id88B4A4D7938A4519A26B500815CC3F01"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusion</header><text>The term <term>private entity</term> includes a State, tribal, or local government performing electric utility services.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0f1fb3365c6241c59b4d531682c565f0"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text>The term <term>private entity</term> does not include a foreign power as defined in section 101 of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1801">50 U.S.C. 1801</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9fc26e5c0fdb47dca1959b170081bf59"><enum>(16)</enum><header>Security control</header><text>The term <term>security control</term> means the management, operational, and technical controls used to protect against an unauthorized effort to adversely affect the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of an information system or its information.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id95985de5ebd54d19a6dc01958ff098fa"><enum>(17)</enum><header>Security vulnerability</header><text>The term <term>security vulnerability</term> means any attribute of hardware, software, process, or procedure that could enable or facilitate the defeat of a security control.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id1ff0154c145d47d898d82584e5b887a0"><enum>(18)</enum><header>Tribal</header><text>The term <term>tribal</term> has the meaning given the term <term>Indian tribe</term> in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/450b">25 U.S.C. 450b</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph></section><section id="ide272b572449646ad8add7175c744bf49"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sharing of information by the Federal Government</header> <subsection id="id60DEB92652994092B3BD9A557EBF9C00"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Consistent with the protection of classified information, intelligence sources and methods, and privacy and civil liberties, the Director of National Intelligence, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Secretary of Defense, and the Attorney General, in consultation with the heads of the appropriate Federal entities, shall develop and promulgate procedures to facilitate and promote—</text>
 <paragraph id="id17178d7f14d5447ba2cf74d8d0754f8d"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the timely sharing of classified cyber threat indicators in the possession of the Federal Government with cleared representatives of relevant entities;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idaa37297793944613b57d44e7ef4a28ba"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the timely sharing with relevant entities of cyber threat indicators or information in the possession of the Federal Government that may be declassified and shared at an unclassified level;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id587c88ae4a724f7486685d3cb9d2d393"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the sharing with relevant entities, or the public if appropriate, of unclassified, including controlled unclassified, cyber threat indicators in the possession of the Federal Government; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id5691FEB935454D38A0876D8C496F1A0D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the sharing with entities, if appropriate, of information in the possession of the Federal Government about cybersecurity threats to such entities to prevent or mitigate adverse effects from such cybersecurity threats.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id922aa5c9ab7642759ccea3085ddfaef9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Development of procedures</header>
 <paragraph id="idf200c18b8c8d46d59fcd156a08154542"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The procedures developed and promulgated under subsection (a) shall—</text> <subparagraph id="id8af1c5fbcf7b4b17a1b8602c5488a029"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ensure the Federal Government has and maintains the capability to share cyber threat indicators in real time consistent with the protection of classified information;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide44e737d03e74500a0988f66f4f15a0c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>incorporate, to the greatest extent practicable, existing processes and existing roles and responsibilities of Federal and non-Federal entities for information sharing by the Federal Government, including sector specific information sharing and analysis centers;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD4D680545DBB4D0683C44A982BA470C8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>include procedures for notifying entities that have received a cyber threat indicator from a Federal entity under this Act that is known or determined to be in error or in contravention of the requirements of this Act or another provision of Federal law or policy of such error or contravention;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id21bf0801e7ab4ecc98bf54f5623308e7"><enum>(D)</enum><text>include requirements for Federal entities receiving cyber threat indicators or defensive measures to implement and utilize security controls to protect against unauthorized access to or acquisition of such cyber threat indicators or defensive measures; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8731035ee9cb4b3799150b4faa2a49dc"><enum>(E)</enum><text>include procedures that require a Federal entity, prior to the sharing of a cyber threat indicator—</text> <clause id="id62c309c20c714affa1590f20773434b5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to review such cyber threat indicator to assess whether such cyber threat indicator contains any information that such Federal entity knows at the time of sharing to be personal information of or identifying a specific person not directly related to a cybersecurity threat and remove such information; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="id95bb868c37d54dae8b139a0172961aab"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to implement and utilize a technical capability configured to remove any personal information of or identifying a specific person not directly related to a cybersecurity threat.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id88f37ed9ddcf415c91085b6d0cf60d5d"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>In developing the procedures required under this section, the Director of National Intelligence, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Secretary of Defense, and the Attorney General shall coordinate with appropriate Federal entities, including the National Laboratories (as defined in section 2 of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/15801">42 U.S.C. 15801</external-xref>)), to ensure that effective protocols are implemented that will facilitate and promote the sharing of cyber threat indicators by the Federal Government in a timely manner.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id01034de7deaa45c1a3883845c6a94e5f"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Submittal to Congress</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of National Intelligence, in consultation with the heads of the appropriate Federal entities, shall submit to Congress the procedures required by subsection (a).</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="idc220a261d0c34c7ea5df4103764ca4a6"><enum>4.</enum><header>Authorizations for preventing, detecting, analyzing, and mitigating cybersecurity threats</header>
			<subsection id="idd550b0c82d524ff9a8d38985eb37851e"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization for monitoring</header>
 <paragraph id="idDB27390EFA5F41FF97FDAA4AEF62CD72"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a private entity may, for cybersecurity purposes, monitor—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id74adfb4028e94cc29bdf57ae9d35de27"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an information system of such private entity;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id045a1dc05ec34ea7b419984c9b3b5ba0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an information system of another entity, upon the authorization and written consent of such other entity;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id94d8a7d84c304e979aa66f69894ec07e"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an information system of a Federal entity, upon the authorization and written consent of an authorized representative of the Federal entity; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd1537e93404445dba2655931b805c747"><enum>(D)</enum><text>information that is stored on, processed by, or transiting an information system monitored by the private entity under this paragraph.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9450ca4516e84034a89ab975eb457ebe"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Construction</header><text>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed—</text> <subparagraph id="id44B1BC0D3D6A4F55887FD75883BD64F0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to authorize the monitoring of an information system, or the use of any information obtained through such monitoring, other than as provided in this Act; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7CDDD5F642C340789ABB4B2FDC71EDA9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to limit otherwise lawful activity.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5024fba425fd40c6a8c34e8139619def"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorization for operation of defensive measures</header>
 <paragraph id="idD6133CA490934BC59B9909539483DDAB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a private entity may, for cybersecurity purposes, operate a defensive measure that is applied to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id1b1394c2ffe242f8b323473c77cc80a9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an information system of such private entity in order to protect the rights or property of the private entity;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id75de45e29dc94653ae72747204a7338e"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an information system of another entity upon written consent of such entity for operation of such defensive measure to protect the rights or property of such entity; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd819986e1f004dbb9b7d9673cb573516"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an information system of a Federal entity upon written consent of an authorized representative of such Federal entity for operation of such defensive measure to protect the rights or property of the Federal Government.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id710EC71FC0D64DE3AD3F53AB74EEE36D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Construction</header><text>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed—</text> <subparagraph id="idDE240D7CDF844BBCA901A8278CD1355C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to authorize the use of a defensive measure other than as provided in this subsection; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA2583FDFA80C4F45A19D485861996849"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to limit otherwise lawful activity.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id15b2286059ea465fa50995c1c53ac62d"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization for sharing or receiving cyber threat indicators or defensive measures</header> <paragraph id="idC45ACCCE3F664AF69548C7905E7D17BC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2) and notwithstanding any other provision of law, an entity may, for the purposes permitted under this Act and consistent with the protection of classified information, share with, or receive from, any other entity or the Federal Government a cyber threat indicator or defensive measure.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idD048C56DEE8245F38BDCC9FD4C52578C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Lawful restriction</header><text>An entity receiving a cyber threat indicator or defensive measure from another entity or Federal entity shall comply with otherwise lawful restrictions placed on the sharing or use of such cyber threat indicator or defensive measure by the sharing entity or Federal entity.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id06E7B35EA8F44AA58B27CFDCDADC64A3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Construction</header><text>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed—</text> <subparagraph id="idAA3CB71E5CD84159986B359496DA9FC6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to authorize the sharing or receiving of a cyber threat indicator or defensive measure other than as provided in this subsection; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id61F53768004A4DF682C350E52E60506F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to limit otherwise lawful activity.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id587f30812c154c47b7a72dbcec9a83bd"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Protection and use of information</header> <paragraph id="ida6094e1f362e4307a556581d7abffd60"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Security of information</header><text>An entity monitoring an information system, operating a defensive measure, or providing or receiving a cyber threat indicator or defensive measure under this section shall implement and utilize a security control to protect against unauthorized access to or acquisition of such cyber threat indicator or defensive measure.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ida331bc57ccbf4bffa8e657c0f8299c41"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Removal of certain personal information</header><text>An entity sharing a cyber threat indicator pursuant to this Act shall, prior to such sharing—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="idffbb5dad7c244f64899b96629f8a37c9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>review such cyber threat indicator to assess whether such cyber threat indicator contains any information that the entity knows at the time of sharing to be personal information of or identifying a specific person not directly related to a cybersecurity threat and remove such information; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id31dc63ccd4284240949250e9b1b14b6e"><enum>(B)</enum><text>implement and utilize a technical capability configured to remove any information contained within such indicator that the entity knows at the time of sharing to be personal information of or identifying a specific person not directly related to a cybersecurity threat.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id542108e23505448ebfa58823faea2ec2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Use of cyber threat indicators and defensive measures by entities</header>
 <subparagraph id="id09F209BD772541E796D9836514D9D478"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Consistent with this Act, a cyber threat indicator or defensive measure shared or received under this section may, for cybersecurity purposes—</text>
 <clause id="idc7c7d3fbd4f0412e8c4e336a500ae1f6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>be used by an entity to monitor or operate a defensive measure on—</text> <subclause id="id60A8B29F396E4C7D9D433D8632EBEECF"><enum>(I)</enum><text>an information system of the entity; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="idF3F0A12330BD44378A414F60D968A41E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>an information system of another entity or a Federal entity upon the written consent of that other entity or that Federal entity; and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="ida926c3ac486045348f9ca3330247567c"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>be otherwise used, retained, and further shared by an entity subject to—</text> <subclause id="id528040E3BA254ABB8108F6D333ACCB68"><enum>(I)</enum><text>an otherwise lawful restriction placed by the sharing entity or Federal entity on such cyber threat indicator or defensive measure; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id894F10C7053347A984E81725DEB7A5FD"><enum>(II)</enum><text>an otherwise applicable provision of law.</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2D4D0386EC12402AA790E18E135BDFBA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Construction</header><text>Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed to authorize the use of a cyber threat indicator or defensive measure other than as provided in this section.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide531a9590589423083371385be37d52b"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Use of cyber threat indicators by  State, tribal, or local government</header>
					<subparagraph id="idf28a4ddfd8d94413afa3ff626be9263a"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Law enforcement use</header>
 <clause id="id4B21ADA28A5D4F6F962ECD3A88A5D785"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Prior written consent</header><text>Except as provided in clause (ii), a cyber threat indicator shared with a State, tribal, or local government under this section may, with the prior written consent of the entity sharing such indicator, be used by a State, tribal, or local government for the purpose of preventing, investigating, or prosecuting any of the offenses described in section 5(d)(5)(A)(vi).</text>
 </clause><clause id="idA1B35615DC7E4F378B4A5F70BC410325"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Oral consent</header><text>If exigent circumstances prevent obtaining written consent under clause (i), such consent may be provided orally with subsequent documentation of the consent.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id85179ad1c3184c86b2d5ab0249a086e0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exemption from disclosure</header><text>A cyber threat indicator shared with a State, tribal, or local government under this section shall be—</text>
 <clause id="idEFD5B8F6BCBD4719892C94B7EE07DEF3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>deemed voluntarily shared information; and</text> </clause><clause id="id01453FCD88A94F66B47EEC1C78660123"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>exempt from disclosure under any State, tribal, or local law requiring disclosure of information or records.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id689e729395e8448fbcdbac024ac4c65f"><enum>(C)</enum><header>State, tribal, and local regulatory authority</header>
 <clause id="id1F0817CB4A9B4A3BB6C7B6DE89205F83"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in clause (ii), a cyber threat indicator or defensive measure shared with a State, tribal, or local government under this Act shall not be directly used by any State, tribal, or local government to regulate, including an enforcement action, the lawful activity of any entity, including an activity relating to monitoring, operating a defensive measure, or sharing of a cyber threat indicator.</text>
 </clause><clause id="id1D203FF03AC7488BBD26DBA7DF1F5448"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Regulatory authority specifically relating to prevention or mitigation of cybersecurity threats</header><text>A cyber threat indicator or defensive measures shared as described in clause (i) may, consistent with a State, tribal, or local government regulatory authority specifically relating to the prevention or mitigation of cybersecurity threats to information systems, inform the development or implementation of a regulation relating to such information systems.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idca6ef7800a0749e3846b9957943213ef"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Antitrust exemption</header>
 <paragraph id="idBB17B5D2F92B400194DE548260A909BA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in section 8(e), it shall not be considered a violation of any provision of antitrust laws for 2 or more private entities to exchange or provide a cyber threat indicator, or assistance relating to the prevention, investigation, or mitigation of a cybersecurity threat, for cybersecurity purposes under this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idF128322AFA864B8997221B30E09358C6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>Paragraph (1) shall apply only to information that is exchanged or assistance provided in order to assist with—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id0d54aaad820143f08a40e5483d25bc97"><enum>(A)</enum><text>facilitating the prevention, investigation, or mitigation of a cybersecurity threat to an information system or information that is stored on, processed by, or transiting an information system; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id61ba9e5953bd4c018f2f39fbf1110345"><enum>(B)</enum><text>communicating or disclosing a cyber threat indicator to help prevent, investigate, or mitigate the effect of a cybersecurity threat to an information system or information that is stored on, processed by, or transiting an information system.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id544c084bb95644d484d2f897c79da9cd"><enum>(f)</enum><header>No right or benefit</header><text>The sharing of a cyber threat indicator with an entity under this Act shall not create a right or benefit to similar information by such entity or any other entity.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="id7aa014d8219640b0be5ba8486e0f5776"><enum>5.</enum><header>Sharing of cyber threat indicators and defensive measures with the Federal Government</header>
			<subsection id="idF4A427F16FBF41B48FE2A9275581CB4B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement for policies and procedures</header>
 <paragraph id="id562B6AE8A3424E2B8264ED2FBB5D083E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Interim policies and procedures</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Attorney General, in coordination with the heads of the appropriate Federal entities, shall develop and submit to Congress interim policies and procedures relating to the receipt of cyber threat indicators and defensive measures by the Federal Government.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id2A7F0128D1154A88A3A6245172D0B6C6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Final policies and procedures</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall, in coordination with the heads of the appropriate Federal entities, promulgate final policies and procedures relating to the receipt of cyber threat indicators and defensive measures by the Federal Government.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id9B662B7751CE4C79BFACB082FD05A044"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Requirements concerning policies and procedures</header><text>Consistent with the guidelines required by subsection (b), the policies and procedures developed and promulgated under this subsection shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id46848b1ab370433983dc66be06250f83"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ensure that cyber threat indicators are shared with the Federal Government by any entity pursuant to section 4(c) through the real-time process described in subsection (c) of this section—</text>
 <clause id="id83525bef716841da9ec642a5ee837ab0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>are shared in an automated manner with all of the appropriate Federal entities;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idBF4B7E7F9DF8408DA2E16EA1CE55EDFD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>are not subject to any delay, modification, or any other action that could impede real-time receipt by all of the appropriate Federal entities; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idd29644ade3514e2b997145512e9572af"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>may be provided to other Federal entities;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id20fee7f3d5e14cefac3d26ea24bbb426"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensure that cyber threat indicators shared with the Federal Government by any entity pursuant to section 4 in a manner other than the real-time process described in subsection (c) of this section—</text>
 <clause id="idE55D02C30F6B449CA568E5E566248803"><enum>(i)</enum><text>are shared as quickly as operationally practicable with all of the appropriate Federal entities;</text> </clause><clause id="id2A18CB52D7D7440EA25D33E62AEB9118"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>are not subject to any unnecessary delay, interference, or any other action that could impede receipt by all of the appropriate Federal entities; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id9105D63B7406406293D11A9F56C1B975"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>may be provided to other Federal entities;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd90508deb253401085cf9a53076dca5f"><enum>(C)</enum><text>consistent with this Act, any other applicable provisions of law, and the fair information practice principles set forth in appendix A of the document entitled <quote>National Strategy for Trusted Identities in Cyberspace</quote> and published by the President in April 2011, govern the retention, use, and dissemination by the Federal Government of cyber threat indicators shared with the Federal Government under this Act, including the extent, if any, to which such cyber threat indicators may be used by the Federal Government; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id390c6fb37dbe4361b3c04bc619ea9b51"><enum>(D)</enum><text>ensure there is—</text> <clause id="id5BAEAFAF49CC494D8D32E42EA1068FC6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an audit capability; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id6A2DDD66B1D547C9BF0F40F537C87B1B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>appropriate sanctions in place for officers, employees, or agents of a Federal entity who knowingly and willfully conduct activities under this Act in an unauthorized manner.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idF4B0BCB34ADC4EF48C7B755302EA2ED6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Guidelines for entities sharing cyber threat indicators with Federal Government</header>
 <subparagraph id="id16F4106B844649B4871F4053B8280A89"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall develop and make publicly available guidance to assist entities and promote sharing of cyber threat indicators with Federal entities under this Act.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5B00AC3DF5BF40548922813537E20ABC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The guidelines developed and made publicly available under subparagraph (A) shall include guidance on the following:</text>
 <clause id="ide466af24f4904150957a01bf01091527"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Identification of types of information that would qualify as a cyber threat indicator under this Act that would be unlikely to include personal information of or identifying a specific person not directly related to a cyber security threat.</text>
 </clause><clause id="idffdd60b0dbe84828aa33290e88ca24e8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Identification of types of information protected under otherwise applicable privacy laws that are unlikely to be directly related to a cybersecurity threat.</text>
 </clause><clause id="idf6328d9fb9fd499bb6e4e21a74aea344"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Such other matters as the Attorney General considers appropriate for entities sharing cyber threat indicators with Federal entities under this Act.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idc4e88348b4f741e6b631cee57276b7e3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Privacy and civil liberties</header>
 <paragraph id="id6680ED1E23CF4C0DBCA0BE106858360F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Guidelines of Attorney General</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall, in coordination with heads of the appropriate Federal entities and in consultation with officers designated under section 1062 of the National Security Intelligence Reform Act of 2004 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000ee-1">42 U.S.C. 2000ee–1</external-xref>), develop, submit to Congress, and make available to the public interim guidelines relating to privacy and civil liberties which shall govern the receipt, retention, use, and dissemination of cyber threat indicators by a Federal entity obtained in connection with activities authorized in this Act.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="id19A864680EA146A497F39CE15D4606D7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Final guidelines</header>
 <subparagraph id="idC611CA124C374C0E8CED941F42B47AA6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall, in coordination with heads of the appropriate Federal entities and in consultation with officers designated under section 1062 of the National Security Intelligence Reform Act of 2004 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000ee-1">42 U.S.C. 2000ee–1</external-xref>) and such private entities with industry expertise as the Attorney General considers relevant, promulgate final guidelines relating to privacy and civil liberties which shall govern the receipt, retention, use, and dissemination of cyber threat indicators by a Federal entity obtained in connection with activities authorized in this Act.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE071952D990A4562A6A4D6CD572AC577"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Periodic review</header><text>The Attorney General shall, in coordination with heads of the appropriate Federal entities and in consultation with officers and private entities described in subparagraph (A), periodically review the guidelines promulgated under subparagraph (A).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idd38b114fb48e4ed286601bc98d9b5b46"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Content</header><text>The guidelines required by paragraphs (1) and (2) shall, consistent with the need to protect information systems from cybersecurity threats and mitigate cybersecurity threats—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idF48AF86D46C14BB39F9797A98D64B1CB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>limit the impact on privacy and civil liberties of activities by the Federal Government under this Act;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id53B7C21C00D340ED97D9CA6E1C0E483E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>limit the receipt, retention, use, and dissemination of cyber threat indicators containing personal information of or identifying specific persons, including by establishing—</text>
 <clause id="id09B4555D69A24398BAA6734C3628DB34"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a process for the timely destruction of such information that is known not to be directly related to uses authorized under this Act; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id4F35A6A92ECE45BD890898FC67DE3EAA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>specific limitations on the length of any period in which a cyber threat indicator may be retained;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id29f3959c54434f549d88de486a12cb6e"><enum>(C)</enum><text>include requirements to safeguard cyber threat indicators containing personal information of or identifying specific persons from unauthorized access or acquisition, including appropriate sanctions for activities by officers, employees, or agents of the Federal Government in contravention of such guidelines;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8aaff28200b0440ca7a02c65394da273"><enum>(D)</enum><text>include procedures for notifying entities and Federal entities if information received pursuant to this section is known or determined by a Federal entity receiving such information not to constitute a cyber threat indicator;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc07b89ca741e4f2281bc8787da22148c"><enum>(E)</enum><text>protect the confidentiality of cyber threat indicators containing personal information of or identifying specific persons to the greatest extent practicable and require recipients to be informed that such indicators may only be used for purposes authorized under this Act; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0205777B9F4D49918D54B32D4F394712"><enum>(F)</enum><text>include steps that may be needed so that dissemination of cyber threat indicators is consistent with the protection of classified and other sensitive national security information.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="iddb705fe5b65947b59c9bbda071afefb5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Capability and process within the Department of Homeland Security</header>
 <paragraph id="id2ab86b40a5f14172826c12a273f89e21"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security, in coordination with the heads of the appropriate Federal entities, shall develop and implement a capability and process within the Department of Homeland Security that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id44ee3aafbad94167bb404d110a404054"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall accept from any entity in real time cyber threat indicators and defensive measures, pursuant to this section;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idaf6edbc862e14bceaba148302772d046"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall, upon submittal of the certification under paragraph (2) that such capability and process fully and effectively operates as described in such paragraph, be the process by which the Federal Government receives cyber threat indicators and defensive measures under this Act that are shared by a private entity with the Federal Government through electronic mail or media, an interactive form on an Internet website, or a real time, automated process between information systems except—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="ida4a6d3b6de884ddab47f2822a897566d"><enum>(i)</enum><text>communications between a Federal entity and a private entity regarding a previously shared cyber threat indicator; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="idb2889f4a630c4f3b9835f013a90cc94a"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>communications by a regulated entity with such entity's Federal regulatory authority regarding a cybersecurity threat;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id74228c1b10af4e2f9a04458781c9c40b"><enum>(C)</enum><text>ensures that all of the appropriate Federal entities receive in an automated manner such cyber threat indicators shared through the real-time process within the Department of Homeland Security;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id4658dd957f3a451396385a71f177d8ef"><enum>(D)</enum><text>is in compliance with the policies, procedures, and guidelines required by this section; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id4949F76333004EDE93160983224E2179"><enum>(E)</enum><text>does not limit or prohibit otherwise lawful disclosures of communications, records, or other information, including—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="id55E5D410080648D28DABF980329B77EB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>reporting of known or suspected criminal activity, by an entity to any other entity or a Federal entity;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="id68AE287726F0478F9DC5A27D149B5894"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>voluntary or legally compelled participation in a Federal investigation; and</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="id168293381BA84B839BE416B24E19B827"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>providing cyber threat indicators or defensive measures as part of a statutory or authorized contractual requirement.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idAFB54A8154BE419DA4A0CAD5731005AD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Certification</header><text>Not later than 10 days prior to the implementation of the capability and process required by paragraph (1), the Secretary of Homeland Security shall, in consultation with the heads of the appropriate Federal entities, certify to Congress whether such capability and process fully and effectively operates—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="idE28D93148B224B7EB6FBD70BD45B5EFE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>as the process by which the Federal Government receives from any entity a cyber threat indicator or defensive measure under this Act; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id106A6D13128D42E7A712537DB02031CD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in accordance with the policies, procedures, and guidelines developed under this section.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idbbd76c0a3411466f8f187c461899c97a"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public notice and access</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall ensure there is public notice of, and access to, the capability and process developed and implemented under paragraph (1) so that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id47F653902340407FAEE2C7315991BE04"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any entity may share cyber threat indicators and defensive measures through such process with the Federal Government; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB444C4C8BD244E7F92BDD05092FF1D06"><enum>(B)</enum><text>all of the appropriate Federal entities receive such cyber threat indicators and defensive measures in real time with receipt through the process within the Department of Homeland Security.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ida17d6de9ed734287a44a64a020d061c6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Other Federal entities</header><text>The process developed and implemented under paragraph (1) shall ensure that other Federal entities receive in a timely manner any cyber threat indicators and defensive measures shared with the Federal Government through such process.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="id17557069211545e79a2c9620f921f153"><enum>(5)</enum><header> Report on development and implementation</header>
 <subparagraph id="id000B97E78A814FE9B0A3212896692326"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit to Congress a report on the development and implementation of the capability and process required by paragraph (1), including a description of such capability and process and the public notice of, and access to, such process.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7161E1CA5F5C4E928692BCC57B3EF178"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Classified annex</header><text>The report required by subparagraph (A) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="iddae8dc75074c4b98a7e132d8a744a408"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Information shared with or provided to the Federal Government</header>
 <paragraph id="id9065ee798e41498595da5b9d27c8ae9a"><enum>(1)</enum><header>No waiver of privilege or protection</header><text>The provision of cyber threat indicators and defensive measures to the Federal Government under this Act shall not constitute a waiver of any applicable privilege or protection provided by law, including trade secret protection.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id3C35A115EA704CA284C8019913B6B668"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Proprietary information</header><text>Consistent with section 4(c)(2), a cyber threat indicator or defensive measure provided by an entity to the Federal Government under this Act shall be considered the commercial, financial, and proprietary information of such entity when so designated by the originating entity or a third party acting in accordance with the written authorization of the originating entity.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id7fca19fc3add4e38a5ca2ffccfbd3920"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exemption from disclosure</header><text>Cyber threat indicators and defensive measures provided to the Federal Government under this Act shall be—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id49C6040B9979451B9B6B4D7CF55200C4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>deemed voluntarily shared information and exempt from disclosure under section 552 of title 5, United States Code, and any State, tribal, or local law requiring disclosure of information or records; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1DC432B22621405FB766EA876DBB4E21"><enum>(B)</enum><text>withheld, without discretion, from the public under section 552(b)(3)(B) of title 5, United States Code, and any State, tribal, or local provision of law requiring disclosure of information or records.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id30c7cf5b0901423dbc881bbf1162920d"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Ex parte communications</header><text>The provision of a cyber threat indicator or defensive measure to the Federal Government under this Act shall not be subject to a rule of any Federal agency or department or any judicial doctrine regarding ex parte communications with a decisionmaking official.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="id59233618d29b4833b1ac319f6f6d7d44"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Disclosure, retention, and use</header>
 <subparagraph id="id7E37CEEA30DD42F1825FC17937D572A2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Authorized activities</header><text>Cyber threat indicators and defensive measures provided to the Federal Government under this Act may be disclosed to, retained by, and used by, consistent with otherwise applicable provisions of Federal law, any Federal agency or department, component, officer, employee, or agent of the Federal Government solely for—</text>
 <clause id="idaf06042c50e74e5b8ec0b1f7075b3287"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a cybersecurity purpose;</text> </clause><clause id="id714D97D6684546FCABFA22F119FBA152"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the purpose of identifying a cybersecurity threat, including the source of such cybersecurity threat, or a security vulnerability;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id49EB5D715F2D4FCF9B3A9365699A2EA5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the purpose of identifying a cybersecurity threat involving the use of an information system by a foreign adversary or terrorist;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id54ee3cb88baf42a59f100f8506f4deda"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the purpose of responding to, or otherwise preventing or mitigating, an imminent threat of death, serious bodily harm, or serious economic harm, including a terrorist act or a use of a weapon of mass destruction;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idFCF9D140F9974FF9BA081A55CA28CB3D"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the purpose of responding to, or otherwise preventing or mitigating, a serious threat to a minor, including sexual exploitation and threats to physical safety; or</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="idb506d03ef20e4285a387fe03f8dfa7a2"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the purpose of preventing, investigating, disrupting, or prosecuting an offense arising out of a threat described in clause (iv) or any of the offenses listed in—</text>
 <subclause commented="no" id="id6FFDC2406B074668BFC89C52F09F4ACA"><enum>(I)</enum><text>section 3559(c)(2)(F) of title 18, United States Code (relating to serious violent felonies);</text> </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="id4A52A1ABCE76493CA28CEC9E07FBA367"><enum>(II)</enum><text>sections 1028 through 1030 of such title (relating to fraud and identity theft);</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="id91767279A0FA4C4E8CCB83722B6335F0"><enum>(III)</enum><text>chapter 37 of such title (relating to espionage and censorship); and</text> </subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id65F3C175E2CA45BFABDD54FF80033130"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>chapter 90 of such title (relating to protection of trade secrets).</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id0eac03d62bf34dd5a15a96712a4cc176"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Prohibited activities</header><text>Cyber threat indicators and defensive measures provided to the Federal Government under this Act shall not be disclosed to, retained by, or used by any Federal agency or department for any use not permitted under subparagraph (A).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0bbc2ab9a8ea4195be0389994d9b23de"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Privacy and civil liberties</header><text>Cyber threat indicators and defensive measures provided to the Federal Government under this Act shall be retained, used, and disseminated by the Federal Government—</text>
 <clause id="id1089c9a8162f46c2be9642433e38162a"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in accordance with the policies, procedures, and guidelines required by subsections (a) and (b);</text> </clause><clause id="id962b067ce7d74e71a0d4f63b58879412"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in a manner that protects from unauthorized use or disclosure any cyber threat indicators that may contain personal information of or identifying specific persons; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2307b2e7658a4d15994b310064ebb505"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in a manner that protects the confidentiality of cyber threat indicators containing personal information of or identifying a specific person.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2f06afa647834a7886338b680abe67b2"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Federal regulatory authority</header>
 <clause commented="no" id="idAA84E14692C74F77AAAB3CFFE3DAF905"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in clause (ii), cyber threat indicators and defensive measures provided to the Federal Government under this Act shall not be directly used by any Federal, State, tribal, or local government to regulate, including an enforcement action, the lawful activities of any entity, including activities relating to monitoring, operating defensive measures, or sharing cyber threat indicators.</text>
						</clause><clause id="id07E20EBBCF3F4F5AA36A56400049B089"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Exceptions</header>
 <subclause commented="no" id="idCBF33B278D07494EB1B9BFABF96E564E"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Regulatory authority specifically relating to prevention or mitigation of cybersecurity threats</header><text>Cyber threat indicators and defensive measures provided to the Federal Government under this Act may, consistent with Federal or State regulatory authority specifically relating to the prevention or mitigation of cybersecurity threats to information systems, inform the development or implementation of regulations relating to such information systems.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id176DA9CF7D734C1BA1BE3C1FCD1D2534"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Procedures developed and implemented under this Act</header><text>Clause (i) shall not apply to procedures developed and implemented under this Act.</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idc6842ed051194cfda77e2d250867c1f7"><enum>6.</enum><header>Protection from liability</header> <subsection id="idA56F9B9D8920425C821356A66C4BB593"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Monitoring of information systems</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No cause of action shall lie or be maintained in any court against any private entity, and such action shall be promptly dismissed, for the monitoring of information systems and information under section 4(a) that is conducted in accordance with this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id97dc00b638b84749a0fd175d94c3925e"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sharing or receipt of cyber threat indicators</header><text>No cause of action shall lie or be maintained in any court against any entity, and such action shall be promptly dismissed, for the sharing or receipt of cyber threat indicators or defensive measures under section 4(c) if—</text>
 <paragraph id="idFBE18C0605034B43A0780EBF456D16AC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>such sharing or receipt is conducted in accordance with this Act; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id0130D4E9A3E84202B4265D8C7E5F925D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in a case in which a cyber threat indicator or defensive measure is shared with the Federal Government, the cyber threat indicator or defensive measure is shared in a manner that is consistent with section 5(c)(1)(B) and the sharing or receipt, as the case may be, occurs after the earlier of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id2F9C00725094490D93F8202AE7AC183A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the date on which the interim policies and procedures are submitted to Congress under section 5(a)(1); or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6F3642FC5ED546E5A26CD56AD35A7D7B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the date that is 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1a00df004fff47cfabd2fc8e4aeb6824"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed—</text>
 <paragraph id="id2628A749FBAE4BFDBDEA971ED403810C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to require dismissal of a cause of action against an entity that has engaged in gross negligence or willful misconduct in the course of conducting activities authorized by this Act; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id35E92FB4FEFC403BBF909950A67987A4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to undermine or limit the availability of otherwise applicable common law or statutory defenses.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id17447f6b123447758c2de795a3e321f1"><enum>7.</enum><header>Oversight of Government activities</header> <subsection id="idE4EF5DD3988D413E95B568BCE925A888"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Biennial report on implementation</header> <paragraph id="idF7792866F1EF4DBEB79FFDEB07596A81"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and not less frequently than once every 2 years thereafter, the heads of the appropriate Federal entities shall jointly submit and the Inspector General of the Department of Homeland Security, the Inspector General of the Intelligence Community, the Inspector General of the Department of Justice, the Inspector General of the Department of Defense, and the Inspector General of the Department of Energy, in consultation with the Council of Inspectors General on Financial Oversight, shall jointly submit to Congress a detailed report concerning the implementation of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id4AE32785598848C698AD7EF79DA8CE26"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each report submitted under paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text> <subparagraph id="id3852b6f274374eb1b3ab4dbe0f227301"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An assessment of the sufficiency of the policies, procedures, and guidelines required by section 5 in ensuring that cyber threat indicators are shared effectively and responsibly within the Federal Government.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf97d8842dde7429ab273a8a72d7d6be6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An evaluation of the effectiveness of real-time information sharing through the capability and process developed under section 5(c), including any impediments to such real-time sharing.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idef4a7c10103c4ba1ba2f4f5827eb90e6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An assessment of the sufficiency of the procedures developed under section 3 in ensuring that cyber threat indicators in the possession of the Federal Government are shared in a timely and adequate manner with appropriate entities, or, if appropriate, are made publicly available.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3ef99b7506ed4725b88bcf3b26878353"><enum>(D)</enum><text>An assessment of whether cyber threat indicators have been properly classified and an accounting of the number of security clearances authorized by the Federal Government for the purposes of this Act.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9e05ebad3c344f0b892ecf0f0e47085b"><enum>(E)</enum><text>A review of the type of cyber threat indicators shared with the Federal Government under this Act, including the following:</text>
 <clause id="id2B4083E2628F425192F0F93F9BE56929"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The degree to which such information may impact the privacy and civil liberties of specific persons.</text>
 </clause><clause id="idD7E07621B03342FC8520747A004FD6AD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A quantitative and qualitative assessment of the impact of the sharing of such cyber threat indicators with the Federal Government on privacy and civil liberties of specific persons.</text>
 </clause><clause id="id5FF176C4EBD94EBC9CEF41B2EA547A0A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The adequacy of any steps taken by the Federal Government to reduce such impact.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id08fc3a9133104c3baf7a38569b754d58"><enum>(F)</enum><text>A review of actions taken by the Federal Government based on cyber threat indicators shared with the Federal Government under this Act, including the appropriateness of any subsequent use or dissemination of such cyber threat indicators by a Federal entity under section 5.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb5b648c83f0d43b287b7d668eaef001c"><enum>(G)</enum><text>A description of any significant violations of the requirements of this Act by the Federal Government.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8b2f1d8433814428ade548d97c87f735"><enum>(H)</enum><text>A summary of the number and type of entities that received classified cyber threat indicators from the Federal Government under this Act and an evaluation of the risks and benefits of sharing such cyber threat indicators.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idd9554f38981740998167f6db541366b4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Recommendations</header><text>Each report submitted under paragraph (1) may include recommendations for improvements or modifications to the authorities and processes under this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id8b279b70a56247d7850d2652285cfd28"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Form of report</header><text>Each report required by paragraph (1) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id55db35d3c60146b0a1634ae21599f03f"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reports on privacy and civil liberties</header>
 <paragraph id="idad3dfb9c95a84fe59cb725fad2904849"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Biennial report from Privacy and Civil Liberties Oversight Board</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act and not less frequently than once every 2 years thereafter, the Privacy and Civil Liberties Oversight Board shall submit to Congress and the President a report providing—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idaa62163796c9482b8d7ab37fd5499661"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an assessment of the effect on privacy and civil liberties by the type of activities carried out under this Act; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4fa6087e051045f88990a26df97743ed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an assessment of the sufficiency of the policies, procedures, and guidelines established pursuant to section 5 in addressing concerns relating to privacy and civil liberties.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="iddf317d62d98b45e69576eac9305b0ae9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Biennial report of Inspectors general</header>
 <subparagraph id="id138051056BAB4C1FBC824C06F277BF28"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act and not less frequently than once every 2 years thereafter, the Inspector General of the Department of Homeland Security, the Inspector General of the Intelligence Community, the Inspector General of the Department of Justice, the Inspector General of the Department of Defense, and the Inspector General of the Department of Energy shall, in consultation with the Council of Inspectors General on Financial Oversight, jointly submit to Congress a report on the receipt, use, and dissemination of cyber threat indicators and defensive measures that have been shared with Federal entities under this Act.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1DE9148571C74CC188D42FB66C2AA983"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Each report submitted under subparagraph (A) shall include the following:</text> <clause id="id86dcdbef4fe841e4b4b3d4d0443f316b"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A review of the types of cyber threat indicators shared with Federal entities.</text>
 </clause><clause id="id1bfef3fef3304ab4956bd39b515c6b8a"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A review of the actions taken by Federal entities as a result of the receipt of such cyber threat indicators.</text>
 </clause><clause id="id0ce37ba80e424fbe86b4ffc95a320f43"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>A list of Federal entities receiving such cyber threat indicators.</text> </clause><clause id="id04c26c1c89424bc094682760a4d80fea"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>A review of the sharing of such cyber threat indicators among Federal entities to identify inappropriate barriers to sharing information.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id2f4b2fd399fc4ae3a2aa5d7a721809f4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Recommendations</header><text>Each report submitted under this subsection may include such recommendations as the Privacy and Civil Liberties Oversight Board, with respect to a report submitted under paragraph (1), or the Inspectors General referred to in paragraph (2)(A), with respect to a report submitted under paragraph (2), may have for improvements or modifications to the authorities under this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id20850f3c5d8943dbaf14895d0e9d513e"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Form</header><text>Each report required under this subsection shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id898778e8394a4fe4ad6887b0a43e323a"><enum>8.</enum><header>Construction and preemption</header>
 <subsection id="id01094e3d32d84751adb549236c55ae3c"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Otherwise lawful disclosures</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed—</text> <paragraph id="id421AB63E624143778D2CFBF8B71AE4CF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to limit or prohibit otherwise lawful disclosures of communications, records, or other information, including reporting of known or suspected criminal activity, by an entity to any other entity or the Federal Government under this Act; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id69BDBAC8799C49E3A821441D08D5455B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to limit or prohibit otherwise lawful use of such disclosures by any Federal entity, even when such otherwise lawful disclosures duplicate or replicate disclosures made under this Act.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id3b0460af5e864c82b35f384a55e46052"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Whistle blower protections</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to prohibit or limit the disclosure of information protected under section 2302(b)(8) of title 5, United States Code (governing disclosures of illegality, waste, fraud, abuse, or public health or safety threats), section 7211 of title 5, United States Code (governing disclosures to Congress), section 1034 of title 10, United States Code (governing disclosure to Congress by members of the military), section 1104 of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3234">50 U.S.C. 3234</external-xref>) (governing disclosure by employees of elements of the intelligence community), or any similar provision of Federal or State law.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id0428049fd23d498f8726928467ba72c4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Protection of sources and methods</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed—</text> <paragraph id="id1e77f6c5be6d4bc498e4f3d0b548e80a"><enum>(1)</enum><text>as creating any immunity against, or otherwise affecting, any action brought by the Federal Government, or any agency or department thereof, to enforce any law, executive order, or procedure governing the appropriate handling, disclosure, or use of classified information;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id5a648a7f478445af8fae3a8818867252"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to affect the conduct of authorized law enforcement or intelligence activities; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id831996503a3b455fa9d4ea31cca7b6ea"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to modify the authority of a department or agency of the Federal Government to protect classified information and sources and methods and the national security of the United States.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id52d5f3a83ecc471f90bd1edf09a99d23"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Relationship to other laws</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to affect any requirement under any other provision of law for an entity to provide information to the Federal Government.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id09bd6b0d51e1459c9e5ec1a3f437a4b7"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Prohibited conduct</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to permit price-fixing, allocating a market between competitors, monopolizing or attempting to monopolize a market, boycotting, or exchanges of price or cost information, customer lists, or information regarding future competitive planning.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id0368eef2178849c7aefb212bd9af543b"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Information sharing relationships</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed—</text> <paragraph id="id9e1f9b73e5644e58ab28bb21ae4bc802"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to limit or modify an existing information sharing relationship;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id9a330e2010a04e84b09fc175f1b6e19a"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to prohibit a new information sharing relationship;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id66bcf9a068a140b99eb5fcb43fc1756e"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to require a new information sharing relationship between any entity and the Federal Government; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id9d383d9defeb4873879900d9607d47ed"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to require the use of the capability and process within the Department of Homeland Security developed under section 5(c).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="idE5357ED55B784464B28AD07F58B503D4"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Preservation of contractual obligations and rights</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed—</text> <paragraph id="id1971448dd2694a959980eee0f37b4fa7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to amend, repeal, or supersede any current or future contractual agreement, terms of service agreement, or other contractual relationship between any entities, or between any entity and a Federal entity; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idDC7096C89EA747C4935C7F2A8A8FE619"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to abrogate trade secret or intellectual property rights of any entity or Federal entity.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idfc76defb0e374ca2af80fae94395eab1"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Anti-Tasking restriction</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to permit the Federal Government—</text>
 <paragraph id="id9799dd6d733545b8893b4b08126ca85c"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to require an entity to provide information to the Federal Government;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id707a8c0eeb50482fa43ad91ebae21779"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to condition the sharing of cyber threat indicators with an entity on such entity’s provision of cyber threat indicators to the Federal Government; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idEC05A50E34E14EA392E8C2073F545B48"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to condition the award of any Federal grant, contract, or purchase on the provision of a cyber threat indicator to a Federal entity.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id166289c7280b426692f84d11fc89245f"><enum>(i)</enum><header>No liability for non-Participation</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to subject any entity to liability for choosing not to engage in the voluntary activities authorized in this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id8f83fea1bb424982a443ed0a45348031"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Use and retention of information</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to authorize, or to modify any existing authority of, a department or agency of the Federal Government to retain or use any information shared under this Act for any use other than permitted in this Act.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="id0ebbc5ec18b344fc9a62946d240cd1aa"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Federal preemption</header>
 <paragraph id="id1b518304a8e341f297ae1fd88a7016b5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>This Act supersedes any statute or other provision of law of a State or political subdivision of a State that restricts or otherwise expressly regulates an activity authorized under this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idd735561560c94aac89a78e67e5d83c14"><enum>(2)</enum><header>State law enforcement</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to supersede any statute or other provision of law of a State or political subdivision of a State concerning the use of authorized law enforcement practices and procedures.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idC2B69684B97946DB95AE520587D3BC3A"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Regulatory authority</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed—</text> <paragraph id="id3554DA6E85034573813908982840758B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to authorize the promulgation of any regulations not specifically authorized by this Act;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id86067F7520B4499B866349D8F1DF6E0E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to establish or limit any regulatory authority not specifically established or limited under this Act; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id64A7E6012A344CA385F6955A5BDB056E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to authorize regulatory actions that would duplicate or conflict with regulatory requirements, mandatory standards, or related processes under another provision of Federal law.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="id0A1A27EF81FF4CB4991EB890DD9B3E79"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Authority of Secretary of Defense To respond to cyber attacks</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to limit the authority of the Secretary of Defense to develop, prepare, coordinate, or, when authorized by the President to do so, conduct a military cyber operation in response to a malicious cyber activity carried out against the United States or a United States person by a foreign government or an organization sponsored by a foreign government or a terrorist organization.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HC8808302347C" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>9.</enum><header>Report on cybersecurity threats</header>
 <subsection id="id319c98d8c890488ea2b4da1fc36a1a28"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report required</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of National Intelligence, in coordination with the heads of other appropriate elements of the intelligence community, shall submit to the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives a report on cybersecurity threats, including cyber attacks, theft, and data breaches.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idAABD4A36414A4923948A0D6AAA4D1E81"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall include the following:</text> <paragraph id="id9b1e0e0223d344a2bcc1f35ff5ca139d"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An assessment of the current intelligence sharing and cooperation relationships of the United States with other countries regarding cybersecurity threats, including cyber attacks, theft, and data breaches, directed against the United States and which threaten the United States national security interests and economy and intellectual property, specifically identifying the relative utility of such relationships, which elements of the intelligence community participate in such relationships, and whether and how such relationships could be improved.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id28a5353763b44f3eb432e2cb164ced1f"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A list and an assessment of the countries and nonstate actors that are the primary threats of carrying out a cybersecurity threat, including a cyber attack, theft, or data breach, against the United States and which threaten the United States national security, economy, and intellectual property.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id828caee5365c4b249cbfed9a1266ffc5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A description of the extent to which the capabilities of the United States Government to respond to or prevent cybersecurity threats, including cyber attacks, theft, or data breaches, directed against the United States private sector are degraded by a delay in the prompt notification by private entities of such threats or cyber attacks, theft, and breaches.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idb66f1fd645c04a44857613c169a72508"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An assessment of additional technologies or capabilities that would enhance the ability of the United States to prevent and to respond to cybersecurity threats, including cyber attacks, theft, and data breaches.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ide21f74c3df7a4c5094f37035251cb41e"><enum>(5)</enum><text>An assessment of any technologies or practices utilized by the private sector that could be rapidly fielded to assist the intelligence community in preventing and responding to cybersecurity threats.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id902c7f7e1ff04b75acd854275f832d2e"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Form of report</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall be made available in classified and unclassified forms.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idA121043EDE794607B8B50F6A369A0B95"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Intelligence community defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>intelligence community</term> has the meaning given that term in section 3 of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3003">50 U.S.C. 3003</external-xref>).</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="idd1aad41644974051a07957b0cab75563"><enum>10.</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header>
 <subsection id="id964DC277775F4B2EAEAA5EA6B1DC7EDE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Public information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 552(b) of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="id5e7a54adfd35440a809e95a822a52968"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (8), by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id45f29de37e68439798f7fa661d0006d7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (9), by striking <quote>wells.</quote> and inserting <quote>wells; or</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idc82d94b0b0dd43f2b290d8359a570730"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (9) the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id398794d4f8b945acbc48dcf6c37505a8" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="id36843ef1abce4195826ae1e8f6655503"><enum>(10)</enum><text>information shared with or provided to the Federal Government pursuant to the <short-title>Cybersecurity Information Sharing Act of 2015</short-title>.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id13968010FB134B62A2117E58BACDD4C9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Modification of limitation on dissemination of certain information concerning penetrations of defense contractor networks</header><text>Section 941(c)(3) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2013 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/239">Public Law 112–239</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/2224">10 U.S.C. 2224</external-xref> note) is amended by inserting at the end the following: <quote>The Secretary may share such information with other Federal entities if such information consists of cyber threat indicators and defensive measures and such information is shared consistent with the policies and procedures promulgated by the Attorney General under section 5 of the <short-title>Cybersecurity Information Sharing Act of 2015</short-title>.</quote>.</text></subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement><action-date>March 17, 2015</action-date><action-desc>Read twice and placed on the calendar</action-desc></endorsement></bill>


