<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1788 IS: SAFE KIDS Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1788</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150716">July 16, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S375">Mr. Daines</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require operators that provide online and similar services to educational agencies,
			 institutions, or programs to protect the privacy and security of
			 personally identifiable information, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H55CF721EF5864935841C76FBDDF42BF0" style="OLC">
 <section id="HD69C6EAE8228479D8A1B1E0096057722" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Safeguarding American Families from Exposure by Keeping Information and Data Secure Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote>SAFE KIDS Act</quote>.</text> </section><section id="H14B9913B00584943A174490EABC18560"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header> <subsection id="H6290D84AD60B4632B5C61AB8A66B6B4D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
 <paragraph id="HFB68679235A14699A354BFC72E0E18EB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Federal Trade Commission.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H6150230950B149D7A154D414C8F553A6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered information</header><text>The term <term>covered information</term> means personally identifiable information, and information that is linked or linkable to personally identifiable information, that—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HD87F194C160A4813AFA2DA574D421522"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is collected or generated through a school service; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HEE0D2E784FF94031B1D96FC65B1ACC32"><enum>(B)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H65BB6E2068DF41ABB8DA0102E8ACA10F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the operator of the school service knows or should know relates to a student; or</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H1251F72D657E4D05A2EF55E470C3AEFA" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is collected, generated, or maintained at the direction of an educational agency, institution, or program serving the student or officials of such an agency, institution, or program, including teachers.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id956ABC70B7724FFA91031C7549895699"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Early childhood education program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>early childhood education program</term> means a program that meets the requirements of clauses (i) and (ii)(III) of section 103(8)(C) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1003">20 U.S.C. 1003</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H2C371373749041AA99294D6F55DA74FC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Educational agency, institution, or program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>educational agency, institution, or program</quote> means—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="id83E8DF7682D243F1836985647EBD890A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an educational agency or institution, as defined in section 444(a)(3) of the General Education Provisions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1232g">20 U.S.C. 1232g(a)(3)</external-xref>), except that such term does not include an institution of higher education; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id866440C94521449C9CC3352816F6000B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an early childhood education program.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3B4B766BABC446F0B4B8C2BA46B73340"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Eligible student</header><text>The term <term>eligible student</term> means a student who—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE944DF18AF054D209B7576A6C5587C1D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is 18 years of age or older;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H458380CB685B40C2AAD8C6D338066CC1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is enrolled in an institution of higher education; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5CF55B7CC7EA470D87F9331222ABAE18"><enum>(C)</enum><text>has graduated from a secondary school.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H331E20B7A3DE4E1A9765BB3DA267A3F2"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>institution of higher education</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 102 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1002">20 U.S.C. 1002</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4A1B84E14AA4411BB4138184A7BF971F"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Pre<enum-in-header>K-12</enum-in-header> purposes</header><text>The term <term>PreK-12 purposes</term> means purposes that—</text> <subparagraph id="HFE1755F574F14F63A262BAD7A5D139A6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>aid in the administration of activities by an educational agency, institution, or program, including instruction in the classroom or at home, administrative activities, and collaboration between students, school personnel, or parents; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H330FDCDDFC254B7A970588F77C330B0A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are for the use and benefit of the educational agency, institution, or program.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H63C2E784F86048C1A07C51D649985E20"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Online contact information</header><text>The term <term>online contact information</term> means, with respect to a student, an email address or any other substantially similar identifier that permits direct contact with the student online, including an instant messaging user identifier, a voice over Internet protocol identifier, a video chat user identifier, or a screen name or user name that permits such contact.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD8663F4C01DB4AD98AD7593C0D992994"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Operator</header><text>The term <term>operator</term> means an entity that operates a school service, except that such term does not include an educational agency, institution, or program.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1CDF61449E1C4939B1FA232B0C26DFD0"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Personally identifiable information</header><text>The term <term>personally identifiable information</term> includes, with respect to a student—</text> <subparagraph id="HB576D5A931C446B4970B34B877A39E8E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the student’s first and last name;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB5F4519CDD814B9CBEBAEA2C284F8126"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the first and last name of the student’s parent or another family member;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC11B3A9C86234837A75F1EBE087A702D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the home or physical address of the student or student’s family;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2413CAEF08AE45D898B9A20088AF0F20"><enum>(D)</enum><text>online contact information for the student;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6267D8F6874445A298A8A5757B33B4EC"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a personal identifier, such as the student’s social security number, student number, or biometric record;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9E578422CAAC4616A0C389B97736F3FC"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a persistent identifier that can be used to recognize a user over time and across different Internet websites, online services, online applications, or mobile applications, including a customer number held in a cookie, an Internet Protocol address, a processor or device serial number, or another unique identifier;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H04BFE9419C6F4796B956EA125C33CD1F"><enum>(G)</enum><text>a photograph, video, or audio recording that contains the student’s image or voice;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H655492DAD4694F7FAED2F040D9D180EB"><enum>(H)</enum><text>geolocation information sufficient to identify the street name and name of a city or town;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAB6CAFF0976C47579C7671A4809A3571"><enum>(I)</enum><text>other indirect identifiers, such as the student’s date of birth, place of birth, or mother’s maiden name;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4143B1073DC245219D9717925885D8D4"><enum>(J)</enum><text>other information that, alone or in combination, would allow an operator or a reasonable person in the school community, who does not have personal knowledge of the relevant circumstances, to identify a specific student with reasonable certainty; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7D6FCC3488F440EBBF2BAF6D8E7E5C8B"><enum>(K)</enum><text>information requested by a person who the educational agency, institution, or program reasonably believes knows the identity of the student to whom the information relates.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC22BBB111992481292EFAF9BA41BFDF3"><enum>(11)</enum><header>School service</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>school service</term> means an Internet website, online service (including a cloud computing service), online application, or mobile application that is used for PreK-12 purposes and was designed and marketed for PreK-12 purposes.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAA67CF17602B408AA1901A7EEC772172"><enum>(12)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means each State of the United States, the District of Columbia, each territory or possession of the United States, and each federally recognized Indian tribe.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB6F207A74E854FB088FB4C518D88DF25"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Student</header><text>The term <term>student</term> means any individual who is or has been enrolled in an early childhood education program, elementary school, or secondary school.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HED7188478E784F25993CC25E60777BA9"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Targeted advertising</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HBFBC39229BAB455F9C8A63ED5DB7501C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>targeted advertising</term> means presenting advertisements to a student or the student’s parent, where the advertisements are selected based on information obtained or inferred from the student’s online behavior or use of online applications or mobile applications or from covered information about the student maintained by the operator of a school service.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HCFF2B77BDBA243D1B32E6B5AA5D2E177"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text>Such term does not include presenting advertisements to a student or the student’s parent at an online location or through an online application or mobile application, if—</text>
 <clause id="H255EBE8D75C64CD68F1327074599D303"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the advertisements are contextually relevant;</text> </clause><clause id="HC6F016FB7DCF42B99BFF4281B56987A6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the advertisements are selected based on a single visit or session of use during which the advertisements are presented; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA669F8F4D62E4E48BE5F5FF1FCBB2D26"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>information about the student’s online behavior or use of online applications or mobile applications is not collected or retained over time.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2FD49279454E483EB39634A5622BBDE3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Terms defined in Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965</header><text>In this Act, the terms <term>elementary school</term>, <term>parent</term>, and <term>secondary school</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 9101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H40314B203C2C4D028A9680C22B90D110"><enum>3.</enum><header>Protecting student privacy</header>
 <subsection id="H85FE77E8DB804E92A1C035B29A2C28D7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibited practices</header><text>An operator may not knowingly—</text> <paragraph id="H1E7C4ABC1E8F4C66ABB1872AA5F1D3DC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>engage in or permit targeted advertising on a school service;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD86EB254BA8C46DD97004F5B37EF874B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">collect, generate, use, or disclose any covered information for purposes of targeted advertising;</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H370E9DAD72AA4CFAB216839E3F416660"><enum>(3)</enum><text>sell covered information to a third party;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H52BC3A83D70C43C7A077917874460A09"><enum>(4)</enum><text>collect, generate, or use covered information (including using covered information to create a personal profile of a student) other than for PreK-12 purposes;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H680D8A0DC8494F59B6394475BA2AB22F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>disclose covered information, unless the disclosure is made—</text> <subparagraph id="H29859570E5C94C6DA9D71F8227CF5E6B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>pursuant to lawful process or to ensure legal and regulatory compliance with Federal or State law;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAE7A09F20B1A414CBF4950D370308BCD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in accordance with subsection (e), pursuant to an affirmative express request through a student's educational agency, institution, or program for disclosure of information specified in the request—</text>
 <clause id="H5E1653C4E9F045A98033DC9DB357D539"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the case of information about a student, from the student’s parent; or</text> </clause><clause id="HC0D94EB42A584C939D4CF60EDB885C64"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case of information about a student’s parent or another user of the school service, from the parent or such other user, as the case may be;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6c323b8fdd3a42d7b4386e36fe83c449"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in accordance with subsection (e), pursuant to an affirmative express request through a student’s educational agency, institution, or program from a student who is or has been enrolled in a secondary school, or the parent of such student, to disclose covered information specified in the request about the student to a third party in furtherance of postsecondary education or employment opportunities, for the purpose of—</text>
 <clause id="HE4073153763C4973B8F2DF850B68AB4D"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">providing or authenticating the student’s transcript, standardized test scores, letters of recommendation, or other information required by an institution of higher education for an application for admission or by a potential employer for an application for employment; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE9F31A27C3A04D368A4156AE75F118B4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>providing information relating to—</text> <subclause id="HF61FE80583A3441F97818886508327B2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>admission to an institution of higher education; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H0433779500EF4CEC8C696152C93F524D"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a scholarship or financial aid for attendance at an institution of higher education; or</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H09450A1990D446279CE855F0909FCA22"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to protect the safety of users or others or the security of the school service; or</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id219516d6ffe1423fb2e33c957e3bd9cf"><enum>(6)</enum><text>notwithstanding paragraph (5), disclose covered information to a third-party service provider of the school service unless the operator contractually requires the provider to comply with all the provisions of this Act (including such paragraph).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H34F27944AE944D77A05BE5F7DB3457E0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>An operator shall—</text> <paragraph id="H7956B15E634F46C788C03C9C24AE9A2B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establish, implement, and maintain reasonable security procedures appropriate to the nature of covered information to protect the confidentiality, security, and integrity of covered information;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H98C2EAC3BC6A438796F86A8EEA9E8A2D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">delete a student’s covered information that is not included in a student’s education records (as defined in section 444(a)(4) of the General Education Provisions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1232g">20 U.S.C. 1232g(a)(4)</external-xref>)) (commonly known as the <quote>Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974</quote>) within—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="id81704F63D01A4C9AA79EFE7DCF580EE9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a reasonable time, not to exceed 45 days, after receiving a request for deletion through an educational agency, institution, or program from the student’s parent; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide3ed77203ed74ebd9ae4c6a8c4d7371c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>within a reasonable time, not to exceed 2 years, after—</text> <clause id="idc9a6dc93b2eb4e6da7e1c51d275a63cf"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the information is no longer being used for PreK-12 purposes; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idd6fefee7605045ad88fc0706319ace04"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>providing notification, through an educational agency, institution, or program, to each student's parent of the impending deletion of the student's covered information;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idd7fe4bdd0cea4a26a1046a3706a98a7d"><enum>(3)</enum><text>obtain consent from the educational agency, institution, or program, through contracts or privacy policies in a manner that is clear and easy to understand, regarding the types of covered information collected or generated (if any), the purposes for which the covered information is used or disclosed to third parties, and the identity of any such third party;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id3d5b74018b21485ead90d5fa2d562344"><enum>(4)</enum><text>disclose publicly, on the website of the operator, every privacy policy that the operator has established with an educational agency, institution, or program;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id3e9d17651d40428b9f6d28ba053d5e4c"><enum>(5)</enum><text>obtain consent from the educational agency, institution, or program and provide sufficient notice on its website before making material changes to a contract or privacy policy for a school service; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idc77a7df221f0421f96ea296247b81b8a"><enum>(6)</enum><text>facilitate access to and correction of covered information, through an educational agency, institution, or program—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id97394a3390ad4d4582bb224b9b01a836"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of information about a student, by the student’s parent; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id24a5d36be976447496b37aeac45725c7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of information about a parent or another user of the school service, by the parent or such other user, as the case may be.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H914ED095A7F24F31A822058F54989666"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effect on mergers and acquisitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The prohibitions of this section on sale and disclosure of covered information do not apply to the merger of an operator with another entity or the acquisition of the operator by another entity (including any subsequent merger or acquisition), provided that the operator or successor entity continues to be subject to the provisions of this section with respect to covered information acquired before the merger or acquisition.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id31b8dc12090b4453b5241a3440194a04"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Continued application</header><text>This section shall continue to apply, after a student is no longer enrolled in an educational agency, institution, or program, to covered information relating to the student that was collected or generated while the student was enrolled.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id28C53A56C0D74A0A848934506856ACBA"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Requirements for certain disclosures</header><text>An operator may disclose covered information under subparagraph (B) or (C) of subsection (a)(5) only after the operator—</text>
 <paragraph id="id4593379fa4fa4cf29e70ffc933eded8d"><enum>(1)</enum><text>ensures that the third-party recipient has provided assurances that it will not further disclose covered information to subsequent third parties, use any covered information pursuant to the request for any purpose other than fulfilling the purpose for which the request was made, nor take any other action inconsistent with this Act;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id19c3717bf6ee402f99e55db56b8a1492"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ensures that the third-party recipient has provided assurances that it will establish, implement and maintain reasonable security procedures as described in subsection (b)(1); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id2f62e3c5c1404f71930da7bbb598e5bd"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provides a readily available mechanism for the requesting party to revoke the request.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H7A3B30121E17409E8F8D691CBCB9D341"><enum>4.</enum><header>Rules of construction</header> <subsection id="H621FD5FAA5744CBD9B2D5BFBFDA73A26"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>This Act shall not—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H6FD2C50CADAE4542A097D10EED4147CB"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be construed to affect or otherwise alter the protections and guarantees set forth in section 444 of the General Education Provisions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1232g">20 U.S.C. 1232g</external-xref>) (commonly known as the <quote>Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974</quote>), the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/6501">15 U.S.C. 6501 et seq.</external-xref>), or any other Federal statute relating to privacy protection;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H22F829F41586459F9436D4B7727B254A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>be construed to limit the authority of a law enforcement agency to obtain content or information from an operator as authorized by law or pursuant to an order of a court of competent jurisdiction;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HE2CE0978DB554A0B9144019877EAF393"><enum>(3)</enum><text>limit the ability of an operator to use information, including covered information, for adaptive or personalized student learning purposes;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HF5A27FAA5613419E8582C87EEF20F6C0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>limit an educational agency, institution, or program from providing Internet access service for its own use, to other educational agencies or institutions, or to students and their families;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H93067532A4094067A3375436D56BCB9E"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be construed to prohibit an operator’s use of covered information for maintaining, developing, supporting, improving, or diagnosing the operator’s school service;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2DD87B2F756046C7B67036620F8561FA"><enum>(6)</enum><text>impose a duty upon a provider of an electronic store, gateway, marketplace, or other means of purchasing or downloading software or applications to review or enforce compliance with this Act by operators of school services; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HF6E9A43B98F84243898E9EF8AB3FBA05"><enum>(7)</enum><text>impede the ability of a student or the student’s parent to download, export, create, or otherwise save or maintain data or documents created by or about the student or noncommercial applications created by the student, except to the extent any such activity would result in disclosure prohibited by this Act of covered information of other students or users of a school service.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDDFEA4A424644567B086B7394F29576E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>De-Identified  covered information</header>
 <paragraph id="H13D51FF16B53418DA88D37E57CC29F6A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Nothing in this Act prohibits an operator from—</text> <subparagraph id="H5BEDB4F0E9874DF98F3FDD3AEAD98024"><enum>(A)</enum><text>using de-identified covered information within the operator’s school service or other sites, services, or applications owned by the operator to improve educational products;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H96927DAF58F04493BB6FF6EDCD0F139A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>using de-identified covered information to demonstrate the effectiveness of the operator’s products or services, including in the marketing of such products or services; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H650CFD8A7A7F44AB98644F7574A315C4"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">disclosing de-identified covered information for research and development, including—</text>
 <clause id="HEC471397B1FF4F908D7EC4E8761C5BB7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>research, development, and improvement of educational sites, services, and applications; and</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="H3842AB151628458EBF245D0DE88D562E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>advancements in the science of learning.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H731D4DF5C8824D46BE440DB72B0C77ED"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Power To Consent and Rights Regarding Information About Eligible Student</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any provision of this Act that refers to the consent of the student’s parent for the use or disclosure of covered information or the right of the student’s parent to access or otherwise obtain, use, correct, request disclosure of, or request deletion of covered information, shall, in the case of covered information about an eligible student, be considered to refer to the consent or right of the student and not the student’s parent.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H25B8E4F872BD40F68214C091B5B3E9A2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>No effect on consent under other law</header><text>This Act does not modify the requirements or standards for consent, including consent from minors and employees on behalf of educational institutions, under any other provision of Federal law or under State law.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H937B84D1685C41CAA79072B6B97AB9CC"><enum>5.</enum><header>Implementation and enforcement</header>
			<subsection id="H0CEA91C517BA42788E8DAA179E985A5E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Enforcement by Federal Trade Commission</header>
 <paragraph id="H52DDCB5BCCC8468BAEF6DB0145D72DC0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Unfair or deceptive acts or practices</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A violation of this Act or a regulation promulgated under this Act shall be treated as a violation of a regulation under section 18(a)(1)(B) of the <act-name parsable-cite="FTCA">Federal Trade Commission Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/57a">15 U.S.C. 57a(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>) regarding unfair or deceptive acts or practices.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2749DB1DA02C44A8B14604E4632DA1B7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Powers of the Commission</header><text>The Commission shall enforce this Act and the regulations promulgated under this Act in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>) were incorporated into and made a part of this Act, and any person who violates this Act or a regulation promulgated under this Act shall be subject to the penalties entitled to the privileges and immunities provided in the Federal Trade Commission Act, except as provided in paragraph (3).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7A189F6DF9AB4E20B98A82F338AC27C8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Enforcement with respect to nonprofit organizations</header><text>Notwithstanding sections 4 and 5(a)(2) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/44">15 U.S.C. 44</external-xref>; 45(a)(2)), any jurisdictional limitation of the Commission with respect to nonprofit organizations shall not apply for purposes of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H0CBD1FA7DA624D1FB3DCFD84EEC7D14D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Preservation of Commission authority</header><text>Nothing in this Act may be construed in any way to limit or affect the Commission’s authority under any other provision of law.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5F989378161943F5980FC641A7D11204"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Commission may promulgate regulations under section 553 of title 5, United States Code, to carry out this Act. Such regulations shall further define the terms <term>targeted advertising</term>, <term>research, development, and improvement of educational sites, services, and applications</term>, <term>advancements in the science of learning</term>, <term>postsecondary education or employment opportunities</term>, and <term>adaptive or personalized student learning purposes</term>, as used in this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HAB183B8CE5AA422AA1EB34B588850D1D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Consultation and cooperation with Secretary of Education</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall consult and cooperate with the Secretary of Education in implementing and enforcing this Act, including in promulgating any regulations to carry out this Act, in matters involving educational agencies or institutions.</text>
			</subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HBD1C4B05226745479AED14FAE3426005"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Relationship to State law</header>
 <paragraph id="H12BDBE119C3C4B4CBD00B3F5A8C30D31"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>This Act does not annul, alter, or affect, or exempt any person subject to the provisions of this Act from complying with, the laws of any State with respect to the treatment of covered information by operators of school services, except to the extent that such laws are inconsistent with any provision of this Act, and then only to the extent of the inconsistency. For purposes of this paragraph, a law of a State is not inconsistent with this Act if the protection such law affords any user of a school service is greater than the protection provided by this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3EC80608EDAB4334BB11FDAEB4390010"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Any reference in this Act to State law shall be considered also to refer to the law of a political subdivision of a State.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HF137339EDCA64191AAD8613FACBFCBF4"><enum>6.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act shall take effect on the date that is 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></section></legis-body></bill>


