<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1704 IS: Securing Urgent Resources Vital to Indian Victim Empowerment Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 1704</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150707">July 7, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S317">Mr. Barrasso</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S288">Ms. Murkowski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S314">Mr. Tester</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S375">Mr. Daines</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S347">Mr. Moran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S353">Mr. Schatz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S326">Mr. Udall</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S360">Ms. Heitkamp</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S344">Mr. Hoeven</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SLIA00">Committee on Indian Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To amend the Indian Tribal Justice Act to secure urgent resources vital to Indian victims of
			 crime, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Securing Urgent Resources Vital to Indian Victim Empowerment Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SURVIVE Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="idF133F93B97FD42CF8F0E6D9FB42EA7BA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Tribal victims of crime</header>
 <subsection id="id912A751E42F84269A997A43B9FFCCC9F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>Section 3 of the Indian Tribal Justice Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/3602">25 U.S.C. 3602</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="id3F90CEB87E91457B895E29C0F881744D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>The term</quote> and inserting <quote>Except as provided in section 105, the term</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idC4A8D5EA28744B7AACFD9091EF7E7F5D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (5), by inserting <quote>and Victim Services</quote> after <quote>Support</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id66B6D03A8FF7449B931ED845E5283A1A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idA8D00A897D494ABF956553AD338A966E" style="OLC">
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF38E062678544B38A39C6D8A110A3F6D"><enum>(9)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Victim of crime</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>victim of crime</term> includes any individual directly or proximately harmed due to the commission of a crime.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph id="idA67A080FF10E4772B145482B26A33F3A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (3) through (9) as paragraphs (5) through (11), respectively; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id60BE56BD0D4D41CB963DC7AFDA6C53F3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (2) the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id17E623EABBBA4F99AD888773C6E04F2D" style="OLC"> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1C56921148E44F06A530520299EC1700"><enum>(3)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Indian</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Indian</term> means a member of an Indian tribe.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id09F45B28C7B84E0781791E86AC5AB78A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Indian country</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Indian country</term> has the meaning given the term in section 1151 of title 18, United States Code.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id2322AA2C5AF74AD98FC840A73CC9AB05"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Office of Tribal Justice Support and Victims Services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 101 of the Indian Tribal Justice Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/3611">25 U.S.C. 3611</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="idBB6DDD300F484DE687D81FEB083FA0FE"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the section heading, by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">and Victim Services</header-in-text></quote> after <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">Support</header-in-text></quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id03CB3FE98BBB44F2B4724B13FA226E65"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (a)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id65E939F7BAC9422E9E97746ECCCDF4DD"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the first sentence—</text> <clause id="id70238D60BE744DAFA37912B16A607470"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting <quote>and Victim Services</quote> after <quote>Support</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="idBE5E97806D8047F0ACD42E5E76C45B91"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>There is</quote> and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idFBE047DCC29F491D9230162B064B4CA0" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="idE98D43C358EF4ACF9C8B670AB3789AC9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id61A21F3BB70D489F85C3B77C9F661D86"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (1) (as designated by subparagraph (A)(ii)), in the second sentence, by striking <quote>The purpose</quote> and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id63A7CB0D7C8D4A1EA440708F78036BEF" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="id73F458D85E70474C9593F515E031F1BF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7CB5EE2651B247B698D3AB6E4797B2E6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (2) (as designated by subparagraph (B)), by inserting <quote>and to provide services to victims of crime</quote> after <quote>Courts of Indian Offenses</quote>;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id6ADED9C33DC145A48E3CCC75E825AB87"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (b), by inserting <quote>and Victim Services</quote> after <quote>Support</quote> each place it appears; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id9D633D36AF8F4907B1EABE993F85D228"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (c), by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id440E5C73294444AC839C5356EEC02347" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="idF071F96F24684A218C4F9FB05BAE02F7"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Make grants for victims of crime in accordance with section 105.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0AA837CD4D8448709D454C0730584F8F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Grant program</header><text>The Indian Tribal Justice Act is amended by inserting after section 104 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/3614">25 U.S.C. 3614</external-xref>) the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF18C7D2D64664B6E9C2EB3AC40B98FBB" style="OLC">
					<section id="idA14C6CD4DC0B4737BD7461FB16655E7B"><enum>105.</enum><header>Grant program for tribal crime victim services</header>
 <subsection id="idCD86351CBE2141C8B20EEF12A59B6953"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition of Indian tribe</header><text>In this section, the term <term>Indian tribe</term> has the meaning given the term in section 4 of the <act-name parsable-cite="ISDA">Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/450b">25 U.S.C. 450b</external-xref>).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idD19A276660774211940166E9EFBF20C7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Office shall—</text> <paragraph id="id1E3DE17EA6BD4AAF89AC06036C62855A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>administer the grant program described in subsection (c); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idDEF88F009B8B42ADBB2C721DD4B71614"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide planning, research, training, and technical assistance to the programs to be carried out using a grant provided under subsection (c).</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4D45721C8E9245FF9E60D3445B0DE0C8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Grant program</header>
 <paragraph id="idFAD22E75D88746CAB3CAE591C3632A16"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Office shall make grants to Indian tribes for the purposes of funding—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idBC85DEE113F34BBD9A9436B8DC2B5C41"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a crime victim compensation program that provides compensation to victims of crime for the services described in subparagraphs (A) through (C) of section 1403(b)(1) of the Victims of Crime Act of 1984 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/10602">42 U.S.C. 10602(b)(1)</external-xref>);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7EA2AB0C23AB4241AB7D1DA34EFA260B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>services to victims of crime, which may be provided in traditional form or through electronic, digital, or other technological formats, including—</text>
 <clause id="id5DB98F1B50CA484B91E26537E2E70731"><enum>(i)</enum><text>services provided through subgrants to victim services agencies or departments of tribal governments or nonprofit organizations;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idD20916A34C454FA7A37FAC51B0479553"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>domestic violence shelters, rape crisis centers, and child advocacy centers providing services to victims of crime in Indian country or in Alaska Native villages;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id693015AC1A01476AB776DEFEAB2DC04B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>relocation and transitional housing for victims of crime and family members of victims of crime;</text> </clause><clause id="idCFB7AB6D4AB34E8CA3F1CC0A126D97BE"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>medical care, treatment, and related evaluations arising from the victimization, including—</text>
 <subclause id="id72053656E7DA4F17B16DDEFEED3CF9A2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>emergency medical care and evaluation, nonemergency medical care and evaluation, psychological and psychiatric care and evaluation, and other forms of medical assistance, treatment, or therapy, regardless of the setting in which the services are delivered;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id0EE8777FC0CB41D2AE15189256D3AAC0"><enum>(II)</enum><text>mental health and crisis counseling, evaluation, and assistance, including outpatient therapy, counseling services, referral to substance abuse treatment, and other forms of specialized treatment; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id6D07CE011A934C23A681F8980BCBC9FD"><enum>(III)</enum><text>prophylactic treatment to prevent a victim of crime from contracting HIV/AIDS or any other sexually transmitted disease or infection;</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="id1EC3A46891D44A159B98C070804B35F3"><enum>(v)</enum><text>medical equipment, such as wheel chairs, prosthetics, crutches, canes, hearing aids, and eyeglasses, the need for which arises directly from the victimization;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id16A162D043E94434AA08BDF84EE66BA7"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>legal services, legal assistance services, and legal clinics (including services provided by pro bono legal clinics and practitioners), the need for which arises directly from the victimization;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id65C65B3FDC8745C49FA0B2D9C414857D"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>ambulance and other medical transport and emergency response services;</text> </clause><clause id="id322A323DFF5641008BE6AF3B1ECA012F"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>the training and certification of service animals and therapy animals; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id496B1B2DEC3543E2B1E49090225932B7"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>forensic interviews, medical evaluations, and forensic medical evidence collection examinations for victims of crime, the need for which arises directly from the victimization;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id12790F8ADA3D49A693E1BAB9AE7D4F46"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the development, establishment, and operation of programs designed to improve the handling of, including the investigation and prosecution of, violent crime cases, particularly cases of child abuse, domestic violence, sexual assault, stalking, human trafficking, and identity theft, in a manner that limits additional trauma to the victims;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id03F16247868A44E8A2E21D8068AFA35F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>housing for tribal law enforcement officers and other personnel, including victim advocates, whose work is dedicated to providing services to victims of crime;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id581BD9E179C44959AA904CF5AE7DF921"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the repair, renovation, or rehabilitation of existing facilities used for providing services to victims of crime, including improvements necessary to comply with the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12101">42 U.S.C. 12101 et seq.</external-xref>);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE46D3E3B8E6944CFB71356AA1ABCFDDF"><enum>(F)</enum><text>communication devices, as necessary to ensure the safety and security of victims of crime;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC55EE945A1CF476AB00F0A058ED826E3"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the design, development, purchase, upgrade, improvement, implementation, or support (including training in the use) of technological equipment, hardware, technology platforms, software, or applications used in programs providing or managing services to victims of crime;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id470756D4CCFF4F9BBD65E169DED3FC0F"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the development or implementation of training, technical assistance, or professional development that improves or enhances the quality of services to victims of crime;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9DDA5C6726894E6897ADB5F1633872EB"><enum>(I)</enum><text>transportation for victims of crime;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id34BC6D74AA994C92AA0E8FAA0092F343"><enum>(J)</enum><text>grant writing activities for grants described under this subsection;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0430B8D5C35949AAACB27ADAD9DBE2D9"><enum>(K)</enum><text>administration of the program and services described in this paragraph;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id25B4C96D94AB4FA0A30E094EF18F401F"><enum>(L)</enum><text>activities that impact the delivery and quality of services and justice to victims of crime, including strategies to increase the capacity of Indian tribes to provide services to victims of crime; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0C7C7066B0CE40B58509EF902F91EFB5"><enum>(M)</enum><text>any other services permitted under a regulation lawfully promulgated by the Attorney General or Secretary in accordance with this Act.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id76D4D4C81E0D4375BF346FBD3E80DF16"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>An Indian tribe seeking a grant under this subsection shall submit to the Office a written victim assistance proposal that includes, at a minimum—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id5E324349801C4FFEA917F3573155DEDE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of the need for services and the mission and goals of the activity to be carried out using the grant;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1B3788199FD242B1AB63D22F44F2E458"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of how amounts received under the grant would be used;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3B10397DD6DA47D4A2B2FB4738584B61"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the proposed annual budget for the activities for each fiscal year in which amounts received under the grant may be used;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id36FF53B2AEAF449D88D7286A64C8C252"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any qualifications, certifications, or licenses that may be required for individuals involved in administering the program;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5A479968AE5B44F0A6299920C51141DA"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a certification by the Indian tribe that—</text> <clause id="id110BB504D8CE4CD2949A0E8E06D9A0F9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>victims of crime are entitled to the rights and protections described in section 3771(a) of title 18, United States Code, or substantially similar rights and protections under tribal law; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id3355A8B6624845039F70F4D528FF1858"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>individuals who report crimes are protected by law from retribution and retaliation;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0EE2D1FF963E4C059B962EDA28153ECD"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a description of any plans or agreements to coordinate crime victim services among Federal, State, local, and tribal governments; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8862CF87060142CA86573F4BCC99A748"><enum>(G)</enum><text>any additional information required by the Secretary through written guidance, after consultation with Indian tribes.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idAB9AAE5124804DC3A8568BCA391FBD88"><enum>(3)</enum><header>No matching requirement</header><text>A recipient or subrecipient of a grant under this subsection shall not be required to make a matching contribution for Federal dollars received.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id8F651198AE3044D1BB8AF672E9D2D51B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>A recipient or subrecipient of a grant under this subsection shall, on an annual basis, submit to the Office a report describing the purpose for which the grant was used, which shall include, at a minimum—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idA7A485DD38024064A477BBB5C93E84CD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the purpose for which grant funds were obligated and the amount of funds obligated by the recipient or subrecipient for each purpose, including, on a quarterly basis—</text>
 <clause id="idECD2FABB0B2B4A69805AE7026153B1FF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the amount of grant funds used by the recipient or subrecipient for administrative costs;</text> </clause><clause id="id84E4FE1418A84FE694BDAC0C30E08A5A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the amount of grant funds used by the recipient or subrecipient for direct services; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id91A5ECC67E7B484B849B45E2CDB214CD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the amount of grant funds used by the recipient or subrecipient for capital investments;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6667A2CB334A43EE99E36F4C69768F82"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of victims served as a result of the grant;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE6FD0B2044B240E09F61AE685D94B152"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a description of the types of victims served under a program carried out using the grant, which, for each victim, shall include, at a minimum—</text>
 <clause id="idA9F9676151054811A11F0FDB19BC6F3C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the alleged crime and injury involved;</text> </clause><clause id="id555D49EF772442D78EA6670018C0378F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>whether the victim is an Indian; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id11A9E588712140CB807D40104788B715"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>other demographic information, including the age, sex, and tribal affiliation of the victim, if applicable;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id315DFC3DE18D46FEB181ECA1BD76DC29"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the nature and location of the alleged crime involved in each incident, including—</text> <clause id="id80CEEC2BD1E14B24BAE29DCA2521B551"><enum>(i)</enum><text>whether the crime was committed in Indian country;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idDEA5212E57114854AE8408E40BDDC35B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>whether the alleged perpetrator is an Indian; and</text> </clause><clause id="id57F7DBA56EE0440EB49F95735C2D6421"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the disposition of the incident, including any resulting charge, verdict, fine, fee, penalty, sentence, dismissal, or decision to settle or otherwise not pursue prosecution; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id617099DD7F4B40B89CEB8108D1551FD4"><enum>(E)</enum><text>all jurisdictions involved in any disposition.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id73963DB5C3634FB08322C30CECE00328"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Oversight and enforcement authority</header> <paragraph id="id40497267B1BF48B5B92DA6963C8BCCDB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authority</header><text>The Office shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id55D8F82837764C22A61FBD6F64D9697B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>regularly monitor and review grants awarded under subsection (c); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idAF2970B235A046E4832B70BE24E89A15"><enum>(B)</enum><text>conduct investigations and audits—</text> <clause id="idB680E0F5954E4A9580DFF647838A8CFD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to ensure compliance with all applicable Federal law; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id044A9AACC0134881A6E985A18C489194"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to prevent duplication and redundancy in the awarding of grants under subsection (c).</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5641D92C916343FD8CAAFF23899BFE39"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Performance measures and enforceable agreements</header><text>The Office shall ensure that all grants awarded under subsection (c), are subject to performance measures and enforceable agreements that allow for thorough program oversight by the Secretary.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id72C817B80735471693E9C94B94AFE00D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Compliance reports to Congress</header><text>For fiscal year 2017 and each fiscal year thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Indian Affairs of the Senate and the Subcommittee on Indian, Insular and Alaska Native Affairs of the House of Representatives an annual compliance report on all grants awarded under subsection (c).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9A5A4DE802F447C787C4719B95847567"><enum>(e)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Deadline for awarding grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date on which funding is made available to carry out this section, the Office shall award all funds available for grants under this section to eligible recipients.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idD443C6E040A2408597E3983F141ED9E2"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Availability of grant funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any amount awarded under this section that remains unobligated at the end of the fiscal year in which the grant is made may be expended for the purpose for which the grant was made at any time during the 5 succeeding fiscal years, at the end of which period, any unobligated sums shall remain available to the Office for award under this section in the following fiscal year.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id29616688026949EEBD84283E17DCCFC2"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Effect</header><text>Nothing in this section—</text> <paragraph id="idC2D508D353314E35941DF93BB252F8A7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>precludes an Indian tribe from contracting with another Indian tribe or tribal organization for the administration of a program funded under this subsection; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id102938C7F9E944BA8DF790F38A8C68F8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>prevents multiple Indian tribes or tribal organizations from forming a consortium for any of the purposes described in this subsection.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id33E554DF8F3B4F33B6E964196ECFA7C5"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Funding</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB0E25584F1274EE6963E8504F74E940F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The grant program established under this section shall be carried out using funds made available under section 1402(d)(1) of the Victims of Crime Act of 1984 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/10601">42 U.S.C. 10601(d)(1)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7F1C5AB4EC364126AE62460334108FB8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administrative expenses</header><text>With respect to the grant program under this section only, for each fiscal year in which a grant is made or grant funds may be obligated, an amount not to exceed 4 percent of the funds made available to the Office under this section may be used by the Office for administrative expenses, the management and administration of grants made under this section, and training and technical assistance.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id71DC96FBCADD42CF99AF4BF8FAF22F8E"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Term</header><text>This section shall be effective for—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8F73CBE69874401DA83D2DA19C6971B5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the first fiscal year beginning after the date of enactment of this section; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id59EA95EBD13945C78A858E929FD73E44"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the 9 fiscal years following such year.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="id1E83C419571E4DC18D65F199D9304FAB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Funding for grants for tribal victims of crime</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1402(d) of the Victims of Crime Act of 1984 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/10601">42 U.S.C. 10601(d)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="id56CC8ECFC56B4AFFB9F63070B4FE14D1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by inserting before paragraph (2) the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idA457FD7F13B64DA8A102309826F4CA70" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="id6D84CF2184BE427DB65978686927183F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Beginning on October 1, 2015, and each fiscal year thereafter for a period of 10 fiscal years, 5 percent of the total amount in the Fund available for obligation during a fiscal year shall be made available to the Secretary of the Interior to make grants under section 105 of the Indian Tribal Justice Act.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idB0D2811A7EA746EC9EFEF9DFCC2F6329"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)(A), in the matter preceding clause (i), by striking <quote>paragraph (2)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraphs (1) and (2)</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id95A88F5E16A94EFB85ADC1BEACBA185E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Regulations regarding Indian tribes</header> <subsection id="id1904b4b180db41b0884b80f0ec2e9a39"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Existing regulations</header><text>Any regulation, rule, or guidance promulgated by the Attorney General or the Secretary of the Interior before the date of enactment of this Act shall have no force or effect with respect to section 105 of the Indian Tribal Justice Act, as added by section 2.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="id7357912731f142a5a31157ef035443b5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Negotiated rulemaking</header>
 <paragraph id="idC7CB8CAB1B35489A947B5155246F80D0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Interior, in consultation with Indian tribes (as defined in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/450b">25 U.S.C. 450b</external-xref>)) and through notice and comment rulemaking, shall promulgate final regulations carrying out section 105 of the Indian Tribal Justice Act, as added by section 2.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id4A95CAE397604B198F12FF9EE0515513"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The Secretary of the Interior shall ensure that—</text> <subparagraph id="id0493DF0F5C1442509A05651A3146A95E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not fewer than 2 Indian tribes from each Bureau of Indian Affairs region participate in the consultation; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF0A54D0BCFB44F6CAEC64B3D646493FE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>small, medium, and large land-based Indian tribes are represented.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body> </bill> 

