<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S445 IS: Simplifying Access to Student Loan Information Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 445</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150210">February 10, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S331">Mrs. Gillibrand</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To increase students’ and borrowers’ access to student loan information within the National Student
			 Loan Data System. </official-title></form>
	<legis-body>
 <section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Simplifying Access to Student Loan Information Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="id32CE1E6357394A708BD2D51AC6D1ECF6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Amendment to the Truth in Lending Act</header>
 <subsection id="id1C224344FC1445D6A1D6C2B1A92DC684"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 128(e) of the Truth in Lending Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1638">15 U.S.C. 1638(e)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id83B139A1C39D478CAF04FD3DE26F44AE" style="OLC">
					<paragraph id="id74F2EBC12ADC4CF0AFEF6AFCA88F044D"><enum>(12)</enum><header>National Student Loan Data System</header>
 <subparagraph id="id58CFAA06B4F64BF2A3AB416F5E4FCE37"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each private educational lender shall—</text> <clause id="id2659E2A45DB34CA2962134A6D99DD475"><enum>(i)</enum><text>submit to the Secretary of Education for inclusion in the National Student Loan Data System established under section 485B of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1092b">20 U.S.C. 1092b</external-xref>) information regarding each private education loan made by such lender that will allow for the electronic exchange of data between borrowers of private education loans and the System; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id55B4E5CD77F44B349E553AEDAC85B117"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in carrying out clause (i), ensure the privacy of private education loan borrowers.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA00310790490462094DB791E822ECABA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Information to be submitted</header><text>The information regarding private education loans required under subparagraph (A) to be included in the National Student Loan Data System shall include the following if determined appropriate by the Secretary of Education:</text>
 <clause id="ID7B59A917F7F24435B7195137E9CD9019"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The total amount and type of each such loan made, including out­stand­ing interest and outstanding principal on such loan.</text>
 </clause><clause id="id5A9D45F6ECB347FD81AEF3443A10BABD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The interest rate of each such loan made.</text> </clause><clause id="IDBC045CBB0AD84F5E8FA2FE7F5B16653B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Information regarding the borrower that the Secretary of Education determines is necessary to ensure the electronic exchange of data between borrowers of private education loans and the System.</text>
 </clause><clause id="id49e594388f314ee3a968e846f10305ff"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Information, including contact information, regarding the lender that owns the loan.</text> </clause><clause id="id0be0b9c997044b41b8200cb9a104f37e"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Information, including contact information, regarding the servicer that is handling the loan.</text>
 </clause><clause id="id796070ECBB59430298C075A16DD676A1"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Information concerning the date of any default on the loan and the collection of the loan, including any information concerning the repayment status of any defaulted loan.</text>
 </clause><clause id="idABF41F554B0346918CE06095D8D5B8D3"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>Information regarding any deferment or forbearance granted on the loan.</text> </clause><clause id="idFBFAAD6FFFE948889E361FE0408210D9"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>The date of the completion of repayment by the borrower of the loan.</text>
 </clause><clause id="id49C2E152330847F797D2D8C0CA5FA7A4"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>Any other information determined by the Secretary of Education to be necessary for the operation of the National Student Loan Data System.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE7572A9F82AE473D9D3227ACF720062C"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Update</header><text>Each private educational lender shall update the information regarding private education loans required under subparagraph (A) to be included in the National Student Loan Data System on the same schedule as information is updated under the System under section 485B of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1092b">20 U.S.C. 1092b</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="id2D21288BA2814C619233C5B4E3C5BB65"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (a) shall apply to private education loans that were made for the 2011–2012 academic year or later.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="id487A39E6D6444499A797A9A08243FC57"><enum>3.</enum><header>Amendment to the Higher Education Act of 1965</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 485B of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1092b">20 U.S.C. 1092b</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE8BE2A9CD5104701B7A3B34713C15548" style="OLC">
				<subsection id="id4F1929A07ED7464C8003FD9BCB66E8C7"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Private education loans</header>
 <paragraph id="id913DC95806CE48F8AEB82C48867829DB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Simplifying Access to Student Loan Information Act of 2015</short-title>, the National Student Loan Data System established pursuant to subsection (a) shall contain the information required to be included under section 128(e)(12) of the Truth in Lending Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1638">15 U.S.C. 1638(e)(12)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id67F2BD4CA92D485686CFD3A4F7FB8AF3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Cosigner</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary shall ensure that any cosigner of a private education loan for which information is included in the National Student Loan Data System—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idE51CAEA326004658AFC41F852D26FAA5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is able to access the information in such System with respect to such private education loan in a separate account for such cosigner; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id96BEC2328FF6417BBF23290F42C64284"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not have access to any information in such System with respect to any loan for which the cosigner has not cosigned.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id068733B2F16C46C68A38E3F111CF856D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Privacy</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that a private educational lender—</text> <subparagraph id="id1DDFF72E2CB240B99EE474179C616317"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has access to the National Student Loan Data System only to submit information for such System regarding the private education loans of such lender; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id97B4C9AB52F24BDC9FDE00272590E8F1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may not see information in the System regarding the loans of any other lender.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idCEA7444FCF644033B64E106DCF8ED8C5"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Repayment options</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Simplifying Access to Student Loan Information Act of 2015</short-title>, the Secretary shall establish a functionality within the National Student Loan Data System established pursuant to subsection (a) that enables a student borrower of a loan made, insured, or guaranteed under this title to input information necessary for the estimation of repayment amounts under the various repayment plans available to the borrower of such loan to compare such repayment plans.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill>


