<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1700 IS: Mitigation Facilitation Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-06-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1700</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150625">June 25, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S288">Ms. Murkowski</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEV00">Committee on Environment and Public Works</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, to establish a program
			 to provide loans and loan guarantees to enable eligible public entities to
			 purchase credits from mitigation banks or in-lieu fee programs or acquire
			 interests in real property that are acquired pursuant to mitigation
			 projects required under certain Federal Water Pollution Control Act
			 permits, and for other purposes. </official-title></form>
	<legis-body>
 <section id="id56AFA5C2D19A4B4EBD3BADE5E267EB84" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Mitigation Facilitation Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="idEFF226A190A749849DA4983881A60145"><enum>2.</enum><header>Mitigation
			 loan and loan guarantee program</header>
 <subsection id="ID2e423bdcd11945568df55fd5e0c58665"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text>
				<paragraph id="ID03f23d7845e241f2a516656f05c99710"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible public
 entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible public entity</term> means a political subdivision of a State, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="ID7203d1fc16b94b639783e1ac96d696d1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a duly established town, township, or county;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA6D935B60BED42638F048A567450993E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an entity established for the purpose of regional governance;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE125790278924D4CA520498E587567BA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a special purpose entity; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6EC3A58445364691BF420870F5ED4EB5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a joint powers authority, or other entity certified by the Governor of a State, to have authority to implement a mitigation project required by the Secretary under a permit required by section 404 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1344">33 U.S.C. 1344</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="IDe8344868b6904382864d61ddcf7653d1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Program</header><text>The term <term>program</term> means the mitigation loan and loan guarantee program established by the Secretary under subsection (b)(1).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="IDe112b476104d4320a86369bb4af5de05"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="IDe5ee0b8cf9094cd3853678f3c4c34830"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Loan and loan
			 guarantee program</header>
 <paragraph id="ID821519cdf13b4f65b3a980c186df58f4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>As soon as practicable after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall establish a program to provide loans and loan guarantees to eligible public entities to enable the eligible public entities—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id4063F784D7CA48EF9C368252BD02812D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to purchase credits from mitigation banks or in-lieu fee programs; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idEB3DCAAD30B54F22B33D6F1D4D44D0A6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to acquire interests in real property that are acquired pursuant to a mitigation project required by the Secretary under a permit required by section 404 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1344">33 U.S.C. 1344</external-xref>).</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID5f5a47a8fec04f0a87cc1b4407c91f5b"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application;
			 approval process</header>
					<subparagraph id="ID85f01c70b243423b821e960687786395"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Application</header>
						<clause id="id5D90868C167F4E9280F1AE363FE92DC4"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>To be eligible to receive a loan or loan guarantee under the program, an eligible public entity shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such form and manner, and including such information as the Secretary may require.</text>
						</clause><clause id="idE734C3C66BFA46F49299B7F600E44828"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Solicitation
 of applications</header><text>On a rolling basis, the Secretary shall accept from eligible public entities applications for loans and loan guarantees in accordance with this section.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID1a1e90eb5925494fb2dce546b9c08a62"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Approval by
			 Secretary</header>
						<clause id="IDf7b0791873be40978909d3aef490e041"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text>Not later than 120 days after receipt of an application under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall approve or disapprove the application.</text>
 </clause><clause id="ID3079eb28f2be44569fb4067dece11692"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Factors</header><text>In approving or disapproving an application of an eligible public entity under clause (i), the Secretary may consider—</text>
 <subclause id="ID48f8fcf799d84e249d0c7c4c62e9006d"><enum>(I)</enum><text>whether the financial plan of the eligible public entity for use of the loan or loan guarantee is in compliance with any requirements set forth in the applicable permit;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="IDbf27d7d7520444d081dbac7ef5651f67"><enum>(II)</enum><text>whether the eligible public entity has the ability to repay a loan or meet the terms of a loan guarantee under the program; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="id99E21553892B4EBDA987D71EA3B25C80"><enum>(III)</enum><text>any other factor that the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</text>
							</subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="IDe8aab917e5904ac487cb963cbe16887d"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Administration
 of loans and loan guarantees</header><text>As soon as practicable after the date on which the Secretary approves an application under subparagraph (B), the Secretary shall—</text>
 <clause id="IDd2df2e003a394784ba8bcc88ca8b1b11"><enum>(i)</enum><text>establish the loan or loan guarantee with respect to the eligible public entity that is the subject of the application (including such terms and conditions as the Secretary may prescribe); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="IDabada512a67047df97039f2ac8cb683e"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>carry out the administration of the loan or loan guarantee.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id57475FB49CB9445681D57C42C76BC5FE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization
 of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this section such sums as are necessary.</text>
			</subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7E42794BF39E4CE5BA3BF6718BEC3577"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Termination of
 authority</header><text>The authority under this section shall terminate on the date that is 10 years after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


