<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1478 IS: Department of Defense Cyber Support to Civil Authorities Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-06-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1478</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150602">June 2, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S381">Mr. Rounds</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Secretary of Defense to develop a comprehensive plan to support civil authorities in
			 response to cyber attacks by foreign powers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body>
 <section id="id0805E845E79646ECBF43877AB6A345F8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Department of Defense Cyber Support to Civil Authorities Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H429F72CCED254500B9F1A08E21A5FE7A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Comprehensive plan of Department of Defense to support civil authorities in response to cyber attacks by foreign powers</header> <subsection id="idAEEDD827B8764B438DC251B648BC2542"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Plan required</header> <paragraph id="id7FED455E7F0D4BA9A71CCBE39B6B19A8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall develop a comprehensive plan for the United States Cyber Command to support civil authorities in responding to cyber attacks by foreign powers (as defined in section 101 of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1801">50 U.S.C. 1801</external-xref>)) against the United States or a United States person.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idE8B9FD269FE34796ADDDAF9B07D14400"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The plan required by paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text> <subparagraph id="id2c064241b3bf4328a018c26d80f03335"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A plan for internal Department of Defense collective training activities that are integrated with exercises conducted with other agencies and State and local governments.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idaa1392b674594edfa8f5a02190c626fb"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Plans for coordination with the heads of other Federal agencies and State and local governments pursuant to the exercises required under subparagraph (A).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id366b40e0b13446e0ae6b057fe1d116dc"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Note of any historical frameworks that are used, if any, in the formulation of the plan required by paragraph (1), such as Operation Noble Eagle.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0fa83adbe10d4154aca7d9514b86d612"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Descriptions of the roles, responsibilities, and expectations of Federal, State, and local authorities as the Secretary understands them.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5c6c57d0c5464ee68ae43a3a1d3ac665"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Descriptions of the roles, responsibilities, and expectations of the active components and reserve components of the Armed Forces.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id200ba44fdb4b402aace8796380e3054d"><enum>(F)</enum><text>A description of such legislative and administrative action as may be necessary to carry out the plan required by paragraph (1).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id77FAD5B411274AF0A31CB37F6919CB37"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Comptroller General of the United States review of plan</header><text>The Comptroller General of the United States shall review the plan developed under subsection (a)(1).</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


