<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1984 IS: Keeping out Illegal Drugs Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-08-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 1984</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150805">August 5, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S378">Mr. Lankford</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SLIA00">Committee on Indian Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To prevent Indian tribes and tribal organizations that cultivate, manufacture, or distribute
			 marijuana on Indian land from receiving Federal funds.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Keeping out Illegal Drugs Act of 2015</short-title></quote> or <quote><short-title>KIDs Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </section><section id="id67aff67a42d141249102724f0461a707" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text> <paragraph id="id4c0835bbac27451e858eddeb4e14b411"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the fiduciary responsibility of the United States to Indians includes protecting future generations of Indians from the harmful effects of illegal drugs;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id2C95268E9602439D9C6072D8F31BEE5C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>testimony at numerous congressional hearings has established that rampant drug abuse on Indian lands has had an especially destructive impact on the lives and families of all Native Americans, including Native Americans who do not use drugs;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idb1f70b37f07947ccbbc87e07d0ebb7b9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the report entitled <quote>Rates of Substance Use of American Indian Students in 8th, 10th, and 12th Grades Living on or Near Reservations: Update, 2009–2012 </quote>, published by Public Health Reports with funds from the National Institute on Drug Abuse of the National Institutes of Health, indicates that 56.2 percent of eighth grade Native American children and 61.4 percent of tenth grade Native American children who attend school on Indian lands had used marijuana, as compared to the national average of 16.4 percent and 33.4 percent, respectively;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idb5b243d37cd8439d9aa414a677ff232c"><enum>(4)</enum><text>according to the Office of Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention, individuals who begin using an illegal drug at a young age are far more likely than individuals who do not begin using an illegal drug at a young age—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idDA808A98969E4D0B9159D8C068A636A6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to use other drugs;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF1BBE93BEDA64BD6A2837CE081713952"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to be incarcerated; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB5B1D9FC327D405E992342A40A929508"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to have a lower quality of life;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idd93747bb3a494b34a474891477676543"><enum>(5)</enum><text>according to the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration, American Indians and Alaska Natives experience some of the highest rates of substance use, as compared to other racial and ethnic groups in the United States;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id8af5e69d6be84fbe8eb64136c1976952"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the National Institutes of Health have shown that marijuana use—</text> <subparagraph id="idF0EC230F3CF147E69125A3A9E036E0ED"><enum>(A)</enum><text>may cause permanent developmental damage to the brain; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4B419943158E40F380A0B5C918A6F0BB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is linked to poor educational outcomes;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id267082efeb844399a1e1a0c1026e933e"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the higher incidence of illegal drug use in Indian country, as compared to the rest of the United States, has directly contributed to higher levels of poverty and crime and a lower life expectancy in Indian country;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id9A797A36C4474712B7DF81C24A69D290"><enum>(8)</enum><text>according to the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration, in 2010, American Indians and Alaska Natives had a 17.1 percent rate of drug-induced death, the highest rate among other racial and ethnic groups in the United States;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idb76443c1ce5041eaa7ee51c9258fb20c"><enum>(9)</enum><text>according to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention report entitled <quote>CDC Health Disparities and Inequalities Report–United States, 2013</quote>, from 1999–2010, American Indians and Alaska Natives aged between 30 and 40 years experienced the highest drug-induced death rate, as compared to other racial and ethnic groups in the United States; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id70EF94D9B84C4A7E8E5FEEFA88B2E7E8"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Federal law already prohibits the production, cultivation, manufacture, and distribution of marijuana.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="idda1d86c1e5ba4adeaa292bdd67d80a50"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="id2E972488BE034FEB8A236FEC0AA96EDF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Indian lands</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Indian lands</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3 of the Native American Business Development, Trade Promotion, and Tourism Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/4302">25 U.S.C. 4302</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id09FA036CC28845F5A67E3A948DC5ACBA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Indian tribe</header><text>The term <term>Indian tribe</term> has the meaning given the term in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/450b">25 U.S.C. 450b</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idbbd3e5d31ddc4829b2c42d663625a528"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Tribal organization</header><text>The term <term>tribal organization</term> has the meaning given the term in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/450b">25 U.S.C. 450b</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="id333d45fe93f5434d90663ab5af454322"><enum>4.</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, it is unlawful for an Indian tribe or a tribal organization—</text>
 <paragraph id="id69115962069E41B19F56CDCF4C82CB7F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to knowingly or intentionally cultivate, manufacture, or distribute marijuana on Indian lands;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idAED6FAA49BAC432A8FBE484AFFCA5018"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to knowingly or intentionally allow the cultivation, manufacture, or distribution of marijuana on Indian lands; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id82F58167A81842579714023739114237"><enum>(3)</enum><text>on discovery by the Indian tribe or tribal organization that an individual or entity on Indian lands subject to the jurisdiction of the Indian tribe or tribal organization is cultivating, manufacturing, or distributing marijuana on Indian lands—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idE2612EE64D094461929225D0CEDED87A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>as applicable, to fail to prosecute, or notify the appropriate Federal official regarding that individual or entity; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id66C6014DCF7843FDBB63DF1CDF8E6C20"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to fail to destroy the relevant marijuana crop in accordance with applicable Federal law.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="id6ae8c69c6cfc435293b29ad8e3fb293f"><enum>5.</enum><header>Penalty</header> <subsection id="id250FE8263E334A20ADDE1357F1CD6413"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>No funds authorized or appropriated by Federal law shall be made available for any purpose to an Indian tribe or a tribal organization if the Indian tribe or tribal organization is determined to have violated section 4 during the period—</text>
 <paragraph id="idD3BE161F280C486AA9661575E51FAF33"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">beginning on the date on which the Indian tribe or tribal organization violates section 4; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idF64E6D79783B4AD09912A614A897FE93"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ending on the date on which the Indian tribe or tribal organization has remedied the violation and achieved compliance with this Act, as determined by the Attorney General of the United States.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idFAEE77E6E1014FCEB376E51CF36A9E27"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Return of funds required</header>
 <paragraph id="id70E758F1EA8642D781DFD3DE9CE1180D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An Indian tribe or tribal organization in violation of section 4 shall return to the relevant Federal agency any funds received during a period in which the Indian tribe or tribal organization is in violation of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id247FB8142616439E9D5240F7D4B626FD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No return of refunded funds</header><text>Funds returned to a Federal agency under paragraph (1) shall not be returned to the Indian tribe or tribal organization upon compliance with this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


