<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S1401 IS: To provide for the annual designation of cities in the United States as an “American World War II City”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 1401</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150520">May 20, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S384">Mr. Tillis</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S300">Mr. Burr</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To provide for the annual designation of cities in the United States as an <quote>American World War II City</quote>.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Annual designation of cities in United States as an <quote>American World War II City</quote></header>
 <subsection id="id051f4e8989ba4fb7aa5191abdb8cbcc0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Annual designation</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense, designate each year at least one city in the United States as an <quote>American World War II City</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id52ed302b48e7475092ff1b82f6d08ebc"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Criteria for designation</header><text>The criteria used for designations under subsection (a) shall include the following:</text> <paragraph id="id0784c908b5a348e0bac86fc25f18fc58"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Contributions by a city to the war effort during World War II, including defense manufacturing carried out in the city, bond drives conducted or supported by the city, service of the population of the city in the Armed Forces, and the presence of military facilities in the city.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ide96784201bba4d5fb4f952b23cf89362"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Efforts by a city to preserve the history of the contributions of the city to the war effort during World War II, including through the establishment of preservation organizations or museums, the restoration of facilities that contributed to the war effort, and the recognition of veterans of World War II.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idf1a29a6e6c544484818250aad48a4646"><enum>(c)</enum><header>First designation</header><text>The first city designated as an American World War II City pursuant to subsection (a) shall be the City of Wilmington, North Carolina.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


