<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S2192 IS: NICS Reporting Improvement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-10-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. 2192</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20151021">October 21, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S270">Mr. Schumer</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>To ensure that States submit all records of individuals who should be prohibited from buying a
			 firearm to the national instant criminal background check system.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>NICS Reporting Improvement Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="ida17cedda42d7414e8e7d8612dc4ef123"><enum>2.</enum><header>Penalties for States that do not make data electronically available to the national instant
 criminal background check</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 102(b) of the NICS Improvement Amendments Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/922">18 U.S.C. 922</external-xref> note) is amended to read as follows:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idba10ebd6348242d29603b5f74278cf75" style="OLC">
				<subsection id="id2782d3a478c54a7389a6cd16933ef176"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Implementation plan</header>
 <paragraph id="id52db9930d9d245aa876c4f9710f79244"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this subsection, the Attorney General, in coordination with the States, shall establish for each State or Indian tribal government, a plan to ensure maximum coordination and automation of the reporting of records or making of records available to the National Instant Criminal Background Check System, during a 4-year period specified in the plan.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id4577f77e79a9450aae87cb079a1fa655"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Benchmark requirements</header><text>Each plan required under paragraph (1) shall include annual benchmarks, including qualitative goals and quantitative measures, to enable the Attorney General to assess implementation of the plan.</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="idfde72c81f2b247f29774a9ac6e01dec9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Penalties for non-compliance</header>
 <subparagraph id="id1cabbc1ba2874e938ccef761a8c79320"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>During the 4-year period covered by the plan required under paragraph (1), the Attorney General shall withhold—</text>
 <clause id="idf398a0790b4f43e89134126407a8d54e"><enum>(i)</enum><text>10 percent of the amount that would otherwise be allocated to a State under section 505 of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3755">42 U.S.C. 3755</external-xref>) if the State does not meet the benchmark established pursuant to paragraph (2) for the first year in the 4-year period;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idce3f2cab683248c58e89843a1079c15d"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>11 percent of the amount that would otherwise be allocated to a State under section 505 of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3755">42 U.S.C. 3755</external-xref>) if the State does not meet the benchmark established pursuant to paragraph (2) for the second year in the 4-year period;</text>
 </clause><clause id="id001a51a862304e76bd130baeee45cf35"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>13 percent of the amount that would otherwise be allocated to a State under section 505 of title I the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3755">42 U.S.C. 3755</external-xref>) if the State does not meet the benchmark established pursuant to paragraph (2) for the third year in the 4-year period; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="id6a86d296fa5f41819c8eb82974ea3a43"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>15 percent of the amount that would otherwise be allocated to a State under section 505 of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3755">42 U.S.C. 3755</external-xref>) if the State does not meet the benchmark established pursuant to paragraph (2) for the fourth year in the 4-year period.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id436febf68b9a416f804f9f95ef946a25"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Failure to establish a plan</header><text>A State with respect to which a plan is not established under paragraph (1) shall be treated as having not met any benchmark established pursuant to paragraph (2).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id84599fca55144d519d13b97a722344df"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Annual doj report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this subsection, and each year thereafter, the Attorney General shall publish a report on the website of the Department of Justice on whether each State is in compliance with the benchmarks established pursuant to paragraph (2).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section><section id="id5c6bee4106a045fe94270e1f6d1d49f5"><enum>3.</enum><header>Grants incentives to States for improvement of coordination and automation of NICS record reporting</header>
 <subsection id="idcb2faa95d6e9498b8e12ffcfcabe1b99"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The NICS Improvement Amendments Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/922">18 U.S.C. 922</external-xref> note) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="id292d0ac8f61945a888981eee5430b0ba"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking section 103 and inserting the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7f8006edfca944eb88d082d1bb1ef42a" style="OLC">
						<section id="idd95cbfaa1c6b41b2a1085e3eea4773bc"><enum>103.</enum><header>Grants to States for improvement of coordination and automation of NICS record reporting</header>
 <subsection id="idd7f3c18514c04936882de6c621dda00e"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text>From amounts made available to carry out this section, the Attorney General shall make grants to States, Indian tribal governments, and State court systems, in a manner consistent with the National Criminal History Improvement Program and consistent with State plans for integration, automation, and accessibility of criminal history records, for use by the State, or units of local government of the State, Indian tribal government, or State court system to improve the automation and transmittal of any records that identify persons who are prohibited from possessing or receiving a firearm under section 922(g) of title 18, United States Code, in accordance with section 102 and the National Criminal History Improvement Program.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="idc53f8fd65556458b949746a4ca8f36f8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of grant amounts</header><text>Grants awarded to States, Indian tribal governments, or State court systems under this section may only be used to—</text>
 <paragraph id="id9a282f9e17704cf7b9a23d15df5b2f23"><enum>(1)</enum><text>carry out, as necessary, assessments of the capabilities of the courts of the State or Indian tribal government for the automation and transmission of arrest and conviction records, court orders including those for domestic violence, and mental health adjudications or commitments to Federal and State record repositories;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id664882827ad348f7b8b0247942acf30e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>implement policies, systems, and procedures for the automation and transmission of arrest and conviction records, court orders including those for domestic violence, and mental health adjudications or commitments to Federal and State record repositories;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id94baeb932ee84b39a0c7f4ea5525c165"><enum>(3)</enum><text>create electronic systems that provide accurate and up-to-date information which is directly related to checks under the National Instant Criminal Background Check System, including court disposition and corrections records;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idf0e176c346ac4706bb23d503e0d80bc7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>assist States or Indian tribal governments in establishing or enhancing their own capacities to perform background checks using the National Instant Criminal Background Check System; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id77fe0b99b57c4f8d9a4acbe8fd632917"><enum>(5)</enum><text>develop and maintain the relief from disabilities program in accordance with section 105.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="iddf77d200f77a4b14967b4736e1e3eca2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>To be eligible for a grant under this section, a State, Indian tribal government, or State court system shall certify, to the satisfaction of the Attorney General, that the State, Indian tribal government, or State court system is not prohibited by State law or court order from submitting mental health records to the National Instant Criminal Background Check System.</text>
							</subsection><subsection id="idd8c6a82a5ee04f0eb9be6bd4c134d316"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Federal share</header>
 <paragraph id="idb26b13ee867549d0b924a687802a5905"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Studies, assessments, non-material activities</header><text>The Federal share of a study, assessment, creation of a task force, or other non-material activity, as determined by the Attorney General, carried out with a grant under this section shall be not more than 25 percent.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id344b00b241ce44548e1dd58187a3c620"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Infrastructure or system development</header><text>The Federal share of an activity involving infrastructure or system development, including labor-related costs, for the purpose of improving State or Indian tribal government record reporting to the National Instant Criminal Background Check System carried out with a grant under this section may amount to 100 percent of the cost of the activity.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4ead1288bf89484caa4e35bf5d6734d7"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Grants to Indian tribes</header><text>Up to 5 percent of the grant funding available under this section may be reserved for Indian tribal governments for use by Indian tribal judicial systems.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id1ee4d02cc9974bc3bcae7530a1cf07d3"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Preferential consideration</header><text>In awarding grants under this section, the Attorney General shall give preferential consideration to a State or Indian tribal government that has—</text>
 <paragraph id="id8bb177ac73c44073ace4820fcb1418e0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>successfully met the benchmarks established under section 102(b)(2); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id32c26968b8de42c1b6c426eec1e7a03f"><enum>(2)</enum><text>implemented a relief from disabilities program in accordance with section 105.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5832a214ff4f49599546d34d8046dac9"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $100,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2016 through 2020.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id33a28e5dc43645438ef3327205b6aed0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking title III; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id259153ece37a46bf8ffef0fc72cf5ad0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in section 401(b), by inserting after <quote>of this Act</quote> the following: <quote>and 18 months after the date of enactment of the NICS Reporting Improvement Act</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ida5cb0029df9446b483d00c9b01824d1a"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendment</header><text>The table of sections in section 1(b) of the NICS Improvement Amendments Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/922">18 U.S.C. 922</external-xref> note) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="id88332f826c344122ace964e54fdc6744"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking the item relating to section 103 and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id28BFFAF84D194B50973939C11C65C94C" style="OLC"><toc><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Sec. 103. Grants to States for improvement of coordination and automation of NICS record reporting.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph id="id9ace824e71b642b8b22d194594107172"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking the item relating to title III; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id2eca124808fa4ab9a98f80bacaad3d68"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking the item relating to section 301.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idbe55960769ec4ab1954b4c1210e25e98"><enum>4.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The amendments made by this Act shall take effect 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


