<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S506 IS: To amend part B of title XVIII of the Social Security Act to exclude customary prompt pay discounts from manufacturers to wholesalers from the average sales price for drugs and biologicals under Medicare, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 506</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150212">February 12, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S260">Mr. Roberts</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S284">Ms. Stabenow</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S309">Mr. Casey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S307">Mr. Brown</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S373">Mr. Cassidy</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S377">Mr. Gardner</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend part B of title XVIII of the Social Security Act to exclude customary prompt pay discounts
			 from manufacturers to wholesalers from the average sales price for drugs
			 and biologicals under Medicare, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H6C90EA777A3F4673B20BB353DE376ECA" style="OLC">
		<section id="H4FFC720374C1417A913DC1D50D2B4EB2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Excluding customary prompt pay discounts from manufacturers to wholesalers from the average sales
			 price for Medicare payments for drugs and biologicals</header>
 <subsection id="HA8C57ECEE4A3492E8A16980DE4DAE000"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1847A(c)(3) of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 1395w–3a(c)(3)) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H5FC027743E5540F19573A0021D9ADD12"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the first sentence, by inserting <quote>(other than customary prompt pay discounts extended to wholesalers)</quote> after <quote>prompt pay discounts</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H08ABA7AB83864E20839C8ADD404387FA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the second sentence, by inserting <quote>(other than customary prompt pay discounts extended to wholesalers)</quote> after <quote>other price concessions</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H21A21C79E2044D7290C19D2EE8CDC247"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this section shall apply to the calculation of the average sales price for calendar quarters beginning more than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


