<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S2248 IS: Congenital Heart Futures Reauthorization Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-11-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 2248</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20151105">November 5, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S309">Mr. Casey</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Public Health Service Act to coordinate Federal congenital heart disease research
			 efforts and to improve public education and awareness of congenital heart
			 disease, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H34913623FE394EADA04626ED59875CC8" style="OLC">
 <section id="HDBAE328E90E7455D913FDE588CD93D09" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Congenital Heart Futures Reauthorization Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HCD8CCC57B29946F38DC5864FF2A94E3C"><enum>2.</enum><header>National congenital heart disease cohort study and awareness campaign</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 301 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/241">42 U.S.C. 241</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following—</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1B46DB00C96D466EA096817B2FBF5BF9" style="OLC">
				<subsection id="H2B431270A7824577A3EB74C282EA103C"><enum>(f)</enum><header>National congenital heart disease cohort study</header>
 <paragraph id="H7B592E25461645D9A4CAADD35A869D73"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, shall plan, develop, implement, and submit annual reports to the Congress on surveillance and research activities of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, including a cohort study to improve understanding of the epidemiology of congenital heart disease (referred to in this subsection and subsection (g) as <quote>CHD</quote>) across the lifespan, from birth to adulthood, with particular interest in the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA72936B880E7494B8D2D4A2481DE80C6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Health care utilization and natural history of those affected by CHD.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA99EA6B1B5544C8A85FBAF840395302B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Demographic factors associated with CHD, such as age, race, ethnicity, gender, and family history of individuals who are diagnosed with the disease.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H61FB10E47E824F28BCCB76BB934D0512"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Outcome measures, such that analysis of the outcome measures will allow derivation of evidence-based best practices and guidelines for CHD patients.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF220C677160545C5B9EF5731DE9ABF11"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Permissible considerations</header><text>The study under this subsection may—</text> <subparagraph id="H51114714F4614B3894669117F119405E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>gather data on the health outcomes of a diverse population of those affected by CHD;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDC76A99E31D94DC9B2139ABE87F5291B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>consider health disparities among those affected by CHD which may include the consideration of prenatal exposures; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H92E2723742CB4BB8AB868B258F02BE75"><enum>(C)</enum><text>incorporate behavioral, emotional, and educational outcomes of those affected by CHD.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2E09369BC43546719B1AF071C326EEB1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public access</header><text>Subject to paragraph (4), the data generated from the studies under this subsection shall be made available to CHD researchers subject to appropriate privacy protections, and aggregate data from such studies shall be made available to the public.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5FEDF26F59E847109233A84AF701A770"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Patient privacy</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that the study under this subsection is carried out in a manner that complies with the requirements applicable to a covered entity under the regulations promulgated pursuant to section 264(c) of the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF77916F011CB4343A69A1901ECA1C49B"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Congenital heart disease awareness campaign</header>
 <paragraph id="H32A5F3F8B94F4015A8CF87CF5178CC01"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, shall establish and implement an awareness, outreach, and education campaign regarding CHD across the lifespan. The information expressed through such campaign may—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H559082EB6A1742C2BE9AB2DBEC49A1FB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>emphasize that CHD is the most prevalent birth defect;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA62D0A1B02A94438985384CB0C86C19B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identify CHD as a condition that affects those diagnosed throughout their lives; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H42ED2D9EDCA64A63A8E8DCD20AD3AD9A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>promote the need for pediatric, adolescent, and adult individuals with CHD to seek and maintain lifelong, specialized care.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H50C3613909C54E6DBC8F31DB38D6562B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Permissible activities</header><text>The campaign under this subsection shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HA1D7A3FEF29144FEA3E7D1FF72826695"><enum>(A)</enum><text>utilize collaborations or partnerships with other agencies, health care professionals, and patient advocacy organizations that specialize in the needs of individuals with CHD; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCBDCBA669984499796C8D909EE05A9A2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>include the use of print, film, or electronic materials distributed via television, radio, Internet, or other commercial marketing venues.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="H96BF9F8A764E4DC8AB6DF7A08EDA1EA8"><enum>3.</enum><header>Congenital heart disease research</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 425 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/285b-8">42 U.S.C. 285b–8</external-xref>) is amended by adding the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1CAE5A6A3F6A4499A0417B66A7637D31" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H62C17C0CE5524F42BAD7B1A5DEA0837F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report from NIH</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Congenital Heart Futures Reauthorization Act of 2015</short-title>, the Director of NIH, acting through the Director of the Institute, shall provide a report to Congress—</text>
 <paragraph id="H678741112324422FB380F22CD4F13628"><enum>(1)</enum><text>outlining the ongoing research efforts of the National Institutes of Health regarding congenital heart disease; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5CBE285C083D4A5EAD9F8B722B74B43A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>identifying—</text> <subparagraph id="H2E41DEE636DD47AEACB261590FAC7A85"><enum>(A)</enum><text>future plans for research regarding congenital heart disease; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBD5D44163B4349998C3EF750E1341F99"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the areas of greatest need for such research.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

