<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 S852 IS: A Voice for Victims Act of 2015</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 852</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150324">March 24, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S299">Mr. Vitter</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To provide that employment-related arbitration agreements shall not be enforceable with respect to
			 any claim related to a tort arising out of rape.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body>
		<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short
 title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as <quote><short-title>A Voice for Victims Act of 2015</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="ID83673f652059443c9c4aa874a6566135"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings; purpose</header> <subsection id="id4D09F09C7B2D4FBD9645F968DE65162A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="ID2238cb826b2b45a9b17300a4066c8714"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Federal law has long held that workplace disputes may be the subject of valid agreements to arbitrate unless Congress <quote>has evinced an intention to preclude</quote> such agreements for the disputes at issue. (See Gilmer v. Interstate/Johnson Lane Corp., 500 U.S. 20, 26 (1991)).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ID2b72fa96ecf6437cb7a056e8ed03e2e5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>It is the intent of Congress that employees not be compelled by an employer to arbitrate any claim related to a tort arising out of rape.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="IDa551ffaf69b5411cb1b73f4ca6a63c3b"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of this Act is to evidence the intent of Congress to preclude an employer from enforcing an agreement to arbitrate any claim related to a tort arising out of rape.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="ID996bc794eefa4c17aa7e6dce078e0714"><enum>3.</enum><header>Arbitration of
			 certain controversies</header>
			<subsection id="id113A28C9CDCB4C48A75814ABCF678FC9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In
 general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any agreement made between an employer and an employee to arbitrate a dispute shall not be enforceable with respect to any claim related to a tort arising out of rape.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="ID73ead8a40b47463e823a4c191acdb0d6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rule of
 construction</header><text>This Act shall not be construed to limit, in any way, the broad construction given to the scope of employment under any Federal or State workers’ compensation law.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="idBF3B59B961D54C6180A297C8F811AA20"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text>
 <paragraph id="idAE154FF4916746159C843AABC529C46D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Commerce</header><text>The term <term>commerce</term> means trade, traffic, commerce, transportation, transmission, or communication—</text>
 <subparagraph id="idB7996DCDCAB14FB58F03F28922726BFD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>among the several States;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id27469943FB6A4143980C8FA06F245996"><enum>(B)</enum><text>between a State and any place outside thereof;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9D147A8A357E44F3808C9C476FBEA7E5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>within the District of Columbia or a possession of the United States; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id94B3502434744894BFA2A02DF62D0322"><enum>(D)</enum><text>between points in the same State but through a point outside thereof.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="IDF22425EB46C4484D9A60DB8D630875D4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Industry
 affecting commerce</header><text>The term <term>industry affecting commerce</term>—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id1F66410224AB40B1B6C6857EE5038C9C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means any activity, business, or industry in commerce or in which a labor dispute would hinder or obstruct commerce or the free flow of commerce;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6727E547892648DA86792A423B562451"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes any activity or industry affecting commerce, within the meaning of the Labor-Management Reporting and Disclosure Act of 1959 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/401">29 U.S.C. 401 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id15E8E2C694484DBA8F4D0403BB75F3B9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>includes any governmental industry, business, or activity.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="IDB7FBF6133ADD4B62A3EA3F990EF3EFA6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Employer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>employer</term> means a person engaged in an industry affecting commerce who has 15 or more employees for each working day in each of 20 or more calendar weeks in the current or preceding calendar year, and any agent of such a person, but such term does not include—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2D87604EBE54440BA42E7E94125CFB93"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the United States, a corporation wholly owned by the Government of the United States, or any department or agency of the District of Columbia subject by statute to procedures of the competitive service (as defined in section 2102 of title 5, United States Code); or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idEF297B6013994E0DA3A14E2700F67649"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a bona fide private membership club (other than a labor organization) which is exempt from taxation under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID79735FEC73C84FBCAC9F0E46163C48A7"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Employee</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>employee</term> means an individual employed by an employer, except that the term <term>employee</term> shall not include any person elected to public office in any State or political subdivision of any State by the qualified voters thereof, or any person chosen by such officer to be on such officer's personal staff, or an appointee on the policy making level or an immediate adviser with respect to the exercise of the constitutional or legal powers of the office. The exemption set forth in the preceding sentence shall not include employees subject to the civil service laws of a State government, governmental agency or political subdivision. With respect to employment in a foreign country, such term includes an individual who is a citizen of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


