<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4491" measure-id="id114hr4491" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-02-08" update-date="2016-03-18">
<title>MyRA Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4491v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-03-18">
<action-date>2016-02-08</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Making Your Retirement Accessible Act or the MyRA Act</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to establish an employee retirement option known as a MyRA account. A MyRA account functions as a Roth Individual Retirement Account. An employee who elects to establish a MyRA account may contribute any portion of a tax refund or make automatic payroll contributions to the account. </p> <p>The funding of MyRA accounts is limited to retirement savings bonds issued by the Department of the Treasury with a specified interest rate and maturity date. </p> <p>The bill imposes a tax on any employer who fails to comply with the requirement for making direct deposits to a MyRA account of wages designated by an employee.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
