<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2985" measure-id="id114hr2985" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-07-08" update-date="2015-09-26">
<title>Confidential Informant Accountability Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2985v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-09-26">
<action-date>2015-07-08</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Confidential Informant Accountability Act of 2015</strong></p> <p> Directs the Departments of Justice, Homeland Security, and Treasury to report biannually to Congress on: (1) all serious crimes, authorized and unauthorized, committed by informants maintained by their respective law enforcement agencies (i.e., the Federal Bureau of Investigation, the Drug Enforcement Administration, the U.S. Secret Service, U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement, and the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives); and (2) the amounts expended by each of such agencies on payments to such informants.</p> <p>Defines a "serious crime" as any serious violent felony or drug offense or any offense of racketeering, bribery, child pornography, obstruction of justice, or perjury that an agent or employee of the relevant law enforcement agency has reasonable grounds to believe an informant has committed.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
