<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1567" measure-id="id114hr1567" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-03-24" update-date="2016-06-06">
<title>Global Food Security Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1567v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-06-06">
<action-date>2016-04-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Global Food Security Act of 2016 </b></p> <p>This bill requires the President to develop and implement a Global Food Security Strategy to promote global food security, resilience, and nutrition. </p> <p>(Sec. 2) This section specifies that it is in the U.S. national security interest to promote global food security, resilience, and nutrition, consistent with national food security investment plans through programs and activities that: </p> <ul> <li>accelerate inclusive, agricultural-led economic growth that reduces global poverty, hunger, and malnutrition; </li> <li> increase the productivity, incomes, and livelihoods of small-scale producers; </li> <li> build resilience to food shocks among vulnerable populations and households while reducing reliance upon emergency food assistance; </li> <li> create an environment for agricultural growth and investment; </li> <li> improve the nutritional status of women and children; </li> <li> align with and leverage U.S strategies and investments in trade, economic growth, science and technology, agricultural research and extension, maternal and child health, nutrition, and water, sanitation, and hygiene; </li> <li> strengthen partnerships between U.S. and foreign universities that build agricultural capacity; and </li> <li> ensure the effective use of taxpayer dollars in achieving these objectives. </li> </ul> <p>(Sec. 3) This section sets forth definitions that apply to this bill. </p> <p>(Sec. 4) The President must coordinate a whole-of-government strategy to promote global food security, resilience, and nutrition, consistent with national food security investment plans. </p> <p>This section specifies required goals and criteria for the strategy. The President must coordinate the efforts of federal departments and agencies to implement the strategy by establishing: (1) monitoring and evaluation systems, coherence, and coordination across federal departments and agencies; and (2) platforms for regular consultation and collaboration with key stakeholders and congressional committees.</p> <p>The President must submit the strategy, including agency-specific plans, to Congress by October 1, 2016. </p> <p>(Sec. 5) To carry out the strategy, the President may provide assistance under the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to prevent or address food shortages. </p> <p>(Sec. 6) The President must report annually to Congress on the implementation of the Global Food Security Strategy. </p> <p>(Sec. 7) This section specifies that nothing in the Global Food Security Strategy or this bill should be construed to supersede or otherwise affect the authority of federal departments and agencies to carry out specified food and nutrition security or emergency and nonemergency food assistance programs. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1567v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-07-10">
<action-date>2015-03-24</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Global Food Security Act of 2015 </b></p> <p>This bill requires the President to coordinate the development and implementation of a comprehensive strategy to accomplish the objectives of promoting global food security, resilience, and nutrition consistent with national food security investment plans. </p> <p>The President must coordinate the efforts of relevant departments and agencies in implementing the Global Food Security Strategy by establishing monitoring and evaluation systems, coherence, and coordination across relevant departments and agencies; and platforms for regular consultation and collaboration with key stakeholders. </p> <p>By October 1, 2016, the President must submit the strategy to Congress, including a detailed description of how the United States intends to advance the objectives and agency-specific implementation plans. </p> <p>The bill authorizes the President to provide foreign assistance to implement the strategy and prevent or address food shortages. The President must ensure that assistance to implement the strategy is provided under established parameters for a system to monitor and evaluate the progress and impact of the strategy, including by providing specified reports to Congress and the public. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
