<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4509" measure-id="id114hr4509" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-02-09" update-date="2016-05-20">
<title>State and High-Risk Urban Area Working Group Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4509v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-05-20">
<action-date>2016-04-13</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>State and High-Risk Urban Area Working Group Act</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to require any state or high-risk urban area receiving a grant under the State Homeland Security Grant Program or the Urban Area Security Initiative to establish an urban area working group to assist in preparation and revision of the state, regional, or local homeland security plan or the threat and hazard identification and risk assessment.</p> <p>The bill adds to the stakeholders who shall have at least one representative on such a committee or working group:</p> <ul> <li>public health officials and other appropriate medical practitioners,</li> <li>individuals representing educational institutions,</li> <li>state and regional interoperable communications coordinators, and</li> <li>state and major urban area fusion centers.</li> </ul> <p>(A fusion center serves as a focal point within the state and local environment for the receipt, analysis, gathering, and sharing of threat-related information between the federal government and state, local, tribal, territorial, and private sector partners.)</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4509v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-05-20">
<action-date>2016-02-09</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>State and High-Risk Urban Area Working Group Act</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to require any state or high-risk urban area receiving a grant under the State Homeland Security Grant Program or the Urban Area Security Initiative to establish an urban area working group to assist in preparation and revision of the state, regional, or local homeland security plan or the threat and hazard identification and risk assessment.</p> <p>The bill adds to the stakeholders who shall have at least one representative on such a committee or working group:</p> <ul> <li>public health officials and other appropriate medical practitioners,</li> <li>individuals representing educational institutions,</li> <li>state and regional interoperable communications coordinators, and</li> <li>state and major urban area fusion centers.</li> </ul> <p>(A fusion center serves as a focal point within the state and local environment for the receipt, analysis, gathering, and sharing of threat-related information between the federal government and state, local, tribal, territorial, and private sector partners.)</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
