<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5926" measure-id="id114hr5926" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-07-22" update-date="2016-07-25">
<title>Departments of Labor, Health and Human Services, and Education, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5926v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-07-25">
<action-date>2016-07-22</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Departments of Labor, Health and Human Services, and Education, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2017</b></p> <p>Provides FY2017 appropriations to the Departments of Labor, Health and Human Services, and Education; and related agencies. </p> <p><i>Department of Labor Appropriations Act, 2017</i></p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Department of Labor for: </p> <ul> <li>the Employment and Training Administration,</li> <li>the Employee Benefits Security Administration,</li> <li>the Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation, </li> <li>the Wage and Hour Division, </li> <li>the Office of Labor-Management Standards,</li> <li>the Office of Federal Contract Compliance Programs,</li> <li>the Office of Workers' Compensation Programs,</li> <li>the Occupational Safety and Health Administration, </li> <li>the Mine Safety and Health Administration, </li> <li>the Bureau of Labor Statistics, </li> <li>the Office of Disability Employment Policy, and</li> <li>Departmental Management. </li> </ul> <p><i>Department of Health and Human Services Appropriations Act, 2017</i></p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Department of Health and Human Services for: </p> <ul> <li>the Health Resources and Services Administration, </li> <li>the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, </li> <li>the National Institutes of Health, </li> <li>the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration, </li> <li>the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality,</li> <li>the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services,</li> <li>the Administration for Children and Families, </li> <li>the Administration for Community Living, and </li> <li>the Office of the Secretary. </li> </ul> <p><i>Department of Education Appropriations Act, 2017 </i></p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Department of Education for: </p> <ul> <li>Education for the Disadvantaged; </li> <li>Impact Aid; </li> <li>School Improvement Programs; </li> <li>Indian Education; </li> <li>Innovation and Improvement; </li> <li>Safe Schools and Citizenship Education; </li> <li>English Language Acquisition; </li> <li>Special Education; </li> <li>Rehabilitation Services; </li> <li>Special Institutions for Persons with Disabilities; </li> <li>Career, Technical, and Adult Education; </li> <li>Student Financial Assistance; </li> <li>Student Aid Administration; </li> <li>Higher Education; </li> <li>Howard University; </li> <li>the College Housing and Academic Facilities Loan Program; </li> <li>the Historically Black College and University Capital Financing Program Account; </li> <li>the Institute of Education Sciences; and </li> <li>Departmental Management. </li> </ul> <p>Provides appropriations to Related Agencies, including: </p> <ul> <li>the Committee for Purchase From People Who Are Blind or Severely Disabled, </li> <li>the Corporation for National and Community Service, </li> <li>the Corporation for Public Broadcasting, </li> <li>the Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service, </li> <li>the Federal Mine Safety and Health Review Commission, </li> <li>the Institute of Museum and Library Services, </li> <li>the Medicaid and CHIP Payment and Access Commission,</li> <li>the Medicare Payment Advisory Commission, </li> <li>the National Council on Disability, </li> <li>the National Labor Relations Board, </li> <li>the National Mediation Board, </li> <li>the Occupational Safety and Health Review Commission, </li> <li>the Railroad Retirement Board, and </li> <li>the Social Security Administration. </li> </ul> <p>Sets forth permissible and prohibited uses for funds provided by this and other appropriations Acts. </p> <p><i>Health Care Conscience Rights Act</i></p> <p>Amends the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act to specify that health care sponsors, individuals, and insurers are not required to purchase or provide coverage for abortion or other items or services if they have moral or religious objections. <p>Amends the Public Health Service Act to prohibit the federal government and any state or local government receiving federal financial assistance from discriminating against health care entities that refuse to participate in abortion-related activities. <p> <p> <p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
