<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3466" measure-id="id114hr3466" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-09-09" update-date="2015-11-02">
<title>Next Generation Researchers Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3466v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-11-02">
<action-date>2015-09-09</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Next Generation Researchers Act</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Public Health Service Act to establish the Next Generation of Researchers Initiative in the National Institutes of Health (NIH) to coordinate NIH policies and programs aimed at promoting and providing opportunities for new researchers and earlier research independence.</p> <p>The NIH must: (1) promote policies and programs to improve opportunities for new researchers and promote earlier research independence; (2) develop, modify, or accelerate policies, as needed, to promote opportunities for new researchers and earlier research independence, including policies to enhance training opportunities for research-related career options, strengthen mentorship programs, enhance diversity efforts, and help new researchers obtain renewal funding; (3) coordinate with agencies and academic institutions to improve tracking of career progress of biomedical postdoctoral researchers and students; and (4) request the National Academy of Sciences to conduct a comprehensive study and report on policies affecting the next generation of researchers as part of a study on biomedical and behavioral research personnel.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
