<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4486" measure-id="id114hr4486" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-02-04" update-date="2016-03-22">
<title>Do Your Job Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4486v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-03-22">
<action-date>2016-02-04</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Do Your Job Act </b></p> <p>This bill withholds the salaries of Members of a chamber of Congress if the chamber has not considered and voted on final passage of each regular appropriations bill before the beginning of the fiscal year. </p> <p>The salaries are withheld until the earlier of the: (1) the date on which the chamber has considered and held votes on final passage of each of the bills, or (2) the last day of the Congress. In the House of Representatives, consideration of the bills must include permitting Members to offer amendments. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
