<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5718" measure-id="id114hr5718" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-07-11" update-date="2016-10-31">
<title>Central Wasatch National Conservation and Recreation Area Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5718v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-10-31">
<action-date>2016-07-11</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Central Wasatch National Conservation and Recreation Area Act</b></p> <p>This bill establishes the Central Wasatch National Conservation and Recreation Area in Utah, comprising approximately 79,109 acres of federal land in the Wasatch-Cache National Forest.</p> <p>The Department of Agriculture (USDA) shall develop a comprehensive plan for the long-term management of the area.</p> <p>The bill adjusts the boundaries of Mount Olympus, Twin Peaks, and Lone Peak Wildernesses. </p> <p>The bill designates certain land in the forest as the Grandeur Peak-Mount Aire Wilderness and a component of the National Wilderness Preservation System. </p> <p>The bill designates approximately 1,800 acres of federal land in the Wasatch-Cache National Forest as the White Pine Special Management Area. </p> <p>The bill prohibits timber harvesting within the special management area. </p> <p>The bill withdraws all federal land within the conservation and recreation area from: (1) all forms of entry, appropriation, and disposal under the public land laws; (2) location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and (3) disposition under the mineral leasing, mineral materials, and geothermal leasing laws. </p> <p>USDA shall allow installation of access and avalanche control devices, excluding ski lifts, within or adjacent to the area. </p> <p>The bill arranges for a potential land exchange involving specified National Forest System land and private ski areas in Utah. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
