<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1070" measure-id="id114hr1070" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-02-25" update-date="2015-03-20">
<title>Student Bill of Rights</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1070v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-03-20">
<action-date>2015-02-25</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Student Bill of Rights</strong></p> <p>Directs the Secretary of Education to make annual determinations as to whether each state's public school system provides all its students with the educational resources to succeed academically and in life. Requires such education to enable students to: (1) acquire the knowledge and skills necessary for responsible citizenship, (2) meet challenging academic achievement standards, and (3) compete and succeed in a global economy.</p> <p>Requires each system to do so by: (1) satisfying certain opportunity to learn indicators for all its schools, including highly effective teachers and equitable instructional resources; (2) providing educational services in local educational agencies (LEAs) that receive funds for disadvantaged students that are, taken as a whole, at least comparable to educational services provided in LEAs not receiving such funds; and (3) complying with any final federal or state court order in any matter concerning the adequacy or equitableness of the system. <p>Requires withholding of specified portions of its federal funding for administrative expenses if a system: (1) fails to meet a yearly interim goal; (2) does not remedy, after two school years, a failure to provide comparable educational services to schools that receive funds for disadvantaged children; or (3) does not comply with a court order. <p>Allows students or parents aggrieved by violations of this Act to bring civil actions for enforcement in federal district courts. <p>Directs the Commissioner of Education Statistics to study the effects of educational disparities on economic growth and on national defense.]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
