<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3659" measure-id="id114hr3659" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-09-30" update-date="2015-11-16">
<title>Exchange Inclusion for a Healthy America Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3659v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-11-16">
<action-date>2015-09-30</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Exchange Inclusion for a Healthy America Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>This bill allows undocumented aliens to obtain health care coverage by amending: (1) the Internal Revenue Code to eliminate the restriction of the&nbsp;tax credit for health care insurance premium assistance to persons lawfully present in the United States; and (2) the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (PPACA) to eliminate restrictions of benefits&nbsp;under such Act, including cost-sharing reduction, pre-existing condition coverage, and minimum essential health care coverage, to persons lawfully present in the United States.&nbsp;This expanded coverage is effective for&nbsp;taxable or plan years beginning after December 31, 2015. </p> <p>The bill also extends PPACA benefits to individuals who are granted deferral from removal under specified Department of Homeland Security deferred action&nbsp;plans. &nbsp;</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
