<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3003" measure-id="id114hr3003" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-07-09" update-date="2015-07-21">
<title>Jobs for Heroes Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3003v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-07-21">
<action-date>2015-07-09</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Jobs for Heroes Act </strong></p> <p> Amends the Internal Revenue Code, with respect to the work opportunity tax credit, to: (1)&nbsp;revise the definition of "qualified veteran" to&nbsp;expand the eligibility of veterans for such credit,&nbsp;(2) allow such credit for the hiring of a qualified member of the Ready Reserve or National Guard, and (3) make such credit permanent. </p> <p>Revises the tax credit for differential wage&nbsp;payments made by employers on behalf of Members of the Uniformed Services to: (1)&nbsp;extend eligibility for such credit to an employer without regard to the size of such employer's workforce, and (2) make such credit permanent.&nbsp;</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
