<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2314" measure-id="id114hr2314" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-13" update-date="2015-06-02">
<title>Accountability in Immigration Detention Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2314v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-06-02">
<action-date>2015-05-13</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Accountability in Immigration Detention Act of 2015</strong> </p> <p>Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to ensure that persons detained pursuant to the Immigration and Nationality Act are treated in compliance with specified requirements regarding: (1) humane treatment, (2) detention facility standards, (3) solitary confinement limitations, (4) telephone access, (5) facility location, (6) investigation of grievances, (7) transfers, (8) language and translation services, (9) recreational programs and voluntary work, (10) medical care, (11) vulnerable populations, and (12) legal access.</p> <p>Directs the Secretary to establish nationwide alternatives to detention programs that incorporate case management services in each DHS field office to ensure appearances at immigration proceedings and public safety.</p> <p>States that the number of detention beds maintained shall be determined by the Secretary and shall be based solely on detention needs. </p> <p>Expresses the sense of Congress that appropriations Acts shall not mandate maintenance of a minimum number of detention beds.</p> <p>Requires that all detention facilities be inspected by the Secretary on an annual basis and by an independent (third party) auditor on a biannual basis. </p> <p>Directs the Secretary to impose meaningful financial penalties upon facilities that fail to comply with applicable detention standards.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
