<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3311" measure-id="id114hr3311" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-07-29" update-date="2015-10-08">
<title>End Oil and Gas Tax Subsidies Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3311v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-10-08">
<action-date>2015-07-29</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>End Oil and Gas Tax Subsidies Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to: </p> <ul> <li>increase to seven years the amortization period for geological and geophysical expenditures; </li> <li>repeal the tax credits for producing oil and gas from marginal wells and for enhanced oil recovery;</li> <li>repeal the tax deduction for the intangible drilling and development costs of oil and gas wells; </li> <li>repeal percentage depletion for oil and gas wells;</li> <li>repeal the tax deduction for tertiary injectant expenses; </li> <li>repeal the passive loss exception for working interests in oil and gas property; </li> <li>deny the tax deduction for income attributable to domestic production activities for oil and gas activities; </li> <li>prohibit the use of the last-in, first-out (LIFO) accounting method by major integrated oil companies; and </li> <li>limit the foreign tax credit for dual capacity taxpayers (i.e., taxpayers who are subject to a levy of a foreign country or U.S. possession and receive specific economic benefits from such country or possession). </li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
