<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1440" measure-id="id114hr1440" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-03-18" update-date="2015-04-10">
<title>To amend the Age Discrimination in Employment Act of 1967 to treat employment as a field emergency medical service practitioner in the same manner as employment as a firefighter for purposes of such Act.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1440v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-04-10">
<action-date>2015-03-18</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Amends the Age Discrimination in Employment Act of 1967 to treat field emergency medical service practitioners in the same manner as firefighters or law enforcement officers for purposes of exempting state employers from otherwise prohibited age discrimination practices.</p> <p>Allows an employer that is a state, political subdivision, and interstate agency to fail or refuse to hire, or to discharge, any such practitioner because of the individual's age if the employer provides the practitioner an annual opportunity to demonstrate physical and mental fitness by passing a job performance test identified by the Department of Health and Human Services in order to continue employment.</p> <p>Defines &quot;field emergency medical service practitioner&quot; as an employee, the duties of whose position are primarily to perform work directly connected with the responsibility of administration of specialized pre-hospital emergency care for victims of acute illnesses or injury, including an employee engaged in such activity who is transferred to a supervisory or administrative position.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
