<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1831" measure-id="id114hr1831" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-04-16" update-date="2016-04-05">
<title>Evidence-Based Policymaking Commission Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1831v49" currentChamber="BOTH" update-date="2016-04-05">
<action-date>2016-03-30</action-date>
<action-desc>Public Law</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Evidence-Based Policymaking Commission Act of 201</strong><strong>6</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill establishes in the executive branch a Commission on Evidence-Based Policymaking. </p> <p>(Sec. 3) The bill provides for a 15 member Commission appointed by the President and congressional leaders with consideration given to individuals with expertise in economics, statistics, program evaluation, data security, confidentiality, or database management.</p> <p>(Sec. 4) The Commission must conduct a comprehensive study of the data inventory, data infrastructure, database security, and statistical protocols related to federal policymaking and the agencies responsible for maintaining that data to:</p> <ul> <li>determine the optimal arrangement for which administrative data on federal programs and tax expenditures, survey data, and related statistical data series may be integrated and made available to facilitate program evaluation, continuous improvement, policy-relevant research, and cost-benefit analyses; </li> <li>make recommendations on how data infrastructure, database security, and statistical protocols should be modified to best fulfill those objectives; and </li> <li>make recommendations on how best to incorporate outcomes measurement, institutionalize randomized controlled trials, and rigorous impact analysis into program design. </li></ul> <p>The Commission shall consider whether a clearinghouse for program and survey data should be established and how to create such clearinghouse. </p> <p>The Commission shall evaluate:</p> <ul> <li>what administrative data and survey data are relevant for program evaluation and federal policy-making and should be included in a clearinghouse; </li> <li>which survey data such administrative data may be linked to, in addition to linkages across administrative data series; </li> <li>what are the legal and administrative barriers to including or linking these data series; </li> <li>what data-sharing infrastructure should be used to facilitate data merging and access for research purposes; </li> <li>how a clearinghouse could be self-funded; </li> <li>which researchers, officials, and institutions should have access to data; </li> <li>what limitations should be placed on the use of data; </li> <li>how to protect information and ensure individual privacy and confidentiality; </li> <li>how data and results of research can be used to inform program administrators and policymakers to improve program design;</li> <li>what incentives may facilitate interagency sharing of information to improve programmatic effectiveness and enhance data accuracy and comprehensiveness; and</li> <li>how individuals whose data are used should be notified of its usages. </li> </ul> <p>The Commission shall, upon the affirmative vote of at least three-quarters of its members, submit to the President and Congress a detailed statement of its findings and conclusions, together with its recommendations for appropriate legislation or administrative actions.</p> <p>(Sec. 5) The following agencies shall advise and consult with the Commission on matters within their respective areas of responsibility:</p> <ul> <li>the Bureau of the Census;</li> <li>the Internal Revenue Service;</li> <li>the Social Security Administration;</li> <li>the Departments of Health and Human Services, Agriculture, Housing and Urban Development, Education, and Justice;</li> <li>the Office of Management and Budget;</li> <li>the Bureau of Economic Analysis; and </li> <li>the Bureau of Labor Statistics. </li></ul> <p>(Sec. 6) The agencies identified as Principal Statistical Agencies in the report entitled "Statistical Programs of the United States Government, Fiscal Year 2015," published by the Office of Management and Budget, shall transfer up to $3 million to the Bureau of the Census, upon request, for carrying out the activities of the Commission.</p> <p>The Bureau of the Census shall provide administrative support to the Commission. </p> <p>No additional funds may be authorized to carry out this Act. </p> <p>(Sec. 8) The Commission shall terminate not later than 18 months after enactment of this Act.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1831v35" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-04-05">
<action-date>2016-03-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed Senate amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Evidence-Based Policymaking Commission Act of 201</strong><strong>6</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill establishes in the executive branch a Commission on Evidence-Based Policymaking. </p> <p>(Sec. 3) The bill sets forth the membership composition, terms, and compensation of the Commission and requires the appointment of experts in protecting personally-identifiable information and data minimization. Consideration shall also be given in the appointment process to individuals with expertise in economics, statistics, program evaluation, data security, confidentiality, or database management. </p> <p>(Sec. 4) The Commission shall conduct a comprehensive study of the data inventory, data infrastructure, database security, and statistical protocols related to federal policymaking and the agencies responsible for maintaining that data to:</p> <ul> <li>determine the optimal arrangement for which administrative data on federal programs and tax expenditures, survey data, and related statistical data series may be integrated and made available to facilitate program evaluation, continuous improvement, policy-relevant research, and cost-benefit analyses while weighing how integration might lead to the intentional or unintentional access, breach, or release of personally-identifiable information or records; </li> <li>make recommendations on how data infrastructure, database security, and statistical protocols should be modified to best fulfill those objectives; and </li> <li>make recommendations on how best to incorporate outcomes measurement, institutionalize randomized controlled trials, and rigorous impact analysis into program design. </li></ul> <p>The Commission shall consider whether a clearinghouse for program and survey data should be established and how to create such clearinghouse. The Commission shall evaluate:</p> <ul> <li>what administrative data and survey data are relevant for program evaluation and federal policy-making and should be included in a clearinghouse; </li> <li>which survey data such administrative data may be linked to, in addition to linkages across administrative data series, including the effect such linkages may have on the security of those data; </li> <li>what are the legal and administrative barriers to including or linking these data series; </li> <li>what data-sharing infrastructure should be used to facilitate data merging and access for research purposes; </li> <li>how a clearinghouse could be self-funded; </li> <li>which researchers, officials, and institutions should have access to data and their qualifications; </li> <li>what limitations should be placed on the use of data; </li> <li>how to protect information and ensure individual privacy and confidentiality; </li> <li>how data and results of research can be used to inform program administrators and policymakers to improve program design; </li> <li>what incentives may facilitate interagency sharing of information to improve programmatic effectiveness and enhance data accuracy and comprehensiveness; and</li> <li>how individuals whose data are used should be notified of its usages. </li> </ul> <p>The Commission shall, upon the affirmative vote of at least three-quarters of its members, submit to the President and Congress a detailed statement of its findings and conclusions, together with its recommendations for appropriate legislation or administrative actions.</p> <p>(Sec. 5) The following agencies shall advise and consult with the Commission on matters within their respective areas of responsibility:</p> <ul> <li>the Bureau of the Census;</li> <li>the Internal Revenue Service;</li> <li>the Social Security Administration;</li> <li>the Departments of Health and Human Services, Agriculture, Housing and Urban Development, Education, and Justice;</li> <li>the Office of Management and Budget;</li> <li>the Bureau of Economic Analysis; </li> <li>the Bureau of Labor Statistics; and</li> <li>any other agency, as determined by the Commission. </li> </ul> <p>(Sec. 6) The bill requires: (1) the agencies identified as Principal Statistical Agencies in the report entitled "Statistical Programs of the United States Government, Fiscal Year 2015," published by the Office of Management and Budget, to transfer up to $3 million to the Bureau of the Census, upon request, for carrying out the activities of the Commission; and (2) the Bureau to provide administrative support to the Commission. </p> <p>No additional funds may be authorized to carry out this Act. </p> <p>(Sec. 7) The Commission shall have a Director appointed by the chairperson with the concurrence of the co-chairperson. </p> <p>(Sec. 8) The Commission shall terminate not later than 18 months after the enactment of this Act.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1831v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-10-20">
<action-date>2015-07-27</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Evidence-Based Policymaking Commission Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) Establishes in the executive branch a Commission on Evidence-Based Policymaking. </p> <p>(Sec. 4) Directs the Commission to conduct a comprehensive study of the data inventory, data infrastructure, and statistical protocols related to federal policymaking and the agencies responsible for maintaining that data to:</p> <ul> <li>determine the optimal arrangement for which administrative data on federal programs and tax expenditures, , survey data, and related statistical data series may be integrated and made available to facilitate program evaluation, continuous improvement, policy-relevant research, and cost-benefit analyses; </li> <li>make recommendations on how data infrastructure and statistical protocols should be modified to best fulfill those objectives; and </li> <li>make recommendations on how best to incorporate outcomes measurement, institutionalize randomized controlled trials, and rigorous impact analysis into program design. </li></ul> <p>Requires the Commission to consider whether a clearinghouse for program and survey data should be established and how to create such clearinghouse. Directs the Commission to evaluate:</p> <ul> <li>what administrative data and survey data are relevant for program evaluation and federal policy-making and should be included in a clearinghouse; </li> <li>which survey data such administrative data may be linked to, in addition to linkages across administrative data series; </li> <li>what are the legal and administrative barriers to including or linking these data series; </li> <li>what data-sharing infrastructure should be used to facilitate data merging and access for research purposes; </li> <li>how a clearinghouse could be self-funded; </li> <li>which researchers, officials, and institutions should have access to data; </li> <li>what limitations should be placed on the use of data; </li> <li>how to protect information and ensure individual privacy and confidentiality; </li> <li>how data and results of research can be used to inform program administrators and policymakers to improve program design; and </li> <li>what incentives may facilitate interagency sharing of information to improve programmatic effectiveness and enhance data accuracy and comprehensiveness. </li></ul> <p>Directs the Commission, upon the affirmative vote of at least three-quarters of its members, to submit to the President and Congress a detailed statement of its findings and conclusions, together with its recommendations for appropriate legislation or administrative actions.</p> <p>(Sec. 5) Requires the following agencies to advise and consult with the Commission on matters within their respective areas of responsibility:</p> <ul> <li>the Bureau of the Census;</li> <li>the Internal Revenue Service;</li> <li>the Social Security Administration;</li> <li>the Departments of Health and Human Services, Agriculture, Housing and Urban Development, Education, and Justice;</li> <li>the Office of Management and Budget;</li> <li>the Bureau of Economic Analysis; and </li> <li>the Bureau of Labor Statistics. </li></ul> <p>(Sec. 6) Requires: (1) the agencies identified as Principal Statistical Agencies in the report entitled "Statistical Programs of the United States Government, Fiscal Year 2015," published by the Office of Management and Budget, to transfer up to $3 million to the Bureau of the Census, upon request, for carrying out the activities of the Commission; and (2) the Bureau to provide administrative support to the Commission. Prohibits the authorization of additional funds to carry out this Act. </p> <p>(Sec. 8) Terminates the Commission not later than 18 months after enactment of this Act.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1831v17" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-10-20">
<action-date>2015-07-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Evidence-Based Policymaking Commission Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) Establishes in the executive branch a Commission on Evidence-Based Policymaking. </p> <p>(Sec. 4) Directs the Commission to conduct a comprehensive study of the data inventory, data infrastructure, and statistical protocols related to federal policymaking and the agencies responsible for maintaining that data to:</p> <ul> <li>determine the optimal arrangement for which administrative data on federal programs and tax expenditures and related data series may be integrated and made available to facilitate program evaluation, continuous improvement, policy-relevant research, and cost-benefit analyses; </li> <li>make recommendations on how data infrastructure and protocols should be modified to best fulfill those objectives; and </li> <li>make recommendations on how best to incorporate outcomes measurement, institutionalize randomized controlled trials, and rigorous impact analysis into program design. </li></ul> <p>Requires the Commission to consider whether a clearinghouse for program and survey data should be established and how to create such clearinghouse. Directs the Commission to evaluate:</p> <ul> <li>what administrative data are relevant for program evaluation and federal policy-making and should be included in a clearinghouse; </li> <li>which survey data such administrative data may be linked to, in addition to linkages across administrative data series; </li> <li>what are the legal and administrative barriers to including or linking these data series; </li> <li>what data-sharing infrastructure should be used to facilitate data merging and access for research purposes; </li> <li>how a clearinghouse could be self-funded; </li> <li>which researchers, officials, and institutions should have access to data; </li> <li>what limitations should be placed on the use of data; </li> <li>how to protect information and ensure individual privacy and confidentiality; </li> <li>how data and results of research can be used to inform program administrators and policymakers to improve program design; and </li> <li>what incentives may facilitate interagency sharing of information to improve programmatic effectiveness and enhance data accuracy and comprehensiveness. </li></ul> <p>Directs the Commission, upon the affirmative vote of at least three-quarters of its members, to submit to the President and Congress a detailed statement of its findings and conclusions, together with its recommendations for appropriate legislation or administrative actions.</p> <p>(Sec. 5) Requires the following agencies to advise and consult with the Commission on matters within their respective areas of responsibility:</p> <ul> <li>the Bureau of the Census; </li> <li>the Internal Revenue Service; </li> <li>the Social Security Administration; </li> <li>the Departments of Health and Human Services, Agriculture, Housing and Urban Development, Education, and Justice;</li> <li>the Office of Management and Budget; </li> <li>the Bureau of Economic Analysis; and </li> <li>the Bureau of Labor Statistics. </li></ul> <p>(Sec. 6) Requires: (1) the agencies identified as Principal Statistical Agencies in the report entitled "Statistical Programs of the United States Government, Fiscal Year 2015," published by the Office of Management and Budget, to provide up to $3 million to the Bureau of the Census, upon request, for carrying out the activities of the Commission; and (2) the Bureau to provide administrative support to the Commission.</p> <p>(Sec. 8) Terminates the Commission not later than 18 months after enactment of this Act.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1831v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-07-09">
<action-date>2015-04-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Evidence-Based Policymaking Commission Act of 2015</strong></p> <p> Establishes in the executive branch a Commission on Evidence-Based Policymaking. Directs the Commission to conduct a comprehensive study of the data inventory, data infrastructure, and statistical protocols related to federal policymaking and the statistical and programmatic agencies responsible for maintaining that data to:</p> <ul> <li> determine the optimal arrangement for which administrative data on federal programs and tax expenditures and related data series may be integrated and made available to facilitate program evaluation, continuous improvement, policy-relevant research, and cost-benefit analyses by qualified researchers and institutions; </li> <li> make recommendations on how data infrastructure and protocols should be modified to best fulfill those objectives; and</li> <li> make recommendations on how best to incorporate outcomes measurement, institutionalize randomized controlled trials, and rigorous impact analysis into program design.</li> </ul> <p>Requires the Commission to consider if and how to create a clearinghouse for program and survey data. </p> <p>Terminates the Commission not later than 18 months after enactment of this Act.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
