<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2947" measure-id="id114hr2947" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-07-07" update-date="2016-04-19">
<title>Financial Institution Bankruptcy Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2947v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-04-19">
<action-date>2016-04-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the House on March 23, 2016. The summary of that version is repeated here.)</p> <p><b>Financial Institution Bankruptcy Act of 2016</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends federal bankruptcy law with respect to a "covered financial corporation" incorporated or organized under any federal or state law (other than a stockbroker, a commodity broker, or a domestic or foreign insurance company or financial institution meeting certain criteria) that is: (1) a bank holding company; or (2) a corporation that exists for the primary purpose of owning, controlling, and financing its subsidiaries, has total consolidated assets of $50 billion or greater, and whose annual gross revenues or consolidated assets meet specified tests.</p> <p>(Sec. 3) The bill adds "Subchapter V - Liquidation, Reorganization, or Recapitalization of a Covered Financial Corporation," setting forth requirements and prohibitions regarding: (1) commencement of a case concerning a covered financial corporation; (2) a special trustee and bridge company; (3) special transfer of the property of the estate in bankruptcy; (4) treatment of qualified financial contracts and affiliate contracts; (5) licenses, permits, and registrations; (6) exemption from securities laws; and (7) inapplicability of certain avoiding powers.</p> <p>A debtor holding company may transfer the assets (including executory contracts and unexpired leases) of a covered financial corporation, including the equity in all of its operating subsidiaries, to a newly-formed bridge company over a single weekend, during which a 48-hour stay of debt-collection proceedings (except payment and delivery obligations) shall apply. </p> <p>The bill permits conversion to chapter 7 (Liquidation) of a case under subchapter V if certain conditions are met.</p> <p>The Bankruptcy Court may not order an assets transfer unless it determines by a preponderance of the evidence that a transfer is necessary to prevent serious adverse effects on financial stability in the United States.</p> <p>(Sec. 4) The judicial code is amended to require the Chief Justice of the United States to designate at least 10 bankruptcy judges to be available to hear a Subchapter V case in bankruptcy. Bankruptcy judges may request to be considered for such designation.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2947v17" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-04-14">
<action-date>2016-03-23</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Financial Institution Bankruptcy Act of 2016</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends federal bankruptcy law with respect to a &quot;covered financial corporation&quot; incorporated or organized under any federal or state law (other than a stockbroker, a commodity broker, or a domestic or foreign insurance company or financial institution meeting certain criteria) that is: (1) a bank holding company; or (2) a corporation that exists for the primary purpose of owning, controlling, and financing its subsidiaries, has total consolidated assets of $50 billion or greater, and whose annual gross revenues or consolidated assets meet specified tests.</p> <p>(Sec. 3) The bill adds &quot;Subchapter V - Liquidation, Reorganization, or Recapitalization of a Covered Financial Corporation,&quot; setting forth requirements and prohibitions regarding: (1) commencement of a case concerning a covered financial corporation; (2) a special trustee and bridge company; (3) special transfer of the property of the estate in bankruptcy; (4) treatment of qualified financial contracts and affiliate contracts; (5) licenses, permits, and registrations; (6) exemption from securities laws; and (7) inapplicability of certain avoiding powers.</p> <p>A debtor holding company may transfer the assets (including executory contracts and unexpired leases) of a covered financial corporation, including the equity in all of its operating subsidiaries, to a newly-formed bridge company over a single weekend, during which a 48-hour stay of debt-collection proceedings (except payment and delivery obligations) shall apply. </p> <p>The bill permits conversion to chapter 7 (Liquidation) of a case under subchapter V if certain conditions are met.</p> <p>The Bankruptcy Court may not order an assets transfer unless it determines by a preponderance of the evidence that a transfer is necessary to prevent serious adverse effects on financial stability in the United States.</p> <p>(Sec. 4) The judicial code is amended to require the Chief Justice of the United States to designate at least 10 bankruptcy judges to be available to hear a Subchapter V case in bankruptcy. Bankruptcy judges may request to be considered for such designation.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2947v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-07-10">
<action-date>2015-07-07</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p> <b>Financial Institution Bankruptcy Act of 2015</b></p> <p>Amends federal bankruptcy law with respect to a &quot;covered financial corporation&quot; incorporated or organized under any federal or state law (other than a stockbroker, a commodity broker, or a domestic or foreign insurance company or financial institution meeting certain criteria) that is: (1) a bank holding company; or (2) a corporation that exists for the primary purpose of owning, controlling, and financing its subsidiaries, has total consolidated assets of $50 billion or greater, and whose annual gross revenues or consolidated assets meet specified tests.</p> <p>Adds &quot;Subchapter V - Liquidation, Reorganization, or Recapitalization of a Covered Financial Corporation,&quot; setting forth requirements and prohibitions regarding: (1) commencement of a case concerning a covered financial corporation; (2) a special trustee and bridge company; (3) special transfer of the property of the estate in bankruptcy; (4) treatment of qualified financial contracts and affiliate contracts; (5) licenses, permits, and registrations; (6) exemption from securities laws; and (7) inapplicability of certain avoiding powers.</p> <p>Allows conversion to chapter 7 (Liquidation) of a case under subchapter V if certain conditions are met.</p> <p>Amends the Judicial Code to require the Chief Justice of the United States to designate: (1) at least three district judges in at least four circuits to serve on an appellate panel available to hear appeals in a bankruptcy case concerning a covered financial corporation, and (2) a panel of at least 10 bankruptcy judges.</p> <p>Prescribes requirements for the assignment of bankruptcy judges to subchapter V cases.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
