<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5912" measure-id="id114hr5912" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-07-15" update-date="2016-07-18">
<title>Department of State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5912v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-07-18">
<action-date>2016-07-15</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Department of State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 2017 </b></p> <p>Provides FY2017 appropriations for the Department of State, foreign operations, and related programs. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the State Department for: </p> <ul> <li> Administration of Foreign Affairs, </li> <li>International Organizations, and </li> <li>International Commissions. </li> </ul> <p>Provides appropriations for Related Agencies and Related Programs, including: </p> <ul> <li> the Broadcasting Board of Governors, </li> <li>the Asia Foundation, </li> <li> the U.S. Institute of Peace, </li> <li> the Center for Middle Eastern-Western Dialogue Trust Fund, </li> <li> the Eisenhower Exchange Fellowship Program, </li> <li> the Israeli Arab Scholarship Program, and </li> <li> the National Endowment for Democracy. </li> </ul> <p>Provides appropriations for Other Commissions, including:</p> <ul> <li> the Commission for the Preservation of America's Heritage Abroad, </li> <li> the U.S. Commission on International Religious Freedom, </li> <li> the Commission on Security and Cooperation in Europe, </li> <li> the Congressional-Executive Commission on the People's Republic of China, and </li> <li> the U.S.-China Economic and Security Review Commission. </li> </ul> <p>Provides appropriations for the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID). </p> <p>Provides appropriations for Bilateral Economic Assistance to: </p> <ul> <li> the President; </li> <li> the State Department; </li> <li> Independent Agencies, including the Peace Corps, the Millennium Challenge Corporation, the Inter-American Foundation, and the U.S. African Development Foundation; and </li> <li> the Department of the Treasury. </li> </ul> <p>Provides appropriations to the State Department and the President for International Security Assistance. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to International Financial Institutions for Multilateral Assistance. </p> <p>Provides appropriations for Export and Investment Assistance to:</p> <ul> <li>the Export-Import Bank of the United States, </li> <li>the Overseas Private Investment Corporation, and </li> <li>the U.S. Trade and Development Agency.</li> </ul> <p>Provides appropriations to specified accounts for Overseas Contingency Operations. </p> <p>Sets forth permissible and prohibited uses for funds provided by this and other appropriations Acts. </p> <p><i></i> </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
