<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2870" measure-id="id114hr2870" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-06-24" update-date="2015-07-01">
<title>Torture Victims Relief Reauthorization Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2870v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-07-01">
<action-date>2015-06-24</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Torture Victims Relief Reauthorization Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>Amends the Torture Victims Relief Act of 1998 to authorize FY2016-FY2017 appropriations to: </p> <ul> <li>the Department of Health and Human Services for grants to domestic treatment centers for the costs of services in the rehabilitation of victims of torture (including treatment of both physical and psychological effects), social and legal services, and research and training of health care providers outside of treatment centers or programs; and </li> <li>the President for grants to foreign treatment centers and programs for activities designed to treat victims for the physical and psychological effects of torture. </li> </ul>  <p>Directs the U.S. Agency for International Development to support indigenous foreign treatment centers and programs for torture victims in order to increase their capacities to train other local health care providers.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
