<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4719" measure-id="id114hr4719" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-03-07" update-date="2016-04-13">
<title>COMPLI Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4719v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-04-13">
<action-date>2016-03-07</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Correcting Obstructions to Mediate, Prevent, and Limit Inaccessibility Act or the COMPLI Act</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 to prohibit persons aggrieved by certain public accommodation violations from commencing a civil action for discrimination unless they: (1) provide the owner or operator of the accommodation with a written notice that is specific enough to identify the violation; (2) specify in the notice that the owner or operator has 90 days to remove or correct the violation before an action will be brought; and (3) refrain from sending demand letters, requests for settlement, or other communications to the owner or operator during such 90-day period.</p> <p>An owner or operator of a public accommodation who is provided such a notice must notify the public of the alleged violation and the steps being taken to remedy it. </p> <p>Owners or operators are entitled to an additional 30 days to comply if they make a good faith effort but are unable to correct the violation within the original 90-day period.</p> <p>A civil action for discrimination based on such a violation may not be commenced while a civil action relating to the same violation is pending.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
