<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1961" measure-id="id114hr1961" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-04-22" update-date="2016-05-18">
<title>Climate Change Education Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1961v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-05-18">
<action-date>2015-04-22</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Climate Change Education Act </b></p> <p> This bill declares that the evidence for human-induced climate change is overwhelming and undeniable.</p> <p>The National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) must establish a Climate Change Education Program to:</p> <ul> <li> broaden the understanding of human-induced climate change, possible consequences, and potential solutions;</li> <li> apply the latest scientific and technological discoveries to provide learning opportunities to people of all ages;</li> <li>conduct a national information campaign to help people understand and promote implementation of new technologies, programs, and incentives related to energy conservation, renewable energy, and greenhouse gas reduction; and</li> <li> inform the public of impacts to human health and safety as a result of climate change.</li> </ul> <p>NOAA must establish a grant program for climate change education. This grant program must be included in the Program.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
