<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1562" measure-id="id114hr1562" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-03-24" update-date="2015-05-20">
<title>Contracting and Tax Accountability Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1562v81" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-05-20">
<action-date>2015-04-15</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The expanded summary of the House reported version is repeated here.)</p> <p><strong>Contracting and Tax Accountability Act of 2015</strong> </p> <p>(Sec. 2) Declares it the policy of the U.S. government that no government contracts or grants should be awarded to individuals or companies with seriously delinquent federal tax debts. </p> <p>(Sec. 3) Requires the head of any executive agency that issues an invitation for bids or a request for proposals for a contract, or that offers a grant, in an amount greater than the simplified acquisition threshold, to require each person submitting a bid or proposal or grant application to: (1) certify that such person does not have a seriously delinquent tax debt, and (2) authorize the Department of the Treasury to disclose information limited to describing whether such person has a seriously delinquent tax debt. Subjects a person who has a seriously delinquent tax debt to a negative responsibility or high risk determination when applying for a federal contract or grant, or to suspension or debarment from the federal procurement process. Authorizes an agency head to waive a suspension or debarment proceeding for a person with a seriously delinquent tax debt upon a written finding of urgent and compelling circumstances significantly affecting the interests of the United States. </p> <p>(Sec. 5) Defines "seriously delinquent tax debt" as a federal tax liability that has been assessed by the Internal Revenue Service and is collectible by levy or a court proceeding, except a tax debt: (1) that is being paid in a timely manner under an approved installment agreement or an offer-in-compromise, (2) for which a collection due process hearing has been requested or is pending; (3) for which a continuous levy has been issued or agreed to by an applicant for employment, or (4) with respect to which such a levy is released because it has been determined to be an economic hardship to the taxpayer.</p> <p>(Sec. 6) Makes this Act applicable to contracts and grants awarded on or after 270 days after the enactment date of this Act. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1562v79" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-05-20">
<action-date>2015-04-14</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p><strong>Contracting and Tax Accountability Act of 2015</strong> </p> <p>(Sec. 2) Declares it the policy of the U.S. government that no government contracts or grants should be awarded to individuals or companies with seriously delinquent federal tax debts. </p> <p>(Sec. 3) Requires the head of any executive agency that issues an invitation for bids or a request for proposals for a contract, or that offers a grant, in an amount greater than the simplified acquisition threshold, to require each person submitting a bid or proposal or grant application to: (1) certify that such person does not have a seriously delinquent tax debt, and (2) authorize the Department of the Treasury to disclose information limited to describing whether such person has a seriously delinquent tax debt. Subjects a person who has a seriously delinquent tax debt to a negative responsibility or high risk determination when applying for a federal contract or grant, or to suspension or debarment from the federal procurement process. Authorizes an agency head to waive a suspension or debarment proceeding for a person with a seriously delinquent tax debt upon a written finding of urgent and compelling circumstances significantly affecting the interests of the United States. </p> <p>(Sec. 5) Defines "seriously delinquent tax debt" as a federal tax liability that has been assessed by the Internal Revenue Service and is collectible by levy or a court proceeding, except a tax debt: (1) that is being paid in a timely manner under an approved installment agreement or an offer-in-compromise, (2) for which a collection due process hearing has been requested or is pending; (3) for which a continuous levy has been issued or agreed to by an applicant for employment, or (4) with respect to which such a levy is released because it has been determined to be an economic hardship to the taxpayer.</p> <p>(Sec. 6) Makes this Act applicable to contracts and grants awarded on or after 270 days after the enactment date of this Act. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1562v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-04-14">
<action-date>2015-03-24</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Contracting and Tax Accountability Act of 2015</strong> </p> <p>Requires the head of any executive agency that issues an invitation for bids or a request for proposals for a contract, or that offers a grant, in an amount greater than the simplified acquisition threshold, to require each person submitting a bid or proposal or grant application to: (1) certify that such person does not have a seriously delinquent tax debt, and (2) authorize the Department of the Treasury to disclose information limited to describing whether such person has a seriously delinquent tax debt. Subjects a person who has a seriously delinquent tax debt to a negative responsibility determination when applying for a federal contract or grant, or to debarment from the federal procurement process.</p> <p>Defines "seriously delinquent tax debt" as a federal tax liability that has been assessed by the Internal Revenue Service and is collectible by levy or a court proceeding, except a tax debt: (1) that is being paid in a timely manner under an approved installment agreement or an offer-in-compromise, (2) for which a collection due process hearing has been requested or is pending; (3) for which a continuous levy has been issued or agreed to by an applicant for employment, or (4) with respect to which such a levy is released because it has been determined to be an economic hardship to the taxpayer.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
