<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1684" measure-id="id114hr1684" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-03-26" update-date="2016-07-13">
<title>Foreign Spill Protection Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1684v17" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-07-13">
<action-date>2016-04-25</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Foreign Spill Protection Act of 2016</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Oil Pollution Act of 1990 to make foreign facilities that are located offshore and outside the boundary of the exclusive economic zone (EEZ) liable for removal costs and damages that result from oil spills that reach (or threaten to reach) U.S. navigable waters, adjoining shorelines, or the EEZ. Specifically, the following parties may be held liable: (1) the owners or operators of the foreign facilities, and (2) the holders of a right of use and easement granted under applicable foreign law for the area in which the facility is located.</p> <p> <p> <p><BR> <BR> </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1684v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-04-26">
<action-date>2015-03-26</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Foreign Spill Protection Act of 2015</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Oil Pollution Act of 1990 to make the owner or operator of a foreign offshore unit liable for removal costs and specified damages that result from a discharge, or substantial threat of discharge, of oil from such unit that reaches or threatens to reach: (1) U.S. navigable waters or adjoining shorelines, or (2) the exclusive economic zone. A &quot;foreign offshore unit&quot; is a facility that is located in the territorial sea or on the continental shelf of a foreign country that is used for oil exploration, drilling, production, or related activities.</p> <p> The bill also amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (commonly known as the Clean Water Act) to: (1) prohibit the discharge of oil from a foreign offshore unit that reaches the navigable waters of the United States, adjoining shorelines, or waters of the contiguous zone; and (2) subject the owner or operator of the unit to penalties under that Act.</p> <p><BR> <BR> </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
