<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3442" measure-id="id114hr3442" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-09-08" update-date="2016-04-08">
<title>Debt Management and Fiscal Responsibility Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3442v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-04-08">
<action-date>2016-02-11</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Debt Management and Fiscal Responsibility Act of 2015 </b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill requires the Secretary of the Treasury to provide a report to Congress prior to any date on which the Secretary anticipates the public debt will reach the statutory limit. </p> <p>The Secretary must appear before the House Ways and Means Committee and the Senate Finance Committee to submit a report including: </p> <ul> <li>historic, current, and projected levels of debt;</li> <li>historic levels of revenue; </li> <li>the drivers and composition of future debt; </li> <li>how the United States will meet debt obligations if the debt limit is raised;</li> <li>reduction measures Treasury intends to take to fund obligations if the debt limit is not raised; and</li> <li>the President's recommendation regarding a balanced budget amendment to the U.S. Constitution.</li> </ul> <p>The Secretary must also provide a detailed explanation of: </p> <ul> <li> proposals to reduce the debt and a progress report on implementing them; </li> <li>the impact an increased debt limit will have on future spending, debt service, and the position of the U.S. dollar as the international reserve currency; </li> <li>projections of the fiscal health and sustainability of major entitlement programs (including Social Security, Medicare, and Medicaid);</li> <li>measures Treasury is taking or intends to take to avoid default, including a plan to publicly disclose the details; and</li> <li>Treasury's capability to pay only principal and interest on the debt if the limit is reached.</li> </ul> <p> Treasury must make the information required by this bill available to the public on its website. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3442v79" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-01-29">
<action-date>2015-10-07</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p><b>Debt Management and Fiscal Responsibility Act of 2015 </b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill requires the Secretary of the Treasury to provide a report to Congress prior to any date on which the Secretary anticipates the public debt will reach the statutory limit. </p> <p>The Secretary must appear before the House Ways and Means Committee and the Senate Finance Committee to submit a report including: the historic, current, and projected levels of the debt; the drivers and composition of future debt; and how the United States will meet debt obligations if the debt limit is raised. </p> <p>The Secretary must also provide a detailed explanation of: </p> <ul> <li> proposals of the President to reduce the debt and a progress report on implementing them; </li> <li>the impact an increased debt limit will have on future government spending, debt service, and the position of the U.S. dollar as the international reserve currency; and </li> <li>projections of the fiscal health and sustainability of major entitlement programs (including Social Security, Medicare, and Medicaid). </li> </ul> <p>The Department of the Treasury must make the information required by this bill available to the public on the Treasury website. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3442v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-09-14">
<action-date>2015-09-08</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Debt Management and Fiscal Responsibility Act of 2015 </b></p> <p>This bill requires the Secretary of the Treasury to provide a report to Congress prior to any date on which the Secretary anticipates the public debt will reach the statutory limit. </p> <p>The Secretary must appear before the House Ways and Means Committee and the Senate Finance Committee to submit a report including: the historic, current, and projected levels of the debt; the drivers and composition of future debt; and how the U.S. will meet debt obligations if the debt limit is raised. </p> <p>The Secretary must also provide a detailed explanation of: </p> <ul> <li> proposals of the President to reduce the debt and a progress report on implementing them; </li> <li>the impact an increased debt limit will have on future government spending, debt service, and the position of the U.S. dollar as the international reserve currency; and </li> <li>projections of the fiscal health and sustainability of major entitlement programs (including Social Security, Medicare, and Medicaid). </li> </ul> <p>The Department of the Treasury must make the information required by this bill available to the public on the Treasury website. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
