<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4495" measure-id="id114hr4495" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-02-08" update-date="2016-07-18">
<title>Education for Jobs Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4495v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-07-18">
<action-date>2016-02-08</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Education for Jobs Act</b></p> <p>This bill amends title IV (Student Assistance) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to make an individual eligible to apply for a loan under the William D. Ford Federal Direct Loan program if that individual: (1) is carrying at least three credit hours or the equivalent coursework for the course of study the individual is pursuing, (2) is enrolled in an educational program leading to a degree or certificate, and (3) was employed on a full-time basis for at least 10 years.</p> <p>It makes those students eligible for interest subsidies. It requires the repayment period for such a loan to begin the day after six months after the student ceases to meet the loan eligibility requirements.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
