<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1156" measure-id="id114hr1156" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-02-27" update-date="2015-08-11">
<title>International Science and Technology Cooperation Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1156v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-08-11">
<action-date>2015-05-19</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>International Science and Technology Cooperation Act of 2015 </b></p> <p> Directs the Office of Science and Technology Policy (OSTP) to establish or designate a working group under the National Science and Technology Council that has the responsibility of identifying and coordinating international science and technology cooperation that can strengthen U.S. science and technology enterprise, improve economic and national security, and support U.S. foreign policy goals. </p> <p>Requires the working group to be co-chaired by officials from OSTP and the Department of State. </p> <p>Requires the working group to: (1) coordinate interagency international science and technology cooperative research and training activities and partnerships supported or managed by federal agencies; (2) establish federal priorities and policies for aligning such international research, training, and partnerships with U.S. foreign policy goals; (3) identify opportunities for new international research and training partnerships that advance science and technology and U.S. foreign policy priorities; (4) solicit recommendations from non-federal science and technology stakeholders; and (5) identify broad issues that influence the ability of U.S. scientists and engineers to collaborate with foreign counterparts. </p> <p>Requires the Director to report every two years on the working group's activities. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1156v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-03-18">
<action-date>2015-02-27</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>International Science and Technology Cooperation Act of 2015</b></p> <p> Requires the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy (OSTP) to establish a body under the National Science and Technology Council that has the responsibility of identifying and coordinating international science and technology cooperation that can strengthen U.S. science and technology enterprise, improve economic and national security, and support U.S. foreign policy goals. </p> <p>Requires the body to be co-chaired by senior level officials from OSTP and the Department of State. </p> <p>Requires the body to: (1) coordinate interagency international science and technology cooperative research and training activities and partnerships supported or managed by federal agencies, (2) establish federal priorities and policies for aligning such international science and technology cooperative research and training activities and partnerships with the foreign policy goals of the United States, (3) identify opportunities for new international science and technology cooperative research and training partnerships that advance science and technology and U.S. foreign policy priorities, (4) solicit recommendations from non-federal science and technology stakeholders, and (5) identify broad issues that influence the ability of U.S. scientists and engineers to collaborate with foreign counterparts. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
