<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2665" measure-id="id114hr2665" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-06-04" update-date="2015-08-03">
<title>Wild Olympics Wilderness and Wild and Scenic Rivers Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2665v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-08-03">
<action-date>2015-06-04</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Wild Olympics Wilderness and Wild and Scenic Rivers Act of 2015 </b></p> <p> Designates certain federal land in the Olympic National Forest in the state of Washington as wilderness and components of the National Wilderness Preservation System. Designates certain other land, identified on the same map as such proposed areas, as potential wilderness. </p> <p>Amends the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to designate as wild, scenic, or recreational rivers specified segments of the following rivers in the state of Washington:</p> <ul> <li>Elwha River;</li> <li>Dungeness River;</li> <li>Big Quilcene River;</li> <li>Dosewallips River;</li> <li>Duckabush River;</li> <li>Hamma Hamma River;</li> <li>South Fork Skokomish River;</li> <li>Middle Fork Satsop River;</li> <li>West Fork Satsop River;</li> <li>Wynoochee River;</li> <li>East Fork Humptulips River;</li> <li>West Fork Humptulips River;</li> <li>Quinault River;</li> <li>Queets River;</li> <li>Hoh River;</li> <li>Bogachiel River;</li> <li>South Fork Calawah River;</li> <li>Sol Duc River; and</li> <li>Lyre River.</li> </ul> <p>Authorizes the Department of Agriculture to take necessary measures to control fire, insects, and diseases in the wilderness areas designated by this Act. </p> <p>Withdraws the federal land within the boundaries of the designated river segments from: (1) entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws; (2) location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and (3) disposition under all laws relating to mineral and geothermal leasing or mineral materials. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
