<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2650" measure-id="id114hr2650" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-06-04" update-date="2015-06-25">
<title>RESCUE America's Health Care Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2650v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-06-25">
<action-date>2015-06-04</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Restoring Equity, Saving Coverage, and Undoing Errors Act of 2015 or the RESCUE America's Health Care Act of 2015</b></p> <p>This bill applies only: (1) if the Supreme Court determines that the premium tax credit under the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (PPACA) is not applicable to health plans purchased through the federal health insurance exchange, and (2) in states without a state health insurance exchange.</p> <p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow a tax credit for individuals with health insurance who are ineligible for federal health care and not enrolled in an employer-subsidized group health plan.</p> <p>The Department of the Treasury must make payments to health insurers on behalf of taxpayers eligible for the tax credit.</p> <p>This bill repeals certain provisions of PPACA and the Health Care and Education Reconciliation Act of 2010 relating to health insurance, health savings accounts, and health flexible spending accounts. Provisions amended by the repealed provisions are restored.</p> <p>Any health plan fulfills an individual's requirement to maintain minimum essential coverage.</p> <p>Dental plans no longer need to provide pediatric dental benefits to be offered on a health insurance exchange.</p> <p>This bill amends the Public Health Service Act to define individual health pools (IHPs) as nonprofit entities that form health insurance risk pools. IHPs are prohibited from conditioning membership on an individual's health status and must offer the same coverage to all members. State benefit requirements and restrictions on premium variation do not apply to IHPs.</p> <p>Health insurers in the individual market must offer coverage to all individuals.</p> A health insurer may exclude coverage for a preexisting condition or vary premiums based on health status only for individuals who have not had continuous coverage for the last 18 months.]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
