<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3036" measure-id="id114hr3036" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-07-13" update-date="2016-02-12">
<title>9/11 Memorial Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3036v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-02-12">
<action-date>2016-02-09</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p><b>National 9/11 Memorial at the World Trade Center Act </b></p> <p>(Sec. 3) This bill designates the National September 11 Memorial located at the World Trade Center in New York City, New York, as a national memorial. </p> <p>This memorial shall not be a unit of the National Park System. </p> <p>(Sec. 4) The Department of the Interior may award a single grant per year through a competitive process to a tax-exempt, charitable nonprofit organization (eligible entity) for the operation and maintenance of any memorial located within the United States established to commemorate the events of and honor:</p> <ul> <li>the victims of the terrorist attacks on the World Trade Center, the Pentagon, and United Airlines Flight 93 on September 11, 2001; and </li> <li>the victims of the terrorist attack on the World Trade Center on February 26, 1993. </li> </ul> <p>In awarding such grants, Interior shall give greatest weight in the selection of eligible entities using the following criteria: </p> <ul> <li>experience in managing a public memorial that will benefit the largest number of visitors each calendar year; </li> <li>experience in managing a memorial of significant size (four acres or more);</li> <li>successful coordination and cooperation with federal, state, and local governments in the operation and management of the memorial;</li> <li>the ability and commitment to use grant funds to enhance security at the memorial; and</li> <li>the ability to use grant funds to increase the numbers of economically disadvantaged visitors to the memorial and surrounding areas.</li> </ul>  <p>The authority to award grants under this Act shall expire seven years after enactment of this Act. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3036v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-07-24">
<action-date>2015-07-13</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>National 9/11 Memorial at the World Trade Center Act</b></p> <p>This bill designates the National September 11 Memorial located at the World Trade Center in New York City, New York, as a national memorial.</p> <p>The Department of the Interior may award a grant of not more than $25 million each fiscal year to the National September 11 Memorial and Museum at the World Trade Center Foundation, Inc., for the operation and maintenance of the memorial.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
