<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4940" measure-id="id114hr4940" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-04-14" update-date="2016-05-10">
<title>JCPOA Intelligence Enforcement Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4940v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-05-10">
<action-date>2016-04-14</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>JCPOA Intelligence Enforcement Act of 2016</b></p> <p>This bill directs the Director of National Intelligence (DNI) to establish an integration cell among elements of the U.S. intelligence community to integrate intelligence for monitoring and enforcement of the Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action (JCPOA), which is the international agreement on Iran's nuclear program.</p> <p>The cell must coordinate intelligence collection, integrate early warning systems with respect to potential violations, and identify intelligence gaps in monitoring for the JCPOA.</p> <p>The cell must report to Congress annually regarding its awareness of, and its recommendations for better collection regarding, Iran's compliance.</p> <p>The bill expresses the sense of Congress that the intelligence community should establish a joint fusion cell with the Gulf Cooperation Council to:</p> <ul> <li>combat Iran's malevolent regional activities, including its support for terrorist proxies, such as Hezbollah;</li> <li>disrupt illicit transfers of weapons and material in violation of United Nations Security Council Resolution 2231; and</li> <li>protect the territorial integrity of key partner nations.</li> </ul> <p>The bill also expresses the sense of Congress that the DNI should establish a United States-Israel intelligence working group focused specifically on the Iranian threat.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
