<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2513" measure-id="id114hr2513" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-21" update-date="2015-10-26">
<title>PACE Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2513v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-10-26">
<action-date>2015-05-21</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p class="MsoNormal"><b>Promoting Access, Competition, and Equity Act of 2015 or the PACE Act of 2015</b></p> <p>This bill amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to&nbsp;ease application criteria and procedures for physician-owned hospitals to expand their facilities. Under current law, expansion of physician-owned hospitals is subject to certain limitations, such as those&nbsp;regarding the extent and frequency of expansion and requiring community output. The bill suspends these limitations&nbsp;with respect to applications for expansion&nbsp;filed before October 1, 2019. </p> <p>Following the end of this suspension period, hospitals with consistently high quality ratings&nbsp;are included among those hospitals that may apply to expand their facilities. The Centers for Medicare&nbsp;&amp; Medicaid&nbsp;Services may not alter the methodology for computing a hospital's quality rating before October 1, 2019. </p> <p class="MsoNormal">With respect to hospitals under development as of March 23, 2010, the bill extends to May 1, 2015, the date by which a hospital may qualify for an exception to the ownership or investment prohibition on physician self-referrals.</p> <p class="MsoNormal">The bill also: (1) exempts physician-owned hospitals from specified documentation and coding adjustments, and (2) extends reductions in certain inflationary increases associated with Medicare payments for inpatient hospital services.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
