<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3084" measure-id="id114hr3084" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-07-16" update-date="2015-10-16">
<title>Thoroughbred Horseracing Integrity Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3084v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-10-16">
<action-date>2015-07-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Thoroughbred Horseracing Integrity Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>Establishes the Thoroughbred Horseracing Anti-Doping Authority as an independent organization with responsibility for developing and administering an anti-doping program for Thoroughbred horses (covered horses), the trainers, owners, veterinarians, and employees of such persons and other personnel who are engaged in the care, training, or racing of such horses (covered persons), and horseraces that involve only Thoroughbreds and that are the subject of interstate off-track wagers (covered horseraces). Grants the Authority exclusive jurisdiction for anti-doping matters over all covered horses, persons, and horseraces, effective January 1, 2017. </p> <p>Imposes the jurisdiction and authority of the Authority as conditions upon the privilege to accept, receive, or transmit wagers on, and to participate in, covered horseraces. Vests the Authority with the same powers over Thoroughbred horseracing licensees as the state racing commissions have.</p> <p>Directs the Authority to develop and administer the Thoroughbred horseracing anti-doping program, which shall include:</p> <ul> <li /> lists of permitted and prohibited substances and methods; <li> a schedule of sanctions for violations; </li> <li> programs relating to anti-doping research and education; </li> <li> testing procedures, standards, and protocols for in-competition and out-of-competition testing; </li> <li> procedures for investigating, charging, and adjudicating violations and for the enforcement of sanctions for violations; and </li> <li> laboratory standards for accreditation and testing requirements, procedures, and protocols. </li> </ul> <p>Conditions eligibility to participate in covered horseraces on covered persons agreeing that they and their covered horses shall be bound by the provisions of the program.</p> <p>Directs the Authority to establish: (1) a list of anti-doping rule violations applicable to either horses or covered persons; (2) standards of accreditation for laboratories involved in the testing of samples taken from Thoroughbred horses, the process for achieving and maintaining accreditation, and the standards and protocols for testing of samples; (3) rules for anti-doping results management and the disciplinary process for anti-doping rule violations; and (4) uniform rules imposing sanctions against covered persons and/or covered horses for anti-doping rule violations. </p> <p> Requires funds for the establishment and administration of the anti-doping program to be paid by the Thoroughbred horseracing industry.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
