<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1426" measure-id="id114hr1426" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-03-18" update-date="2015-08-12">
<title>Public Access to Public Science Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1426v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-08-12">
<action-date>2015-03-18</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Public Access to Public Science Act</b></p> <p> Directs each of the covered agencies (the National Aeronautics and Space Administration [NASA], National Science Foundation, National Institute of Standards and Technology, and National Weather Service) to formulate and implement a public access policy to make covered works publicly available, without charge, starting on the day after the end of an embargo period. </p> <p>Defines: (1) &quot;covered work&quot; as any research results published in a peer-reviewed scholarly publication based on research funded in whole or in part by a covered agency, with certain exceptions; and (2) &quot;embargo period&quot; as up to 12 months after the initial date of publication of a covered work, unless extended, pursuant to a stakeholder's petition, by the covered agency after determining that the public interest will be substantially and uniquely harmed under the agency's public access policy. </p> <p>Requires the public access policy to: (1) allow the public to read, download, and analyze by machine covered works in digital form; (2) facilitate easy public search of, analysis of, and access to covered works; (3) encourage public-private collaboration to maximize interoperability between public and private platforms, avoid unnecessary duplication of existing mechanisms, and maximize the impact of the covered agency's research investment; (4) ensure that attribution to authors, journals, and original publishers is maintained; and (5) ensure that publications and metadata are stored in an accessible archive. </p> <p>Requires a covered agency's public access policy to ensure full public access to metadata of covered works, without charge, beginning when the covered work is first published. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
