<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="311" measure-id="id114hr311" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-01-13" update-date="2015-03-26">
<title>Adoption Promotion Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr311v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-03-26">
<action-date>2015-01-13</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Adoption Promotion Act of 2015</b></p> <p>Amends the Public Health Service Act (PHSA) to direct the Department of Health and Human Services to ensure that pregnancy options counseling funded through training grants for family planning service program personnel includes adoption counseling and is provided by licensed social workers or counselors who have knowledge and experience in adoption practice. Requires that family planning service program training include training on the adoption process.</p> <p>Requires research related to family planning and population funded under the PHSA to include: (1) the collection of data on the number of pregnancy tests administered to individuals served by family planning service programs and the results of those tests; and (2) the evaluation of the quality, consistency, and outcomes of pregnancy options counseling.</p> <UL> <UL> </UL> </UL> <UL> </UL>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
