<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4403" measure-id="id114hr4403" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-02-01" update-date="2016-04-15">
<title>Enhancing Overseas Traveler Vetting Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4403v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-04-15">
<action-date>2016-04-13</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Enhancing Overseas Traveler Vetting Act</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill authorizes the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) and the Department of State to: </p> <ul> <li>develop open-source software based on U.S. Customs and Border Protection's global travel targeting and analysis systems and the State Department's watch listing, identification, and screening systems to facilitate the vetting of travelers against terrorist watch lists and law enforcement databases, enhance border management, and improve targeting and analysis; and </li> <li>make such software and any related technical assistance or training available to foreign governments or multilateral organizations for such purposes.</li> </ul> <p> DHS and the State Department shall submit an implementing plan to Congress.</p> <p>Before making open-source software available to foreign governments or multilateral organizations, DHS and the State Department shall: (1) certify to Congress that such availability is in U.S. national security interests, and (2) inform Congress on how such software or any related technical assistance or training will be made available. </p> <p> No additional funds are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4403v18" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-04-15">
<action-date>2016-04-11</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House amended, Part I</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Enhancing Overseas Traveler Vetting Act</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill authorizes the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) and the Department of State to: </p> <ul> <li>develop open-source software, in accordance with cyber security best practices, based on U.S. Customs and Border Protection's global travel targeting and analysis systems and the State Department's watch listing, identification, and screening systems to facilitate the vetting of travelers against terrorist watch lists and law enforcement databases, enhance border management, and improve targeting and analysis; and </li> <li>make such software and any related technical assistance or training available to foreign governments or multilateral organizations for such purposes.</li> </ul> <p> DHS and the State Department shall submit an implementing plan to Congress.</p> <p>Before making open-source software available to foreign governments or multilateral organizations, DHS and the State Department shall: (1) certify to Congress that such availability is in U.S. national security interests, and (2) inform Congress on how such software or any related technical assistance or training will be made available. </p> <p> No additional funds are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4403v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-02-05">
<action-date>2016-02-01</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Enhancing Overseas Traveler Vetting Act</strong></p> <p>This bill authorizes the Department of Homeland Security and the Department of State to: </p> <ul> <li>develop open-source software based on U.S. Customs and Border Protection's global travel targeting and analysis systems and the State Department's watchlisting, identification, and screening systems to facilitate the vetting of travelers against terrorist watchlists and law enforcement databases, enhance border management, and improve targeting and analysis; and </li> <li>make such software and any related technical assistance or training available to foreign governments or multilateral organizations for such purposes.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
