<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3955" measure-id="id114hr3955" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-11-05" update-date="2016-01-15">
<title>Small Municipality Flood Relief Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3955v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-01-15">
<action-date>2015-11-05</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Small Municipality Flood Relief Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to authorize the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to release a local government from certain land restrictions imposed on a parcel under the hazard mitigation program for recipients of acquisition or relocation project assistance if:</p> <ul> <li> the local government submits to the state, more than five years after the closeout of the acquisition or relocation project, a request for such release; </li> <li> on the date of the request, the parcel is not in an area designated by FEMA as having special flood hazards; </li> <li> the local government certifies that no coercion took place against the original property owner in acquiring the parcel; </li> <li> the state in which the parcel is located approves the request and submits to FEMA a recommendation for its approval;</li> <li> the local government repays FEMA for the amount of hazard mitigation assistance received for the acquisition or relocation project or substitutes a different parcel that is at least twice as large as, and subject to the same restrictions being released for, the original parcel; and</li> <li>FEMA gives final approval to the request.</li> </ul> <ul> <ul> </ul> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
