<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1996" measure-id="id114hr1996" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-04-23" update-date="2015-05-11">
<title>No Social Security Numbers and Benefits for Illegal Aliens Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1996v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-05-11">
<action-date>2015-04-23</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>No Social Security Numbers and Benefits for Illegal Aliens Act of 2015</b></p> <p> Amends title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) (OASDI) of the Social Security Act to prohibit the Commissioner of Social Security from assigning a Social Security account number to any individual who receives deferred action on removal in accordance with certain Department of Homeland Security memoranda dated June 15, 2012 and November 20, 2014, and who would be subject to removal but for such memoranda.</p> <p>Prohibits the payment of OASDI benefits to such individuals. </p> <p>Denies the crediting of quarters of coverage toward benefits for earnings from unauthorized work by an individual who is not a U.S. citizen or national and who was not authorized to be employed in the United States.</p> <p>Prohibits counting an individual's annual wages or self-employment income for any year for which no quarter of coverage may be credited.</p> <p>Directs the Commissioner and the Secretary to enter into an agreement to establish a system to transmit to the Secretary any Social Security account number assigned to an individual after the enactment of this Act, as well as other identifying information, in any case in which the individual is not a U.S. citizen or national at the time that number is assigned.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
