<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3211" measure-id="id114hr3211" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-07-23" update-date="2016-07-07">
<title>To provide for the addition of certain real property to the reservation of the Siletz Tribe in the State of Oregon.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3211v79" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-07-07">
<action-date>2016-05-11</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Siletz Tribe Indian Restoration Act to authorize the Department of the Interior to take into trust for the Siletz Tribe additional lands that lie within the original 1855 Siletz Coast Reservation and are located in Benton, Douglas, Lane, Lincoln, Tillamook, or Yamhill County in Oregon. </p> <p>Such land must be considered and evaluated as an on-reservation acquisition and become part of the tribe's reservation. (Off-reservation land acquisition requests require Interior to give greater scrutiny to the tribe's justification of the anticipated benefits from the acquisition.)</p> <p>Gaming is prohibited on lands taken into trust pursuant to this bill. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3211v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-09-04">
<action-date>2015-07-23</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Amends the Siletz Tribe Indian Restoration Act to authorize the Department of the Interior to take into trust for the Siletz Tribe additional lands that lie within the original 1855 Siletz Coast Reservation and are located in Benton, Douglas, Lane, Lincoln, Tillamook, or Yamhill County in Oregon. </p> <p>Requires such land to be considered and evaluated as an on-reservation acquisition and become part of the Tribe's reservation. (Off-reservation land acquisition requests require Interior to give greater scrutiny to the tribe's justification of the anticipated benefits from the acquisition.)</p> <p>Prohibits gaming on lands taken into trust pursuant to this Act. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
