<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2039" measure-id="id114hr2039" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-04-28" update-date="2016-05-05">
<title>National Aeronautics and Space Administration Authorization Act for 2016 and 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2039v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-05-05">
<action-date>2015-04-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>National Aeronautics and Space Administration Authorization Act for 2016 and 2017 </b></p> <p>Authorizes appropriations for FY2016-FY2017 for the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA).</p> <p>Authorizes programs, activities, and reports for NASA, including those relating to human exploration of space, the Space Launch System, the Orion multipurpose crew vehicle, space radiation, the International Space Station, the commercial crew program, radioisotope power systems, extrasolar planet exploration, the James Webb Space Telescope, the Wide-Field Infrared Survey Telescope, near-Earth objects, astrobiology, space weather, the Stratospheric Observatory for Infrared Astronomy, Venture class missions, aeronautics research (including transformative aeronautics research), science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (STEM) education, project and program reserves, orbital debris mitigation, remote satellite robotic servicing demonstrations, and astronaut occupational health care. </p> <p>Directs NASA to report to Congress on the proposed Asteroid Retrieval Mission. </p> <p>Directs NASA to utilize the International Space Station and commercial services for space technology demonstration missions in low-Earth orbit whenever it is practical and cost effective to do so.</p> <p>Establishes a space technology program. </p> <p>Directs NASA to: (1) enter into an arrangement with the National Academy of Public Administration to assess the effectiveness of the NASA Advisory Council, (2) enter into an arrangement with the National Academies for a review of the National Space Grant College and Fellowship Program, and (3) revise the NASA Supplement to the Federal Acquisition Regulation to address the detection and avoidance of counterfeit electronic parts. </p> <p>Directs NASA to develop a policy on the use of operational commercial reusable suborbital flight vehicles for carrying out scientific and engineering investigations and educational activities. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
