<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5672" measure-id="id114hr5672" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-07-07" update-date="2016-09-12">
<title>Small Business Access to Capital Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5672v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-09-12">
<action-date>2016-07-07</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Small Business Access to Capital Act of 2016</b> <p class="MsoNormal">This bill amends the Small Business Jobs Act of 2010 to extend for an additional eight fiscal years the State Small Business Credit Initiative to assist participating states to give collateral support and other innovative credit access and guarantee initiatives for small business concerns and manufacturers. </p> <p class="MsoNormal">The bill prescribes allocations of federal funds to participating states. </p> <p>Treasury may award, on a competitive basis, up to a total of $1 billion in two tranches, according to specified criteria, to participating states and consortiums of participating states for use: (1) for making federal contributions to, or for the account of, an approved state program; or (2) as collateral for a qualifying loan or swap funding facility. </p> <p>The State Small Business Credit Initiative Act of 2010 is amended to revise minimum program requirements for state capital access programs.</p> <p>Treasury may not approve any state capital access program that fails to include a plan that promotes a fair share of federal contributions to be used to strengthen and increase economic opportunities for small business concerns in low-and moderate-income, minority, and other underserved communities and women- and minority-owned small business concerns.</p> <p>In making a determination that a state other credit support program is eligible for federal contributions to, or for the account of, the state program, Treasury shall take into account the extent to which the state plans to use these contributions to provide access to capital for small business concerns in low- and moderate-income, minority, and other underserved communities and to women- and minority-owned small businesses, and the extent to which resulting small business lending will expand economic opportunities for such communities and such concerns.</p> <p>The bill revises the mandatory contents of each participating state's annual report to Treasury on its capital access program.</p> <p>Treasury shall:</p> <ul> <li> consult with the Office of Minority and Women Inclusion (OMWI) of the Departmental Offices of Treasury, among others, on the administration of the state capital access program; and </li> <li>ensure adequate oversight of the approved state programs to ensure efforts to expand economic opportunity for minority- and women-owned small business concerns.</li> </ul> <p>Treasury shall also:</p> <ul> <li> consult with the OMWI in issuing such regulations and other guidance to implement the Act; and</li> <li>in issuing these regulations, seek public input from community, civil rights, consumer advocates, small business advocates, and other interested or affected parties.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
