<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2751" measure-id="id114hr2751" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-06-12" update-date="2015-08-04">
<title>Alyce Spotted Bear and Walter Soboleff Commission on Native Children Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2751v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-08-04">
<action-date>2015-06-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Alyce Spotted Bear and Walter Soboleff Commission on Native Children Act</b></p> <p> Establishes the Alyce Spotted Bear and Walter Soboleff Commission on Native Children in the Office of Tribal Justice of the Department of Justice. </p> <p>Requires the President and Congress to appoint to the Commission individuals who have significant experience and expertise in Indian affairs and matters to be studied by the Commission.</p> <p>Requires the Commission to establish a Native Advisory Committee consisting of representatives of Indian tribes from each region of the Bureau of Indian Affairs and a native Hawaiian. </p> <p>Directs the Commission to study federal, state, local, and tribal programs that serve Native children and use the results of the study and analyses of existing federal data to: <ul> <li>develop recommendations for goals and plans for federal policy relating to Native children informed by the development of accurate child well-being measures;</li> <li>recommend modifications and improvements to programs that serve Native children; </li> <li>recommend improvements to the collection of data regarding Native children and the programs that serve them; and</li> <li>identify models of successful federal, state, and tribal programs in the areas studied by the Commission.</li> </ul> <p>Requires the Commission to submit a report to the President, Congress, and the White House Council on Native American Affairs on its findings, conclusions, and recommendations for legislative and administrative action. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
