<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5248" measure-id="id114hr5248" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-05-16" update-date="2016-07-21">
<title>To amend title 38, United States Code, to clarify the eligibility of children of Vietnam veterans born with spina bifida for benefits of the Department of Veterans Affairs.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5248v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-07-21">
<action-date>2016-05-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill states that the effective date for an award of Department of Veterans Affairs benefits for a child of a Vietnam veteran who is suffering from spina bifida is the date of the child's birth.</p> <p>This amendment shall be effective as if included in the Agent Orange Benefits Act.</p> <p>(Under current law the effective date for the provision of such benefits is January, 1, 1997 [but not before receipt of the application for benefits]. This bill thus provides &quot;retroactive&quot; benefits eligibility for children born before January 1, 1997.)</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
