<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4042" measure-id="id114hr4042" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-11-17" update-date="2016-07-07">
<title>Pre-K for USA Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4042v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-07-07">
<action-date>2015-11-17</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Pre-K for USA Act</strong></p> <p>This bill requires the Department of Education (ED) to award high-quality prekindergarten (pre-K) program development grants on a competitive basis to states, local education agencies, or other local government entities. </p> <p>A grant recipient may use the grant funds to award subgrants to local entities, provided that the entity did not receive pre-K program&nbsp;funding within the same fiscal year.</p> <p>Grants are nonrenewable and shall be awarded for a period of no more than three years. </p> <p>Unless granted a financial hardship waiver by ED,&nbsp;a grant recipient shall contribute matching funds equal to at least 20% of the grant amount.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
