<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3298" measure-id="id114hr3298" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-07-29" update-date="2016-04-11">
<title>Medicare Post-Acute Care Value-Based Purchasing Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3298v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-04-11">
<action-date>2015-07-29</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Medicare Post-Acute Care Value-Based Purchasing Act of 2015</b></p> <p>This bill amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to: (1) modify market basket percentages for post-acute care (PAC) providers, and (2) establish a PAC value-based purchasing program under which PAC providers receive value-based incentive payments. PAC providers are skilled nursing facilities, inpatient rehabilitation facilities, home health agencies, and long-term care hospitals.</p> <p>A market basket is an index that reflects inflation and is used to update payments and cost limits. Under current law, market basket percentage increases for PAC providers are generally based on the application of a formula based on costs from the preceding fiscal year, but for FY2018 these increases are fixed at 1%. The bill repeals these fixed increases, leaving FY2018 increases to instead be determined according to the existing formula.</p> <p>With respect to the PAC value-based purchasing program, the bill: (1) requires the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid (CMS) to establish performance standards and scores by which to rank PAC providers; (2) specifies how CMS must calculate value-based incentive payments for each type of PAC provider in accordance with such ranking; (3) requires CMS to make specified annual adjustments to how incentive payments are calculated; and (4) establishes limits on administrative and judicial review.</p> <p>Under current law, a value-based purchasing program for skilled nursing facilities has been established to begin in FY2019. The bill maintains this program but specifies that it must terminate in FY2025.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
