<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5595" measure-id="id114hr5595" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-06-28" update-date="2016-10-26">
<title>Reservoir Operations Improvement Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5595v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-10-26">
<action-date>2016-06-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Reservoir Operations Improvement Act</strong></p> <p>This bill directs the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers to submit a report with respect to each drought state (a state for which the governor has declared a drought or that contains at least one county for which the Department of Agriculture has designated a drought disaster) during water year 2015 or 2016 that includes: </p> <ul> <li>a list of flood control projects in such state;</li> <li> the year during which the original water manual (water operations manuals, flood control rule curves, and water control manuals) for each project was approved;</li> <li> the years during which any revisions to a project's water manual occurred or are requested to occur;</li> <li> a list of projects for which operational deviations for drought contingency, and changes to storage allocations, have been requested and the status of such requests; and</li> <li> a description of the means by which water conservation and water quality improvements were addressed in any response to such requests.</li> </ul> <p> The Corps of Engineers shall: (1) identify each project included in the report that includes a reservoir and for which a non-federal interest has submitted a written request to revise the project's water manual; (2) revise the water manuals of not more than 15 of such projects; and (3) in collaboration with the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, create a forecast-informed reservoir operations plan for each selected project. The water manual revision shall incorporate such plan, new watershed data, and the effects of any structural improvement completed after the date of the most recent prior revision of the water manual.</p> <p> A revision of a water manual may not reduce the water supply for any authorized purpose, other than flood control, of a flood control project. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
