<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4441" measure-id="id114hr4441" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-02-03" update-date="2016-05-09">
<title>Aviation Innovation, Reform, and Reauthorization Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4441v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-05-09">
<action-date>2016-02-03</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Aviation Innovation, Reform, and Reauthorization Act of 2016</b></p> <p>This bill reauthorizes the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) through FY2019 and specified FAA programs for FY2016-FY2022.</p> <p>The bill revises requirements for the pilot program for passenger facility charges at nonhub airports and airport improvement program.</p> <p>The bill establishes:</p> <ul> <li> the ATC Corporation as a federally-chartered, not-for-profit corporation; and</li> <li>an Advisory Board of the Corporation. </li> </ul> <p>The Department of Transportation (DOT) shall transfer to the Corporation:</p> <ul> <li> by a certain deadline FAA employees, property, and facilities; and</li> <li>on October 1, 2019, operational control of FAA air traffic services.</li> </ul> <p>DOT shall establish a Safety Oversight and Certification Advisory Committee.</p> <p>The FAA shall issue a notice of a proposed rule reorganizing the certification of, and streamlining the approval of safety advancements for, small airplanes. </p> <p>The FAA shall establish:</p> <ul> <li>the FAA Task Force on Flight Standards Reform, and </li> <li>a Regional Consistency Communications Board. </li> </ul> <p>The FAA shall establish a safety workforce training strategy.</p> <p>DOT shall take appropriate actions to promote U.S. aerospace standards, products, and services abroad. </p> <p>The FAA shall appoint a Designated Agency Safety and Health Officer.</p> <p>DOT shall develop a comprehensive plan to accelerate the integration of civil unmanned aircraft systems (drones) into the national airspace system.</p> <p>The bill establishes in the FAA an Unmanned Aircraft Systems (UAS) Integration Office.</p> <p>DOT shall establish a UAS detection systems pilot program.</p> <p>The bill prescribes certain requirements with respect to improving passenger air service. </p> <p>The bill also reauthorizes for FY2016-FY2022 the essential air service program and the small community air service development program.</p> <p>The FAA shall submit to Congress a strategic cybersecurity plan.</p> <p>DOT shall establish a remote air traffic control tower pilot program for rural or small communities.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
