<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1064" measure-id="id114hr1064" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-02-25" update-date="2015-03-18">
<title>Access to Education and Training Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1064v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-03-18">
<action-date>2015-02-25</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Access to Education and Training Act</strong></p> <p>Amends title IV (Student Assistance) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to allow the Secretary of Education to award a student two Pell Grants during a single award year if the student is enrolled in an associate or baccalaureate degree or certificate program at an institution of higher education on at least a half-time basis for the equivalent of more than one academic year or more than two semesters during the Pell Grant award year.</p> <p>Permits the total amount of Pell Grants awarded to such a student for the award year to exceed the maximum basic grant level specified in the appropriate appropriations Act for that award year.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
