<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="617" measure-id="id114hr617" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-01-28" update-date="2015-06-11">
<title>Clinical Trial Cancer Mission 2020 Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr617v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-06-11">
<action-date>2015-01-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Clinical Trial Cancer Mission 2020 Act</b></p> <p>Amends the Public Health Service Act to revise clinical trial registry data bank provisions to specify that a device or drug clinical trial must be included in the clinical trial registry data bank regardless of whether it results in a positive or negative outcome.</p> <p>Requires the responsible party of any clinical trials funded in whole or in part by the Department of Defense (DOD) to certify in all required grant or progress forms that the required submissions to the clinical trial registry data bank have been made. Requires DOD to verify that the clinical trial information has been submitted before releasing any remaining grant funds or funding future grants. </p> <p>Makes a clinical trial grantee of the Department of Health and Human Services or DOD who fails to submit the required information to the data bank ineligible for the remaining grant funds or future funds. Makes the grantee liable for repayment of grant amounts already provided.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
