<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2848" measure-id="id114hr2848" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-06-23" update-date="2015-12-03">
<title>Visa Overstay Enforcement Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2848v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-12-03">
<action-date>2015-06-23</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Visa Overstay Enforcement Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to subject any alien who remains in the United States after any visa or status under which the alien is lawfully present has expired to: (1) a fine or imprisonment for up to six months, or both, for a first offense; and (2) a fine or imprisonment for up to two years, or both, for any subsequent offense.</p> <p> Such penalties shall be waived if the overstay was due to medical necessity, public safety, or national security.</p> <p>An alien convicted of a first offense may not be admitted to the United States for 5 years or granted a visa for 10 years.</p> <p> An alien convicted of a subsequent offense may not be admitted to the United States at all or granted a visa.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
