<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1338" measure-id="id114hr1338" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-03-06" update-date="2015-12-01">
<title>Dignified Interment of Our Veterans Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1338v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-12-01">
<action-date>2015-11-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the House on October 26, 2015. The summary of that version is repeated here.)</p> <p><strong>Dignified Interment of Our Veterans Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill directs the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to study and report to Congress on matters relating to the interring of veterans' unclaimed remains in national cemeteries under the control of the National Cemetery Administration, including:</p> <ul> <li> the scope of the issues relating to veterans' unclaimed remains, including the estimated number of such remains;</li> <li> the effectiveness of VA procedures for working with persons or entities having custody of unclaimed remains to facilitate their interment in such cemeteries;</li> <li> state and local laws that affect the Secretary's ability to inter unclaimed veterans' remains in such cemeteries; and</li> <li> recommendations for appropriate legislative or administrative action.</li> </ul> <p> (Sec. 3) The Veterans Access, Choice, and Accountability Act of 2014 is amended to limit FY2016 awards and bonuses to $2 million for VA employees who are members of the Senior Executive Service.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1338v17" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-12-01">
<action-date>2015-10-26</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Dignified Interment of Our Veterans Act of 2015</strong></p> <p> (Sec. 2) This bill directs the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to study and report to Congress on matters relating to the interring of veterans' unclaimed remains in national cemeteries under the control of the National Cemetery Administration, including:</p> <ul> <li> the scope of the issues relating to veterans' unclaimed remains, including the estimated number of such remains;</li> <li> the effectiveness of VA procedures for working with persons or entities having custody of unclaimed remains to facilitate their interment in such cemeteries;</li> <li> state and local laws that affect the Secretary's ability to inter unclaimed veterans' remains in such cemeteries; and</li> <li> recommendations for appropriate legislative or administrative action.</li> </ul> <p> (Sec. 3) The Veterans Access, Choice, and Accountability Act of 2014 is amended to limit FY2016 awards and bonuses to $2 million for VA employees who are members of the Senior Executive Service.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1338v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-03-21">
<action-date>2015-03-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Dignified Interment of Our Veterans Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>Requires the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA) to study and report to Congress on matters relating to the interring of veterans' unclaimed remains in national cemeteries under the control of the National Cemetery Administration, including:</p> <ul> <li> the scope of the issues relating to veterans' unclaimed remains, including the estimated number of such remains;</li> <li> the effectiveness of VA procedures for working with persons or entities having custody of unclaimed remains to facilitate the interment of such remains in such cemeteries;</li> <li> state and local laws that affect the Secretary's ability to inter unclaimed veterans' remains in such cemeteries; and</li> <li> recommendations for appropriate legislative or administrative action.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
