<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4199" measure-id="id114hr4199" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-12-09" update-date="2016-04-18">
<title>Puerto Rico Financial Stability and Debt Restructuring Choice Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4199v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-04-18">
<action-date>2015-12-09</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Puerto Rico Financial Stability and Debt Restructuring Choice Act</b></p> <p>This bill establishes the Puerto Rico Financial Stability Council, subject to enactment of a law by the Legislative Assembly and the governor of Puerto Rico.</p>      <p>For each fiscal year the governor of Puerto Rico shall develop a financial plan, and the Legislative Assembly shall develop a budget, that meet specified requirements to promote financial stability, and both shall submit them to the Council for its approval. The bill prescribes procedures for submission to the Council of revised financial plans or revised budgets in the event of disapproval for failing meet specified criteria. </p>  <p>The government of Puerto Rico may not borrow money unless the Council certifies in advance that both the receipt of borrowed funds and the repayment of obligations incurred are consistent with the financial plan and budget for the year.</p> <p>The bill also prescribes procedures for addressing any variance of actual revenues and expenditures from the adopted financial plan and budget, including the withholding of funds under federal programs.</p> <p>The Council shall recommend to the governor, the Legislative Assembly, the President, and Congress actions for the government of Puerto Rico or the federal government to take to ensure compliance with a financial plan and budget.</p> <p>The bill amends federal bankruptcy law to apply to Puerto Rico treatment as a state with respect to Adjustments of Debts of a Municipality. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
