<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4890" measure-id="id114hr4890" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-04-11" update-date="2016-04-25">
<title>To impose a ban on the payment of bonuses to employees of the Internal Revenue Service until the Secretary of the Treasury develops and implements a comprehensive customer service strategy.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4890v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-04-25">
<action-date>2016-04-21</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(Sec. 1) This bill prohibits the Department of the Treasury from paying a bonus, award, or similar cash payment to any Internal Revenue Service (IRS) employee until Treasury develops and submits to Congress a comprehensive customer service strategy that has been reviewed and approved by the Treasury Inspector General for Tax Administration.</p> <p> The strategy must include: (1) appropriate telephone and correspondence levels of service; (2) a thorough assessment of which services the IRS can shift to self-service options; and (3) proposals to improve customer service over the short-term, the medium-term, and the long-term. </p> <p>In developing the strategy, Treasury must consult with the National Taxpayer Advocate. </p> <p>Treasury must submit semiannual reports to Congress on the status of its customer service strategy and actions taken to improve customer service. </p> <p>(Sec. 2) No additional funds are authorized to be appropriated or otherwise made available to carry out this bill. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4890v17" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-04-21">
<action-date>2016-04-18</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(Sec. 1) This bill prohibits the Department of the Treasury from paying a bonus, award, or similar cash payment to any Internal Revenue Service (IRS) employee until Treasury develops and submits to Congress a comprehensive customer service strategy that has been reviewed and approved by the Treasury Inspector General for Tax Administration.</p> <p> The strategy must include: (1) appropriate telephone and correspondence levels of service; (2) a thorough assessment of which services the IRS can shift to self-service options; and (3) proposals to improve customer service over the short-term, the medium-term, and the long-term. </p> <p>Treasury must submit semiannual reports to Congress on the status of its customer service strategy and actions taken to improve customer service. </p> <p>(Sec. 2) No additional funds are authorized to be appropriated or otherwise made available to carry out this bill. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4890v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-04-12">
<action-date>2016-04-11</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill prohibits the Department of the Treasury from paying a bonus, award, or similar cash payment to an Internal Revenue Service (IRS) employee until Treasury submits to Congress a comprehensive customer service strategy that has been reviewed and approved by the Treasury Inspector General for Tax Administration.</p> <p> The strategy must include: (1) appropriate telephone and correspondence levels of service; (2) an assessment of which services the IRS can shift to self-service options; and (3) proposals to improve customer service over the short-term, the medium-term, and the long-term. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
