<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5057" measure-id="id114hr5057" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-04-26" update-date="2016-06-27">
<title>Safe Prescribing for Veterans Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5057v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-06-27">
<action-date>2016-04-26</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Safe Prescribing for Veterans Act</strong></p> <p>This bill directs the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to require a VA employee (including a temporary full-time, part-time, or without-compensation employee) who is authorized to prescribe any controlled substance to complete at least one accredited continuing education course on pain management every two years. </p> <p>Such requirement shall: </p> <ul> <li>apply to an employee who is employed by the VA for at least 180 days during any 24-month period; and </li> <li>not apply to an employee licensed or certified by a state licensure or specialty board that requires the completion of pain management or substance use disorder management continuing education. </li> </ul> <p>Continuing education courses shall include information on safe prescribing practices, controlled substance disposal, pain management principles, and identification of potential substance use disorders and addiction treatment. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
