<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3578" measure-id="id114hr3578" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-09-18" update-date="2016-03-23">
<title>DHS Science and Technology Reform and Improvement Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3578v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-03-23">
<action-date>2015-12-10</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>DHS Science and Technology Reform and Improvement Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to declare that the Directorate of Science and Technology of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) shall be the primary research, development, testing, and evaluation arm of DHS, responsible for coordinating such activities to strengthen the security and resiliency of the United States. The Directorate shall be headed by the DHS Undersecretary for Science and Technology, who shall: (1) serve as the DHS senior scientific advisor, and (2) identify and develop countermeasures to terrorist threats that may serve as the basis for a national strategy. </p> <p>The Directorate shall: (1) develop and deliver knowledge, analyses, and innovative solutions that are responsive to homeland security capability gaps and threats; (2) seek innovative, system-based solutions to complex homeland security problems and threats; and (3) build partnerships and leverage technology solutions developed by other governmental entities, universities, and the private sector. </p> <p>The bill expands to duties of the Directorate to include: </p> <ul> <li> coordinating and integrating all research, development, demonstration, testing, and evaluation activities of DHS, including through a centralized federal clearinghouse relating to technologies that would further the DHS mission;</li> <li> establishing a process that includes Directorate and DHS leadership and through which research and development projects are assessed on a regular basis; </li> <li> developing and overseeing the administration of guidelines for periodic review of research and development programs or activities; </li> <li> partnering with DHS components and offices to develop and deliver knowledge, analyses, and innovative solutions that are responsive to identified homeland security capability gaps and threats; and </li> <li> acting as a coordinating office for technology development and coordinating with organizations that provide venture capital to businesses, particularly small businesses, to assist in the commercialization of innovative homeland security technologies.</li> </ul> <p> DHS must review and revise departmental policies on personnel conflicts of interest to ensure that such policies specifcally address employees of federally-funded research and development centers who are in a position to make or materially influence research findings or agency decision-making. </p> <p>The criteria for designating colleges or universities as a center for homeland security is modified to require expertise in nuclear explosives countermeasures or detection.</p> <p>The bill establishes in the Directorate a Test, Evaluation, and Standards Division to serve as an adviser to the DHS Secretary and the DHS Under Secretary of Management on all test and evaluation or standards activities in DHS. </p> <p>The Directorate shall:</p> <ul> <li> establish a process to define, identify, prioritize, fund, and task its basic and applied homeland security research and development activities;</li> <li>develop and submit to appropriate congressional committees a strategy to guide its activities; </li> <li>develop and update, at least once every five years, a five-year research and development plan for its activities; </li> <li>establish and utilize a system to track the progress of its research, development, testing, and evaluation activities;</li> <li>establish the Homeland Security Science and Technology Fellows Program;</li> <li>support research, development, testing, evaluation, and transition of cybersecurity technology;</li> <li>establish Integrated Product Teams to assist DHS in identifying, coordinating, and aligning research and development efforts with departmental missions; and </li> <li>establish a Homeland Security-STEM internship program to encourage students to pursue STEM (science, technology, engineering, and mathematics) careers in homeland security related fields.</li> </ul> <p>The bill extends through FY2020 DHS authority for certain research and development projects. </p> <p>The bill revises the definition of &quot;incident&quot; used with respect to the National Cybersecurity and Communications Integration Center. </p> <p>The Government Accountability Office shall initiate a study to assess the university-based centers for homeland security program and provide recommendations to the congressional homeland security committees for appropriate improvements. </p> <p>The Directorate shall utilize, as appropriate, prize authority granted pursuant to current law. </p> <p>No new funds are authorized to carry out this Act. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3578v17" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-03-23">
<action-date>2015-12-08</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>DHS Science and Technology Reform and Improvement Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to declare that the Directorate of Science and Technology of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) shall be the primary research, development, testing, and evaluation arm of DHS, responsible for coordinating such activities to strengthen the security and resiliency of the United States. The Directorate shall be headed by the DHS Undersecretary for Science and Technology, who shall: (1) serve as the DHS senior scientific advisor, and (2) identify and develop countermeasures to terrorist threats that may serve as the basis for a national strategy. </p> <p>The Directorate shall: (1) develop and deliver knowledge, analyses, and innovative solutions that are responsive to homeland security capability gaps; (2) seek innovative, system-based solutions to complex homeland security problems; and (3) build partnerships and leverage technology solutions developed by other governmental entities, universities, and the private sector. </p> <p>The bill expands to duties of the Directorate to include: </p> <ul> <li> coordinating and integrating all research, development, demonstration, testing, and evaluation activities of DHS, including through a centralized federal clearinghouse relating to technologies that would further the DHS mission;</li> <li> establishing a process that includes Directorate and DHS leadership and through which research and development projects are assessed on a regular basis; </li> <li> developing and overseeing the administration of guidelines for periodic review of research and development programs or activities; </li> <li> partnering with DHS components and offices to develop and deliver knowledge, analyses, and innovative solutions that are responsive to identified homeland security capability gaps; and </li> <li> acting as a coordinating office for technology development and coordinating with organizations that provide venture capital to businesses, particularly small businesses, to assist in the commercialization of innovative homeland security technologies.</li> </ul> <p> DHS must review and revise departmental policies on personnel conflicts of interest to ensure that such policies specifically address employees of federally-funded research and development centers who are in a position to make or materially influence research findings or agency decision-making. </p> <p>The criteria for designating colleges or universities as a center for homeland security is modified to require expertise in nuclear explosives countermeasures or detection.</p> <p>The bill establishes in the Directorate a Test, Evaluation, and Standards Division to serve as an adviser to the DHS Secretary and the DHS Under Secretary of Management on all test and evaluation or standards activities in DHS. </p> <p>The Directorate shall:</p> <ul> <li> establish a process to define, identify, prioritize, fund, and task its basic and applied homeland security research and development activities;</li> <li>develop and submit to appropriate congressional committees a strategy to guide its activities; </li> <li>develop and update, at least once every five years, a five-year research and development plan for its activities; </li> <li>establish and utilize a system to track the progress of its research, development, testing, and evaluation activities;</li> <li>establish the Homeland Security Science and Technology Fellows Program;</li> <li>support research, development, testing, evaluation, and transition of cybersecurity technology;</li> <li>establish Integrated Product Teams to assist DHS in identifying, coordinating, and aligning research and development efforts with departmental missions; and </li> <li>establish a Homeland Security-STEM internship program to encourage students to pursue STEM (science, technology, engineering, and mathematics) careers in homeland security related fields.</li> </ul> <p>The bill extends through FY2020 DHS authority for certain research and development projects. </p> <p>The bill revises the definition of &quot;incident&quot; used with respect to the National Cybersecurity and Communications Integration Center. </p> <p>The Government Accountability Office shall initiate a study to assess the university-based centers for homeland security program and provide recommendations to the congressional homeland security committees for appropriate improvements. </p> <p>The Directorate shall utilize, as appropriate, prize authority granted pursuant to current law. </p> <p>No new funds are authorized to carry out this Act. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3578v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-10-26">
<action-date>2015-09-18</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>DHS Science and Technology Reform and Improvement Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to expand: (1) the role of the Directorate of Science and Technology as the primary research, development, testing, and evaluation arm of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS); and (2) the duties of the Under Secretary for Science and Technology, who is the head of the Directorate, to include: </p> <ul> <li>enhanced oversight and coordination&nbsp;of all DHS research, development, demonstration, testing, and evaluation activities; </li> <li>identification of&nbsp;technologies that address an existing or imminent homeland security capability gap; </li> <li>review of DHS conflict of interest policies; </li> <li>establishment of a process to define, identify, prioritize, fund, and task the basic and applied homeland security research and development activities of the Directorate;&nbsp; </li> <li>development of a strategy to guide the activities of the Directorate and a five-year research and development plan for its activities; </li> <li>establishment and utilization of a system to track the progress of the research, development, testing, and evaluation activities of the Directorate; </li> <li>establishment of&nbsp;the Homeland Security Science and Technology Fellows Program to place fellows in relevant scientific or technological fields in DHS components; </li> <li>support of cybersecurity research and development; and </li> <li>establishment of integrated product teams to identify, coordinate, and align DHS research and development efforts with departmental missions. </li></ul> <p>The bill also establishes in the Directorate a Test, Evaluation, and Standards Division to establish, review, and update DHS test and evaluation policies.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
