<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4387" measure-id="id114hr4387" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-01-13" update-date="2016-01-28">
<title>Tule Lake National Historic Site Establishment Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4387v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-01-28">
<action-date>2016-01-13</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Tule Lake National Historic Site Establishment Act of 2015</b></p> <p>This bill establishes the Tule Lake National Historic Site in California as a unit of the National Park System in order to preserve, protect, and interpret the site of incarceration and segregation of U.S. citizens of Japanese descent and resident immigrants of Japanese citizenry at Tule Lake during World War II. </p> <p>The National Park Service (NPS) and the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service shall enter into an agreement to allow the NPS to manage and interpret the resources of the portions of the Site within the Tule Lake National Wildlife Refuge. </p> <p>The resources of the Lava Beds National Monument may be used to administer the Site. </p> <p> The Department of the Interior shall prepare a general management plan for the Site. </p> <p>The boundaries of the World War II Valor in the Pacific National Monument are revised to exclude from the Monument the Tule Lake Unit, consisting of portions of the Tule Lake Segregation Center National Historic Landmark and Camp Tule Lake, and incorporate the excluded lands and interests into the Site.</p> <p>The President may not designate, nor may Interior acquire, lands for inclusion in the Site outside specified boundaries unless Interior has: (1) consulted with the county of Modoc and the city of Tulelake, and (2) obtained their written concurrence for the designation or acquisition.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
