<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2263" measure-id="id114hr2263" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-12" update-date="2015-07-06">
<title>Office of Space Commerce Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2263v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-07-06">
<action-date>2015-05-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Office of Space Commerce Act</b></p> <p>This bill renames the Office of Space Commercialization as the Office of Space Commerce. </p> <p>The Office of Space Commerce shall:</p> <ul> <li> foster the conditions for the economic growth and technological advancement of the U.S. space commerce industry;</li> <li> coordinate space commerce policy issues and actions within the Department of Commerce;</li> <li> represent Commerce in the development of U.S. policies and in negotiations with foreign countries to promote U.S. space commerce;</li> <li> promote the advancement of U.S. geospatial technologies related to space commerce in cooperation with relevant interagency working groups; and </li> <li> support federal government organizations working on Space-Based Positioning, Navigation, and Timing policy. </li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
