<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3594" measure-id="id114hr3594" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-09-24" update-date="2016-06-03">
<title>Federal Perkins Loan Program Extension Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3594v49" currentChamber="BOTH" update-date="2016-06-03">
<action-date>2015-12-18</action-date>
<action-desc>Public Law</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was passed by the Senate on December 16, 2015. The summary of that version is repeated here.)</p> <p><b>Federal Perkins Loan Program Extension Act of 2015</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends title IV (Student Assistance) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to extend the authority of institutions of higher education (IHEs) to disburse Federal Perkins Loans to new undergraduate borrowers through September 30, 2017. A student must first exhaust Federal Direct Subsidized and Unsubsidized Stafford Loan eligibility. </p> <p>IHEs may continue to disburse Perkins Loans to current undergraduate borrowers through September 30, 2017. A student must first exhaust all Federal Direct Subsidized Stafford Loan eligibility.</p> <p>IHEs may continue to disburse Perkins Loans to certain graduate borrowers through September 30, 2016, to enable students to continue or complete an academic program. A student must have received a Perkins loan prior to October 1, 2015. </p> <p>The bill prohibits Perkins Loan disbursement beyond September 30, 2017. </p> <p>It also prohibits authorization of additional appropriations for the Federal Perkins Loan program beyond September 30, 2016. </p> <p>Beginning October 1, 2017, each participating IHE must pay to the Department of Education: (1) a portion of the federal share of the balance of its Perkins Loan funds; (2) a portion of the Perkins student loan payments, including principal and interest, received by the institution; and (3) a capital distribution from its Perkins Loan fund. </p> <p>(Sec. 3) The bill also expands disclosure requirements for IHEs that participate in the Federal Perkins Loan program. </p> <p>Specifically, prior to Perkins Loan disbursement, an IHE must provide notice and explanation to all borrowers regarding unavailability of future Perkins loans, limited Perkins loan repayment and forgiveness options, and Direct Loan consolidation options. Also, an IHE must provide notice and explanation to new and current undergraduate borrowers regarding a comparison of Perkins and Direct loan interest rates.&nbsp; </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3594v35" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-05-27">
<action-date>2015-12-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed Senate amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Federal Perkins Loan Program Extension Act of 2015</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends title IV (Student Assistance) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to extend the authority of institutions of higher education (IHEs) to disburse Federal Perkins Loans to new undergraduate borrowers through September 30, 2017. A student must first exhaust Federal Direct Subsidized and Unsubsidized Stafford Loan eligibility. </p> <p>IHEs may continue to disburse Perkins Loans to current undergraduate borrowers through September 30, 2017. A student must first exhaust all Federal Direct Subsidized Stafford Loan eligibility.</p> <p>IHEs may continue to disburse Perkins Loans to certain graduate borrowers through September 30, 2016, to enable students to continue or complete an academic program. A student must have received a Perkins loan prior to October 1, 2015. </p> <p>The bill prohibits Perkins Loan disbursement beyond September 30, 2017. </p> <p>It also prohibits authorization of additional appropriations for the Federal Perkins Loan program beyond September 30, 2016. </p> <p>Beginning October 1, 2017, each participating IHE must pay to the Department of Education: (1) a portion of the federal share of the balance of its Perkins Loan funds; (2) a portion of the Perkins student loan payments, including principal and interest, received by the institution; and (3) a capital distribution from its Perkins Loan fund. </p> <p>(Sec. 3) The bill also expands disclosure requirements for IHEs that participate in the Federal Perkins Loan program. </p> <p>Specifically, prior to Perkins Loan disbursement, an IHE must provide notice and explanation to all borrowers regarding unavailability of future Perkins loans, limited Perkins loan repayment and forgiveness options, and Direct Loan consolidation options. Also, an IHE must provide notice and explanation to new and current undergraduate borrowers regarding a comparison of Perkins and Direct loan interest rates.&nbsp; </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3594v81" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-10-02">
<action-date>2015-09-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p><b>Higher Education Extension Act of 2015</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 to extend by one year, through FY2016, the term of the National Advisory Committee on Institutional Quality and Integrity. </p> <p>(Sec. 3) The legislation extends the authority of institutions of higher education (IHEs) to make loans to new borrowers under the Federal Perkins Loan program through September 30, 2016. IHEs may continue to disburse Perkins Loans through March 31, 2018, to enable students to continue or complete an academic program if the student received a Perkins loan prior to October 1, 2016, and the student has exhausted Federal Direct Stafford Loans. </p> <p>The bill prohibits any further automatic extensions of the Perkins Loan program. </p> <p>It also prohibits authorization of additional appropriations for the Federal Perkins Loan program beyond FY2015. </p> <p>Beginning October 1, 2016, each participating IHE must pay to the Department of Education a certain portion of: (1) the federal share of the balance of its Perkins Loan funds; and (2) the </s>Perkins student loan payments, including principal and interest, received by the institution. </p> <p>(Sec. 4) The bill extends by one year, through FY2016, the term of the Advisory Committee on Student Financial Assistance. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3594v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-09-29">
<action-date>2015-09-24</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Higher Education Extension Act of 2015</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 to extend by one year, through FY2016, the term of the National Advisory Committee on Institutional Quality and Integrity. </p> <p>The legislation extends the authority of institutions of higher education (IHEs) to make loans to new borrowers under the Federal Perkins Loan program through September 30, 2016. IHEs may continue to disburse Perkins Loans through March 31, 2018, to enable students to continue or complete an academic program if the student received a Perkins loan prior to October 1, 2016, and the student has exhausted Federal Direct Stafford Loans. </p> <p>The bill prohibits any further automatic extensions of the Perkins Loan program. </p> <p>It also prohibits authorization of additional appropriations for the Federal Perkins Loan program beyond FY2015. </p> <p>Beginning October 1, 2016, each participating IHE must pay to the Department of Education a certain portion of: (1) the federal share of the balance of its Perkins Loan funds; and (2) the </s>Perkins student loan payments, including principal and interest, received by the institution. </p> <p>The bill extends by one year, through FY2016, the term of the Advisory Committee on Student Financial Assistance. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
