<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4897" measure-id="id114hr4897" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-04-11" update-date="2016-05-04">
<title>Information Technology Modernization Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4897v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-05-04">
<action-date>2016-04-11</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Information Technology Modernization Act</strong></p> <p>This bill establishes in the Treasury an Information Technology Modernization Fund for technology related activities, to improve information technology, and to enhance cybersecurity across the federal government. </p> <p>The Fund shall be administered by the General Services Administration (GSA). The GSA may:</p> <ul> <li>transfer amounts from the Fund to an agency to improve, retire, or replace existing information technology systems to enhance cybersecurity and improve efficiency and effectiveness;</li> <li> use amounts in the Fund for the development, operation, and procurement of information technology products, services, and acquisition vehicles for use by agencies to improve efficiency and cybersecurity; and</li> <li> use amounts in the Fund to provide services or work performed in support of such activities.</li> </ul> <p>An agency shall: (1) reimburse the Fund for any such transfer, and (2) pay a price to be fixed by the GSA for any such product or service the agency uses. </p> <p>The bill establishes an Information Technology Modernization Board, which shall: (1) evaluate proposals for modernization submitted by agencies; (2) make recommendations to the GSA to assist agencies in the further development and refinement of select proposals; and (3) monitor progress and performance in executing approved projects and, if necessary, recommend the suspension or termination of funding. </p> <p>The GSA shall support Board activities and provide technical support to, and oversight of, agencies that receive transfers from the Fund.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
