<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1673" measure-id="id114hr1673" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-03-26" update-date="2015-04-30">
<title>Enterprise Secondary Reserve Taxpayer Protection and Government Accountability Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1673v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-04-30">
<action-date>2015-03-26</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Enterprise Secondary Reserve Taxpayer Protection and Government Accountability Act of 2015</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Federal Housing Enterprises Financial Safety and Soundness Act of 1992 to direct the Director of the Federal Housing Finance Agency to: (1) establish for any government sponsored enterprise (GSE, including the Federal National Mortgage Association [Fannie Mae] and the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation [Freddie Mac]) operating in conservatorship a secondary reserve fund, and (2) deposit in it from any GSE revenues an amount equal to its required minimum capital level. </p> <p>The GSE must hold secondary reserve fund amounts in escrow until the Director uses them according to this Act or until the fund is abolished.</p> <p>The Director shall: (1) decide whether to use funds held in the secondary reserve of a GSE operating in conservatorship if the GSE's losses will exceed other available amounts, and (2) abolish any secondary reserve upon dissolution of the GSE's conservatorship.</p> <p>Any amounts remaining in a secondary reserve upon abolishment shall revert first to meet the GSE's capital requirements and then to its earnings.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
