<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2467" measure-id="id114hr2467" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-20" update-date="2015-07-07">
<title>Organ Mountains-Desert Peaks National Monument Correction Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2467v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-07-07">
<action-date>2015-05-20</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Organ Mountains-Desert Peaks National Monument Correction Act</b></p> <p> Prohibits construing either the national monument designation or any management plan in furtherance of the Organ Mountains-Desert Peaks National Monument, New Mexico (designated on May 21, 2014) as:</p> <ul> <li>preventing the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) from undertaking law enforcement and border security activities within the areas designated as the Monument, including the ability to use motorized vehicles within it;</li> <li>limiting the 2006 Memorandum of Understanding among DHS, the Department of the Interior, and the Department of Agriculture regarding cooperative national security and counterterrorism efforts on federal land along U.S. borders;</li> <li>preventing DHS from conducting low-level overflights over the Monument for law enforcement and border security purposes; or</li> <li>preventing Interior from allowing within the Monument the installation and maintenance of communication or surveillance infrastructure necessary for law enforcement or border security activities.</li> </ul> <p>Makes the route excluded from the Potrillo Mountains, identified as "Restricted--Administrative Access" on the map entitled "Potrillo Mountains Complex," dated December 10, 2013, available for administrative and law enforcement uses, including border security activities.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
