<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5107" measure-id="id114hr5107" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-04-28" update-date="2016-05-25">
<title>Social Networking Online Protection Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5107v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-05-25">
<action-date>2016-04-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Social Networking Online Protection Act</strong></p> <p>This bill prohibits employers from: (1) requiring or requesting that employees or applicants for employment provide their passwords or any other means for accessing their private email accounts or personal online accounts, including social networking websites; or (2) discharging, disciplining, discriminating against, denying employment or promotion to, or threatening to take any such action against employees or applicants who refuse to provide such information, file a complaint or institute a proceeding under this bill, or testify in any such proceeding. </p> <p>Employers who violate these prohibitions are subject to: (1) civil penalties; (2) the authority of the Department of Labor to bring injunctive actions; and (3) the jurisdiction of U.S. district courts to provide legal or equitable relief including employment, reinstatement, promotion, and payment of lost wages and benefits.</p> <p>The Higher Education Act of 1965 and the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 are amended to prohibit certain institutions of higher education and local educational agencies from requesting such password or account information from students or potential students. The bill prohibits denial of admission, suspension, expulsion, and other discipline or discrimination against students who decline to provide such information, file a complaint, institute a proceeding, or testify in any related proceeding.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
