<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3178" measure-id="id114hr3178" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-07-23" update-date="2016-10-12">
<title>Strengthening Transparency in Higher Education Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3178v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-10-12">
<action-date>2016-07-11</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Strengthening Transparency in Higher Education Act</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends title I (General Provisions) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to modify consumer information disclosure requirements related to college costs and student characteristics. </p> <p>Specifically, it eliminates the existing restriction that limits calculations of cost of attendance, net price, and tuition and fees to first time students only. </p> <p>Additionally, it eliminates provisions that require the Department of Education (ED) to make publicly available the following: (1) college affordability and transparency lists, (2) annual summaries of institutional reports, (3) state higher education spending charts; and (4) a multi-year tuition and fees calculator.</p> <p>(Sec. 3) The bill directs ED to develop, annually update, and make publicly available a College Dashboard website to replace the College Navigator website. </p> <p>It revises the consumer information ED must make publicly available regarding an institution that participates in federal student aid programs under title IV (Student Assistance). ED must also publish and link to the College Dashboard website additional information regarding student enrollment, completion rates, costs, use of financial aid, and faculty.</p> <p>The bill establishes certain minimum requirements for an institution's net price calculator, including website location and information provided. Sale or distribution of personally identifiable information collected by a net price calculator is prohibited.</p> <p>(Sec. 4) No additional funds are authorized to carry out the requirements of this bill.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3178v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-07-11">
<action-date>2015-07-23</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Strengthening Transparency in Higher Education Act</b></p> <p>This bill amends title I (General Provisions) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to modify consumer information disclosure requirements related to college costs and student characteristics. </p> <p>Specifically, it eliminates the existing restriction that limits calculations of cost of attendance, net price, and tuition and fees to first time students only. </p> <p>Additionally, it eliminates provisions that require the Department of Education (ED) to make publicly available the following: (1) college affordability and transparency lists, (2) annual summaries of institutional reports, (3) state higher education spending charts; and (4) a multi-year tuition and fees calculator.</p> <p>The bill directs ED to develop, annually update, and make publicly available a College Dashboard website to replace the College Navigator website. </p> <p>It revises the consumer information ED must make publicly available regarding an institution that participates in title IV federal student aid programs. ED must also publish and link to the College Dashboard website additional information regarding student enrollment, completion rates, costs, use of financial aid, and faculty.</p> <p>The bill establishes certain minimum requirements for an institution's net price calculator, including website location and information provided. Sale or distribution of personally identifiable information collected by a net price calculator is prohibited.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
