<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1709" measure-id="id114hr1709" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-03-26" update-date="2016-04-27">
<title>To amend the Safe Drinking Water Act to provide for the assessment and management of the risks of drought to drinking water, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1709v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-04-27">
<action-date>2015-03-26</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill amends the Safe Drinking Water Act to direct the Environmental Protection Agency to develop and submit to Congress a strategic plan for assessing and managing risks associated with drought to drinking water provided by public water systems. </p> <p>The plan must include steps and time lines to:</p> <ul> <li>evaluate the risks posed by drought to drinking water provided by public water systems;</li> <li> establish a comprehensive list of the effects of drought on drinking water that may have an adverse effect on human health;</li> <li> summarize the known adverse human health effects, factors that cause drought, and factors that exacerbate the effects of drought on drinking water provided by public water systems; </li> <li>determine whether to establish guidance for quantifying the effects of drought on drinking water and for determining the frequency of monitoring necessary to detect the effects; </li> <li>recommend feasible treatment options to mitigate such effects, including procedures, equipment, and source water protection practices; and </li> <li>enter into cooperative agreements with, and provide technical assistance to, affected states and public water systems to manage risks associated with the effects of drought on drinking water. </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
