<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1012" measure-id="id114hr1012" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-02-17" update-date="2015-03-09">
<title>MediFair Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1012v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-03-09">
<action-date>2015-02-17</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>MediFair Act of 2015 </b></p> <p> Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a system for making adjustments to the amount of payment made to entities and individuals for items and services provided under the original Medicare fee-for-service program under Medicare parts A (Hospital Insurance) and B (Supplementary Medical Insurance). Requires such adjustments in order to make the state average per beneficiary amount equal to the national average per beneficiary amount.</p> <p>Directs the Medicare Payment Advisory Commission to develop recommendations on policies and practices that would encourage: (1) healthy outcomes and quality care under the Medicare program in states with respect to which payments are reduced under such system, and (2) the efficient use of payments made under the Medicare program in such states.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
