<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4527" measure-id="id114hr4527" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-02-10" update-date="2016-02-25">
<title>Military Retiree Employment Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4527v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-02-25">
<action-date>2016-02-10</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Military Retiree Employment Act</strong></p> <p>This bill permits, for a specified five-year period, retired members of the Armed Forces to be appointed to civil service positions in or under the Department of Defense (DOD) during the first 180 days after retirement without meeting current requirements regarding: (1) appointment authorization, (2) basic pay increase, or (3) existence of a state of national emergency. </p> <p>The Office of Personnel Management shall establish an oversight plan to monitor such appointments. </p> <p>DOD shall ensure that every DOD employee is informed, within one calendar day, of the publication of a vacancy within that employee's office that requires qualifications related to the employee's current duties. </p> <p>DOD shall ensure for 10 years that each employee who is a veteran and who is newly hired or appointed to a DOD position shall be informed of the effect of certain DOD guidelines for reduction in force protection.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
