<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5826" measure-id="id114hr5826" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-07-14" update-date="2016-11-04">
<title>Detain and Deport Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5826v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-11-04">
<action-date>2016-07-14</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Detain and Deport Act</strong></p> <p>This bill provides that a state or political subdivision that has in effect a statute, policy, or practice providing that it not comply with any Department of Homeland Security (DHS) detainer ordering it to temporarily hold an alien in its custody so that the alien may be taken into federal custody or to transport the alien for transfer to federal custody shall not be eligible to receive: (1) funds for the incarceration of undocumented criminal aliens or for the Cops on the Beat program, or (2) any other law enforcement or DHS grant.</p> <p>A state or political subdivision acting in compliance with such a DHS detainer shall be considered to be acting under color of federal authority for purposes of determining its liability and immunity from suit in civil actions brought by the aliens. </a></p> <p>It is the sense of Congress that DHS has probable cause to believe that an alien is inadmissible or deportable when it issues a detainer regarding the alien under the standards in place on the date of introduction of this bill.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
