<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4160" measure-id="id114hr4160" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-12-02" update-date="2016-01-07">
<title>Rural Broadband Infrastructure Investment Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4160v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-01-07">
<action-date>2015-12-02</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Rural Broadband Infrastructure Investment Act </b></p> <p>This bill amends the Rural Electrification Act of 1936 to authorize the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to provide additional loans and grants for the development of telecommunications and broadband services in rural areas. </p> <p>USDA may give preference to loan applications for projects that support the development of telecommunications services in rural areas on a multijurisdictional basis. </p> <p>In evaluating applications, USDA must consider whether: </p> <ul> <li> the project was developed through the collaboration and participation of multiple stakeholders in the service area; </li> <li>the applicant understands the regional resources that could support the project, including natural resources, human resources, infrastructure, and financial resources; and </li> <li>the project has clear objectives and a means to establish performance measures. </li> </ul> <p>For the purpose of loans, loan guarantees, and grants, a rural area is any area of the United States not included within the boundaries of any incorporated or unincorporated city, village, or borough having a population in excess of 20,000 inhabitants. </p> <p>USDA may provide grants, in addition to loans and loan guarantees permitted under current law, for the construction, improvement, and acquisition of facilities and equipment for broadband service in rural areas. In providing loans, loan guarantees, and grants, USDA may give priority to multijurisdictional projects for the development of broadband service in rural areas that are developed through the collaboration and participation of multiple stakeholders in the service area. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
