<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4081" measure-id="id114hr4081" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-11-19" update-date="2015-12-17">
<title>TIFIA 2.0 Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4081v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-12-17">
<action-date>2015-11-19</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>TIFIA 2.0 Act </b></p> <p> This bill amends the Transportation Infrastructure Finance and Innovation Act (TIFIA) to revise the Department of Transportation (DOT) TIFIA program of direct loans, loan guarantees, and credit for surface transportation projects.</p> <p>A TIFIA Revolving Fund is established in the Treasury.</p> <p>A set-aside of up to 10% of Fund amounts is required for rural infrastructure projects (as similarly required in current funding law).</p> <p>The DOT is directed to transfer from the Fund to the general fund of the Treasury amounts equal to moneys deposited in the Fund as a result of the repayment of principal and interest on direct loans for transportation infrastructure projects before enactment of this Act.</p> <p>Project eligibility requirements are revised.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
