<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4882" measure-id="id114hr4882" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-03-23" update-date="2016-04-06">
<title>Cesar Chavez National Historical Park Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4882v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-04-06">
<action-date>2016-03-23</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Cesar Chavez National Historical Park Act</b></p> <p>This bill establishes as a unit of the National Park System the Cesar Chavez National Historical Park in California and Arizona, replacing the Cesar E. Chavez National Monument and incorporating the Monument lands and interests within, and as part of, the Historical Park. </p>  <p>The Department of the Interior may provide staff and technical assistance for the interpretation of historic sites, museums, and resources on lands not administered by Interior related to the life of Cesar Chavez and the history of the farm worker movement. </p>  <p>Interior may designate a vehicular tour route, to be known as the American Farm Worker Movement Interpretive Route, to link properties in California and Arizona that are historically and thematically associated with Cesar Chavez and the farm worker movement. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
