<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5892" measure-id="id114hr5892" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-07-14" update-date="2016-08-05">
<title>To amend title II of the Social Security Act to improve social security benefits for widows and widowers in two-income households.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5892v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-08-05">
<action-date>2016-07-14</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill amends title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) of the Social Security Act to revise the widow's or widower's insurance benefit for any month to equal the greater of: (1) the primary insurance amount of a deceased individual (as under current law); or (2) in the case of a fully-insured widow or surviving divorced spouse, 75% of the sum of any old-age or disability insurance benefit to which the widow, widower, or surviving divorced spouse is entitled plus the primary insurance amount of the deceased individual.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
