<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1908" measure-id="id114hr1908" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-04-21" update-date="2015-05-12">
<title>Housing Financial Literacy Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1908v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-05-12">
<action-date>2015-04-21</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Housing Financial Literacy Act of 2015 </b></p> <p> Amends the National Housing Act to revise the single insurance premium payment for a mortgage (secured by a one- to four-family dwelling that is an obligation of the Mutual Mortgage Insurance Fund) of a first-time homebuyer who completes a program of counseling on the responsibilities and financial management involved in homeownership that is approved by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development.</p> <p>Repeals the current maximum premium payment of 2.75% of the amount of the mortgage's original insured principal obligation.</p> <p>Sets the single mortgage insurance premium payment at 25 basis points lower than the premium payment amount otherwise established.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
