<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2732" measure-id="id114hr2732" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-06-11" update-date="2015-09-22">
<title>Handgun Purchaser Licensing Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2732v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-09-22">
<action-date>2015-06-11</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Handgun Purchaser Licensing Act</strong></p> <p>Authorizes the Attorney General to award grants to states, local governments, and Indian tribes for the development, implementation, and evaluation of handgun purchaser licensing requirements and the implementation and improvement of handgun purchaser licensing programs.</p> <p> Requires grant applications to include a description of: (1) the law that the applicant has enacted to require a license for any purchase of a handgun, including any exemptions; and (2) how the applicant will use the grant to carry out or improve its program.</p> <p>Requires an applicant, to be eligible for a grant, to have in effect handgun purchaser licensing laws that include requirements that:</p> <ul> <li>an applicant for a handgun license or permit must be at least 21 years old and must be a national or lawful permanent resident of the United States;</li> <li>such an individual must apply for the license or permit at a law enforcement agency in the state in which he or she resides, must reapply within five years, and must submit to a background investigation and a criminal history check;</li> <li>such an individual must submit fingerprints and photographs and must provide proof that the individual is legally present and lawfully resides in the United States; and</li> <li>any individual who is prohibited from possessing a firearm under the federal criminal code may not receive a license or permit. <p> </li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
