<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4620" measure-id="id114hr4620" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-02-25" update-date="2016-06-02">
<title>Preserving Access to CRE Capital Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4620v79" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-06-02">
<action-date>2016-05-26</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p><b>Preserving Access to CRE Capital Act of 2016 </b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 concerning credit risk retention standards for commercial real estate loans to revise the optional standard that may include retention of the first-loss position by a third-party purchaser that specifically negotiates for the purchase of that first loss position, holds adequate financial resources to back losses, provides due diligence on all individual assets in the pool before issuance of the asset-backed securities, and meets the same standards for risk retention as the federal banking agencies and the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) require of the securitizer.</p> <p>The revised specifications for retention of the first-loss position by a third-party purchaser shall mean the permissible risk retention of the first-loss position by a one or two party third-party purchaser, who may hold the retention obligation in either a senior-subordinate structure or <i>pari passu</i> (where two or more assets, securities, creditors or obligations are equally managed without any display of preference), as long as each party meets the requirements expressed above.</p> <p>The bill exempts from risk retention requirements the securitization of a single commercial real estate loan or a group of cross-collateralized or cross-defaulted commercial real estate loans that represent the obligation of one or more related borrowers secured by commercial properties under direct or indirect common ownership or control.</p> <p>The SEC and the federal banking agencies shall jointly maintain specified regulations which exempt qualified commercial real estate loans from risk retention requirements.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4620v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-06-02">
<action-date>2016-02-25</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Preserving Access to CRE Capital Act of 2016 </b></p> <p>This bill amends the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 concerning credit risk retention standards for commercial real estate loans to revise the optional standard that may include retention of the first-loss position by a third-party purchaser that specifically negotiates for the purchase of that first loss position, holds adequate financial resources to back losses, provides due diligence on all individual assets in the pool before issuance of the asset-backed securities, and meets the same standards for risk retention as the federal banking agencies and the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) require of the securitizer.</p> <p>The revised specifications for retention of the first-loss position by a third-party purchaser shall mean the permissible risk retention of the first-loss position by a one or two party third-party purchaser, who may hold the retention obligation in either a senior-subordinate structure or <i>pari passu</i> (where two or more assets, securities, creditors or obligations are equally managed without any display of preference), as long as each party meets the requirements expressed above.</p> <p>The bill exempts from risk retention requirements the securitization of a single commercial real estate loan or a group of cross-collateralized or cross-defaulted commercial real estate loans that represent the obligation of one or more related borrowers secured by commercial properties under direct or indirect common ownership or control.</p> <p>The SEC and the federal banking agencies shall jointly maintain specified regulations which exempt qualified commercial real estate loans from risk retention requirements.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
