<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5550" measure-id="id114hr5550" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-06-21" update-date="2016-10-24">
<title>No Dollars for Ayatollahs Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5550v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-10-24">
<action-date>2016-06-21</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>No Dollars for Ayatollahs Act </b></p> <p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to impose an excise tax on any U.S. person who clears or transfers more than $1 million U.S. dollars per year for the direct or indirect benefit of the government of Iran or any Iranian person. The tax is equal to 100% of the amount that is cleared or transferred.</p> <p>The tax also applies to transactions by certain related entities, including the clearing or transferring of U.S dollars by: (1) a foreign member of a U.S. person's worldwide affiliated group, or (2) a foreign person who is not a member of a U.S. person's worldwide affiliated group, but has a correspondent account or payable-through account for or with such a member or a U.S. person. The tax applies to transactions by a foreign person described above if the member or U.S. person for or with whom the account is maintained knew or had reason to know the dollars were being cleared or transferred.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
