<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2234" measure-id="id114hr2234" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-05" update-date="2015-05-19">
<title>Emerging Business Encouragement Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2234v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-05-19">
<action-date>2015-05-05</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Emerging Business Encouragement Act of 2015</b></p> <p> Amends the Small Business Act to direct the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA), for each industry category for which the Administrator established a size standard, to establish procedures, by rule, for designating a small business in that industry category as an emerging business enterprise (EBE).</p> <p>Requires the designation to expire when the small business is no longer in compliance with the criteria, except that:</p> <ul> <li>in the case of an EBE which existed as a business entity before its EBE designation, the designation shall not expire until five years after it was made; and</li> <li>if the EBE exceeds the required size limitation its designation shall expire only if the size is 50% or more of the maximum size of a small business within that industry category.</li> </ul> <p>Directs the Administrator to establish specified criteria for designation of an EBE.</p> <p>Requires the head of each federal agency to establish goals for participation by the designated EBEs in at least 5% of all contracts, including prime contracts and subcontracts, for each fiscal year.</p> <p>Authorizes the Administrator to make a loan to a designated EBE under the SBA Express Loan Program, but only in accordance with specified terms.</p> <p>Requires the Administrator, by rule, to establish a process for initial self-certification of EBEs for purposes of participation in federal contracts and eligibility for the Express Loans.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
