<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1913" measure-id="id114hr1913" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-04-21" update-date="2015-06-18">
<title>Protecting American Taxpayers from Fraud Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1913v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-06-18">
<action-date>2015-04-21</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Protecting American Taxpayers from Fraud Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>This bill directs the Department of the Treasury to develop referral procedures for, and establish a liaison to, tax preparation firms to seek recovery of refunds for taxpayers defrauded by employees or agents of such firms. In developing such procedures, Treasury shall ensure that there is coordination among the following Internal Revenue Service (IRS) entities: (1) the Taxpayer Advocate Service, (2) the Wage &amp; Investment Division, (3) Criminal Investigation, (4) the Office of Chief Counsel, (5) the Return Preparer Office, and (6) the Office of Professional Responsibility. </p> <p>The bill also directs Treasury to develop comprehensive guidance for the treatment by IRS of all claims for refunds relating to tax return preparer fraud. Such guidance must provide a clear description of the rights and responsibilities of taxpayers with respect to actions taken by the taxpayer to minimize loss from tax preparer fraud, to receive restitution, and to substantiate a claim of fraud. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
