<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1839" measure-id="id114hr1839" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-04-16" update-date="2015-11-17">
<title>Reforming Access for Investments in Startup Enterprises Act of 2015 or the RAISE Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1839v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-11-17">
<action-date>2015-10-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b> Reforming Access for Investments in Startup Enterprises Act of 2015 or the RAISE Act of 2015</b></p> <p> (Sec. 2) The Securities Act of 1933 is amended to exempt from security registration requirements, and related prohibitions against using interstate commerce and the mails for the sale or delivery of securities after sale, any transaction where:</p> <ul> <li>each purchaser is an accredited investor;</li> <li>neither the seller, nor any person acting on the seller's behalf, offers or sells securities by general solicitation or advertising;</li> <li>the seller and prospective purchaser obtain from an issuer meeting certain criteria reasonably current specified information;</li> <li>the transaction is not for the sale of a security whose seller is neither an issuer nor a subsidiary of the issuer;</li> <li>neither the seller, nor any person receiving remuneration for participating in the offer or sale of the securities, is subject to certain legal disqualification (bad actor);</li> <li>the issuer is engaged in business, is not in the organizational stage or in bankruptcy or receivership, and is not a blank check, blind pool, or shell company with no specific business plan or purpose or has indicated that the issuer's primary business plan is to engage in a merger or combination of the business with, or an acquisition of, an unidentified person;</li> <li>the transaction does not involve a security that constitutes the whole or part of an unsold allotment to, or a subscription or participation by, a broker or dealer as an underwriter of the security or a redistribution; and</li> <li>the transaction does involve a security of a class authorized and outstanding for at least 90 days before the transaction. </li> </ul> <p>Securities acquired in such exempt transactions shall be deemed to: (1) have been acquired in a transaction not involving any public offering, (2) not be a distribution involving an underwriter, and (2) be restricted securities not subject to certain transaction requirements.</p>  <p>All transactions under this Act shall be exempt from state regulation of securities offerings.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1839v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-04-29">
<action-date>2015-04-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p> <b> Reforming Access for Investments in Startup Enterprises Act of 2015 or the RAISE Act of 2015</b></p> <p> Amends the Securities Act of 1933 to exempt from prohibitions relating to interstate commerce and the mails any transaction where: (1) each purchaser is an accredited investor; and (2) if the securities are offered by means of any general solicitation or general advertising, all such sales are made through a platform available only to accredited investors.</p> <p>Denies such exemption to transactions where the seller is: (1) either an issuer, its subsidiaries or parent; (2) a dealer; or (3) an underwriter acting on behalf of the issuer, its subsidiaries, or parent, which receives compensation from the issuer with respect to such sale.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
