<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3609" measure-id="id114hr3609" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-09-24" update-date="2015-10-02">
<title>To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to modify requirements for payment under the Medicare program for ambulance services furnished by critical access hospitals, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3609v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-10-02">
<action-date>2015-09-24</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to modify requirements for payment under the Medicare program for ambulance services furnished by critical access hospitals (CAHs), which are rural community hospitals that meet specified criteria and receive special payment.</p> <p>Under current law, ambulance services furnished either by a CAH or by an entity owned or operated by a CAH are paid at a rate of 101% of reasonable costs incurred in furnishing those services, as long as the CAH or entity is the only provider of ambulance services that is located within a 35-mile drive of the CAH. The bill maintains this requirement but further requires that the CAH or entity furnishing the ambulance services be licensed or otherwise authorized to furnish services in the state in which the CAH is located.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
