<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4576" measure-id="id114hr4576" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-02-12" update-date="2016-09-29">
<title>Ensuring Access to Pacific Fisheries Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4576v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-09-29">
<action-date>2016-02-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Ensuring Access to Pacific Fisheries Act</b></p> <p>This bill authorizes the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) to promulgate regulations to implement U.S. participation in the North Pacific Fisheries Convention and South Pacific Fisheries Convention. These conventions are designed to ensure the long-term conservation and sustainable use of fishery resources and marine ecosystems in the North Pacific and South Pacific Ocean of the United States. <p>The North Pacific Fisheries Commission and the Commission of the South Pacific Regional Fisheries Management Organisation were both established by the North and South Pacific fishery conventions, respectively. The United States must be represented by five commissioners on the North Pacific commission and not more than three on the South Pacific commission. In addition, permanent advisory committees are established to represent groups concerned with the fishery resources covered by each convention.</p> <p>The Department of State has certain authority and responsibilities with respect to both commissions.</p> <p>NOAA and the U.S. Coast Guard are required to administer and enforce this bill.</p> <p> This bill lists fishing and shipping activities that are prohibited in the North and South Pacific Ocean.</p> <p> The bill also amends the Western and Central Pacific Fisheries Convention Implementation Act to include commercial fishing as practical experience the President should consider when selecting a commissioner for the Western and Central Pacific Fisheries Commission. The advisory committee is required to submit agenda recommendations at least 15 days prior to the annual Western and Central Pacific Fisheries Commission meeting. The recommendations must be considered in formulating the U.S. position for meetings and negotiations. In addition, NOAA should conduct negotiations to secure agreements with other nations to ensure access and equal treatment of United States fishing boats in the Western and Central Pacific Ocean while taking conservation and management measures into consideration.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
