<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5174" measure-id="id114hr5174" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-05-10" update-date="2016-08-04">
<title>Veterans Education Enhancement Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5174v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-08-04">
<action-date>2016-05-10</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Veterans Education Enhancement Act of 2016</strong></p> <p>This bill revises the fee that is deducted from a veteran's education entitlement under the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) Post-9/11 educational assistance program from a monthly to a prorated fee for: (1) certain license and certification tests, and (2) national tests.</p> <p>The Veterans' Advisory Committee on Education is extended through December 31, 2021.</p> <p>The VA shall, in consultation with state approving agencies, prescribe training requirements for a school certifying official (SCO) employed by a covered educational institution offering approved veterans education courses. The VA may disapprove any course of education offered by a covered educational institution that does not ensure that an SCO meets such requirements. (A covered educational institution is an institution that has enrolled 20 or more individuals using veterans educational assistance.) </p> <p>The bill extends the applicability of provisions requiring rounding down, and delays the applicability of provisions requiring rounding up, of veterans educational assistance increases for: (1) the All-Volunteer Force, and (2) survivors and dependents.</p> <p>The VA shall reduce the monthly housing stipend on a pro rata basis for a student who reduces his or her course load, effective for a month that begins on or after August 1, 2017.</p> <p>A reporting fee paid by the VA to an educational institution or joint apprenticeship training committee for costs associated with required reports or certifications: </p> <ul> <li>shall be utilized solely for required certifications or for otherwise supporting veterans programs; and </li> <li>with respect to an institution that has 75 or more enrollees, may not be used for or merged with amounts available for the general fund of the educational institution or joint apprenticeship training committee.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
