<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3766" measure-id="id114hr3766" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-10-20" update-date="2016-09-01">
<title>Foreign Aid Transparency and Accountability Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3766v49" currentChamber="BOTH" update-date="2016-09-01">
<action-date>2016-07-15</action-date>
<action-desc>Public Law</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was passed by the Senate on July 5, 2016. The summary of that version is repeated here.)</p> <p><strong>Foreign Aid Transparency and Accountability Act of 2016</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill defines &quot;covered U.S. foreign assistance&quot; as assistance authorized under: </p> <ul> <li> part I of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (development assistance), except for title IV of chapter 2 (relating to the Overseas Private Investment Corporation), and chapter 3 (relating to International Organizations and Programs); </li> <li> chapter 4 of part II of such Act (Economic Support Fund); </li> <li> the Millennium Challenge Act of 2003; and </li> <li> the Food for Peace Act. </li> </ul> <p>(Sec. 3) The President shall within 18 months prescribe guidelines for establishment of goals, performance metrics, and monitoring and evaluation plans for covered U.S. foreign assistance.</p> <p> The guidelines shall direct federal departments and agencies that administer such assistance on how to: </p> <ul> <li> establish annual monitoring and evaluation agendas and objectives; </li> <li> develop specific project monitoring and evaluation plans;</li> <li> apply monitoring and evaluation methodologies to covered U.S. foreign assistance programs; </li> <li> disseminate guidelines for the development and implementation of monitoring and evaluation programs to all personnel responsible for program design, implementation, and management of covered U.S. foreign assistance programs; </li> <li> establish data collection methodologies;</li> <li> evaluate, at least once in their lifetime, all programs whose dollar value equals or exceeds the median program size for the relevant office or bureau; </li> <li> develop a clearinghouse capacity for the collection and dissemination of knowledge and lessons learned that serve as benchmarks for future programs; </li> <li> distribute evaluation reports internally; </li> <li> publicly report evaluations and related recommendations;</li> <li> undertake collaborative partnerships and coordinate efforts with academic, national and international institutions; </li> <li> make verifiable and timely data available to monitoring and evaluation personnel; and </li> <li> ensure that standards of professional evaluation organizations for monitoring and evaluation efforts are employed.</li> </ul> <p> The President shall within 18 months give Congress a detailed description of these guidelines. </p> <p> The Government Accountability Office shall analyze the guidelines and assess their implementation by the appropriate agencies, bureaus, and offices. </p> <p>(Sec. 4) The Department of State shall within 90 days update its Internet website, ForeignAssistance.gov, to make publicly available comprehensive and accessible information on covered U.S. foreign assistance programs.</p> <p>The head of each federal department or agency that administers such assistance shall give the State Department comprehensive program information each quarter.</p> <p>Assistance program information shall be published: (1) on an award-by-award and country-by-country basis, or (2) on an award-by-award and region-by-region basis if provided on a regional level.</p> <p>Such information shall include: (1) links to all regional, country, and sector assistance strategies, annual budget documents, congressional budget justifications, and evaluations; (2) basic descriptive summaries for foreign development and economic assistance programs and awards under such programs; and (3) obligations and expenditures.</p> <p>If a federal department or agency determines that the inclusion of a required item of information online would jeopardize the health or security of an implementing partner or program beneficiary, or would require the release of proprietary information, it shall give Congress that determination in writing.</p> <p>If the State Department determines that online inclusion of a required item of information would be detrimental to U.S. national interests, it shall also give Congress that determination in writing.</p> <p>The bill expresses the sense of Congress that the State Department and the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) should, by the end of FY2018, coordinate data collection consolidation for the State Department's website, ForeignAssistance.gov, and USAID's website, Explorer.USAID.gov.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3766v35" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-09-01">
<action-date>2016-06-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed Senate amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Foreign Aid Transparency and Accountability Act of 2016</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill defines "covered U.S. foreign assistance" as assistance authorized under: </p> <ul> <li> part I of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (development assistance), except for title IV of chapter 2 (relating to the Overseas Private Investment Corporation), and chapter 3 (relating to International Organizations and Programs); </li> <li> chapter 4 of part II of such Act (Economic Support Fund); </li> <li> the Millennium Challenge Act of 2003; and </li> <li> the Food for Peace Act. </li> </ul> <p>(Sec. 3) The President shall within 18 months prescribe guidelines for establishment of goals, performance metrics, and monitoring and evaluation plans for covered U.S. foreign assistance.</p> <p> The guidelines shall direct federal departments and agencies that administer such assistance on how to: </p> <ul> <li> establish annual monitoring and evaluation agendas and objectives; </li> <li> develop specific project monitoring and evaluation plans;</li> <li> apply monitoring and evaluation methodologies to covered U.S. foreign assistance programs; </li> <li> disseminate guidelines for the development and implementation of monitoring and evaluation programs to all personnel responsible for program design, implementation, and management of covered U.S. foreign assistance programs; </li> <li> establish data collection methodologies;</li> <li> evaluate, at least once in their lifetime, all programs whose dollar value equals or exceeds the median program size for the relevant office or bureau; </li> <li> develop a clearinghouse capacity for the collection and dissemination of knowledge and lessons learned that serve as benchmarks for future programs; </li> <li> distribute evaluation reports internally; </li> <li> publicly report evaluations and related recommendations;</li> <li> undertake collaborative partnerships and coordinate efforts with academic, national and international institutions; </li> <li> make verifiable and timely data available to monitoring and evaluation personnel; and </li> <li> ensure that standards of professional evaluation organizations for monitoring and evaluation efforts are employed.</li> </ul> <p> The President shall within 18 months give Congress a detailed description of these guidelines. </p> <p> The Government Accountability Office shall analyze the guidelines and assess their implementation by the appropriate agencies, bureaus, and offices. </p> <p>(Sec. 4) The Department of State shall within 90 days update its Internet website, ForeignAssistance.gov, to make publicly available comprehensive and accessible information on covered U.S. foreign assistance programs.</p> <p>The head of each federal department or agency that administers such assistance shall give the State Department comprehensive program information each quarter.</p> <p>Assistance program information shall be published: (1) on an award-by-award and country-by-country basis, or (2) on an award-by-award and region-by-region basis if provided on a regional level.</p> <p>Such information shall include: (1) links to all regional, country, and sector assistance strategies, annual budget documents, congressional budget justifications, and evaluations; (2) basic descriptive summaries for foreign development and economic assistance programs and awards under such programs; and (3) obligations and expenditures.</p> <p>If a federal department or agency determines that the inclusion of a required item of information online would jeopardize the health or security of an implementing partner or program beneficiary, or would require the release of proprietary information, it shall give Congress that determination in writing.</p> <p>If the State Department determines that online inclusion of a required item of information would be detrimental to U.S. national interests, it shall also give Congress that determination in writing.</p> <p>The bill expresses the sense of Congress that the State Department and the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) should, by the end of FY2018, coordinate data collection consolidation for the State Department's website, ForeignAssistance.gov, and USAID's website, Explorer.USAID.gov.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3766v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-02-26">
<action-date>2015-12-08</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Foreign Aid Transparency and Accountability Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill requires the President to establish guidelines for the establishment of measurable goals, performance metrics, and monitoring and evaluation plans for U.S. foreign development and economic assistance.</p> <p>The guidelines shall require federal departments and agencies that administer foreign development and economic assistance to: </p> <ul> <li>establish annual monitoring and evaluation objectives; </li> <li>develop specific project monitoring and evaluation plans, and apply monitoring and evaluation methodologies to such programs; </li> <li>disseminate guidelines for the development and implementation of monitoring and evaluation programs to personnel who are responsible for program design, implementation, and management;</li> <li>establish data collection methodologies; </li> <li>evaluate at least once in their lifetime all programs whose dollar value equals or exceeds the median program size for the relevant office or bureau; </li> <li>conduct impact evaluations on all pilot programs; </li> <li>develop a clearinghouse capacity for the collection and dissemination of knowledge and lessons learned that serve as benchmarks for future programs;</li> <li>distribute evaluation reports internally;</li> <li>publicly report evaluations and related recommendations;</li> <li>undertake collaborative partnerships and coordinate efforts with appropriate implementing partners, and academic, national and international institutions; and </li> <li> make verifiable and timely data available to monitoring and evaluation personnel. </li> </ul> <p>The President shall provide Congress with a detailed description of such guidelines. </p> <p>The Government Accountability Office shall submit a report to Congress that: (1) analyzes such guidelines; and (2) compares the President's fiscal year budget request of every operational unit that carries out U.S. foreign development and economic assistance, and the prior year's performance of such units.</p> <p>(Sec. 3) The Department of State shall update its Internet website, ForeignAssistance.gov, to make publicly available comprehensive and accessible information on U.S. foreign development and economic assistance programs. </p> <p>The head of each federal department or agency that administers U.S. foreign development and economic assistance shall provide the State Department each quarter with comprehensive information about such assistance programs. </p> <p>Assistance program information shall be published: (1) on an award-by-award and country-by-country basis, or (2) on an award-by-award and region-by-region basis if provided on a regional level. </p> <p>Such information shall include: (1) links to all regional, country, and sector assistance strategies, annual budget documents, congressional budget justifications, and evaluations; (2) basic descriptive summaries for foreign development and economic assistance programs and awards under such programs; and (3) obligations and expenditures. </p> <p>If the head of a federal department or agency determines that the inclusion of a required item of information online would jeopardize the health or security of an implementing partner or program beneficiary or would require the release of proprietary information, he or she shall provide such determination along with a briefing or written report to Congress. </p> <p>If the State Department determines that the inclusion of a required item of information online would be detrimental to U.S. national interests the State Department shall provide such determination to Congress along with a briefing or written report. </p> <p>If a federal department or agency fails to provide required information that is not otherwise excluded from such requirement, the Office of Management and Budget, in consultation with the head of such department or agency, shall submit to Congress by September 1, 2016, a report describing for each required information item not made publicly available: </p> <ul> <li> the reason for not making such information publicly available; and </li> <li>the department's or agency's plan and time line for making such information publicly available, and for ensuring that future information is made available. </li> </ul> <p>(Sec. 4) Specified terms are defined.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3766v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-02-05">
<action-date>2015-10-20</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Foreign Aid Transparency and Accountability Act of 2015</strong></p> <p> The President shall establish guidelines for the establishment of measurable goals, performance metrics, and monitoring and evaluation plans for U.S. foreign development and economic assistance. </p> <p> The Department of State shall update its Internet website, ForeignAssistance.gov, to make publicly available comprehensive and accessible information on U.S. foreign development and economic assistance programs.</p> <p> The head of each federal department or agency that administers U.S. foreign development and economic assistance shall provide the State Department with comprehensive information about such assistance programs.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
