<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2402" measure-id="id114hr2402" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-18" update-date="2015-09-09">
<title>Protecting Critical Infrastructure Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2402v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-09-09">
<action-date>2015-05-18</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Protecting Critical Infrastructure Act</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Federal Power Act to: (1) exempt protected electric security information from mandatory public disclosure under the Freedom of Information Act; and (2) prohibit any state, local, or tribal authority from disclosing such information pursuant to state, local, or tribal law. </p> <p>The Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) shall promulgate specified regulations and issue the orders necessary to designate protected electric security information and to prohibit its unauthorized disclosure. </p> <p>There is no requirement for a person or entity in possession of protected electric security information to share it with federal, state, local, or tribal authorities. Sharing information with Congress, however, is permitted.</p> <p> Unless specifically redesignated by FERC, information may not be designated as protected electric security information for longer than five years. FERC shall remove a designation, in whole or in part, if it determines that its unauthorized disclosure could no longer be used to impair the security or reliability of the bulk-power system or distribution facilities.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
