<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1777" measure-id="id114hr1777" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-04-14" update-date="2016-06-27">
<title>Presidential Allowance Modernization Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1777v35" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-06-27">
<action-date>2016-06-21</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed Senate amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Presidential Allowance Modernization Act of 2016</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill revises provisions relating to presidential pensions to&nbsp;allow former&nbsp;Presidents&nbsp;a lifetime annual annuity&nbsp;of $200,000&nbsp;and an additional annual monetary&nbsp;allowance&nbsp;of $200,000, each adjusted annually for cost-of-living increases as provided by the Social Security Act. It reduces the annual monetary allowance by the amount that a former President's adjusted gross income in a taxable year exceeds $400,000.&nbsp; </p> <p>The bill prohibits the monetary allowance from being less than the amount that the General Services Administration and the U.S. Secret Service determine is needed to pay the increased cost of doing business that is attributable to the security needs of the former President.</p> <p>The annuity and allowance shall not be payable for any period during which a former President holds an appointive or elective position in or under the federal government that pays more than a nominal rate.</p> <p>The bill increases from $20,000 to $100,000 the annual annuity of a surviving spouse of a former President. </p> <p>(Sec. 3) Nothing in this bill shall be construed to affect: (1) a law relating to the security or protection of a former President or a family member of a former President, or (2) funding to carry out such security or protection.</p> <p>(Sec. 4) The bill applies to an individual who is a former President or the widow of a former President as of the date of enactment. </p> <p>(Sec. 5) For a former President receiving a monetary allowance before the enactment of this bill, the reduction of the monetary allowance for adjusted gross income required by this bill applies, except to the extent that it would prevent the former President from being able to pay the cost of a lease or other contract that is in effect on the day before enactment of this bill and under which the former President makes payments using the monetary allowance.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1777v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-01-19">
<action-date>2016-01-11</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the House on July 16, 2015. The summary of that version is repeated here.)</p> <p><strong>Presidential Allowance Modernization Act</strong></p> <p>(Sec 2) Allows each former U.S. President a lifetime annual annuity of $200,000 and an annual monetary allowance of $200,000, each adjusted annually for inflation as provided by the Social Security Act. Reduces such annual allowance by the amount that a President's adjusted gross income in a taxable year exceeds $400,000. Denies such annuity and monetary allowance to a former President who holds an appointive or elective position in or under the federal government that pays more than a nominal amount. </p> <p>Increases from $20,000 to $100,000 the annual annuity of a surviving spouse of a former President, with an annual inflation adjustment to such increased amount as provided by the Social Security Act. </p> <p>(Sec. 3) Declares that nothing in this Act shall be considered to affect: (1) any provision of law relating to the security or protection of a former President or a family member of the President, or (2) funding to carry out security or protection of the former President. </p> <p>(Sec. 4) Makes this Act applicable to any individual who is a former President or the widow of a former President as of the date of enactment. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1777v17" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-09-24">
<action-date>2015-07-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Presidential Allowance Modernization Act</strong></p> <p>(Sec 2)&nbsp;Allows each former U.S. President a lifetime&nbsp;annual&nbsp;annuity of $200,000 and an annual monetary allowance of $200,000, each adjusted&nbsp;annually for inflation as provided by the Social Security Act.&nbsp;Reduces such annual allowance by the amount that a President's adjusted gross income in a taxable year&nbsp;exceeds $400,000. Denies such annuity and monetary allowance to a former President who holds an appointive or elective position in or under the federal government that pays more than a nominal amount. </p> <p>Increases from $20,000 to $100,000 the annual annuity of a surviving spouse of a former President, with an annual inflation adjustment to such increased amount as provided by the Social Security Act. </p> <p>(Sec. 3) Declares that nothing in this Act shall be considered to affect: (1) any provision of law relating to the security or protection of a former President or a family member of the President, or (2) funding to carry out security or protection of the former President. </p> <p>(Sec. 4) Makes this Act applicable to any individual who is a former President or the widow of a former President&nbsp;as of the date of enactment.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1777v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-04-22">
<action-date>2015-04-14</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Presidential Allowance Modernization Act</strong></p> <p>Revises provisions relating to presidential pensions to&nbsp;allow former&nbsp;Presidents&nbsp;an annuity&nbsp;of $200,000&nbsp;and an additional monetary&nbsp;allowance&nbsp;of $200,000 per year. Reduces such pension by the amount that a President's adjusted gross income in a taxable year exceeds $400,000.&nbsp; </p> <p>Increases from $20,000 to $100,000 the annual annuity of a surviving spouse of a former President. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
