<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5345" measure-id="id114hr5345" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-05-26" update-date="2016-07-22">
<title>Justice for Victims of IRS Scams and Identity Theft Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5345v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-07-22">
<action-date>2016-05-26</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Justice for Victims of IRS Scams and Identity Theft Act of 2016</b></p> <p>This bill directs the Department of Justice (DOJ) to establish procedures to expedite the review of, and seek an indictment in, any case involving identity theft or aggravated identity theft by an individual who impersonates an employee or officer of the Internal Revenue Service.</p> <p>DOJ must submit to Congress and publish a report that contains certain information on the status of prosecutions for such offenses.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
