<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="826" measure-id="id114hr826" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-02-10" update-date="2015-06-30">
<title>Examining America's Mental Health Services Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr826v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-06-30">
<action-date>2015-02-10</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Examining America's Mental Health Services Act of 2015</b></p> <p>Requires the Department of Health and Human Services to enter into an agreement with the Institute of Medicine (or, if the Institute declines to enter into such an arrangement, another appropriate entity) to conduct a comprehensive study on gaps in mental health services and how these gaps can increase the risk of violent acts.</p> <p>Requires the study to include consideration of: (1) gaps in mental health treatment services for adults and children with severe and persistent mental illness, (2) barriers to receiving mental health services that result in high rates of untreated mental illness, and (3) the availability of interventions such as assisted outpatient treatment designed to reach individuals with untreated severe mental illness.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
