<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4347" measure-id="id114hr4347" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-01-07" update-date="2016-04-25">
<title>Debt Collection Practices Harmonization Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4347v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-04-25">
<action-date>2016-01-07</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Debt Collection Practices Harmonization Act</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Fair Debt Collection Practices Act to:</p> <ul> <li>cover debt owed to a state, and</li> <li>require the Consumer Financial Protection Board to prescribe a percentage increase based on the Consumer Price Index for All Urban Consumers in order to index annually for inflation civil damages awarded for abusive practices by a debt collector. </li> </ul> <p>The bill also empowers the court to award injunctive relief for violations of the Act.</p> <p>The Department of the Treasury may not contract with any debt collector or other private party to recoup overpayments of disaster assistance to an individual or household by the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
