<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2406" measure-id="id114hr2406" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-19" update-date="2016-04-04">
<title>SHARE Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2406v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-04-04">
<action-date>2015-05-19</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Sportsmen's Heritage and Recreational Enhancement Act of 2015 or the SHARE Act</b></p> <p>This bill revises a variety of existing programs to expand access to, and opportunities for, hunting, fishing, and recreational shooting.</p> <p><i>Hunting, Fishing, and Recreational Shooting Protection Act</i></p> <p>Components of firearms and ammunition and sport fishing equipment and its components (such as lead sinkers) are exempted from regulations of chemical substances under the Toxic Substances Control Act. The authority of the Department of the Interior and the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to regulate the use of ammunition and fishing tackle based on its lead content is limited.</p> <p><i>Target Practice and Marksmanship Training Support Act</i></p> <p>The Pittman-Robertson Wildlife Restoration Act is amended to: (1) increase the proportion of funding from the Act that states may use for acquiring land for public target ranges, and (2) delay by 10 years until 2026 the date after which interest from the wildlife conservation and restoration fund is available for apportionment. </p> <p><i>Polar Bear Conservation and Fairness Act of 2015</i></p> <p>Interior must issue permits to allow a hunter to import polar bear parts (other than internal organs) if the bear was legally harvested in Canada from an approved population before the May 15, 2008, listing of the polar bear as threatened.</p> <p><i>Recreational Lands Self-Defense Act of 2015</i></p> <p>The U.S. Army Corps of Engineers may not prohibit individuals from possessing a firearm in public areas of a water resources development project. </p> <p> <p><i>Recreational Fishing and Hunting Heritage and Opportunities Act</i></p> <p>Federal public land management officials must facilitate hunting, fishing, and recreational shooting on certain federal public land.</p> <p><i>Hunter and Farmer Protection Act</i></p> <p>The bill revises standards for determining what a baited area is for purposes of the prohibition on taking migratory game birds. </p> <p>The National Park Service (NPS) may not prohibit individuals from transporting bows and crossbows if certain requirements are met. </p> <p>The NPS may establish hunter access corridors.</p> <p><i>Federal Land Transaction Facilitation Act Reauthorization of 2015</i></p> <p>This bill revises the Federal Land Transaction Facilitation Act to extend the authority provided to Interior under the Act.</p> <p><i>African Elephant Conservation and Legal Ivory Possession Act of 2015</i></p> <p>This bill revises and reauthorizes the African Elephant Conservation Act through FY2020. </p> <p>This bill provides special rules to expand access to federal land and waterways for film crews of five people or fewer.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
