<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4342" measure-id="id114hr4342" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-01-07" update-date="2016-01-11">
<title>Iran Ballistic Missile Prevention and Sanctions Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4342v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-01-11">
<action-date>2016-01-07</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Iran Ballistic Missile Prevention and Sanctions Act of 2016</strong></p> <p>This bill directs the President to impose five or more sanctions with respect to a person (or an entity) that knowingly transfers to or from Iran advanced conventional weapons or ballistic missiles, or technology, parts, components, or technical information related to advanced conventional weapons or ballistic missiles.</p> <p>Sanctions may include:</p> <ul> <li>prohibitions on Export-Import Bank assistance,</li> <li>prohibitions on loans from U.S. financial institutions and other financial services,</li> <li>prohibitions on foreign exchange and other banking transactions,</li> <li>prohibitions on property transactions,</li> <li>prohibitions on exports and federal procurement,</li> <li>prohibitions on equity and debt investment,</li> <li>U.S. exclusion of corporate officers, and</li> <li>imposition of sanctions on principal executive officers.</li> </ul> <p>The President shall include a sanctioned person on the list of specially designated nationals and blocked persons maintained by the Department of the Treasury's Office of Foreign Assets Control. </p> <p>The President may, with prior congressional notice, waive the application of sanctions on a case-by-case basis if in the U.S. national security interests.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
