<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5220" measure-id="id114hr5220" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-05-12" update-date="2016-07-13">
<title>Cyber Act of War Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5220v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-07-13">
<action-date>2016-05-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Cyber Act of War Act of 2016</strong></p> <p>This bill directs the President to: (1) develop a policy for determining when an action carried out in cyberspace constitutes a use of force against the United States, and (2) revise the Department of Defense Law of War Manual accordingly. </p> <p>In developing this policy, the President shall consider: (1) the ways in which a cyber attack's effects may be equivalent to a conventional attack's effects, including physical destruction or casualties; and (2) intangible effects of significant scope or duration.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
