<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2530" measure-id="id114hr2530" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-21" update-date="2015-12-04">
<title>Friendly Airports for Mothers Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2530v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-12-04">
<action-date>2015-05-21</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Friendly Airports for Mothers Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>This bill authorizes the Secretary of Transportation to approve a grant application for an airport development project only if the Secretary receives written assurances that the owner or operator of a large or medium hub airport will maintain a lactation area at each passenger terminal building of the airport behind the airport security screening area.</p> <p>The bill defines &quot;lactation area&quot; to mean a room or other location in a commercial service airport for members of the public to express breast milk that: </p> <ul> <li> is shielded from view and free from intrusion from the public; </li> <li> has a door that can be locked; </li> <li> includes a place to sit, a table or other flat surface, and an electrical outlet; </li> <li> is readily accessible to and usable by individuals with disabilities; and </li> <li> is not located in a restroom.</li> </ul> <p>The Secretary may approve a terminal development project for the construction or installation of a lactation area at a commercial service airport.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
