<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4594" measure-id="id114hr4594" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-02-23" update-date="2016-05-25">
<title>Making College Affordable and Accessible Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4594v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-05-25">
<action-date>2016-02-23</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Making College Affordable and Accessible Act of 2016</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 to: (1) extend the authorization of appropriations for the Fund for the Improvement of Postsecondary Education through FY2022, and (2) authorize the Department of Education (ED) to award grants to institutions of higher education to carry out credit-based academic transition programs established through partnerships between high schools and such institutions that utilize dual or concurrent enrollment programs or early college high school programs that enable students to earn college credits while in high school.</p> <p>ED shall give priority in awarding grants to institutions that serve students from low-income families, students from rural communities, or students who are the first in their family to receive postsecondary education.</p> <p>Institutions shall use grant funds to: </p> <ul> <li>provide teachers, principals, and other school leaders with professional development activities that enhance or enable the provision of the appropriate coursework through such programs; and </li> <li>support activities including curriculum design, establishment of a course articulation process, outreach programs to provide elementary school and secondary school students information about and academic preparation for the transition programs, helping students meet eligibility criteria for the postsecondary courses, and coordinating secondary and postsecondary support services and academic calendars. </li></ul> <p>Institutions may use grant funds for costs associated with carrying out such transition programs, including the costs of: (1) tuition and fees, books, and required instructional materials; and (2) transportation to and from such programs.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
