<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2416" measure-id="id114hr2416" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-19" update-date="2015-10-28">
<title>To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to evaluate the potential use of evidence from clinical experience to help support the approval of new indications for approved drugs, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2416v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-10-28">
<action-date>2015-05-19</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to require the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) to establish a program to evaluate the potential use of evidence from clinical experience to support the approval of a new indication for an approved drug and to support post-approval study requirements.</p> <p>&quot;Evidence from clinical experience&quot; means data from sources other than randomized clinical trials, including from observational studies, registries, and therapeutic use.</p> <p>Before implementing the program, the FDA must establish a draft framework for the program that describes current sources of data from clinical experience, gaps in current data collection activities, standards and methodologies for collection and analysis of data from clinical experience, and priority areas, remaining challenges, and potential pilot opportunities that the program will address.</p> The FDA must use the program to inform guidance to industry on the collection and use of evidence from clinical experience.]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
