<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3369" measure-id="id114hr3369" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-07-29" update-date="2016-04-11">
<title>RURAL Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3369v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-04-11">
<action-date>2015-07-29</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Restructuring Underutilized Resources for Advancing Learning Act or the RURAL Act</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow a refundable tax credit of: (1) $1,000 for teachers in schools in rural or high-poverty areas; (2) $2,000 for such teachers who are certified by the National Board for Professional Teaching Standards; or (3) $2,000 for eligible school administrators in rural schools.</p> <p>This bill also amends the Department of Education Organization Act to establish the Office of Rural Education Policy to, among other activities: (1) advise the Department of Education (ED) on matters related to the characteristics and needs of rural schools; (2) establish and maintain a clearinghouse for information related to rural schools; and (3) provide technical assistance to support activities related to improving education in rural areas.</p> <p>ED must prepare, and make publicly available, impact analyses of rules and regulations significantly affecting rural schools.</p> <p>In addition, the bill: (1) authorizes ED to award competitive grants to eligible partnerships, with dedicated funding for partnerships serving rural schools, to implement and evaluate the results of technology-based learning practices, strategies, tools, or courses; and (2) amends the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act to establish and authorize through FY2020 a competitive grant program for eligible entities to establish, expand, or improve expanded learning time and after-school programs in rural areas.</p> <p>The bill amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (ESEA) to require ED to provide outreach and technical assistance for grant programs under that Act.</p> <p>Rural agencies may submit consolidated plans under ESEA for covered programs.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
