<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3848" measure-id="id114hr3848" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-10-28" update-date="2015-11-02">
<title>Burt Lake Band of Ottawa and Chippewa Indians Reaffirmation Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3848v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-11-02">
<action-date>2015-10-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Burt Lake Band of Ottawa and Chippewa Indians Reaffirmation Act</b></p> <p>This bill reaffirms federal recognition and the rights and privileges of the Burt Lake Band of Ottawa and Chippewa Indians in Cheboygan County, Michigan. The band is eligible for all federal services and benefits available to other federally recognized Indian tribes. This bill designates the service area for the delivery of federal services to the band and to other Indians nearby.</p> <p>The Department of the Interior must acquire land in Cheboygan County, Michigan, and other geographic areas and must hold these lands in trust for the benefit of the band.</p> <p>This bill sets forth criteria and evidentiary requirements for determining the initial membership of the band. The band must provide a copy of its base roll to the Bureau of Indian Affairs within one year.</p> <p>The initial constitution of the band shall be the constitution submitted by the band to the Office of Federal Acknowledgment on May 2, 2005.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
