<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3098" measure-id="id114hr3098" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-07-16" update-date="2015-09-16">
<title>Brownfield Redevelopment and Economic Development Innovative Financing Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3098v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-09-16">
<action-date>2015-07-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Brownfield Redevelopment and Economic Development Innovative Financing Act of 2015</b></p> <p>Directs the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to establish the Brownfield Redevelopment and Economic Development Innovative Financing Program, under which HUD may guarantee the repayment of loans made by lenders to local governments, local redevelopment agencies, or Base Realignment and Closure Commission redevelopment projects to carry out projects for redeveloping brownfields and promoting urban renewal.</p> <p>Requires such an entity, in order to receive such a loan guarantee, to submit: (1) a master plan that describes the proposed brownfield redevelopment project, demonstrates that such project will result in major redevelopment, provides evidence of investment commitments from non-federal entities, and includes a remediation action plan approved by the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA); and (2) a certification from EPA that the brownfield to be redeveloped requires environmental remediation. Prohibits an entity from: (1) receiving a loan guarantee if it was responsible for contaminating the brownfield to be redeveloped, or (2) having more than one outstanding loan that is guaranteed under the Program. </p> <p>Sets forth requirements regarding an eligible loan's principal amount, interest rate, duration, and repayment terms. Directs HUD to establish criteria for selecting entities to receive loan guarantees. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
