<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2532" measure-id="id114hr2532" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-21" update-date="2015-06-30">
<title>EASY Savings Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2532v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-06-30">
<action-date>2015-05-21</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Employees of America Streamlining for Your Savings Act of 2015 or the EASY Savings Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>Expands the awards program for disclosures by federal employees of fraud, waste, or mismanagement that result in cost savings to the employee's agency to include identification of potential surplus funds or unnecessary budget authority. Directs that any savings resulting from the identification of such funds or budget authority be deposited in the Treasury and used to reduce a budget deficit or the federal debt. Permits the head of an agency to retain up to 10% of such savings for the purpose of paying cash awards to employees who identify surplus funds or unnecessary budget authority. </p> <p>Prohibits the payment of awards to: (1) the head of an agency; (2) federal officers who serve in a position at level I of the Executive Schedule; or (3) a voting member of an independent establishment. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
