<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="636" measure-id="id114hr636" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-02-02" update-date="2015-02-20">
<title>America's Small Business Tax Relief Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr636v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-02-20">
<action-date>2015-02-13</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>America's Small Business Tax Relief Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to make permanent after 2014 the $500,000 allowance for the expensing of depreciable business property (section 179 property) and the $2 million threshold after which the amount of such allowance is reduced. Both the allowance and the threshold amount are indexed for inflation for taxable years beginning after 2015. The allowance is also made permanent for computer software and qualified real property (i.e., qualified leasehold improvement property, restaurant property, and retail improvement property). The exclusion of air conditioning and heating units from the definition of section 179 property is eliminated. </p> <p>The taxpayer is allowed to revoke an election to expense section 179 property without first obtaining consent from the Department of the Treasury. </p> <p>(Sec. 3) The reduction (from 10 years to 5 years) of the period during which the built-in gains of an S corporation are subject to tax is made permanent.</p> <p>(Sec. 4) The tax rule requiring a decrease in the basis of a shareholder's stock in an S corporation that makes tax deductible charitable contributions of property is made permanent. </p> <p>(Sec. 5) The budgetary effects of this Act are excluded from PAYGO scorecards under the Statutory Pay-As-You-Go Act of 2010. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr636v18" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-02-13">
<action-date>2015-02-09</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House amended, Part I</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p><strong>America's Small Business Tax Relief Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill makes permanent after 2014 the $500,000 allowance for the expensing of depreciable business property (section 179 property) and the $2 million threshold after which the amount of such allowance is reduced. Both the allowance and the threshold amount are indexed for inflation for taxable years beginning after 2015. The allowance is also made permanent for computer software and qualified real property (i.e., qualified leasehold improvement property, restaurant property, and retail improvement property). The exclusion of air conditioning and heating units from the definition of section 179 property is eliminated. </p> <p>The taxpayer is allowed to revoke an election to expense section 179 property without first obtaining consent from the Department of the Treasury. </p> <p>(Sec. 3) This provision exempts the budgetary effects of this Act from PAYGO scorecards under the Statutory Pay-As-You-Go Act of 2010. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr636v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-02-06">
<action-date>2015-02-02</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>America's Small Business Tax Relief Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>Amends the Internal Revenue Code, with respect to the expensing allowance for depreciable business property, to make permanent: (1) the increased $500,000 expensing allowance for such property; (2) the increased $2,000,000 threshold amount for such property over which the amount of the expensing allowance is reduced; (3) expensing of computer software; and (4) rules for the expensing of qualified real property (i.e.,&nbsp;leasehold improvement, restaurant, and retail improvement property).&nbsp; Allow an inflation adjustment to the dollar amounts of the expensing allowance for taxable years beginning after 2015. Eliminates the exclusion of air conditioning and heating units from property eligible for the expensing allowance. </p> <p>Prohibits the entry of the budgetary effects of this Act on&nbsp;PAYGO scorecards under the Statutory Pay-As-You-Go Act of 2010.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
