<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2136" measure-id="id114hr2136" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-04-30" update-date="2015-09-18">
<title>Improving the Quality of Disability Decisions Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2136v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-09-18">
<action-date>2015-04-30</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Improving the Quality of Disability Decisions Act of 2015</b></p> <p>This bill amends titles II (Old Age, Survivors, and Disability Insurance) (OASDI) and XVI (Supplemental Security Income) (SSI) of the Social Security Act to direct the Social Security Administration (SSA) to conduct pre-effectuation and post-effectuation quality reviews of hearing dispositions with respect to decisions in connection with applications for OASDI or SSI benefits, in a sufficient number to ensure compliance with laws, regulations, and other guidance.</p> <p>The SSA shall report annually Congress on: (1) the total number of cases selected for quality review, (2) the number in which a decision is remanded, and (3) the number in which a decision is modified or reversed.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
