<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5244" measure-id="id114hr5244" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-05-16" update-date="2016-07-15">
<title>Saint Francis Dam Disaster National Memorial Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5244v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-07-15">
<action-date>2016-07-05</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Saint Francis Dam Disaster National Memorial Act</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 3) This bill authorizes the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to establish the Saint Francis Dam Disaster National Memorial at the Dam site in Los Angeles County, California, to honor the victims of the Saint Francis Dam disaster of March 12, 1928. The Memorial shall be managed by the Forest Service.</p> <p>(Sec. 4) USDA shall submit to Congress, by three years after this bill's enactment, recommendations regarding:</p> <ul> <li> the planning, design, construction, and long-term management of the Memorial;</li> <li> the proposed boundaries; </li> <li> a visitor center and educational facilities; and </li> <li> ensuring public access to the Memorial.</li> </ul> <p>(Sec. 5) The bill establishes the Saint Francis Dam Disaster National Monument on specified National Forest System land administered by USDA in Los Angeles County for the purpose of conserving and enhancing the cultural, archaeological, historical, watershed, educational, and recreational resources and values of the Monument.</p> <p>(Sec. 6) USDA shall develop a management plan for the Monument by four years after this bill's enactment. USDA shall manage the Monument: (1) in a manner that conserves and enhances its cultural and historic resources, and (2) in accordance with the Forest and Rangeland Renewable Resources Planning Act of 1974. The bill limits the use of motorized vehicles but permits grazing within the Monument.</p> <p>(Sec. 7) No additional funds are authorized to carry out this bill's requirements.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5244v17" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-07-06">
<action-date>2016-07-01</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Saint Francis Dam Disaster National Memorial Act</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 3) This bill authorizes the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to establish the Saint Francis Dam Disaster National Memorial at the Dam site in Los Angeles County, California, to honor the victims of the Saint Francis Dam disaster of March 12, 1928. The Memorial shall be managed by the Forest Service.</p> <p>(Sec. 4) USDA shall submit to Congress, by three years after this bill's enactment, recommendations regarding:</p> <ul> <li> the planning, design, construction, and long-term management of the Memorial;</li> <li> the proposed boundaries; </li> <li> a visitor center and educational facilities; and </li> <li> ensuring public access to the Memorial.</li> </ul> <p>(Sec. 5) The bill establishes the Saint Francis Dam Disaster National Monument on specified National Forest System land administered by USDA in Los Angeles County for the purpose of conserving and enhancing the cultural, archaeological, historical, watershed, educational, and recreational resources and values of the Monument.</p> <p>(Sec. 6) USDA shall develop a management plan for the Monument by four years after this bill's enactment. USDA shall manage the Monument: (1) in a manner that conserves and enhances its cultural and historic resources, and (2) in accordance with the Forest and Rangeland Renewable Resources Planning Act of 1974. The bill limits the use of motorized vehicles but permits grazing within the Monument.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5244v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-07-06">
<action-date>2016-05-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Saint Francis Dam Disaster National Memorial Act</strong></p> <p>This bill authorizes the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to establish the Saint Francis Dam Disaster National Memorial at the dam site in Los Angeles County, California, to honor the victims of the Saint Francis Dam disaster of March 12, 1928. The Memorial shall be managed by the Forest Service.</p> <p>The bill establishes the Saint Francis Dam Disaster National Monument on specified National Forest System land administered by USDA in Los Angeles County. USDA shall: (1) develop for the Monument a management plan and a watershed health assessment to identify opportunities for watershed restoration, and (2) manage the Monument in a manner that conserves and enhances its cultural and historic resources and in accordance with the Forest and Rangeland Renewable Resources Planning Act of 1974. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
