<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3946" measure-id="id114hr3946" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-11-05" update-date="2016-03-25">
<title>Protecting Local Communities from Executive Overreach Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3946v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-03-25">
<action-date>2015-11-05</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Protecting Local Communities from Executive Overreach Act</b></p> <p>This bill declares that the President may not designate lands to be a new or expanded national monument unless within one year before a designation the Department of the Interior consults with each community, county, municipality, city, town, or township with boundaries within or adjacent to the land affected by the designation and obtains concurrence for the designation from:</p> <ul> <li>the governing body of each such community, county, municipality, city, town, or township; and </li> <li>the wildlife management and land management authorities and the governor of each state in which the new or expanded national monument would be located. </li> </ul> <p>Furthermore, a declaration of a national monument shall not:</p> <ul> <li>include private property without the informed written consent of the property owner; </li> <li>be construed to increase the amount of funding for the monument for any fiscal year; </li> <li>apply to more than 5,000 acres; or </li> <li>be used to create or expand a national monument located in specified counties in Arizona, California, Colorado, Nevada, New Mexico, Oregon, and Utah. </li> </ul> <p>Water rights associated with a national monument created or expanded by a declaration:</p> <ul> <li>may not be reserved expressly or by implication by such a declaration, and </li> <li>may be acquired for a national monument created or expanded by a declaration only according to the laws of the state in which the water rights are based.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
