<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2351" measure-id="id114hr2351" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-15" update-date="2015-07-31">
<title>Professional Boxing Safety Enhancement Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2351v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-07-31">
<action-date>2015-05-15</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Professional Boxing Safety Enhancement Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>Amends the Professional Boxing Safety Act of 1996 to repeal a provision allowing a professional boxing match to meet an alternative requirement in effect under regulations of a boxing commission that provides protection of the health and safety of boxers and that is equivalent to requirements otherwise provided under such Act.</p> <p>Requires a boxer to provide with the application for a boxing license or for renewal of such license an original or certified copy of the results of medical tests that: (1) were performed by a laboratory during the calendar year for which the license is being issued or no earlier than 30 days before the application is submitted, and (2) show that the boxer is not infected with the human immunodeficiency virus or the hepatitis virus.</p> <p>Requires an ambulance and emergency medical personnel with appropriate resuscitation equipment (currently, one or the other) to be continuously present on site.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
