<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4236" measure-id="id114hr4236" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-12-10" update-date="2016-02-11">
<title>Financial Security Credit Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4236v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-02-11">
<action-date>2015-12-10</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Financial Security Credit Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow an income-based tax credit equal to the lesser of $500 or 50% of the total amount deposited or contributed into designated savings products in a taxable year (financial security credit). A "designated savings product" is a qualified retirement plan, a qualified tuition plan, a Coverdell education savings account, a U.S. savings bond, a certificate of deposit with a duration of at least eight months, a savings account, or other savings product considered appropriate by the&nbsp;Department&nbsp;of the Treasury. </p> <p>The Internal Revenue Service must notify individual taxpayers who may qualify for a financial security credit that they have the option of an electronic direct deposit if they deposit any portion of their tax refund into a designated savings product. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
