<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5461" measure-id="id114hr5461" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-06-13" update-date="2016-11-01">
<title>Iranian Leadership Asset Transparency Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5461v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-11-01">
<action-date>2016-09-21</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Iranian Leadership Asset Transparency Act</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 3) This bill requires the Department of the Treasury, in furtherance of efforts to prevent the financing of terrorism, money laundering, or related illicit finance and to make financial institutions' required compliance with remaining sanctions more easily understood, to submit within 270 days and annually thereafter for the next two years a report regarding: </p> <ul> <li>the funds or assets held in U.S. and foreign financial institutions that are directly or indirectly controlled by specified Iranian officials; </li> <li>any equity stake such official has in an entity on Treasury's list of Specially Designated Nationals or in any other sanctioned entity; </li> <li>how such funds, assets, or equity interests were acquired and used; </li> <li>new methods used to evade anti-money laundering and related laws, including recommendations to improve techniques to combat illicit uses of the U.S. financial system by each such official. </li> <li> recommendations for revising U.S. economic sanctions against Iran to prevent Iranian officials from using funds or assets to develop and procure ballistic missile technology; </li> <li> how Treasury assesses the effectiveness of U.S. economic sanctions against Iran; and</li> <li> recommendations for improving Treasury's ability to develop and enforce additional economic sanctions against Iran if so ordered by the President. </li> </ul> <p>The unclassified portion of the report shall be made available to the public and posted on Treasury's website in downloadable English, Farsi, Arabic, and Azeri versions.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5461v28" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-10-28">
<action-date>2016-09-13</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House without amendment, Part I</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p><strong>Iranian Leadership Asset Transparency Act</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 3) This bill requires the Department of the Treasury, in furtherance of efforts to prevent the financing of terrorism, money laundering, or related illicit finance and to make financial institutions' required compliance with remaining sanctions more easily understood, to submit within 270 days and annually thereafter for the next two years a report regarding: </p> <ul> <li>the funds or assets held in U.S. and foreign financial institutions that are directly or indirectly controlled by specified Iranian officials; </li> <li>any equity stake such official has in an entity on Treasury's list of Specially Designated Nationals or in any other sanctioned entity; </li> <li>how such funds, assets, or equity interests were acquired and used; and </li> <li>new methods used to evade anti-money laundering and related laws, including recommendations to improve techniques to combat illicit uses of the U.S. financial system by each such official. </li> </ul>  <p>The unclassified portion of the report shall be made available to the public and posted on Treasury's website in downloadable English, Farsi, Arabic, and Azeri versions.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5461v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-09-21">
<action-date>2016-06-13</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Iranian Leadership Asset Transparency Act</strong></p> <p>This bill requires the Department of the Treasury to submit within 270 days and annually for the next two years a report regarding: </p> <ul> <li>the estimated total funds or assets held in U.S. and foreign financial institutions that are controlled by specified Iranian officials,</li> <li>any equity stake such officials have in an entity on Treasury's list of Specially Designated Nationals or in any other sanctioned entity,</li> <li> how such funds or assets or equity interests were acquired and how they have been used, and </li> <li>new methods used to evade anti-money laundering and related laws and recommendations to improve techniques to combat illicit uses of the U.S. financial system by each such official.</li> </ul>  <p>The unclassified portion of the report shall be made available to the public and posted on Treasury's website in downloadable English, Farsi, Arabic, and Azeri versions.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
