<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2634" measure-id="id114hr2634" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-06-03" update-date="2015-09-02">
<title>Public School Emergency Relief Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2634v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-09-02">
<action-date>2015-06-03</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Public School Emergency Relief Act</b></p> <p>This bill authorizes a program of emergency impact aid payments to states and, through them, to local educational agencies and Indian schools for each quarter of the 2015-2016 school year to respond to any increase in the enrollment of immigrant children from the corresponding quarter of the 2013-2014 school year.</p> <p>Payments shall be used to provide services and assistance to schools that enroll immigrant students. </p> <p>Funds may be used for:</p> <ul> <li>compensating school personnel,</li> <li>identifying and acquiring curricular material and mobile educational units and leasing sites or spaces,</li> <li>basic instructional services for immigrant students,</li> <li>reasonable transportation costs,</li> <li>health and counseling services,</li> <li>education and support services, and</li> <li>other uses allowed under title III (Language Instruction for Limited English Proficient and Immigrant Students) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965.</li> </ul> <p>Any payment made on behalf of a disabled immigrant student is to be used for special education and related services.</p> <p>Emergency impact aid funds that are not obligated during the 2015-2016 school year must be returned to the Department of Education. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
