<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5458" measure-id="id114hr5458" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-06-13" update-date="2016-08-29">
<title>Veterans TRICARE Choice Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5458v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-08-29">
<action-date>2016-06-13</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Veterans TRICARE Choice Act</b></p> <p> This bill allows, as of January 1, 2017, an individual who is eligible to be a covered beneficiary entitled to health care benefits under the TRICARE program (a Department of Defense [DOD] managed health care program) and who is not serving on active duty in the uniformed services to: (1) elect to be ineligible to enroll in TRICARE, (2) make tax deductible contributions to a health savings account during the period such individual elects to be ineligible for TRICARE coverage, and (3) enroll in the TRICARE program at a later date during a special enrollment period.</p> <p> DOD shall submit to the Internal Revenue Service information on each TRICARE-eligible individual who makes such election for purposes of determining such individual's eligibility for a health savings account. </p> <p> DOD shall provide to each TRICARE-eligible individual who seeks to make such election information regarding: (1) health savings accounts, and (2) changing an election.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
