<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2810" measure-id="id114hr2810" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-06-17" update-date="2015-07-07">
<title>Stay in Place, Cut the Waste Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2810v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-07-07">
<action-date>2015-06-17</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Stay in Place, Cut the Waste Act of 2015 </b></p> <p>This bill requires the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) to: (1) review the extent to which federal agencies have reduced travel expenses by using video conferencing, and (2) develop a plan to reduce federal agency travel expenses by 50% below FY2015 levels or the greatest reduction OMB considers feasible by FY2019. Beginning in FY2019, OMB must implement the plan by rescinding from agency budgets the amounts proposed for reduction by the plan. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
