<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1646" measure-id="id114hr1646" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-03-26" update-date="2015-06-29">
<title>Homeland Security Drone Assessment and Analysis Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1646v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-06-29">
<action-date>2015-06-23</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Homeland Security Drone Assessment and Analysis Act</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) Directs the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to: (1) research how commercially available small and medium sized unmanned aircraft, excluding aircraft over 1,300 pounds, could be used to perpetuate an attack; and (2) develop policies, guidance, and protocols for DHS to prevent, or mitigate the risks of, such an attack. Authorizes DHS to provide the Departments of Defense, Transportation, and Energy and the Nuclear Regulatory Commission information regarding how to best prevent and mitigate the risk of such an attack.</p> <p>Requires DHS to: (1) disseminate to state, local, and tribal law enforcement officials and to state and major urban area fusion centers information regarding how such officials may bolster preparedness for, and responses to, attacks by such aircraft; and (2) submit an assessment of the security risk associated with such aircraft.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1646v18" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-06-23">
<action-date>2015-06-18</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House amended, Part I</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Homeland Security Drone Assessment and Analysis Act</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) Directs the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to: (1) research how commercially available small and medium sized unmanned aircraft, excluding aircraft over 1,300 pounds, could be used to perpetuate an attack; and (2) develop policies, guidance, and protocols to prevent, or mitigate the risks of, such an attack. Authorizes DHS to provide the Departments of Defense, Transportation, and Energy and the Nuclear Regulatory Commission advice regarding how to best prevent and mitigate the risk of such an attack.</p> <p>Requires DHS to: (1) disseminate to state, local, and tribal law enforcement officials and to state and major urban area fusion centers information regarding how such officials may bolster preparedness for, and responses to, attacks by such aircraft; and (2) submit an assessment of the security risk associated with such aircraft.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1646v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-06-23">
<action-date>2015-03-26</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Homeland Security Drone Assessment and Analysis Act</strong></p> <p>Directs the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to: (1) research how commercially available small and medium sized unmanned aerial systems could be used to perpetuate an attack; (2) develop federal policies, guidance, and protocols to prevent, or mitigate the effects of, such an attack; (3) disseminate to state, local, and tribal law enforcement officials information regarding how such officials may bolster preparedness for, and responses to, attacks by such systems; and (4) submit an assessment of the security threat associated with the commercial availability of such systems.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
