<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1014" measure-id="id114hr1014" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-02-20" update-date="2015-03-27">
<title>Marijuana Tax Revenue Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1014v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-03-27">
<action-date>2015-02-20</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Marijuana Tax Revenue Act of 2015 </strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to impose an excise tax on: (1) the sale of marijuana by producers or importers, and (2) each person who is engaged in a marijuana enterprise. Defines "marijuana enterprise" to mean a producer, importer, manufacturer, distributor, retailer or any person who transports, stores, displays, or otherwise participates in any business activity that handles marijuana or marijuana products.</p> <p>Any person who engages in a marijuana enterprise must obtain a permit to engage in such an enterprise. </p> <p>The bill imposes civil penalties for failure to comply with the requirements of this Act and criminal penalties for engaging in a marijuana enterprise without a permit, failing to keep or make required records or for making false records, or refusing to pay or evading a tax imposed by this Act and for other offenses related to the sale of marijuana.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
