<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3983" measure-id="id114hr3983" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-11-05" update-date="2016-01-11">
<title>BOSS Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3983v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-01-11">
<action-date>2015-11-05</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Building Opportunity for Student Startups Act or the BOSS Act</strong></p> <p>This bill directs the Under Secretary of Commerce for Standards and Technology to enter into an arrangement with the National Academy of Sciences to conduct a study on the role of incubators and accelerators in the commercialization of federally funded research and regional economic development.</p> <p>The study shall: (1) include an examination of metrics for comparing startups that have, and startups that have not, completed incubator or accelerator programs; (2) include the role of incubators and accelerators in developing regional innovation clusters; and (3) identify best practices in the structure, goals, operation, management, and funding mechanisms of leading incubators and accelerators.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
