<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2558" measure-id="id114hr2558" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-21" update-date="2015-06-12">
<title>Examination of Exposures to Environmental Hazards During Military Service and Health Care for Atsugi Naval Air Facility Veterans and their Families Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2558v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-06-12">
<action-date>2015-05-21</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Examination of Exposures to Environmental Hazards During Military Service and Health Care for Atsugi Naval Air Facility Veterans and their Families Act of 2015 </strong></p> <p>Directs the Secretaries of Defense (DOD) and of Veterans Affairs (VA) to jointly establish the Advisory Board on Environmental Exposures at Atsugi Naval Air Facility to provide expert advice to DOD and VA on matters relating to exposure of current and former members of the Armed Forces (members) and their dependents to environmental hazards at Atsugi Naval Air Facility, Japan, during the period beginning in 1983 in which the air, water, or soil at such facility was contaminated due to an incinerator.</p> <p>Requires the Board to: (1) consider and study cases of such exposure, (2) evaluate submitted exposure claims, and (3) recommend to such Secretaries that either a claim is insufficient to warrant further consideration or is sufficient to warrant health care or compensation. Authorizes the Board to convene a science panel to consider exposure claims and report results to the Board.</p> <p>Authorizes the DOD Secretary to provide to such members and dependents the health care benefits recommended by the Board.</p> <p>Requires the DOD Secretary to: (1) compile a list of individuals exposed to environmental hazards at the facility during the period in which the air, water, or soil was contaminated; and (2) submit a related report to Congress. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
