<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1634" measure-id="id114hr1634" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-03-25" update-date="2015-10-20">
<title>Border Security Technology Accountability Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1634v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-10-20">
<action-date>2015-07-27</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Border Security Technology Accountability Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to require the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to: (1) ensure that each border security technology acquisition program that is determined to be a major acquisition program has an acquisition program baseline approved by the relevant acquisition decision authority; (2) document that each such program is meeting the cost, schedule, and performance thresholds specified in such baseline in compliance with relevant departmental acquisition policies and the Federal Acquisition Regulation; and (3) have a plan for each such program to meet program implementation objectives by managing contractor performance.</p> <p>Directs: (1) the Under Secretary for Management and the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection to ensure that border security technology acquisition program managers adhere to relevant internal control standards identified by the Comptroller General, and (2) the Commissioner to provide information to assist the Under Secretary in monitoring proper program management of such acquisition programs.</p> <p>Requires the Under Secretary for Management, in coordination with the Under Secretary for Science and Technology and the Commissioner, to submit a plan for testing and evaluation, as well as the use of independent verification and validation resources, for border security technology so that new border security technologies are evaluated through a series of assessments, processes, and audits to ensure compliance with relevant departmental acquisition policies and the Federal Acquisition Regulation, as well as the effectiveness of taxpayer dollars.</p> <p>Defines "major acquisition program" to mean a DHS acquisition program that is estimated by DHS to require an eventual total expenditure of at least $300 million over its life cycle cost.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1634v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-09-08">
<action-date>2015-03-25</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Border Security Technology Accountability Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to require each border security technology acquisition program of the Department of Homeland Security with a significant lifecycle cost estimate to: (1) have written documentation demonstrating that each such program has an acquisition program baseline approved by the relevant acquisition decision authority; and (2) demonstrate that each such program is meeting agreed-upon cost, schedule, and performance thresholds, in compliance with the Federal Acquisition Regulation.</p> <p>Directs: (1) the Under Secretary for Management, in coordination with U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP), to ensure that border security technology acquisition program managers adhere to relevant internal control standards identified by the Government Accountability Office; and (2) CBP to provide information to assist the Under Secretary in monitoring proper program management of such acquisition programs.</p> <p>Requires the Under Secretary, in coordination with CBP, to submit a plan for testing and evaluation, as well as the use of independent verification and validation resources, for border security technology so that new border security technologies are evaluated through a series of assessments, processes, and audits to ensure the effectiveness of taxpayer dollars.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
