<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1097" measure-id="id114hr1097" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-02-26" update-date="2015-03-09">
<title>Ban Insider Trading Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1097v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-03-09">
<action-date>2015-02-26</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Ban Insider Trading Act of 2015</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to make it unlawful to purchase or sell any security, or securities-based swap agreement, that is based upon information that the person knows (or should know) is material inside information. </p> <p>&quot;Inside information&quot; is defined as information that is nonpublic and obtained:</p> <ul> <li>illegally,</li> <li>directly or indirectly from an issuer who expects either confidentiality or that it will only be used for a legitimate business purpose, or</li> <li>in violation of a fiduciary duty. </li> </ul> <p>&quot;Material information&quot; is defined as information relating to an issuer or to a security which, if it were made public, would likely have a significant effect upon the security's price. </p> <p>Subjects a person to liability to prosecution for trading in prohibited securities while in possession of material nonpublic information if the person, without a legitimate business purpose, discloses intentionally to another person information that the discloser knows (or should know) is material inside information.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
