<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4340" measure-id="id114hr4340" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-01-07" update-date="2016-02-01">
<title>SB CAPE Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4340v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-02-01">
<action-date>2016-01-07</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Small Business Contracting and Acquisition Programs Efficiency Act of 2016 or the SB CAPE Act of 2016</b></p> <p>This bill directs the Government Accountability Office (GAO) to initiate a review of the Office of Government Contracting and Business Development (OGCBD) of the Small Business Administration (SBA). </p> <p>This review shall examine: </p> <ul> <li>the extent to which SBA personnel who carry out certain procurement and business development programs report to the OGCBD, </li> <li>whether greater efficiency and consistency in the certification process of the procurement and business development programs could be achieved by creating a single organizational unit of employees to process all certifications required by such programs,</li> <li>whether greater efficiency and efficacy in the performance of such programs could be achieved by improving the alignment of the field personnel assigned to them,</li> <li>how the OGCBD could improve its staffing of regulatory drafting functions and its coordination with the Federal Acquisition Regulatory Council to ensure timely rulemaking by the SBA, and </li> <li>any other areas in which the GAO determines that the SBA could improve its performance with respect to procurement and business development programs.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
