<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2623" measure-id="id114hr2623" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-06-03" update-date="2015-09-03">
<title>Personal Drug Importation Fairness Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2623v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-09-03">
<action-date>2015-06-03</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Personal Drug Importation Fairness Act of 2015</b></p> <p>This bill allows a drug to be imported by a person other than the drug's manufacturer if the drug: (1) has the same active ingredients, route of administration, and strength as an approved drug; (2) may be lawfully marketed in, and is imported or reimported from, a country included on a list in this Act that the Food and Drug Administration determines has standards for ensuring drug safety and effectiveness that are at least as protective as U.S. standards; (3) is dispensed by a licensed pharmacist; (4) is shipped directly to, or is imported by, the ultimate consumer; (5) is shipped or imported in quantities that do not exceed a 90-day supply; (6) is accompanied by a copy of a valid prescription; and (7) is not a controlled substance. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
