<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3886" measure-id="id114hr3886" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-11-03" update-date="2016-06-30">
<title>Early Childhood Nutrition Improvement Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3886v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-06-30">
<action-date>2015-11-03</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Early Childhood Nutrition Improvement Act</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act to revise several provisions related to the child and adult care food program.</p> <p>Under current law: (1)&nbsp;an institution that provides child or day care under the program may be reimbursed for up to two meals and one supplement per day per child; and (2)&nbsp;a&nbsp;family or group day care home sponsoring organization may receive the same&nbsp;maximum reimbursement, but&nbsp;only with respect to a child that is maintained in a child care setting for at least eight hours per day. The bill eliminates this distinction between institutions and sponsoring organizations, and increases maximum reimbursement for both to: (1) two meals and one supplement or one meal and two supplements per day per child; or (2) three meals and one supplement or two meals and two supplements per day per child, for each child that is maintained in a child care setting for at least eight hours per day.</p> <p>A determination of a for-profit day care center's eligibility to participate in the program shall be in effect for six months.</p> <p>The Department of Agriculture (USDA)&nbsp;must issue guidance and, as appropriate, regulations to assist in ensuring a fair and effective process for the identification, review, and&nbsp;correction of serious program deficiencies. </p> <p>USDA&nbsp;shall establish an advisory committee to examine the feasibility of reducing unnecessary or duplicative paperwork for those participating or seeking to participate in the program.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
