<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3628" measure-id="id114hr3628" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-09-28" update-date="2015-10-01">
<title>Pay Our Military Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3628v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-10-01">
<action-date>2015-09-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Pay Our Military Act </b></p> <p>This bill provides FY2016 and FY2017 appropriations for military pay and allowances during any period in which interim or full-year appropriations are not in effect. </p> <p>In the event of a government shutdown, the bill provides continuing appropriations for pay and allowances of: </p> <ul> <li> members of the Armed Forces, including reserve components, who perform active service during the period; </li> <li>members of the reserve components of the Armed Forces who perform inactive-duty training during the period; and</li> <li>civilian personnel or contractors of the Department of Defense (and the Department of Homeland Security in the case of the Coast Guard) that are providing support to members of the Armed Forces. </li> </ul> <p>The appropriations provided by this bill for a fiscal year are available until the earliest of: (1) the enactment into law of specified appropriations legislation for the fiscal year, (2) the end of the fiscal year, or (3) January 1, 2017. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
