<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="792" measure-id="id114hr792" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-02-05" update-date="2015-06-11">
<title>Acre In, Acre Out Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr792v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-06-11">
<action-date>2015-02-05</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Acre In, Acre Out Act</b></p> <p> Prescribes a new requirement for any acquisition of land by the Department of the Interior or the Department of Agriculture that would result in a net increase of total land acreage under the jurisdiction of the National Park Service, the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, the Bureau of Land Management, or the Forest Service. Requires the department concerned to offer for sale an equal number of acres of federal land that is under the same jurisdictional status.</p> <p>Exempts from this requirement any easements acquired to facilitate management of federal lands.</p> <p>Requires land sold pursuant to this Act to be offered for sale at fair market value (based on local comparable sales), with monthly price reductions if the land is not sold in six months.</p> <p> <p>Requires all net proceeds from the sale of federal lands pursuant to this Act to be deposited directly into the Treasury for reduction of the public debt.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
