<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2517" measure-id="id114hr2517" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-21" update-date="2015-06-30">
<title>Powering American Jobs Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2517v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-06-30">
<action-date>2015-05-21</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Powering American Jobs Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>Amends the Internal Revenue Code to extend through 2016: (1) the tax credit for nonbusiness energy efficiency improvements, (2) excise tax credits and payments for alternative fuels and biodiesel and renewable diesel fuel mixtures, (3) the tax credit for alternative fuel vehicle refueling property expenditures, and (4) the income tax credit for biodiesel and renewable fuels. Equalizes the excise tax rate for liquefied natural gas and liquefied petroleum gas. Modifies energy efficiency standards for windows, doors, skylights, roofing, water heaters, biomass stoves, and furnaces or hot water boilers. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
