<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3533" measure-id="id114hr3533" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-09-17" update-date="2016-06-27">
<title>Water System Cost Savings Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3533v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-06-27">
<action-date>2015-09-17</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Water System Cost Savings Act</b></p> <p>This bill requires the Environmental Protection Agency and the Department of Agriculture to: (1) update their programs that provide drinking water technical assistance by including information on cost-effective, innovative, and alternative drinking water delivery systems; and (2) disseminate information on the cost effectiveness of alternative drinking water delivery systems, including wells and well systems, to communities and nonprofit organizations seeking federal funding for drinking water systems serving 500 or fewer persons.</p> <p>In applications for a grant or loan from the federal government or a state that is using federal assistance for those drinking water systems, applicants must self-certify that they have considered as an alternative drinking water supply, drinking water delivery systems sourced by publicly owned individual, shared, and community wells.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
