<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5008" measure-id="id114hr5008" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-04-20" update-date="2016-05-13">
<title>Clarify Workers Misclassification in the Construction Industry Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5008v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-05-13">
<action-date>2016-04-20</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Clarify Workers Misclassification in the Construction Industry Act </b></p> <p>This bill requires the Department of the Treasury to initiate an enforcement initiative to increase tax compliance in the construction industry. </p> <p>The initiative must include: </p> <ul> <li> consultations with industry experts and leaders on its scope and priorities, </li> <li>targeted tax audits of major construction contractors that may not be in compliance with federal tax laws, </li> <li> civil and criminal tax enforcement actions under existing authorities, and</li> <li> educational efforts aimed at increasing voluntary tax compliance in the construction industry. </li> </ul> <p>Treasury must promulgate rules and issue guidance to reclassify individuals who are not currently being treated as employees consistent with the proper classification of employees under common law standards within the construction industry.</p> <p>In implementing this bill, Treasury must: (1) reassign personnel and resources from other activities to carry out this bill, and (2) report to Congress on the implementation and recommendations for further congressional action. </p> <p>The Government Accountability Office must study the various forms of tax fraud (including employee misclassification) in the construction industry, efforts to combat fraud, and recommendations for further action. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
