<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5715" measure-id="id114hr5715" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-07-11" update-date="2016-08-25">
<title>No Ex-Im Assistance for Terrorism Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5715v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-08-25">
<action-date>2016-07-11</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>No Ex-Im Assistance for Terrorism Act</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Export-Import Bank Act of 1945 to prohibit the Export-Import Bank from guaranteeing, insuring, extending credit, or participating in the extension of credit in connection with the export of U.S. goods or services sought by:</p> <ul> <li> the Government of Iran, an entity owned or controlled by it, or an entity created under Iranian law;</li> <li> an entity involving the Government of Iran, owned or controlled by the Government of Iran, or created under Iranian law; or</li> <li> a non-U.S. entity that, in the last five-years, has leased or re-exported aircraft to the Government of Iran. </li></ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
