<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4555" measure-id="id114hr4555" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-02-12" update-date="2016-02-22">
<title>Non-Discrimination of Israel in Labeling Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4555v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-02-22">
<action-date>2016-02-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Non-Discrimination of Israel in Labeling Act</strong></p> <p>This bill requires that, for purposes of marking imported articles and containers under the Tariff Act of 1930, every article of origin from the geographical area known as the West Bank (or its container) imported into the United States shall include the words: </p> <ul> <li>&quot;West Bank&quot; in the case of an article of an area in the West Bank not administered by Israel; and </li> <li>&quot;Israel,&quot; &quot;Made in Israel,&quot; or &quot;Product of Israel&quot; in the case of an article of an area in the West Bank administered by Israel.</li> </ul> <p>Every article of origin from the geographical area known as the Gaza Strip (or its container) imported into the United States shall include the words &quot;Gaza&quot; or &quot;Gaza Strip.&quot;</p> <p>Neither the Department of the Treasury nor any other federal department or agency may prohibit the use of any of such markings for purposes of satisfying the Tariff Act of 1930. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
