<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4487" measure-id="id114hr4487" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-02-08" update-date="2016-08-08">
<title>Public Buildings Reform and Savings Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4487v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-08-08">
<action-date>2016-05-23</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Public Buildings Reform and Savings Act of 2016</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill: (1) directs the General Services Administration (GSA) to establish and conduct a pilot program through 2021 to execute lease agreements using alternative procedures to reduce costs of leased space and significantly reduce or eliminate the backlog of expiring leases over the next five years, and (2) authorizes the GSA to submit consolidated prospectuses for leases and projects to Congress for approval.</p> <p>(Sec. 3) The bill requires approval by congressional resolution of any costs and expenses associated with administering an acquisition by exchange involving real property or in-kind consideration, including services, with a fair market value of $2.85 million or more. </p> <p>(Sec. 4) The bill authorizes: (1) the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to authorize contract security personnel to carry firearms, and (2) such personnel to detain individuals without a warrant. DHS must&nbsp;establish minimum and uniform training standards for security personnel. </p> <p>(Sec. 5) DHS must&nbsp;report on: (1) the personnel needs of the Federal Protective Service (FPS), including recommendations on the numbers of FPS law enforcement officers needed to carry out the mission of FPS during the 10-year period after the enactment of this Act; and (2) the best method of funding for the FPS. </p> <p>(Sec. 6) The GSA must: (1) justify any need for new or replacement building space, including an explanation of why such space could not be consolidated or colocated into other owned or leased space; and (2) notify the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure and the Senate Committee on Environment and Public Works if the cost, scope, or size of any project changes by 5% or more. </p> <p>(Sec. 8) The bill sets a five-year expiration on resolutions adopted by either such committee approving GSA prospectus-level (large) projects. </p> <p>(Sec. 9) The bill directs the GSA to: (1)&nbsp;sell a portion of the Forrestal Complex in Washington, D.C. to generate funds necessary to construct a new Department of Energy headquarters on government-owned land in a manner consistent with the SW Ecodistrict Plan of the National Capital Planning Commission if the GSA determines that such headquarters can be constructed with no net costs to the government.</p> <p>(Sec. 10) The bill requires that any bargain-price option to purchase at less than fair market value that is contained in any lease agreement entered into on or after January 1, 2016, for the accommodation of a federal agency in a building may be exercised only to the extent specifically provided for in an Act of Congress.</p> <p>(Sec. 11) GSA must consider the direct purchase of energy and other utilities in bulk or otherwise for leased facilities when cost-effective.&nbsp;</p> <p>(Sec. 12) The bill exempts an individual acquisition for commercial leasing services from enhanced competition requirements for the purchase of property and services by executive agencies if such individual acquisition is made on a no cost basis and pursuant to a multiple award contract in accordance with requirements for full and open competition.</p> <p>The Government Accountability Office must conduct biennial audits of the GSA National Broker Contract, conduct a review of the application of enhanced competition requirements, and report on such audits and reviews. </p> <p>(Sec. 13) The bill requires the GSA to report to such committees on the justification for using three lease rental caps per fiscal year and their impacts in the National Capital Region.</p> <p>(Sec. 14) The bill amends the Public Works and Economic Development Administration Reform Act of 1965 to authorize the Department of Commerce to release the federal government's interest in economic adjustment grants not less than seven years after the final disbursement of the grant. </p> <p>(Sec. 15) The bill requires a federal authority responsible for the operation of a building that is open to the public and that contains a public restroom to ensure that the building also contains a lactation room that is available for use by members of the public to express breast milk. Exceptions may be allowed if: (1) the building does not contain a lactation room for employees who work in the building and does not have a room that could be repurposed as a lactation room or a space that could be made private using portable materials, at a reasonable cost; or (2) new construction would be required to create a lactation room in the building and the cost of such construction is unfeasible.</p> <p>(Sec. 16) The GSA shall issue a report examining the feasibility of giving preference to the use of reclaimed refrigerants to service existing equipment of federal buildings.</p> <p>(Sec. 17) The bill requires the GSA to sell, by December 31, 2018, the following property located in the District of Columbia at fair market value at highest and best use: (1) property generally consisting of Squares 325 and 326 and a portion of Square 351 and generally bounded by 12th Street, Independence Avenue, C Street, and the James Forrestal Building in southwest Washington; and (2) property generally consisting of Square 326 south of C Street, including the building known as the Cotton Annex. Any net proceeds of such sale shall be paid into an account in the Federal Buildings Fund and may be expended only subject to a specific future appropriation.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4487v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-03-22">
<action-date>2016-02-08</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Public Buildings Reform and Savings Act of 2016</strong></p> <p>This bill: (1) directs the General Services Administration (GSA) to establish and conduct a pilot program through 2021 to execute lease agreements using alternative procedures to reduce costs of leased space and significantly reduce or eliminate the backlog of expiring leases over the next five years, and (2) authorizes the GSA to submit consolidated prospectuses for leases and projects to Congress for approval.</p> <p>The bill requires approval by congressional resolution of any costs and expenses associated with administering an acquisition by exchange involving real property or in-kind consideration, including services, with a fair market value of $2.85 million or more. </p> <p>The bill authorizes: (1) the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to authorize contract security personnel to carry firearms, and (2) such personnel to detain individuals without a warrant. DHS must&nbsp;establish minimum and uniform training standards for security personnel. </p> <p>DHS must&nbsp;report on: (1) the personnel needs of the Federal Protective Service (FPS), including recommendations on the numbers of FPS law enforcement officers needed to carry out the mission of FPS during the 10-year period after the enactment of this Act; and (2) the best method of funding for the FPS. </p> <p>The GSA must: (1) justify any need for new or replacement building space, including an explanation of why such space could not be consolidated or colocated into other owned or leased space; (2) notify the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure and the Senate Committee on Environment and Public Works if the cost, scope, or size of any project changes by 5% or more; and (3) report to such committees on the justification for using three lease rental caps per fiscal year and their impacts in the National Capital Region. </p> <p>The bill directs the GSA to: (1)&nbsp;sell a portion of the Forrestal Complex in Washington, D.C. to generate funds necessary to construct a new Department of Energy headquarters on government-owned land in a manner consistent with the SW Ecodistrict Plan of the National Capital Planning Commission if the GSA determines that such headquarters can be constructed with no net costs to the government; and (2) consider the direct purchase of energy and other utilities in bulk or otherwise for leased facilities when cost-effective.&nbsp;</p> <p>The bill exempts an individual acquisition for commercial leasing services from enhanced competition requirements for the purchase of property and services by executive agencies if such individual acquisition is made on a no cost basis and pursuant to a multiple award contract in accordance with requirements for full and open competition.</p> <p>The Government Accountability Office must conduct biennial audits of the GSA National Broker Contract, conduct a review of the application of enhanced competition requirements, and report on such audits and reviews. </p> <p>The bill amends the Economic Development Administration Reform Act of 1965 to authorize the Department of Commerce to release the federal government's interest in economic adjustment grants not less than seven years after the final disbursement of the grant. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
