<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1499" measure-id="id114hr1499" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-03-19" update-date="2015-03-26">
<title>Physical Activities Recommendations for Americans Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1499v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-03-26">
<action-date>2015-03-19</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Physical Activities Recommendations for Americans Act of 2015</b></p> <p>This bill requires the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to publish a report at least every 10 years that contains physical activity recommendations for the general public based on the most current scientific and medical knowledge, including information for population subgroups, as needed.</p> <p>HHS must publish updated reports that detail evidence-based practices and highlight continuing physical activity issues between the publications of full reports. Updated reports may focus on particular population subgroups or issues relating to physical activity.</p> A federal agency that proposes to issue physical activity recommendations that differ from the recommendations in the most recent full report must submit the proposed recommendations to HHS for review.]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
