<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5094" measure-id="id114hr5094" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-04-28" update-date="2016-06-30">
<title>STAND for Ukraine Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5094v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-06-30">
<action-date>2016-04-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>S<strong>tability and Democracy for Ukraine Act or the STAND for Ukraine Act</strong></p> <p>This bill provides that no federal agency should take any action or extend any assistance that recognizes Russian sovereignty over Crimea, its airspace, or its territorial waters. </p> <p>The Government Publishing Office should not print any document indicating Crimea as part of the Russian Federation (Russia).</p> <p>U.S. sanctions provided for in Executive Orders 13660, 13661, 13662, (blocking property of persons contributing to the situation in Ukraine) and 13685 (blocking property of persons contributing to the situation in the Crimea region of Ukraine) shall remain in effect until the President certifies to Congress that: </p> <ul> <li>Ukraine's sovereignty over Crimea has been restored, or </li> <li>the status of Crimea has been resolved to the satisfaction of a democratically elected government of Ukraine.</li> </ul> <p>The Support for the Sovereignty, Integrity, Democracy, and Economic Stability of Ukraine Act of 2014 is amended to authorize the President to block and prohibit a foreign person's transactions of property or property interests that are U.S.-sited or controlled by a U.S. person if the foreign person has knowingly: (1) violated such executive orders, or (2) facilitated deceptive or structured transactions for or on behalf of any person subject to U.S. sanctions against Russia. </p> <p>Civil and criminal penalties are prescribed for a person subject to sanctions.</p> <p>The President shall: </p> <ul> <li>use U.S. influence to seek North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) adoption of a policy that opposes the transfer of defense articles and services to Russia while Russia occupies the territory of Ukraine or of a NATO member, and </li> <li>direct appropriate U.S. agencies to monitor and identify transfers by NATO members of defense articles and services to Russia.</li> </ul> <p>A license application or other authorization for the transfer of any defense article or service to or on behalf of a NATO member so identified shall be subject to a presumption of denial. </p> <p>The Sergei Magnitsky Rule of Law Accountability Act of 2012 is amended to include in the list of persons responsible for gross violations of human rights persons committing such actions in any territory forcibly occupied or otherwise controlled by Russia.</p> <p>The Department of State shall seek to establish an international consortium to increase private investment in Ukraine that shall include the United States. </p> <p>It is the sense of Congress that the Broadcasting Board of Governors shall establish Crimean Tatar services (subordinate to the Ukrainian language services) and broadcast Crimean Tatar language content into Crimea.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
