<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4405" measure-id="id114hr4405" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-02-01" update-date="2016-07-18">
<title>Kerry Rose Fire Sprinkler Notification Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4405v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-07-18">
<action-date>2016-02-01</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Kerry Rose Fire Sprinkler Notification Act</b></p> <p>This bill amends title IV (Student Assistance) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to modify fire safety reporting requirements for an institution of higher education (IHE) that participates in federal student aid programs.</p> <p>Specifically, it requires an IHE that maintains on-campus student housing facilities to notify students about whether a housing facility is equipped with a fire safety system, including an automatic fire sprinkler system in each bedroom. </p> <p>Additionally, the bill expands the information an IHE must submit in its annual fire safety report to include, with respect to student housing facilities, the number and percentage of beds protected and not protected by an automatic fire sprinkler system in the bedroom. </p> <p>Finally, the Department of Education must publish the number and percentage, in the aggregate and by state, of: </p> <ul> <li>student housing facilities with less than 100% of beds protected by an automatic sprinkler system, <br /></li> <li>student housing facilities with less than 50% of beds protected, <br /></li> <li>beds at student housing facilities that are protected, and <br /></li> <li>beds at student housing facilities that are not protected. <br /> </li> <blockquote> </blockquote> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
