<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="6001" measure-id="id114hr6001" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-09-13" update-date="2016-10-19">
<title>Smithsonian American Latino Museum Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr6001v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-10-19">
<action-date>2016-09-13</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Smithsonian American Latino Museum Act</b></p> <p> This bill establishes a museum to be known as the Smithsonian American Latino Museum in the Smithsonian Institution. </p> <p> The Arts and Industries Building of the Smithsonian Institution, which is located on the National Mall in Washington, DC, including a new underground annex facility, is designated as the location of the museum. </p> <p> The Board of Regents of the Smithsonian Institution may plan and construct the museum and may prepare a plan of action for the museum. </p> <p> The Secretary of the Interior and the Board of Regents shall enter into an agreement that allows for the construction of the underground annex facility by the Board in a manner that is harmonious with, and protects the open space and visual sight lines of, the National Mall. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
