<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1468" measure-id="id114hr1468" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-03-19" update-date="2015-09-11">
<title>Global Brain Health Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1468v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-09-11">
<action-date>2015-03-19</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p> <strong>Global Brain Health Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>Directs the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) to establish and administer a health and education grant program (Global Autism Assistance Program) to: (1) support activities by nongovernmental organizations and other service providers, including advocacy groups, focused on autism in developing countries; and (2) establish a "teach the teachers" program to train health and education professionals working with autistic children in developing countries.</p> <p> Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to authorize the President to provide assistance to support a network of trained medical practitioners to treat hydrocephalus in children at pediatric hospitals and hydrocephalus treatment centers in developing countries. </p> <p>Requires such assistance to provide for surgeon training and establishment of at least 20 treatment centers. </p> <p> Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to: </p> <ul> <li>negotiate with the World Health Organization to develop a plan for addressing Alzheimer's disease and other forms of dementia globally, to be known as the Global Alzheimer's Disease and Dementia Action Plan; and </li> <li>seek to establish the Global Alzheimer's Disease and Dementia Fund to support implementation of the Global Alzheimer's Disease and Dementia Action Plan. </li> </ul> <p> Expresses the sense of Congress that the Group of Eight (G8) nations, working with the Group of Twenty (G20) nations, the Group of Seventy-Seven (G77) nations, and other organizations should investigate systems to monitor and provide care to individuals with Alzheimer's disease and other forms of dementia in developing countries. </p> <p> Directs the President to: </p> <ul> <li>appoint a high-level official to lead federal efforts to develop the Global Alzheimer's Disease and Dementia Action Plan and the Global Alzheimer's Disease and Dementia Fund, and </li> <li>facilitate partnerships between the federal government and the private sector to identify new treatment approaches for Alzheimer's disease and other forms of dementia.</li> </ul> <p> Directs the Administrator of USAID to investigate the foreign aid implications of Alzheimer's disease and other forms of dementia.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
