<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3948" measure-id="id114hr3948" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-11-05" update-date="2016-09-15">
<title>Student Loan Transfers Disclosure Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3948v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-09-15">
<action-date>2015-11-05</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Student Loan Transfers Disclosure Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Truth in Lending Act and the Higher Education Act of 1965 to establish requirements related to the transfer of servicing of postsecondary&nbsp;education loans. "Transfer of servicing" refers to the assignment, sale, or transfer of student loan servicing from one servicer to another.</p> <p>A postsecondary education lender must disclose to each loan applicant, at the time of application,&nbsp;whether there may be a transfer of servicing of the loan.</p> <p>Both the&nbsp;transferor servicer and the transferee servicer must provide specified notice of a transfer to the borrower within a certain timeframe.</p> <p>Loan payments improperly received by the transferor servicer instead of the transferee servicer (or vice versa) during the transfer period may not be treated as late.</p> <p>A transferee servicer shall make available a simple, online process through which the borrower may transfer any electronic fund transfer authority that the borrower had provided to the transferor servicer.</p> <p>The Consumer Financial Protection Bureau is authorized to establish regulations and grant reasonable exceptions in accordance with the bill. A lender shall not be liable to a borrower for failure to comply with the bill's disclosure and notice requirements with respect to&nbsp;events&nbsp;that occur&nbsp;before such regulations take effect.</p> <p>As a condition of eligibility for certain federal funding, an institution of higher education must ensure compliance with the bill's requirements.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
