<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1055" measure-id="id114hr1055" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-02-25" update-date="2015-08-19">
<title>Comprehensive Dental Reform Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1055v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-08-19">
<action-date>2015-02-25</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Comprehensive Dental Reform Act of 2015</b></p> <p>Amends titles XVIII (Medicare) and XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to cover oral health services. </p> <p>Increases the federal medical assistance percentage for oral health services, thereby increasing payments to states under Medicaid.</p> <p>Directs the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services to maintain a database of dental benefits available to adult Medicaid enrollees in each state.</p> <p>Amends the Public Health Service Act to establish, revise, and extend funding for grant programs for:</p> <ul> <li>educating nondental professionals about oral health care;</li> <li>providing dental services in hospital emergency rooms or in community settings;</li> <li>providing scholarships and education loans for oral health professional students;</li> <li>providing oral health services to low-income and underserved individuals;</li> <li>building, operating, or expanding dental clinics in schools; and</li> <li>providing mobile, comprehensive dental services at locations that serve individuals who qualify for benefits under specified programs.</li> </ul> <p> Authorizes community based dental residencies.</p> <p>Authorizes specified agencies to conduct research on oral health issues through FY2019.</p> <p>Amends the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act to make oral health services an essential health benefit.</p> <p><strong></strong>Removes restrictions on the authority of the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to provide dental care to veterans (thereby requiring dental care on the same basis as other VA-provided medical care and services).</p> <p>Authorizes the VA, Department of Defense, Bureau of Prisons, and Indian Health Service to carry out demonstration programs to train and employ alternative dental health care providers in order to increase access to dental services.</p> <p> <p>Directs the Department of Health and Human Services to conduct a cost-benefit analysis of the expansion of dental service coverage pursuant to this Act.</p> <p>Directs the Government Accountability Office to evaluate the implementation and utilization of expanded dental service coverage under this Act and the demonstration programs authorized by this Act.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
