<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1105" measure-id="id114hr1105" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-02-26" update-date="2015-04-23">
<title>Death Tax Repeal Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1105v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-04-23">
<action-date>2015-04-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Death Tax Repeal Act of 2015 </strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to repeal the estate and generation-skipping transfer taxes for estates of decedents dying or for transfers made on or after the enactment date of this Act. In the case of assets placed in a qualified domestic trust by a decedent who dies prior to the enactment of this Act, the current estate tax will not apply to: (1) distributions from such trust before the death of a surviving spouse made more than 10 years after the enactment date of this Act, and (2) assets remaining in such trust upon the death of the surviving spouse.</p> <p>(Sec. 3) This section revises gift tax rates to lower the top rate to 35% and deems a transfer in trust to be a taxable gift unless the trust is treated as wholly-owned by the donor or the donor's spouse.</p> <p> The lifetime exemption for gifts is set at $5 million with a cost-of-living adjustment for calendar years beginning after 2011. The adjusted exemption amount in 2015 is $5.43 million.</p> <p>(Sec. 4) The budgetary effects of this Act are exempted from entry on either PAYGO scorecard maintained under the Statutory Pay-As-You-Go Act of 2010. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1105v17" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-04-14">
<action-date>2015-04-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Death Tax Repeal Act of 2015 </strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to repeal the estate and generation-skipping transfer taxes for estates of decedents dying or for transfers made on or after the enactment date of this Act. In the case of assets placed in a qualified domestic trust by a decedent who dies prior to the enactment of this Act, the current estate tax will not apply to: (1) distributions from such trust before the death of a surviving spouse made more than 10 years after the enactment date of this Act, and (2) assets remaining in such trust upon the death of the surviving spouse.</p> <p>(Sec. 3) This section revises gift tax rates to lower the top rate to 35% and deems a transfer in trust to be a taxable gift unless the trust is treated as wholly-owned by the donor or the donor's spouse.</p> <p> The lifetime exemption for gifts is set at $5 million with a cost-of-living adjustment for calendar years beginning after 2011. The adjusted exemption amount in 2015 is $5.43 million.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1105v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-04-01">
<action-date>2015-02-26</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Death Tax Repeal Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) repeal the estate and generation-skipping transfer taxes, and (2) make permanent the maximum 35% gift tax rate and the lifetime gift tax exemption. Provides for an inflation adjustment to such exemption amount.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
