<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="329" measure-id="id114hr329" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-01-13" update-date="2015-08-04">
<title>Indian Employment, Training and Related Services Consolidation Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr329v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-08-04">
<action-date>2015-01-13</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Indian Employment, Training and Related Services Consolidation Act of 2015 </b></p> <p> Amends the Indian Employment, Training and Related Services Demonstration Act of 1992 to make revisions to the program that provides for the integration of employment, training, and related services programs from federal funds.</p> <p>  <p> <p> Revises the types of programs that may be integrated pursuant to an approved integration plan. </p> <p>Directs the Government Accountability Office to assess the programs of specified departments, and develop an inventory of all programs of those departments that may be integrated. </p>  <p> Sets forth requirements regarding the granting or denial of an Indian tribe's request to waive any applicable statutory, regulatory, or administrative requirements or waive federal agency policies or procedures necessary to efficiently implement the plan. </p> <p> <p> Prescribes certain hearing and appeal rights for an Indian tribe if the Department of the Interior denies its plan. </p> <p> Revises the authority of tribes to use funds available for a plan to place participants in training positions with employers. </p> <p> Revises the responsibilities of the Director of the Bureau of Indian Affairs (BIA) in carrying out this Act to include: </p><ul> <li>the distribution of the funds to the respective Indian tribes by no later than 45 days after the receipt of the funds from the appropriate federal department or agency, </li> <li>the performance of the activities relating to agency waivers, and </li> <li>the establishment of an interagency dispute resolution process. <p> </li> </ul> <p>Prohibits the BIA from developing a reporting format that requires a participating tribe to report on the expenditure of funds transferred to the tribe under the Act. </p> <p> <p>Treats any funds transferred to an Indian tribe under the Act as non-federal funds for purposes of meeting matching requirements under any other federal law. </p> <p>Applies civil liability limitations to plans approved under the Act. </p> <p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
