<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5018" measure-id="id114hr5018" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-04-21" update-date="2016-05-11">
<title>Elder Protection and Abuse Prevention Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5018v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-05-11">
<action-date>2016-04-21</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Elder Protection and Abuse Prevention Act </b></p> <p>This bill amends the Older Americans Act of 1965 to direct the Administration on Aging of the Department of Health and Human Services to: (1) ensure that all programs funded under such Act include appropriate training in elder abuse prevention and services addressing elder justice and exploitation; and (2) update periodically the need for such training related to prevention of abuse, neglect, and exploitation (including financial exploitation) of older adults.</p> <p>The Administration has a duty and function to: (1) establish priority information and assistance services for older individuals; and (2) develop a National Eldercare Locator Service, with a nationwide toll free number.</p> <p>The Administration shall establish a National Adult Protective Services Resources Center.</p> <p>Each area plan shall provide that the area agency on aging: (1) increases public awareness of elder abuse and financial exploitation, and removes barriers to elder abuse education, prevention, investigation, and treatment; and (2) reports instances of elder abuse.</p> <p>The Administration shall make grants to states with approved plans for elder abuse and neglect screening.</p> <p>A state operating a nutrition project shall encourage distributors of nutrition services to distribute information on diabetes, elder abuse, neglect, financial exploitation, and the annual Medicare wellness exam.</p> <p>A state, an area agency on aging, a nonprofit organization, or a tribal organization shall use a grant for an older individuals' protection from violence project to replicate successful prevention and training models.</p> <p>The Administration shall award grants to and contract with eligible organizations for projects to engage volunteers over age 50 in supporting older adults (and their families or caretakers) who have experienced or are at risk of elder abuse.</p> <p>A state may use funds under the National Family Caregiver Support Program to support the Office of the State Long-Term Care Ombudsman.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
