<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3273" measure-id="id114hr3273" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-07-29" update-date="2015-09-04">
<title>Prohibiting Assistance to Nuclear Iran Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3273v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-09-04">
<action-date>2015-07-29</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Prohibiting Assistance to Nuclear Iran Act</strong></p> <p>This bill prohibits the use of federal funds to provide Iran with assistance (including the use of the U.S. Armed Forces) to develop, use, or protect any technology or other assets of its nuclear program. </p> <p>The President may waive such prohibition on a case-by-case basis if: (1) the President submits to Congress a certification that it is necessary to U.S. national interests to do so, and (2) Congress enacts a joint resolution approving such certification within five days of its submission.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
