<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3212" measure-id="id114hr3212" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-07-23" update-date="2016-09-15">
<title>To amend the Grand Ronde Reservation Act to make technical corrections, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3212v17" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-09-15">
<action-date>2016-07-25</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill amends the Grand Ronde Reservation Act to permit the Department of the Interior to accept real property located within the boundaries of the original 1857 reservation of the Confederated Tribes of the Grand Ronde Community of Oregon (comprising land within Polk and Yamhill Counties) that is transferred to the United States by or on behalf of the tribes. </p> <p>Interior must treat applications to take land into trust within the boundaries of the original 1857 reservation as on-reservation trust acquisitions. Gaming is prohibited on such real property taken into trust, except for real property within two miles of a specified gaming facility. All real property taken into trust within those boundaries after September 9, 1988, is part of the tribes' reservation.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3212v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-08-19">
<action-date>2015-07-23</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Authorizes the Department of the Interior to accept title to any additional number of acres of real property located within the boundaries of the original 1857 reservation of the Confederated Tribes of the Grand Ronde Community of Oregon (comprising land within the political boundaries of Polk and Yamhill Counties, Oregon), if such real property is conveyed or otherwise transferred to the United States by or on behalf of the Tribe. </p> <p>States that: (1) Interior shall treat applications to take land into trust within the boundaries of the original 1857 reservation as an on-reservation trust acquisition; (2) the real property taken into trust is not to be eligible, or used, for certain gaming, except for real property within two miles of a specified gaming facility; and (3) all real property taken into trust within those boundaries after September 9, 1988, shall be part of the Tribe's reservation.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
