<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5703" measure-id="id114hr5703" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-07-08" update-date="2016-10-13">
<title>Diversity in Military Leadership Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5703v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-10-13">
<action-date>2016-07-08</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Diversity in Military Leadership Act</strong></p> <p>This bill authorizes the Department of Defense (DOD) to award grants to entities to increase the participation of women and underrepresented minorities in DOD military and civilian leadership positions by carrying out: (1) online interactive workshops, (2) student mentoring programs with Armed Forces members and DOD officers and employees, (3) internships, and (4) outreach programs for elementary and secondary school students.</p> <p>The term &quot;minority&quot; means American Indian, Alaskan Native, Black (not of Hispanic origin), Hispanic (including persons of Mexican, Puerto Rican, Cuban, and Central or South American origin), Asian (including underrepresented subgroups), Native Hawaiian, Pacific Islander origin subgroup, or other ethnic group underrepresented in science and engineering.</p> <p>The term &quot;underrepresented minority&quot; means a minority group whose numbers in DOD military and civilian leadership positions per 10,000 population of that group is substantially below the comparable figure for DOD military and civilian leaders who are White and not of Hispanic origin. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
