<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4982" measure-id="id114hr4982" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-04-18" update-date="2016-06-10">
<title>Examining Opioid Treatment Infrastructure Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4982v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-06-10">
<action-date>2016-05-11</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the House on May 10, 2016. The summary of that version is repeated here.)</p> <p><b>Examining Opioid Treatment Infrastructure Act of 2016</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill requires the Government Accountability Office to report on inpatient and outpatient treatment capacity, availability, and needs, including detoxification programs, clinical stabilization programs, transitional residential support services, rehabilitation programs, treatment programs for pregnant women or adolescents, and treatment through Indian health programs. The report must include the barriers to real-time reporting of drug overdoses at the federal, state, and local level and ways to overcome those barriers.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4982v17" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-06-08">
<action-date>2016-05-10</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Examining Opioid Treatment Infrastructure Act of 2016</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill requires the Government Accountability Office to report on inpatient and outpatient treatment capacity, availability, and needs, including detoxification programs, clinical stabilization programs, transitional residential support services, rehabilitation programs, treatment programs for pregnant women or adolescents, and treatment through Indian health programs. The report must include the barriers to real-time reporting of drug overdoses at the federal, state, and local level and ways to overcome those barriers.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4982v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-05-09">
<action-date>2016-04-18</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Examining Opioid Treatment Infrastructure Act of 2016</b></p> This bill requires the Government Accountability Office to report on inpatient and outpatient treatment capacity, availability, and needs, including detoxification programs, clinical stabilization programs, transitional residential support services, rehabilitation programs, and treatment programs for pregnant women or adolescents.]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
