<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4699" measure-id="id114hr4699" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-03-03" update-date="2016-04-01">
<title>Working Parents Flexibility Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4699v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-04-01">
<action-date>2016-03-03</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Working Parents Flexibility Act of 2016</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to establish a tax-exempt parental leave savings account for the care of a child, to which an individual taxpayer who has earned income from employment during the past 12 months may make tax deductible cash contributions of up to $6,750 in a taxable year and not more than an aggregate of &nbsp;$24,000 for all taxable years. Taxpayers whose adjusted gross income exceeds $250,000 in a taxable year are ineligible for such a tax deduction. </p> <p>The bill excludes from gross income: (1) distributions from a parental leave savings account that are made not later than one year after the birth or adoption of a child of an account holder, and (2) contributions made by an employer to the parental leave savings account of an employee.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
