<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3460" measure-id="id114hr3460" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-09-09" update-date="2015-09-17">
<title>To suspend until January 21, 2017, the authority of the President to waive, suspend, reduce, provide relief from, or otherwise limit the application of sanctions pursuant to an agreement related to the nuclear program of Iran.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3460v81" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-09-17">
<action-date>2015-09-11</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p>(Sec. 1) This bill prohibits the President, prior to January 21, 2017, from: </p> <ul> <li>limiting the application of specified sanctions on Iran or refraining from applying any such sanctions; or </li> <li>removing a foreign person (including entities) listed in Attachments 3 or 4 to Annex II of the Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action (JCPA) from the list of designated nationals and blocked persons maintained by the Office of Foreign Assets Control of the Department of the Treasury. </li> </ul> <p>The sanctions are those contained in: </p> <ul> <li>sections 4 through 7.9 of Annex II of the JCPA; and </li> <li>any other agreement related to Iran's nuclear program that includes the United States, commits the United States to take action, or pursuant to which the United States commits or otherwise agrees to take action, regardless of the form it takes, whether a political commitment or otherwise, and regardless of whether the agreement is legally binding or not.</li> </ul> <p>The Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action is the agreement signed at Vienna on July 14, 2015, by Iran and by China, France, Germany, the Russian Federation, the United Kingdom, and the United States, with the High Representative of the European Union for Foreign Affairs and Security Policy, and all implementing materials and agreements related to the JCPA.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3460v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-09-11">
<action-date>2015-09-09</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill prohibits the President, prior to January 21, 2017, from: </p> <ul> <li>limiting the application of specified sanctions on Iran or refraining from applying any such sanctions; or </li> <li>removing a foreign person (including entities) listed in Attachments 3 or 4 to Annex II of the Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action (JCPA) from the list of designated nationals and blocked persons maintained by the Office of Foreign Assets Control of the Department of the Treasury. </li> </ul> <p>The sanctions are those contained in: </p> <ul> <li>sections 4 through 7.9 of Annex II of the JCPA; and </li> <li>any other agreement related to Iran's nuclear program that includes the United States, commits the United States to take action, or pursuant to which the United States commits or otherwise agrees to take action, regardless of the form it takes, whether a political commitment or otherwise, and regardless of whether the agreement is legally binding or not.</li> </ul> <p>The Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action is the agreement signed at Vienna on July 14, 2015, by Iran and by China, France, Germany, the Russian Federation, the United Kingdom, and the United States, with the High Representative of the European Union for Foreign Affairs and Security Policy, and all implementing materials and agreements related to the JCPA.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
