<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3006" measure-id="id114hr3006" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-07-09" update-date="2015-10-19">
<title>Helping Save Americans' Health Care Choices Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3006v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-10-19">
<action-date>2015-07-09</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Helping Save Americans' Health Care Choices Act of 2015 </strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code, with respect to health savings accounts (HSAs), to: </p> <ul> <li>eliminate the requirement that a participant in an HSA be enrolled in a high deductible health care plan;</li> <li>increase the maximum contribution amount to an HSA;</li> <li>permit both spouses in an HSA to make catch-up contributions to the same account;</li> <li>allow the use of HSAs&nbsp;to pay health insurance premiums and long-term care insurance premiums;</li> <li>treat fees paid in advance for the right to receive medical services as a deductible medical expense;</li> <li>permit Medicare recipients to participate in HSAs;</li> <li>repeal the restriction on payments from HSAs for nonprescription drugs;</li> <li>repeal the additional tax on distributions from HSAs and Archer Medical Savings Accounts; and </li> <li>repeal the $2,500 limitation on salary reduction contributions to a health flexible spending arrangement under a cafeteria plan. </li></ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
