<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2676" measure-id="id114hr2676" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-06-04" update-date="2015-07-08">
<title>Build America Bonds Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2676v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-07-08">
<action-date>2015-06-04</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Build America Bonds Act of 2015</strong></p> <p> Amends the Internal Revenue Code, with respect to build America bonds,&nbsp;to: (1) make permanent the issuance authority for such bonds&nbsp;and the authority for payments to bond issuers, (2) make phased reductions in the credit percentage to bondholders and in the&nbsp;percentage of payments to issuers of such bonds, (3) make federal wage rate and other grant requirements applicable to such bonds, (4) allow refundings of currently-issued bonds, and (5) allow the use of such bonds to fund capital expenditures for levees and flood control projects.</p> Provides for an increase in payments to issuers of build America bonds to compensate for reductions in the amount of such payments due to sequestration.]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
