<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3057" measure-id="id114hr3057" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-07-14" update-date="2015-09-23">
<title>EAT for Health Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3057v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-09-23">
<action-date>2015-07-14</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Education and Training for Health Act of 2015 or the EAT for Health Act of 2015</strong></p> <p> Directs the Department of Health and Human Services to issue guidelines to federal agencies for developing procedures and requirements to ensure that every primary care health professional employed full-time for such agencies have continuing education courses relating to nutrition. Requires each agency to report to Congress annually on the extent to which it has adopted and encouraged such guidelines for such primary care professionals it employed during any portion of the previous year.</p> <p>Requires such courses to: (1) include content on the role of nutrition in the prevention, management, and reversal of obesity, cardiovascular disease, diabetes, or cancer; and (2) meet requirements for Continuing Medical Education or Continuing Education by medical or nurse practitioner professional organizations or certified accrediting bodies.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
