<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1808" measure-id="id114hr1808" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-04-15" update-date="2015-06-16">
<title>Tax Cuts for America Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1808v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-06-16">
<action-date>2015-04-15</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Tax Cuts for America Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>This bill extends through 2015 the following expiring tax provisions: </p> <ul> <li>the new markets tax credit,</li> <li>the work opportunity tax credit,</li> <li>the research tax credit,</li> <li>the tax deduction for certain expenses of elementary and secondary school teachers,</li> <li>the tax credit for differential wage payments to employees who are active duty members of the Uniformed Services,</li> <li>the tax credit for new energy efficient homes, and </li> <li>the tax deduction for state and local sales taxes in lieu of state and local income taxes. </li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
