<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2032" measure-id="id114hr2032" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-04-27" update-date="2015-06-03">
<title>GSA Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2032v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-06-03">
<action-date>2015-04-27</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Government Spending Accountability Act of 2015 or the GSA Act of 2015</strong> </p> <p> Requires each federal agency to post on its public website detailed information on employee presentations at conferences, including: (1) the prepared text of any verbal presentation; and (2) any visual, digital, video, or audio materials presented, including photographs, slides, and audio-visual recordings.</p> <p>Limits to $500,000 the amount that any agency may spend to support a single conference. Allows an agency head to waive such limitation for a specific conference after making a determination that a higher expenditure is justified as the most cost-effective option to achieve a compelling purpose.</p> <p>Prohibits an agency from paying the travel expenses for more than 50 employees stationed in the United States to attend any international conference, unless the Secretary of State determines that attendance of more than 50 employees is in the national interest, or the agency head determines that the attendance of such employees is critical to the agency's mission. </p> <p>Requires each agency to post on its public website quarterly reports on each conference costing more than $10,000 for which the agency paid travel expenses during the preceding three months.</p> <p>Limits agency travel expenses for FY2016-FY2020 to 70% of the aggregate amount of such expenses for FY2010. Requires the Office of Management and Budget to establish guidelines for determining what expenses constitute travel expenses for purposes of the ceiling imposed on such expenses. Exempts from such limitation military travel expenses. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
