<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3918" measure-id="id114hr3918" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-11-04" update-date="2015-11-16">
<title>Strengthen Employment And Seasonal Opportunities Now (SEASON) Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3918v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-11-16">
<action-date>2015-11-04</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Strengthen Employment And Seasonal Opportunities Now (SEASON) Act</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to provide, effective as if enacted on January 1, 2015, that a returning H-2B visa alien (temporary nonagricultural worker) who has already been counted toward the applicable numerical limitation during one of the three preceding fiscal years: (1) shall not again be counted toward such limitation during a fiscal year, but (2) shall be considered a returning worker. </p> <p> &quot;Other temporary service or labor&quot; for H-2B purposes means that an employer's need for labor will not exceed 1 year and is a seasonal (not to exceed 10 months), peak load, or intermittent need, unless it is a one-time occurrence not exceeding 3 years. </p> <p> An H-2B employer shall file an employee petition with the Department of Homeland Security. Additional filings with the Department of Labor are not required. </p> <p> H-2B employer requirements are set forth regarding: (1) petitions, (2) admissions and maximum stay in status, (3) housing, (4) enforcement, (5) transportation, (6) recruitment, (7) U.S. worker protections, and (8) wages. </p> <p> An H-2B worker shall not be entitled to: (1) tax credit assistance for a qualified health plan, and shall be subject to plan rules applicable to individuals not lawfully present in the United States; (2) the child tax credit; and (3) the earned income tax credit.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
