<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5104" measure-id="id114hr5104" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-04-28" update-date="2016-10-04">
<title>BOTS Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5104v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-10-04">
<action-date>2016-09-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the House on September 9, 2016. The summary of that version is repeated here.)</p> <p><b>Better On-line Ticket Sales Act of 2016 or the BOTS Act</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill prohibits the sale of computer software that: (1) is primarily designed to circumvent technology that limits purchases made via an online ticket selling system, (2) has only a limited commercially significant purpose other than for such circumvention, or (3) is marketed to use for such circumvention.</p> <p>The bill also prohibits the use of such circumvention software in violation of a system operator's posted limits on: (1) the quantity of tickets purchased by a single user; (2) the sequence, number, or frequency of transactions; or (3) the geographic location of transactions. </p> <p>In addition, the bill makes it unlawful to resell in commerce tickets that were acquired through such a prohibited use of circumvention software if the reseller participated in, had the ability to control, or should have known about the violation.</p> <p>It shall not be unlawful, however, to create or use software to: (1) investigate or further the enforcement or defense of any alleged violation of this bill, or (2) identify and analyze flaws and vulnerabilities of a computerized event ticketing system if these activities are conducted to advance the state of knowledge in the field of computer system security or to assist in the development of computer security products.</p> <p>Violations shall be treated as unfair and deceptive acts or practices under the Federal Trade Commission Act.</p> <p>The Federal Trade Commission and state attorneys general may enforce against violations.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5104v17" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-10-04">
<action-date>2016-09-09</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Better On-line Ticket Sales Act of 2016 or the BOTS Act</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill prohibits the sale of computer software that: (1) is primarily designed to circumvent technology that limits purchases made via an online ticket selling system, (2) has only a limited commercially significant purpose other than for such circumvention, or (3) is marketed to use for such circumvention.</p> <p>The bill also prohibits the use of such circumvention software in violation of a system operator's posted limits on: (1) the quantity of tickets purchased by a single user; (2) the sequence, number, or frequency of transactions; or (3) the geographic location of transactions. </p> <p>In addition, the bill makes it unlawful to resell in commerce tickets that were acquired through such a prohibited use of circumvention software if the reseller participated in, had the ability to control, or should have known about the violation.</p> <p>It shall not be unlawful, however, to create or use software to: (1) investigate or further the enforcement or defense of any alleged violation of this bill, or (2) identify and analyze flaws and vulnerabilities of a computerized event ticketing system if these activities are conducted to advance the state of knowledge in the field of computer system security or to assist in the development of computer security products.</p> <p>Violations shall be treated as unfair and deceptive acts or practices under the Federal Trade Commission Act.</p> <p>The Federal Trade Commission and state attorneys general may enforce against violations.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5104v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-05-25">
<action-date>2016-04-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Better On-line Ticket Sales Act of 2016 or the BOTS Act</b></p> <p>This bill prohibits: (1) intentionally using or selling software to circumvent a security measure, access control system, or other control or measure on a ticket seller's Internet website that is used by the seller to ensure equitable consumer access to tickets for any given event; or (2) selling any ticket in interstate commerce knowingly obtained in violation of such prohibition.</p> <p>The Federal Trade Commission shall enforce against violations of such prohibitions, which shall be treated as unfair or deceptive acts or practices under the Federal Trade Commission Act. A person who suffers injury as a result of a violation of these prohibitions may bring a civil action for damages plus $1,000 for each distinct use or sale of software, or sale of a ticket, that caused such injury and reasonable attorney's fees. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
