<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5153" measure-id="id114hr5153" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-04-29" update-date="2016-06-14">
<title>FISA COURT Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5153v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-06-14">
<action-date>2016-04-29</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>FISA Court Oversight Underscoring Responsibility and Transparency Act or the FISA COURT Act </b></p> <p>This bill amends the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 to require that the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court consist of 11 publicly designated district court judges, of whom: </p> <ul> <li>2 judges are designated by the President;</li> <li> 1 judge is designated by a majority of the Supreme Court; and</li> <li>2 judges each are designated, respectively, by the Speaker of the House of Representatives, the minority leader of the House of Representatives, and the majority and minority leaders of the Senate.</li> </ul> <p>(Currently, the Chief Justice designates all 11 judges.)</p> <p>A majority of the Supreme Court (currently, the Chief Justice alone) shall designate three judges from the U.S. district courts or courts of appeals who shall comprise the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court of Review.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
