<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1715" measure-id="id114hr1715" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-03-26" update-date="2015-04-13">
<title>Executive Amnesty Prevention Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1715v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-04-13">
<action-date>2015-03-26</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Executive Amnesty Prevention Act</strong></p> <p>This bill prohibits the use of funds to implement specified memoranda from the President, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Director of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE), or other related memoranda. </p> <p>No deposit in the Immigration Examinations Fee Account may be used to implement, administer, or enforce the policies in such memoranda. </p> <p>Such memoranda or substantially similar policy changes are declared to have no statutory or constitutional basis and therefore no legal effect. </p> <p>No funds or fees made available to the Secretary or to any federal official may be used to grant any federal benefit to any alien pursuant to any of such policy changes. </p> <p>The Immigration and Nationality Act is amended to: (1) exclude from the definition of "unauthorized alien," with respect to employment, any alien otherwise admitted to and lawfully present in the United States; and (2) consider any alien without lawful status to be an unauthorized alien whose employment is unlawful.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
