<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2085" measure-id="id114hr2085" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-04-29" update-date="2015-07-18">
<title>To direct the Secretary of the Interior to enter into negotiations with interested local water and power providers for the transfer of ownership, control, and operation of the New Melones Unit, Central Valley Project, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2085v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-07-18">
<action-date>2015-04-29</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Directs the Department of the Interior to: (1) enter into negotiations for the transfer of ownership, control, and operation of the New Melones Unit, Central Valley Project to interested local water and power providers within California; (2) report to specified congressional committees every six months on such negotiations, on actions Interior recommends the United States take to finalize an agreement for such transfer, and on the terms of any agreement reached; and (3) transfer such Unit in accordance with such an agreement.</p> <p>Defines: (1) the &quot;New Melones Unit, Central Valley Project&quot; to mean all federal reclamation projects located within or diverting water from or to the watershed of the Stanislaus and San Joaquin rivers and their tributaries; and (2) &quot;interested local water and power providers&quot; to include the Calaveras County Water District, Central San Joaquin Water Conservation District, Modesto Irrigation District, Oakdale Irrigation District, Stockton East Water District, South San Joaquin Irrigation District, Tuolumne Utilities District, Turlock Irrigation District, and Union Public Utilities District.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
