<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4164" measure-id="id114hr4164" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-12-02" update-date="2016-02-01">
<title>Regulatory Agency Demilitarization Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4164v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-02-01">
<action-date>2015-12-02</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Regulatory Agency Demilitarization Act</strong></p> <p> This bill prohibits a federal agency from purchasing or using a firearm. The bill excludes the Departments of Defense, Justice, and Homeland Security, the military departments, the Nuclear Regulatory Commission, the U.S. Capitol Police, the Bureau of Diplomatic Security, and the Central Intelligence Agency.</p> <p>The Government Accountability Office shall submit to Congress, within 18 months after this Act's enactment, a report that includes:</p> <ul> <li>information regarding each federal agency that has specialized units that receive special tactical or military-style training or use hard-plated body armor, shields, or helmets and that respond to high-risk situations that fall outside the capabilities of regular law enforcement officers; </li> <li>a description of each such unit; </li> <li>a description of the training and weapons of each such unit; </li> <li>the criteria for activating each such unit and how often each such unit was activated for each of the previous ten years; </li> <li>the annual cost of equipping and operating each such unit; and </li> <li>any other information that is relevant to understanding the usefulness and justification for the units. </li></ul> <p>The bill amends the Inspector General Act of 1978 to repeal provisions authorizing law enforcement powers for an Inspector General, any Assistant Inspector General for Investigations under an Inspector General, and any special agent supervised by such an Assistant Inspector General.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
