<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2971" measure-id="id114hr2971" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-07-08" update-date="2015-08-18">
<title>Highway Trust Fund Certainty Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2971v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-08-18">
<action-date>2015-07-08</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Highway Trust Fund Certainty Act </strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) increase the current excise tax rates on gasoline and diesel fuel or kerosene and special fuels and to repeal the reversion of increased fuel tax rates to 4.3 cents per gallon after September 30, 2016, (2) make permanent the excise tax on certain alcohol fuels and fuels used in certain buses, (3) allow U.S. citizens a new tax credit after 2015 for the lesser of 3.1% of earned income or $133, and (4) allow additional appropriations to the Highway and Mass Transit Accounts of the Highway Trust Fund and provide for repayments from such Fund to the general fund of the Treasury for amounts advanced to such Fund. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
