<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2578" measure-id="id114hr2578" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-27" update-date="2016-01-07">
<title>Commerce, Justice, Science, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2578v01" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-01-07">
<action-date>2015-06-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to Senate amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Highlights: </b></p> <p>The Commerce, Justice, Science, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2016 provides FY2016 appropriations to the Department of Commerce, the Department of Justice (DOJ), science agencies, and several related agencies. </p> <p>The bill funds agencies with a wide range of responsibilities for issues such as: addressing violent crime, drug trafficking, financial fraud, terrorism, espionage, and cybercrime; conducting the census; forecasting the weather; managing fisheries; exploring space; advancing science; providing legal services for the poor; enforcing employment discrimination laws; and overseeing patents, trademarks, and trade policy. </p> <p>The bill increases overall FY2016 Commerce, Justice, Science and Related Agencies funding above FY2015 levels, including increases for the Department of Commerce, DOJ, science programs, and Related Agencies. </p> <p>Within the Department of Commerce budget, the bill includes:</p> <ul> <li> increases for the Bureau of Industry and Security, the Bureau of the Census, and the National Institute of Standards and Technology; and </li> <li>decreases for the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration and Departmental Management. </li> </ul> <p>Within the DOJ budget, the bill includes: </p> <ul> <li>increases for Legal Activities, the U.S. Marshals Service, the Federal Bureau of Investigation, the Federal Prison System, and Community Oriented Policing Services (COPS); and </li> <li> decreases for the Office on Violence Against Women and Office of Justice Programs, including State and Local Law Enforcement Assistance. </li> </ul> <p>For science programs, the bill increases funding for the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) and funds the National Science Foundation and the Office of Science and Technology Policy at or slightly below FY2015 levels. </p> <p>The bill includes increases for the Legal Services Corporation and the Marine Mammal Commission, while funding the other related agencies included in the bill at the FY2015 level. </p> <p>The bill includes provisions that restrict or prohibit the use of funds for: </p> <ul> <li>the transfer of Guantanamo detainees or the construction of a new facility in the United States to house them; </li> <li>the enforcement of certain restrictions on firearms; and</li> <li>preventing states from implementing their own laws legalizing medical marijuana. </li> </ul> <p><b>Full Summary: </b></p> <p><b>Commerce, Justice, Science, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2016 </b></p> <p>Provides FY2016 appropriations for the Department of Commerce, the Department of Justice (DOJ), science agencies, and several related agencies. </p> <p><i>Department of Commerce Appropriations Act, 2016 </i></p> <p>TITLE I--DEPARTMENT OF COMMERCE</p> <p> Provides appropriations to the Department of Commerce for: </p> <ul> <li> the International Trade Administration, </li> <li>the Office of the U.S. Trade Representative, </li> <li>the Bureau of Industry and Security, </li> <li>the Economic Development Administration, </li> <li>the Minority Business Development Agency, </li> <li> Economic and Statistical Analysis, </li> <li>the Bureau of the Census, </li> <li>the National Telecommunications and Information Administration, and </li> <li>the U.S. Patent and Trademark Office. </li> </ul> <p>Provides appropriations for the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST), including: Scientific and Technical Research and Services, Industrial Technology Services, and Construction of Research Facilities. </p> <p>Provides appropriations for the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), including: </p> <ul> <li> Operations, Research, and Facilities; </li> <li>Procurement, Acquisition, and Construction; </li> <li>Pacific Coastal Salmon Recovery; </li> <li>the Fishermen's Contingency Fund; and </li> <li>the Fisheries Finance Program Account. </li> </ul> <p>Provides appropriations for Departmental Management, including Salaries and Expenses and the Office of Inspector General. </p> <p>(Sec. 101) Permits funds provided by this bill to be used for advanced payments (prior to the receipt of goods, services, or other assets) only if designated Commerce officials certify that the payments are in the public interest. </p> <p>(Sec. 102) Permits funds provided by this bill to be used for hiring passenger motor vehicles, employment of temporary or intermittent experts and consultants, and the purchase of uniforms. </p> <p>(Sec. 103) Permits the transfer of funds between Commerce accounts, subject to specified limitations and requirements. Requires Commerce to notify Congress prior to the acquisition or disposal of any capital asset not provided for in an Act providing appropriations to Commerce. </p> <p>(Sec. 104) Extends requirements for NOAA to make and report to Congress on determinations regarding the identification and management of technical, cost, and schedule risk; the reliance on demonstrated technologies; and compliance with relevant policies, prior to entering into a contract for a major program with a life cycle cost of more than $250 million. </p> <p>Specifies the life cycle costs for the Joint Polar Satellite System and for the Geostationary Operational Environmental Satellite R-Series Program. </p> <p>(Sec. 105) Permits Commerce to furnish services to facilitate the use or occupancy of Department of Commerce buildings. </p> <p>(Sec. 106) States that grant recipients may continue to deter child pornography, copyright infringement, or any other unlawful activity over their networks. </p> <p>(Sec. 107) Permits NOAA to use, with consent and reimbursement, resources of other federal, state, local, and international entities to carry out the responsibilities of any statute administered by NOAA. </p> <p>(Sec. 108) Prohibits funds from being used to enforce or carry out activities under the Foreign Trade Zone regulation requiring uniform treatment for zone participants. </p> <p>(Sec. 109) Prohibits Commerce from using funds to manage fisheries in the Gulf of Mexico, unless the management activities are subject to state boundaries that are nine nautical miles seaward from the baseline from which the territorial sea of the United States is measured. </p> <p>(Sec. 110) Prohibits the National Technical Information Service from charging for copies of reports or documents generated by the legislative branch unless the Service has provided information on how a copy may be obtained for free online. Requires any charge to be limited to the Service's cost. </p> <p>(Sec. 111) Permits NOAA to work with federal and non-federal agencies and governments by entering into agreements; using land, services, equipment, personnel, and facilities provided by the entities; or receiving and expending funds made available on a consensual basis. </p> <p>(Sec. 112) Permits Commerce to waive the requirement for bonds with respect to contracts for the construction, alteration, or repair of vessels under the Coast and Geodetic Survey Act of 1947. </p> <p>(Sec. 113) Permits the Bureau of Economic Analysis and the Bureau of the Census to use funds to enter into cooperative agreements to assist in improving statistical methodology and research.</p> <p><i>Department of Justice Appropriations Act, 2016</i> </p> <p>TITLE II--DEPARTMENT OF JUSTICE </p> <p>Provides FY2016 appropriations to the Department of Justice (DOJ) for: </p> <ul> <li>General Administration, including Salaries and Expenses, Justice Information Sharing Technology, Administrative Review and Appeals, and the Office of Inspector General; </li> <li>the U.S. Parole Commission; </li> <li>Legal Activities, including General Legal Activities, the Antitrust Division, U.S. Attorneys, the U.S. Trustee System Fund, the Foreign Claims Settlement Commission, Fees and Expenses of Witnesses, the Community Relations Service, and the Assets Forfeiture Fund;</li> <li>the U.S. Marshals Services, including for Construction and Federal Prisoner Detention;</li> <li>the National Security Division; </li> <li>Interagency Law Enforcement; </li> <li>the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI); </li> <li>the Drug Enforcement Administration (DEA); </li> <li>the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives (ATF); and </li> <li>the Federal Prison System, including for Buildings and Facilities and Federal Prison Industries, Incorporated. </li> </ul> <p>Provide appropriations to the Office On Violence Against Women for Violence Against Women Prevention and Prosecution Programs. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Office of Justice Programs for: Research, Evaluation, and Statistics; State and Local Law Enforcement Assistance; Juvenile Justice Programs; and Public Safety Officer Benefits. </p> <p>Provides appropriations for Community Oriented Policing Services (COPS) programs. </p> <p>(Sec. 201) Provides additional funds to the Attorney General for official reception and representation expenses. </p> <p>(Sec. 202) Prohibits funds provided by this title from being used to pay for an abortion, except where the life of the mother would be endangered if the fetus were carried to term, or in the case of rape. </p> <p>(Sec. 203) Prohibits funds provided by this title from being used to require any person to perform or facilitate the performance of an abortion. </p> <p>(Sec. 204) Establishes the obligation of the Director of the Bureau of Prisons to provide escort services to an inmate receiving an abortion outside of a federal facility, except where this obligation conflicts with section 203 of this bill. </p> <p>(Sec. 205) Sets forth requirements and procedures for transferring and reprogramming DOJ funds provided by this bill.</p> <p>(Sec. 206) Permits the Attorney General to use specified ATF funds for retention pay for employees who would otherwise be subject to a pay reduction upon termination of the Personnel Management Demonstration Project. </p> <p>(Sec. 207) Prohibits the FBI or the U.S. Marshals Services from using funds provided by this title to transport prisoners classified as maximum or high security, other than to a facility certified by the Bureau of Prisons as appropriately secure. </p> <p>(Sec. 208) Prohibits federal prisons from using funds provided by this bill to purchase or rent audiovisual equipment, services, and materials used primarily for recreational purposes, except for inmate training, religious, or educational purposes. </p> <p>(Sec. 209) Prohibits funds provided by this title from being used for major information technology projects unless the Deputy Attorney General and the Department Investment Review Board certify to Congress that the program: (1) has appropriate program management controls and contractor oversight mechanisms in place, and (2) is compatible with DOJ enterprise architecture. </p> <p>(Sec. 210) Requires DOJ to follow reprogramming procedures for any deviation from the program amounts specified in this title or the accompanying report, or any use of deobligated funds provided by this title in previous years. </p> <p>(Sec. 211) Prohibits the use of funds provided by this bill for a public-private competition for work performed by employees of the Bureau of Prisons or Federal Prison Industries, Incorporated. </p> <p>(Sec. 212) Prohibits U.S. Attorneys from holding dual or additional responsibilities that exempt them from statutory residency requirements. </p> <p>(Sec. 213) Permits specified percentages of grant and reimbursement program funds provided by this title for the Office of Justice Programs to be used for training and technical assistance, transferred to the National Institute of Justice or the Bureau of Justice Statistics for criminal justice research and statistics, and used for tribal criminal justice assistance. </p> <p>(Sec. 214) Permits the Attorney General to waive matching requirements for Second Chance Act adult and juvenile reentry demonstration projects; state, tribal, and local reentry courts; drug treatment programs; and grants to protect inmates and safeguard communities. </p> <p>(Sec. 215) Waives the requirement that DOJ reserve certain funds provided for offender incarceration for payments for incarceration on tribal lands. </p> <p>(Sec. 216) Prohibits funds, other than funds for the National Instant Criminal Background Check System established under the Brady Handgun Violence Prevention Act, from being used to transfer an operable firearm to a known or suspected agent of a drug cartel if law enforcement personnel do not continuously monitor or control the firearm. </p> <p>(Sec. 217) Requires DOJ to provide the DOJ Inspector General with timely access to records, documents, and other materials. </p> <p>(Sec. 218) Exempts funds appropriated or administered by the Office on Violence Against Women from penalties required by the Prison Rape Elimination Act for states that have failed to adopt national standards for the detection, prevention, reduction, and punishment of prison rape. </p> <p>(Sec. 219) Permits funds provided by this bill for the Office of Justice Programs to be used to participate in Performance Partnership Pilot collaboration programs. </p> <p><i>Science Appropriations Act, 2016 </i></p> <p>TITLE III--SCIENCE </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Office of Science and Technology Policy. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) for: </p> <ul> <li>Science; </li> <li>Aeronautics; </li> <li>Space Technology; </li> <li>Exploration; </li> <li>Space Operations; </li> <li>Education; </li> <li>Safety, Security, and Mission Services; </li> <li>Construction and Environmental Compliance and Restoration; and </li> <li>the Office of Inspector General. </li> </ul> <p>Includes administrative provisions for NASA that: </p> <ul> <li>Permit funds for any announced prize to remain available until the prize is claimed or the offer is withdrawn;</li> <li>Establish the terms and conditions for the transfer of appropriations provided by this bill; </li> <li>Require NASA to submit its spending plan at the theme, program, project, and activity level;</li> <li>Require the spending plan or subsequent changes to be subject to reprogramming procedures; and</li> <li>Permit specified expired funds to remain available through FY2025 for the closeout of all Space Shuttle contracts and associated programs. </li> </ul> <p>Provides appropriations to the National Science Foundation (NSF) for: </p> <ul> <li>Research and Related Activities, </li> <li>Major Research Equipment and Facilities Construction, </li> <li>Education and Human Resources, </li> <li>Agency Operations and Award Management, </li> <li>the Office of the National Science Board, and </li> <li>the Office of Inspector General.</li> </ul> <p>Establishes thresholds for the transfer of appropriations provided by this bill to the NSF. </p> <p>TITLE IV--RELATED AGENCIES </p> <p>Provides appropriations for the Commission on Civil Rights, the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, the U.S. International Trade Commission, the Legal Services Corporation, the Marine Mammal Commission, and the State Justice Institute. </p> <p>Specifies restrictions, terms, and conditions on the use of funds by the Legal Services Corporation. </p> <p>TITLE V--GENERAL PROVISIONS </p> <p>Sets forth permissible, restricted, and prohibited uses for funds provided by this and other appropriations Acts. </p> <p>(Sec. 501) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used for publicity or propaganda purposes that are not authorized by Congress. </p> <p>(Sec. 502) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from remaining available for obligation beyond the current fiscal year, unless expressly permitted in the bill. </p> <p>(Sec. 503) Limits expenditures for consulting services to contracts where the expenditures are a matter of public record and available for public inspection, unless otherwise provided by law. </p> <p>(Sec. 504) Provides that if any provision of this bill or the application of the provision is held invalid, the remainder of the bill is not affected. </p> <p>(Sec. 505) Establishes restrictions and requirements for the reprogramming of funds provided by this bill. </p> <p>(Sec. 506) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to award contracts or subcontracts to a person who has been found to have intentionally affixed a ''Made in America'' label to any product that was not made in America. Requires promotional items purchased using funds provided by this bill to be manufactured, produced, or assembled in the United States or its territories or possessions, to the extent it is practicable. </p> <p>(Sec. 507) Requires Commerce, DOJ, the NSF, and NASA to provide quarterly reports to Congress regarding the status of balances of appropriations at the account level. </p> <p>(Sec. 508) Requires costs incurred by agencies for personnel actions due to funding reductions in this bill to be absorbed within the budgetary resources available to the department or agency. Provides transfer authority between appropriation accounts to carry out this provision, subject to reprogramming procedures. Provides that, for the Department of Commerce, this section applies to actions taken for the care and protection of loan collateral or grant property. </p> <p>(Sec. 509) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to promote the sale or export of tobacco or tobacco products or to seek the reduction or removal of foreign restrictions on the marketing of tobacco products, except for restrictions which are not applied equally to all products of the same type. </p> <p>(Sec. 510) Establishes obligation limits and uses for funds from the Crime Victims Fund. </p> <p>(Sec. 511) Prohibits DOJ from using funds provided by this bill to discriminate against or denigrate the religious or moral beliefs of students or the parents of students participating in programs for which financial assistance is provided. </p> <p>(Sec. 512) Prohibits the transfer of funds provided by this bill to a department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States Government, unless the transfer is pursuant to an appropriations Act. </p> <p>(Sec. 513) Provides that funds included in this this bill to implement E-Government Initiatives are subject to reprogramming procedures and requirements. </p> <p>(Sec. 514) Establishes timetables and procedures for specified audits by Inspectors General of the departments and agencies funded in this bill. Requires recipients of grants or contracts funded by this bill to certify that no grant or contract funds will be provided to anyone with a financial interest in the recipient. </p> <p>(Sec. 515) Prohibits Commerce, DOJ, NASA, or the NSF from using funds provided by this bill to acquire a high-impact information system unless supply chain risks have been reviewed and a mitigation strategy has been developed. </p> <p>(Sec. 516) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to support or justify the use of torture by any official or contract employee of the U.S. government. </p> <p>(Sec. 517) Prohibits the use of funds to require export licenses for exporting components, parts, or attachments for certain firearms to Canada. </p> <p>(Sec. 518) Prohibits the use of funds to deny certain import applications for firearms, parts, or ammunition that are curios or relics. (Curios or relics are firearms which are of special interest to collectors by reason of some quality other than is associated with firearms intended for sporting use or as offensive or defensive weapons.) </p> <p>(Sec. 519) Prohibits the use of funds to include specified patent provisions from the United States-Singapore Free Trade Agreement, the United States-Australia Free Trade Agreement, or the United States-Morocco Free Trade Agreement in any new bilateral or multilateral trade agreement. </p> <p>(Sec. 520) Prohibits the use of funds provided by this bill to authorize or issue a National Security Letter (NSL) in violation of specified laws authorizing the FBI to issue an NSL. (An NSL is a written directive, comparable to an administrative subpoena, used by law enforcement and intelligence agencies to demand certain information from third parties such as telecommunication providers, financial institutions, and consumer credit reporting agencies.)</p> <p> (Sec. 521) Requires congressional notification regarding Commerce, DOJ, NSF, or NASA projects that total more than $75 million and are expected to have cost increases of at least 10%. </p> <p>(Sec. 522) Deems funds provided by this bill for intelligence or intelligence related activities as authorized by Congress during FY2016 until the enactment of the Intelligence Authorization Act for FY2016. </p> <p>(Sec. 523) Prohibits contracts or grant awards above $5 million unless the prospective contractor or grantee certifies that the organization has filed all federal tax returns, has not been convicted of a criminal offense under the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, and has no unpaid federal tax assessment. </p> <p>(Sec. 524) Rescinds specified unobligated balances from prior appropriations to DOJ. </p> <p>(Sec. 525) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to purchase first class or premium airline travel in violation of specified federal travel regulations. </p> <p>(Sec. 526) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to pay for the attendance of more than 50 department or agency employees at any single conference outside the United States, unless it is a law enforcement training or operational event where the majority of federal attendees are law enforcement personnel stationed outside the United States. </p> <p>(Sec. 527) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used in a manner that is inconsistent with the principal negotiating objective of the United States with respect to trade remedy laws. </p> <p>(Sec. 528) Prohibits funds from being used to transfer or release any individual detained at U.S. Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba (Guantanamo) who is not a U.S. citizen or member of the Armed Forces into the United States, its territories, or possessions. </p> <p>(Sec. 529) Prohibits funding from being used to construct, acquire, or modify any U.S. facility (other than the facility at Guantanamo Bay, Cuba) to house any individual detained at Guantanamo. </p> <p>(Sec. 530) Requires, to the extent it is practicable, funds provided by this bill to be used to purchase light bulbs that are ''Energy Star'' qualified or have the ''Federal Energy Management Program'' designation </p> <p>(Sec. 531) Requires the Office of Management and Budget to direct departments and agencies funded by this bill to track undisbursed balances in expired grant accounts and include specified details in annual performance and accountability reports. </p> <p>(Sec. 532) Prohibits funds from being used to deny the importation of shotgun models if no application for the importation of models in the same configuration had been denied prior to January 1, 2011, on the basis that the shotgun was not particularly suitable for or readily adaptable to sporting purposes. </p> <p>(Sec. 533) Prohibits the use of funds made available in this bill for a computer network that does not block pornography, except for law enforcement purposes </p> <p>(Sec. 534) Requires Commerce, DOJ, NASA, and the NSF to submit spending plans to Congress. </p> <p>(Sec. 535) Requires the agencies funded by this bill to report specified details regarding conference spending to the Inspectors General.</p> <p>(Sec. 536) Prohibits the use of funds provided by this bill to implement the Arms Trade Treaty regulating international trade in conventional arms until it is ratified by the Senate. </p> <p>(Sec. 537) Requires all departments and agencies funded in this bill to link all contracts that provide award fees to successful acquisition outcomes.<br> <br> (Sec. 538) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to pay award or incentive fees for contractors with performance that is below satisfactory or does not meet the basic requirements of the contract.<br> <br> (Sec. 539) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used for contract, memorandum of understanding, cooperative agreement, grant, or loan activities if the proposed recipient has been convicted of a felony criminal violation.</p> <p>(Sec. 540) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used for contract, memorandum of understanding, cooperative agreement, grant, or loan activities if the proposed recipient has unpaid federal tax liabilities. </p> <p>(Sec. 541) Prohibits DOJ or the DEA from using funds provided by this bill in contravention of a provision of the Agricultural Act of 2014 that permits an institution of higher education or a state department of agriculture to grow or cultivate industrial hemp for research purposes. </p> <p>(Sec. 542) Prohibits DOJ from using funds provided by this bill to prevent specified states, the District of Columbia, or Guam from implementing their own laws authorizing the use, distribution, possession, or cultivation of medical marijuana. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2578v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-08-17">
<action-date>2015-06-03</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Highlights: </b></p> <p>The Commerce, Justice, Science, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2016 provides FY2016 appropriations to the Department of Commerce, the Department of Justice (DOJ), science agencies, and several related agencies. </p> <p>The bill funds agencies with a wide range of responsibilities for issues such as: addressing violent crime, drug trafficking, financial fraud, terrorism, espionage, and cybercrime; conducting the census; forecasting the weather; managing fisheries; exploring space; advancing science; providing legal services for the poor; enforcing employment discrimination laws; and overseeing patents, trademarks, and trade policy. </p> <p>The bill increases overall FY2016 Commerce, Justice, Science and Related Agencies funding above FY2015 levels, including increases for DOJ and science programs and decreases for the Department of Commerce and Related Agencies. </p> <p>Within the Department of Commerce budget, the bill includes: </p> <ul> <li> increases for the Bureau of Industry and Security and the Minority Business Development Agency; </li> <li>decreases for the Bureau of the Census, the National Telecommunications and Information Administration, the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, and the National Institute of Standards and Technology. </li> </ul> <p>Within the DOJ budget, the bill includes: </p> <ul> <li>increases for: Legal Activities; the U.S. Marshals Service; the Federal Bureau of Investigation; the Drug Enforcement Administration; the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives; the Federal Prison System; the Office on Violence Against Woman; and Community Oriented Policing Services (COPS); and </li> <li>decreases for: Office of Justice Programs such as Research, Evaluation, and Statistics; State and Local Law Enforcement Assistance; and Juvenile Justice Programs. </li> </ul> <p>The bill's increase in funding above FY2015 levels for the science agencies includes increases for both the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) and the National Science Foundation. </p> <p>The bill decreases funding for the Legal Services Corporation. </p> <p>The bill includes provisions that restrict or prohibit the use of funds for: </p> <ul> <li>the transfer of Guantanamo detainees or the construction of a new facility in the United States to house them; </li> <li>the enforcement of certain restrictions and reporting requirements for firearms; </li> <li>bilateral activities with China by NASA or the Office of Science and Technology Policy; </li> <li>facilitating, permitting, licensing, or promoting exports to the Cuban military or intelligence services or their families;</li> <li>preventing states from implementing their own laws legalizing medical marijuana, industrial hemp, or cannabidiol oil (a marijuana extract); and</li> <li>a court case challenging the President's executive actions on immigration.</li> </ul> <p><b>Full Summary: </b></p> <p><b>Commerce, Justice, Science, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2016 </b></p> <p>Provides FY2016 appropriations for Department of Commerce, the Department of Justice (DOJ), science agencies, and several related agencies. </p> <p><i>Department of Commerce Appropriations Act, 2016 </i></p> <p>TITLE I--DEPARTMENT OF COMMERCE</p> <p> Provides appropriations to the Department of Commerce for: </p> <ul> <li> the International Trade Administration, </li> <li>the Bureau of Industry and Security, </li> <li>the Economic Development Administration, </li> <li>the Minority Business Development Agency, </li> <li>Economics and Statistics Analysis, </li> <li>the Bureau of the Census, </li> <li>the National Telecommunication and Information Administration, and </li> <li>the U.S. Patent and Trademark Office. </li> </ul> <p>Limits the use of funds for information technology related to the 2020 census until an investment plan is provided to Congress and the Government Accountability Office. </p> <p>Provides appropriations for the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST), including: Scientific and Technical Research and Services, Industrial Technology Services, and Construction of Research Facilities. </p> <p>Provides appropriations for the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), including: </p> <ul> <li> Operations, Research, and Facilities; </li> <li>Procurement, Acquisition, and Construction; </li> <li>Pacific Coastal Salmon Recovery; </li> <li>the Fishermen's Contingency Fund; and </li> <li>the Fisheries Finance Program Account. </li> </ul> <p>Provides appropriations for Departmental Management, including Salaries and Expenses, Renovation and Modernization, and the Office of Inspector General. </p> <p>(Sec. 101) Permits funds provided by this bill to be used for advanced payments (prior to the receipt of goods, services, or other assets) only if designated Commerce officials certify that the payments are in the public interest. </p> <p>(Sec. 102) Permits funds provided by this bill to be used for hiring passenger motor vehicles, employment of temporary or intermittent experts and consultants, and the purchase of uniforms. </p> <p>(Sec. 103) Permits the transfer of funds between Commerce accounts, subject to specified limitations and requirements. Requires Commerce to notify Congress prior to the acquisition or disposal of any capital asset not provided for in an Act providing appropriations to Commerce. </p> <p>(Sec. 104) Extends requirements for NOAA to make and report to Congress on determinations regarding the identification and management of technical, cost, and schedule risk; the reliance on demonstrated technologies; and compliance with relevant policies, prior to entering into a contract for a major program with a life cycle cost of more than $250 million. </p> <p>Specifies the life cycle costs for the Joint Polar Satellite System and for the Geostationary Operational Environmental Satellite R-Series Program. </p> <p>(Sec. 105) Permits Commerce to furnish services to facilitate the use or occupancy of Department of Commerce buildings. </p> <p>(Sec. 106) States that grant recipients may continue to deter child pornography, copyright infringement, or any other unlawful activity over their networks. </p> <p>(Sec. 107) Permits NOAA to use, with consent and reimbursement, resources of other federal, state, local, and international entities to carry out the responsibilities of any statute administered by NOAA. </p> <p>(Sec. 108) Prohibits the National Technical Information Service from charging for copies of reports or documents generated by the legislative branch unless the Service has provided information on how a copy may be obtained for free online. Requires any charge to be limited to the Service's cost. </p> <p>(Sec. 109) Permits Commerce to waive the requirement for bonds with respect to contracts for the construction, alteration, or repair of vessels under the Coast and Geodetic Survey Act of 1947. </p> <p>(Sec. 110) Permits the National Institute of Standards and Technology to use unobligated balances from the Industrial Technology Services account for purposes related to the Network for Manufacturing Innovation. </p> <p><i>Department of Justice Appropriations Act, 2016</i> </p> <p>TITLE II--DEPARTMENT OF JUSTICE </p> <p>Provides FY2016 appropriations to the Department of Justice (DOJ) for: </p> <ul> <li>General Administration, including Salaries and Expenses, Justice Information Sharing Technology, Administrative Review and Appeals, and the Office of Inspector General; </li> <li>the U.S. Parole Commission; </li> <li>Legal Activities, including General Legal Activities, the Antitrust Division, U.S. Attorneys, the U.S. Trustee Systems Fund, the Foreign Claims Settlement Commission, Fees and Expenses of Witnesses, and the Community Relations Service; </li> <li>the U.S. Marshals Services, including for Construction and Federal Prisoner Detention;</li> <li>the National Security Division; </li> <li>Interagency Law Enforcement; </li> <li>the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI); </li> <li>the Drug Enforcement Administration (DEA); </li> <li>the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives; and </li> <li>the Federal Prison System, including for Buildings and Facilities and Federal Prison Industries, Incorporated. </li> </ul> <p>Provide appropriations to the Office On Violence Against Women for Violence Against Women Prevention and Prosecution Programs. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Office of Justice Programs for State and Local Law Enforcement Assistance, Juvenile Justice Programs, and Public Safety Officer Benefits. </p> <p>Provides appropriations for Community Oriented Policing Services (COPS) programs, including a community trust initiative to improve police-community relations. </p> <p>(Sec. 201) Provides additional funds to the Attorney General for official reception and representation expenses. </p> <p>(Sec. 202) Prohibits funds provided by this title from being used to pay for an abortion, except where the life of the mother would be endangered if the fetus were carried to term, or in the case of rape or incest. </p> <p>(Sec. 203) Prohibits funds provided by this title from being used to require any person to perform or facilitate the performance of an abortion. </p> <p>(Sec. 204) Establishes the obligation of the Director of the Bureau of Prisons to provide escort services to an inmate receiving an abortion outside of a federal facility, except where this obligation conflicts with section 203 of this bill. </p> <p>(Sec. 205) Sets forth requirements and procedures for transferring and reprogramming funds provided to by this bill to DOJ. </p> <p>(Sec. 206) Authorizes the Attorney General to extend the Personnel Management Demonstration Project without limitation on the number of employees or positions covered. </p> <p>(Sec. 207) Prohibits the FBI or the U.S. Marshals Services from using funds provided by this title to transport prisoners classified as maximum or high security, other than to a facility certified by the Bureau of Prisons as appropriately secure. </p> <p>(Sec. 208) Prohibits federal prisons from using funds provided by this bill to purchase or rent audiovisual equipment, services, and materials used primarily for recreational purposes, except for inmate training, religious, or educational purposes </p> <p>(Sec. 209) Prohibits funds provided by this title from being used for major information technology projects unless the Deputy Attorney General and the Department Investment Review Board certify to Congress that the program: (1) has appropriate program management controls and contractor oversight mechanisms in place, and (2) is compatible with DOJ enterprise architecture. </p> <p>(Sec. 210) Requires DOJ to follow reprogramming procedures for any deviation from the program amounts specified in this title or the accompanying report, or any use of deobligated funds provided by this title in previous years. </p> <p>(Sec. 211) Prohibits the use of funds provided by this bill for a public-private competition for work performed by employees of Federal Prison Industries, Incorporated. </p> <p>(Sec. 212) Prohibits U.S. Attorneys from holding dual or additional responsibilities that exempt them from statutory residency requirements. </p> <p>(Sec. 213) Permits up to 3% of grant and reimbursement program funds provided to the Office of Justice Programs to be used for training and technical assistance. Permits grant or reimbursement funds to be used for criminal justice research, evaluation, and statistics. </p> <p>(Sec. 214) Waives the requirement that DOJ reserve certain funds provided for offender incarceration for payments for incarceration on tribal lands. </p> <p>(Sec. 215) Prohibits funds, other than funds for the National Instant Criminal Background Check System established under the Brady Handgun Violence Prevention Act, from being used to transfer an operable firearm to a known or suspected agent of a drug cartel if law enforcement personnel do not continuously monitor or control the firearm. </p> <p>(Sec. 216) Establishes limitations and requirements for the obligation of specified funds from the Department of Justice Working Capital Fund and the Assets Forfeiture Fund. Requires DOJ to submit to Congress a spending plan including the planned distribution of Assets Forfeiture Fund joint law enforcement operations funding during FY2016. </p> <p>(Sec. 217) Limits the use of specified DOJ funds until the Attorney General demonstrates to Congress that DOJ is implementing recommendations included in the Office of Inspector General report entitled &quot;The Handling of Sexual Harassment and Misconduct Allegations by the Department's Law Enforcement Components.&quot; Requires the DOJ Inspector General to report on the implementation. </p> <p><i>Science Appropriations Act, 2016 </i></p> <p>TITLE III--SCIENCE </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Office of Science and Technology Policy. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) for: </p> <ul> <li>Science; </li> <li>Aeronautics; </li> <li>Space Technology; </li> <li>Exploration; </li> <li>Space Operations; </li> <li>Education; </li> <li>Safety, Security, and Mission Services; </li> <li>Construction and Environmental Compliance and Restoration; and </li> <li>the Office of Inspector General. </li> </ul> <p>Includes administrative provisions for NASA that: </p> <ul> <li>Permit funds for any announced prize to remain available until the prize is claimed or the offer is withdrawn;</li> <li>Establish the terms and conditions for the transfer of appropriations provided by this bill; </li> <li>Require NASA to submit its spending plan at the theme, program, project, and activity level;</li> <li>Require the spending plan or subsequent changes to be subject to reprogramming procedures; </li> <li>Permit the transfer of unexpired balances under a previous account structure to the new account structure. </li> </ul> <p>Provides appropriations to the National Science Foundation (NSF) for: </p> <ul> <li>Research and Related Activities, </li> <li>Major Research Equipment and Facilities Construction, </li> <li>Education and Human Resources, </li> <li>Agency Operations and Award Management, </li> <li>the Office of the National Science Board, and </li> <li>the Office of the Inspector General.</li> </ul> <p>Establishes thresholds for the transfer of appropriations provided by this bill to the NSF. </p> <p>TITLE IV--RELATED AGENCIES </p> <p>Provides appropriations for the Commission on Civil Rights, the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, the U.S. International Trade Commission, the Legal Services Corporation, the Marine Mammal Commission, the Office of the U.S. Trade Representative, and the State Justice Institute. </p> <p>Specifies restrictions, terms, and conditions on the use of funds by the Legal Services Corporation. </p> <p>TITLE V--GENERAL PROVISIONS </p> <p>Sets forth permissible, restricted, and prohibited uses for funds provided by this and other appropriations Acts. </p> <p>(Sec. 501) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used for publicity or propaganda purposes that are not authorized by Congress. </p> <p>(Sec. 502) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from remaining available for obligation beyond the current fiscal year, unless expressly permitted in the bill. </p> <p>(Sec. 503) Limits expenditures for consulting services to contracts where the expenditures are a matter of public record and available for public inspection, unless otherwise provided by law. </p> <p>(Sec. 504) Provides that if any provision of this bill or the application of the provision is held invalid, the remainder of the bill is not affected. </p> <p>(Sec. 505) Establishes restrictions and requirements for the reprogramming of funds provided by this bill. </p> <p>(Sec. 506) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to award contracts or subcontracts to a person who has been found to have intentionally affixed a ''Made in America'' label to any product that was not made in America. Requires promotional items purchased using funds provided by this bill to be manufactured, produced, or assembled in the United States or its territories or possessions, to the extent it is practicable. </p> <p>(Sec. 507) Requires Commerce, DOJ, the NSF, and NASA to provide quarterly reports to Congress regarding the status of balances of appropriations at the account level. </p> <p>(Sec. 508) Requires costs incurred by agencies for personnel actions due to funding reductions in this bill to be absorbed within the budgetary resources available to the department or agency. Provides transfer authority between appropriation accounts to carry out this provision, subject to reprogramming procedures. Provides that, for the Department of Commerce, this section applies to actions taken for the care and protection of loan collateral or grant property. </p> <p>(Sec. 509) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to promote the sale or export of tobacco or tobacco products or to seek the reduction or removal of foreign restrictions on the marketing of tobacco products, except for restrictions which are not applied equally to all products of the same type. </p> <p>(Sec. 510) Limits the obligation of receipts deposited into the Crime Victims Fund during FY2016. </p> <p>(Sec. 511) Prohibits DOJ from using funds provided by this bill to discriminate against or denigrate the religious or moral beliefs of students or the parents of students participating in programs for which financial assistance is provided. </p> <p>(Sec. 512) Prohibits the transfer of funds provided by this bill to a department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States Government, unless the transfer is pursuant to an appropriations Act. </p> <p>(Sec. 513) Provides that funds included in this this bill to implement E-Government Initiatives are subject to reprogramming procedures and requirements. </p> <p>(Sec. 514) Establishes timetables and procedures for specified audits by Inspectors General of the departments and agencies funded in this bill. Requires recipients of grants or contracts funded by this bill to certify that no grant or contract funds will be provided to anyone with a financial interest in the recipient. </p> <p>(Sec. 515) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to acquire certain information systems unless the acquiring department or agency has reviewed specified issues related to supply chain risk and the risk of cyber-espionage or sabotage. </p> <p>Prohibits the use of funds provided by this bill to acquire a high-impact or moderate-impact information system reviewed and assessed under this section unless the department or agency has consulted with the NIST and the FBI to: (1) develop a mitigation strategy for any identified risks; (2) report to Congress and the agency Inspector General that the system is in the national interest. </p> <p>(Sec. 516) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to support or justify the use of torture by any official or contract employee of the U.S. government. </p> <p>(Sec. 517) Prohibits the use of funds to require export licenses for exporting components, parts, or attachments for certain firearms to Canada. </p> <p>(Sec. 518) Prohibits the use of funds to deny certain import applications for firearms, parts, or ammunition that are curios or relics. (Curios or relics are firearms which are of special interest to collectors by reason of some quality other than is associated with firearms intended for sporting use or as offensive or defensive weapons.) </p> <p>(Sec. 519) Prohibits the use of funds to include specified patent provisions from the United States-Singapore Free Trade Agreement, the United States-Australia Free Trade Agreement, or the United States-Morocco Free Trade Agreement in any new bilateral or multilateral trade agreement. </p> <p>(Sec. 520) Prohibits the use of funds provided by this bill to authorize or issue a National Security Letter (NSL) in violation of specified laws authorizing the FBI to issue an NSL. (An NSL is a written directive, comparable to an administrative subpoena, used by law enforcement and intelligence agencies to demand certain information from third parties such as telecommunication providers, financial institutions, and consumer credit reporting agencies.)</p> <p> (Sec. 521) Requires congressional notification regarding Commerce, DOJ, NSF, or NASA projects that total more than $75 million and are expected to have cost increases of at least 10%. </p> <p>(Sec. 522) Deems funds provided by this bill for intelligence or intelligence related activities as authorized by Congress during FY2016 until the enactment of the Intelligence Authorization Act for FY2016. </p> <p>(Sec. 523) Prohibits contracts or grant awards above $5 million unless the prospective contractor or grantee certifies that the organization has filed all federal tax returns, has not been convicted of a criminal offense under the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, and has no unpaid federal tax assessment. </p> <p>(Sec. 524) Rescinds specified unobligated balances from prior appropriations to Commerce and DOJ. </p> <p>(Sec. 525) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to purchase first class or premium airline travel in violation of specified federal travel regulations. </p> <p>(Sec. 526) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to pay for the attendance of more than 50 department or agency employees at any single conference outside the United States, unless it is a law enforcement training or operational event where the majority of federal attendees are law enforcement personnel stationed outside the United States. </p> <p>(Sec. 527) Prohibits funds from being used to transfer or release any individual detained at U.S. Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba (Guantanamo) who is not a U.S. citizen or member of the Armed Forces into the United States, its territories, or possessions. </p> <p>(Sec. 528) Prohibits funding from being used to construct, acquire, or modify any U.S. facility (other than the facility at Guantanamo Bay, Cuba) to house any individual detained at Guantanamo. </p> <p>(Sec. 529) Requires, to the extent it is practicable, funds provided by this bill to be used to purchase light bulbs that have the ''Energy Star'' or ''Federal Energy Management Program'' designation </p> <p>(Sec. 530) Requires the Office of Management and Budget to direct departments and agencies funded by this bill to track undisbursed balances in expired grant accounts and include specified details in annual performance and accountability reports. </p> <p>(Sec. 531) Prohibits NASA or the Office of Science and Technology Policy (OSTP) from using funds provided by this bill to: (1) engage in bilateral activities with China or a Chinese-owned company unless the activities are authorized by a law enacted after enactment of this bill, or (2) host official Chinese visitors at NASA facilities. Includes an exception if NASA or OSTP have made a specified certification to Congress regarding an activity. </p> <p>(Sec. 532) Prohibits funds from being used to deny the importation of shotgun models if no application for the importation of models in the same configuration had been denied prior to January 1, 2011, on the basis that the shotgun was not particularly suitable for or readily adaptable to sporting purposes. </p> <p>(Sec. 533) Prohibits the use of funds made available in this bill for a computer network that does not block pornography, except for law enforcement purposes </p> <p>(Sec. 534) Requires each department and agency funded in this bill to submit spending plans to Congress. </p> <p>(Sec. 535) Prohibits the use of funds provided by this bill to implement the Arms Trade Treaty regulating international trade in conventional arms until it is ratified by the Senate. </p> <p>(Sec. 536) Prohibits the use of funds provided by this bill to relinquish the responsibility of the National Telecommunications and Information Administration for Internet domain name system functions. </p> <p>(Sec. 537) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to require a person licensed for importing, manufacturing, or dealing in firearms to report information to DOJ regarding the sale of multiple rifles or shotguns to the same person. </p> <p>(Sec. 538) Requires Commerce, DOJ, NASA, and the NSF to provide Inspectors General with timely access to records, documents, and other materials. </p> <p>(Sec. 539) Requires Commerce, NASA, NSF, and the OSTP to report monthly to Congress on official travel of employees to China. </p> <p>(Sec. 540) Prohibit the use of funds provided by this bill to facilitate, permit, license, or promote exports to the Cuban military or intelligence service, officers of the Cuban military or intelligence service, or an immediate family member, with the exception of goods permitted under the Trade Sanctions Reform and Export Enhancement Act of 2000. </p> <p>(Sec. 541) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to shut down or prepare to shut down the Stratospheric Observatory for Infrared Astronomy. </p> <p>(Sec. 542) Establishes a spending reduction account for the amount by which spending proposed in this bill exceeds the subcommittee's allocation under the Congressional Budget Act of 1974. Specifies that the amount is $1 million. (Under the Rules of the House of Representatives, any savings included in the spending reduction account are not available for further appropriation during consideration of the bill.) </p> <p>(Sec. 543) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to purchase new light-duty vehicles for an executive fleet or an agency's fleet inventory, except in accordance with Presidential Memorandum- Federal Fleet Performance, which establishes requirements for purchasing alternative fueled vehicles. </p> <p>(Sec. 544) Prohibits DOJ or the FBI from using funds provided by this bill to mandate or request that certain products or services be altered to permit the electronic surveillance of any user of the product or service, except for requests or mandates authorized by the Communications Assistance for Law Enforcement Act. </p> <p>(Sec. 545) Prohibits the DEA from using funds provided by this bill to execute a subpoena permitting the bulk data collection of phone records. </p> <p>(Sec. 546) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to make responses to the Census Bureau's American Community Survey mandatory. </p> <p>(Sec. 547) Prohibits DOJ personnel from using funds provided by this bill for a settlement with the federal government that requires a defendant to donate or contribute funds to an organization or individual. </p> <p>(Sec. 548) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to enforce proposed regulations requiring a local chief law enforcement officer to approve National Firearms Act transfers. </p> <p>(Sec. 549) Prohibits DOJ from using funds provided by this bill to: (1) violate the Fifth and Fourteenth Amendments of the U.S. Constitution, or (2) repeal guidance included in the memorandum issued by the Attorney General and entitled &quot;Guidance Regarding the Use of Asset Forfeiture Authorities in Connection with Structuring Offenses.&quot; </p> <p>(Sec. 550) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to require any person to disclose the race or ethnicity of a person in connection with the transfer of a firearm to the person. </p> <p>(Sec. 551) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used for trade agreements that limit U.S. greenhouse gas emissions. </p> <p>(Sec. 552) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used for contracts with companies convicted, indicted, or civilly charged with specified federal crimes or that have more than $3,000 in delinquent federal taxes within a three-year period surrounding the contract. </p> <p>(Sec. 553) Prohibits the use of the funds provided by this bill to classify certain types of ammunition as armor-piercing ammunition. </p> <p>(Sec. 554) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used for specified climate change assessments and plans. </p> <p>(Sec. 555) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used for specified DOJ clemency initiatives or to transfer or temporarily assign employees to the Office of the Pardon Attorney to screen clemency applications. </p> <p>(Sec. 556) Prohibits NOAA from using funds provided by this bill to enforce: (1) recreational sector segmentation for the Gulf of Mexico Red Snapper Fishery, or (2) activities that would lead to the Red Snapper commercial season lasting more than five times as long as the recreational season. </p> <p>(Sec. 557) Prohibits DOJ from using funds provided by this bill to prevent a state from implementing its own laws authorizing the use, distribution, possession, or cultivation of industrial hemp. </p> <p>(Sec. 558) Prohibits DOJ from using funds provided by this bill to prevent specified states, the District of Columbia, or Guam from implementing their own laws authorizing the use, distribution, possession, or cultivation of medical marijuana. </p> <p>(Sec. 559) Prohibits funds provided by this bill to compel a journalist or reporter to testify about information or sources that they regard to be confidential. </p> <p>(Sec. 560) Prohibits the use of funds to prevent a state from implementing any law that makes it lawful to possess, distribute, or use cannabidiol (a marijuana extract) or cannabidiol oil. </p> <p>(Sec. 561) Prohibits DOJ from using funds provided by this bill to enforce the Fair Housing Act by relying on an allegation of liability using disparate impact. (The legal doctrine that a practice has a discriminatory effect where it actually or predictably results in a disparate impact on a group of persons or creates, increases, reinforces, or perpetuates segregated housing patterns because of race, color, religion, sex, handicap, familial status, or national origin.) </p> <p>(Sec. 562) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used for the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives Special Advisory entitled &quot;Test, Examination and Classification of 7N6 5.45 x 39 Ammunition.&quot; </p> <p>(Sec. 563) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to operate or disseminate a cell-site simulator or IMSI catcher in the United States except pursuant to a court order. (These devices mimic cell phone towers and send out signals to trick cell phones into transmitting their locations and identifying information.) </p> <p>(Sec. 564) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to prosecute or hold a person liable for violating provisions of the Migratory Bird Treaty Act that prohibit taking, killing, or possessing certain migratory birds. </p> <p>(Sec. 565) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used for &quot;Operation Choke Point.&quot; (A DOJ investigation of banks and payment processors involved in fraudulent transactions.) </p> <p>(Sec. 566) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used for trade agreements that include provisions related to certain visas issued under the Immigration and Nationality Act. </p> <p>(Sec. 567) Prohibits DOJ or the DEA from using funds provided by this bill in contravention of a provision of the Agricultural Act of 2014 that permits an institution of higher education or a state department of agriculture to grow or cultivate industrial hemp for research purposes. </p> <p>(Sec. 568) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to treat ammunition as armor-piercing except for ammunition designed and intended for use in a handgun. </p> <p>(Sec. 569) Prohibits the National Institute of Standards and Technology from using funds provided by this bill to consult with the National Security Agency or the Central Intelligence Agency to alter cryptographic or computer standards, except to improve information security. </p> <p>(Sec. 570) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to implement Executive Order No. 13547 (Stewardship of the Oceans, Our Coasts, and the Great Lakes), including the National Ocean Policy. </p> <p>(Sec. 571) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used with respect to the Texas v. United States case related to the President's immigration executive order. </p> <p>(Sec. 572) Prohibits funds provided by this bill for Department of Justice--Office of Justice Programs--State and Local Law Enforcement Assistance from being used in contravention of provisions of the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996 that permit certain communications between government entities or officials and the Immigration and Naturalization Service. </p> <p>(Sec. 573) Prohibits NOAA from using funds provided by this bill to implement salmon recovery plans in the California Central Valley Recovery Domain, if the plans do not address predation by non-native species. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2578v79" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-08-17">
<action-date>2015-05-27</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p><b>Highlights: </b></p> <p>The Commerce, Justice, Science, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2016 provides FY2016 appropriations to the Department of Commerce, the Department of Justice (DOJ), science agencies, and several related agencies. </p> <p>The bill funds agencies with a wide range of responsibilities for issues such as: addressing violent crime, drug trafficking, financial fraud, terrorism, and espionage and cybercrime; conducting the census; forecasting the weather; managing fisheries; exploring space; advancing science; providing legal services for the poor; enforcing employment discrimination laws; and overseeing patents, trademarks, and trade policy. </p> <p>The bill increases overall FY2016 Commerce, Justice, Science and Related Agencies funding above FY2015 levels, including increases for DOJ and science programs and decreases for the Department of Commerce and Related Agencies. </p> <p>Within the Department of Commerce budget, the bill includes: </p> <ul> <li> increases for the Bureau of Industry and Security, the Minority Business Development Agency, and the Bureau of the Census; and </li> <li>decreases for the National Telecommunications and Information Administration, the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, and the National Institute of Standards and Technology. </li> </ul> <p>Within the DOJ budget, the bill includes: </p> <ul> <li>increases for: Legal Activities; the U.S. Marshals Service; the Federal Bureau of Investigation; the Drug Enforcement Administration; the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives; the Federal Prison System; the Office on Violence Against Woman, and Community Oriented Policing Services (COPS); and </li> <li>decreases for: Office of Justice Programs such as Research, Evaluation, and Statistics; State and Local Law Enforcement Assistance; and Juvenile Justice Programs. </li> </ul> <p>The bill's increase in funding above FY2015 levels for the science agencies includes increases for both the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) and the National Science Foundation. </p> <p>The bill decreases funding for the Legal Services Corporation and funds the other related agencies at the FY2015 level. </p> <p>The bill includes provisions that restrict or prohibit the use of funds for: </p> <ul> <li>the transfer of Guantanamo detainees or the construction of a new facility in the United States to house them; </li> <li>the enforcement of certain restrictions and reporting requirements for firearms; </li> <li>bilateral activities with China by NASA or the Office of Science and Technology Policy; and </li> <li>facilitating, permitting, licensing, or promoting exports to the Cuban military or intelligence services or their families.</li> </ul> <p><b>Full Summary: </b></p> <p><b>Commerce, Justice, Science, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2016 </b></p> <p>Provides FY2016 appropriations for Department of Commerce, the Department of Justice (DOJ), science agencies, and several related agencies. </p> <p><i>Department of Commerce Appropriations Act, 2016 </i></p> <p>TITLE I--DEPARTMENT OF COMMERCE</p> <p> Provides appropriations to the Department of Commerce for: </p> <ul> <li> the International Trade Administration, </li> <li>the Bureau of Industry and Security, </li> <li>the Economic Development Administration, </li> <li>the Minority Business Development Agency, </li> <li>Economics and Statistics Analysis, </li> <li>the Bureau of the Census, </li> <li>the National Telecommunication and Information Administration, and </li> <li>the U.S. Patent and Trademark Office. </li> </ul> <p>Limits the use of funds for information technology related to the 2020 census until an investment plan is provided to Congress and the Government Accountability Office. </p> <p>Provides appropriations for the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST), including: Scientific and Technical Research and Services, Industrial Technology Services, and Construction of Research Facilities. </p> <p>Provides appropriations for the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), including: </p> <ul> <li> Operations, Research, and Facilities; </li> <li>Procurement, Acquisition, and Construction; </li> <li>Pacific Coastal Salmon Recovery; </li> <li>the Fishermen's Contingency Fund; and </li> <li>the Fisheries Finance Program Account. </li> </ul> <p>Provides appropriations for Departmental Management, including Salaries and Expenses, Renovation and Modernization, and the Office of Inspector General. </p> <p>(Sec. 101) Permits funds provided by this bill to be used for advanced payments (prior to the receipt of goods, services, or other assets) only if designated Commerce officials certify that the payments are in the public interest. </p> <p>(Sec. 102) Permits funds provided by this bill to be used for hiring passenger motor vehicles, employment of temporary or intermittent experts and consultants, and the purchase of uniforms. </p> <p>(Sec. 103) Permits the transfer of funds between Commerce accounts, subject to specified limitations and requirements. Requires Commerce to notify Congress prior to the acquisition or disposal of any capital asset not provided for in an Act providing appropriations to Commerce. </p> <p>(Sec. 104) Extends requirements for NOAA to make and report to Congress on determinations regarding the identification and management of technical, cost, and schedule risk; the reliance on demonstrated technologies; and compliance with relevant policies, prior to entering into a contract for a major program with a life cycle cost of more than $250 million. </p> <p>Specifies the life cycle costs for the Joint Polar Satellite System and for the Geostationary Operational Environmental Satellite R-Series Program. </p> <p>(Sec. 105) Permits Commerce to furnish services to facilitate the use or occupancy of Department of Commerce buildings. </p> <p>(Sec. 106) States that grant recipients may continue to deter child pornography, copyright infringement, or any other unlawful activity over their networks. </p> <p>(Sec. 107) Permits NOAA to use, with consent and reimbursement, resources of other federal, state, local, and international entities to carry out the responsibilities of any statute administered by NOAA. </p> <p>(Sec. 108) Prohibits the National Technical Information Service from charging for copies of reports or documents generated by the legislative branch unless the Service has provided information on how a copy may be obtained for free online. Requires any charge to be limited to the Service's cost. </p> <p>(Sec. 109) Permits Commerce to waive the requirement for bonds with respect to contracts for the construction, alteration, or repair of vessels under the Coast and Geodetic Survey Act of 1947. </p> <p>(Sec. 110) Permits the National Institute of Standards and Technology to use unobligated balances from the Industrial Technology Services account for purposes related to the Network for Manufacturing Innovation. </p> <p><i>Department of Justice Appropriations Act, 2016</i> </p> <p>TITLE II--DEPARTMENT OF JUSTICE </p> <p>Provides FY2016 appropriations to the Department of Justice (DOJ) for: </p> <ul> <li>General Administration, including Salaries and Expenses, Justice Information Sharing Technology, Administrative Review and Appeals, and the Office of Inspector General; </li> <li>the U.S. Parole Commission; </li> <li>Legal Activities, including General Legal Activities, the Antitrust Division, U.S. Attorneys, the U.S. Trustee Systems Fund, the Foreign Claims Settlement Commission, Fees and Expenses of Witnesses, and the Community Relations Service; </li> <li>the U.S. Marshals Services, including for Construction and Federal Prisoner Detention;</li> <li>the National Security Division; </li> <li>Interagency Law Enforcement; </li> <li>the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI); </li> <li>the Drug Enforcement Administration; </li> <li>the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives; and </li> <li>the Federal Prison System, including for Buildings and Facilities and Federal Prison Industries, Incorporated. </li> </ul> <p>Provide appropriations to the Office On Violence Against Women for Violence Against Women Prevention and Prosecution Programs. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Office of Justice Programs for State and Local Law Enforcement Assistance, Juvenile Justice Programs, and Public Safety Officer Benefits. </p> <p>Provides appropriations for Community Oriented Policing Services (COPS) programs, including a community trust initiative to improve police-community relations. </p> <p>(Sec. 201) Provides additional funds to the Attorney General for official reception and representation expenses. </p> <p>(Sec. 202) Prohibits funds provided by this title from being used to pay for an abortion, except where the life of the mother would be endangered if the fetus were carried to term, or in the case of rape or incest. </p> <p>(Sec. 203) Prohibits funds provided by this title from being used to require any person to perform or facilitate the performance of an abortion. </p> <p>(Sec. 204) Establishes the obligation of the Director of the Bureau of Prisons to provide escort services to an inmate receiving an abortion outside of a federal facility, except where this obligation conflicts with section 203 of this bill. </p> <p>(Sec. 205) Sets forth requirements and procedures for transferring and reprogramming funds provided to by this bill to DOJ. </p> <p>(Sec. 206) Authorizes the Attorney General to extend the Personnel Management Demonstration Project without limitation on the number of employees or positions covered. </p> <p>(Sec. 207) Prohibits the FBI or the U.S. Marshals Services from using funds provided by this title to transport prisoners classified as maximum or high security, other than to a facility certified by the Bureau of Prisons as appropriately secure. </p> <p>(Sec. 208) Prohibits federal prisons from using funds provided by this bill to purchase or rent audiovisual equipment, services, and materials used primarily for recreational purposes, except for inmate training, religious, or educational purposes </p> <p>(Sec. 209) Prohibits funds provided by this title from being used for major information technology projects unless the Deputy Attorney General and the Department Investment Review Board certify to Congress that the program: (1) has appropriate program management controls and contractor oversight mechanisms in place, and (2) is compatible with DOJ enterprise architecture. </p> <p>(Sec. 210) Requires DOJ to follow reprogramming procedures for any deviation from the program amounts specified in this title or the accompanying report, or any use of deobligated funds provided by this title in previous years. </p> <p>(Sec. 211) Prohibits the use of funds provided by this bill for a public-private competition for work performed by employees of Federal Prison Industries, Incorporated. </p> <p>(Sec. 212) Prohibits U.S. Attorneys from holding dual or additional responsibilities that exempt them from statutory residency requirements. </p> <p>(Sec. 213) Permits up to 3% of grant and reimbursement program funds provided to the Office of Justice Programs to be used for training and technical assistance. Permits grant or reimbursement funds to be used for criminal justice research, evaluation, and statistics. </p> <p>(Sec. 214) Waives the requirement that DOJ reserve certain funds provided for offender incarceration for payments for incarceration on tribal lands. </p> <p>(Sec. 215) Prohibits funds, other than funds for the National Instant Criminal Background Check System established under the Brady Handgun Violence Prevention Act, from being used to transfer an operable firearm to a known or suspected agent of a drug cartel if law enforcement personnel do not continuously monitor or control the firearm. </p> <p>(Sec. 216) Establishes limitations and requirements for the obligation of specified funds from the Department of Justice Working Capital Fund and the Assets Forfeiture Fund. Requires DOJ to submit to Congress a spending plan including the planned distribution of Assets Forfeiture Fund joint law enforcement operations funding during FY2016. </p> <p>(Sec. 217) Limits the use of specified DOJ funds until the Attorney General demonstrates to Congress that DOJ is implementing recommendations included in the Office of Inspector General report entitled &quot;The Handling of Sexual Harassment and Misconduct Allegations by the Department's Law Enforcement Components.&quot; Requires the DOJ Inspector General to report on the implementation. </p> <p><i>Science Appropriations Act, 2016 </i></p> <p>TITLE III--SCIENCE </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Office of Science and Technology Policy. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) for: </p> <ul> <li>Science; </li> <li>Aeronautics; </li> <li>Space Technology; </li> <li>Exploration; </li> <li>Space Operations; </li> <li>Education; </li> <li>Safety, Security, and Mission Services; </li> <li>Construction and Environmental Compliance and Restoration; and </li> <li>the Office of Inspector General. </li> </ul> <p>Includes administrative provisions for NASA that: </p> <ul> <li>Permit funds for any announced prize to remain available until the prize is claimed or the offer is withdrawn;</li> <li>Establish the terms and conditions for the transfer of appropriations provided by this bill; </li> <li>Require NASA to submit its spending plan at the theme, program, project, and activity level;</li> <li>Require the spending plan or subsequent changes to be subject to reprogramming procedures; </li> <li>Permit the transfer of unexpired balances under a previous account structure to the new account structure. </li> </ul> <p>Provides appropriations to the National Science Foundation (NSF) for: </p> <ul> <li>Research and Related Activities, </li> <li>Major Research Equipment and Facilities Construction, </li> <li>Education and Human Resources, </li> <li>Agency Operations and Award Management, </li> <li>the Office of the National Science Board, and </li> <li>the Office of the Inspector General.</li> </ul> <p>Establishes thresholds for the transfer of appropriations provided by this bill to the NSF. </p> <p>TITLE IV--RELATED AGENCIES </p> <p>Provides appropriations for the Commission on Civil Rights, the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, the U.S. International Trade Commission, the Legal Services Corporation, the Marine Mammal Commission, the Office of the U.S. Trade Representative, and the State Justice Institute. </p> <p>Specifies restrictions, terms, and conditions on the use of funds by the Legal Services Corporation. </p> <p>TITLE V--GENERAL PROVISIONS </p> <p>Sets forth permissible, restricted, and prohibited uses for funds provided by this and other appropriations Acts. </p> <p>(Sec. 501) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used for publicity or propaganda purposes that are not authorized by Congress. </p> <p>(Sec. 502) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from remaining available for obligation beyond the current fiscal year, unless expressly permitted in the bill. </p> <p>(Sec. 503) Limits expenditures for consulting services to contracts where the expenditures are a matter of public record and available for public inspection, unless otherwise provided by law. </p> <p>(Sec. 504) Provides that if any provision of this bill or the application of the provision is held invalid, the remainder of the bill is not affected. </p> <p>(Sec. 505) Establishes restrictions and requirements for the reprogramming of funds provided by this bill. </p> <p>(Sec. 506) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to award contracts or subcontracts to a person who has been found to have intentionally affixed a ''Made in America'' label to any product that was not made in America. Requires promotional items purchased using funds provided by this bill to be manufactured, produced, or assembled in the United States or its territories or possessions, to the extent it is practicable. </p> <p>(Sec. 507) Requires Commerce, DOJ, the NSF, and NASA to provide quarterly reports to Congress regarding the status of balances of appropriations at the account level. </p> <p>(Sec. 508) Requires costs incurred by agencies for personnel actions due to funding reductions in this bill to be absorbed within the budgetary resources available to the department or agency. Provides transfer authority between appropriation accounts to carry out this provision, subject to reprogramming procedures. Provides that, for the Department of Commerce, this section applies to actions taken for the care and protection of loan collateral or grant property. </p> <p>(Sec. 509) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to promote the sale or export of tobacco or tobacco products or to seek the reduction or removal of foreign restrictions on the marketing of tobacco products, except for restrictions which are not applied equally to all products of the same type. </p> <p>(Sec. 510) Limits the obligation of receipts deposited into the Crime Victims Fund during FY2016. </p> <p>(Sec. 511) Prohibits DOJ from using funds provided by this bill to discriminate against or denigrate the religious or moral beliefs of students or the parents of students participating in programs for which financial assistance is provided. </p> <p>(Sec. 512) Prohibits the transfer of funds provided by this bill to a department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States Government, unless the transfer is pursuant to an appropriations Act. </p> <p>(Sec. 513) Provides that funds included in this this bill to implement E-Government Initiatives are subject to reprogramming procedures and requirements. </p> <p>(Sec. 514) Establishes timetables and procedures for specified audits by Inspectors General of the departments and agencies funded in this bill. Requires recipients of grants or contracts funded by this bill to certify that no grant or contract funds will be provided to anyone with a financial interest in the recipient. </p> <p>(Sec. 515) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to acquire certain information systems unless the acquiring department or agency has reviewed specified issues related to supply chain risk and the risk of cyber-espionage or sabotage. </p> <p>Prohibits the use of funds provided by this bill to acquire a high-impact or moderate-impact information system reviewed and assessed under this section unless the department or agency has consulted with the NIST and the FBI to: (1) develop a mitigation strategy for any identified risks; (2) report to Congress and the agency Inspector General that the system is in the national interest. </p> <p>(Sec. 516) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to support or justify the use of torture by any official or contract employee of the U.S. government. </p> <p>(Sec. 517) Prohibits the use of funds to require export licenses for exporting components, parts, or attachments for certain firearms to Canada. </p> <p>(Sec. 518) Prohibits the use of funds to deny certain import applications for firearms, parts, or ammunition that are curios or relics. (Curios or relics are firearms which are of special interest to collectors by reason of some quality other than is associated with firearms intended for sporting use or as offensive or defensive weapons.) </p> <p>(Sec. 519) Prohibits the use of funds to include specified patent provisions from the United States-Singapore Free Trade Agreement, the United States-Australia Free Trade Agreement, or the United States-Morocco Free Trade Agreement in any new bilateral or multilateral trade agreement. </p> <p>(Sec. 520) Prohibits the use of funds provided by this bill to authorize or issue a National Security Letter (NSL) in violation of specified laws authorizing the FBI to issue an NSL. (An NSL is a written directive, comparable to an administrative subpoena, used by law enforcement and intelligence agencies to demand certain information from third parties such as telecommunication providers, financial institutions, and consumer credit reporting agencies.)</p> <p> (Sec. 521) Requires congressional notification regarding Commerce, DOJ, NSF, or NASA projects that total more than $75 million and are expected to have cost increases of at least 10%. </p> <p>(Sec. 522) Deems funds provided by this bill for intelligence or intelligence related activities as authorized by Congress during FY2016 until the enactment of the Intelligence Authorization Act for FY2016. </p> <p>(Sec. 523) Prohibits contracts or grant awards above $5 million unless the prospective contractor or grantee certifies that the organization has filed all federal tax returns, has not been convicted of a criminal offense under the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, and has no unpaid federal tax assessment. </p> <p>(Sec. 524) Rescinds specified unobligated balances from prior appropriations to Commerce and DOJ. </p> <p>(Sec. 525) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to purchase first class or premium airline travel in violation of specified federal travel regulations. </p> <p>(Sec. 526) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to pay for the attendance of more than 50 department or agency employees at any single conference outside the United States, unless it is a law enforcement training or operational event where the majority of federal attendees are law enforcement personnel stationed outside the United States. </p> <p>(Sec. 527) Prohibits funds from being used to transfer or release any individual detained at U.S. Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba (Guantanamo) who is not a U.S. citizen or member of the Armed Forces into the United States, its territories, or possessions. </p> <p>(Sec. 528) Prohibits funding from being used to construct, acquire, or modify any U.S. facility (other than the facility at Guantanamo Bay, Cuba) to house any individual detained at Guantanamo. </p> <p>(Sec. 529) Requires, to the extent it is practicable, funds provided by this bill to be used to purchase light bulbs that have the ''Energy Star'' or ''Federal Energy Management Program'' designation </p> <p>(Sec. 530) Requires the Office of Management and Budget to direct departments and agencies funded by this bill to track undisbursed balances in expired grant accounts and include specified details in annual performance and accountability reports. </p> <p>(Sec. 531) Prohibits NASA or the Office of Science and Technology Policy (OSTP) from using funds provided by this bill to: (1) engage in bilateral activities with China or a Chinese-owned company unless the activities are authorized by a law enacted after enactment of this bill, or (2) host official Chinese visitors at NASA facilities. Includes an exception if NASA or OSTP have made a specified certification to Congress regarding an activity. </p> <p>(Sec. 532) Prohibits funds from being used to deny the importation of shotgun models if no application for the importation of models in the same configuration had been denied prior to January 1, 2011, on the basis that the shotgun was not particularly suitable for or readily adaptable to sporting purposes. </p> <p>(Sec. 533) Prohibits the use of funds made available in this bill for a computer network that does not block pornography, except for law enforcement purposes </p> <p>(Sec. 534) Requires each department and agency funded in this bill to submit spending plans to Congress. </p> <p>(Sec. 535) Prohibits the use of funds provided by this bill to implement the Arms Trade Treaty regulating international trade in conventional arms until it is ratified by the Senate. </p> <p>(Sec. 536) Prohibits the use of funds provided by this bill to relinquish the responsibility of the National Telecommunications and Information Administration for Internet domain name system functions. </p> <p>(Sec. 537) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to require a person licensed for importing, manufacturing, or dealing in firearms to report information to DOJ regarding the sale of multiple rifles or shotguns to the same person. </p> <p>(Sec. 538) Requires Commerce, DOJ, NASA, and the NSF to provide Inspectors General with timely access to records, documents, and other materials. </p> <p>(Sec. 539) Requires Commerce, NASA, NSF, and the OSTP to report monthly to Congress on official travel of employees to China. </p> <p>(Sec. 540) Prohibit the use of funds provided by this bill to facilitate, permit, license, or promote exports to the Cuban military or intelligence service, officers of the Cuban military or intelligence service, or an immediate family member, with the exception of goods permitted under the Trade Sanctions Reform and Export Enhancement Act of 2000. </p> <p>(Sec. 541) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to shut down or prepare to shut down the Stratospheric Observatory for Infrared Astronomy. </p> <p>(Sec. 542) Establishes a spending reduction account for the amount by which the subcommittee's allocation under Section 302(b) of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 exceeds the amount of new budget authority proposed in the bill. Specifies that the amount is $0. (Under the Rules of the House of Representatives, any savings included in the spending reduction account are not available for further appropriation during consideration of the bill.) </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2578v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-05-29">
<action-date>2015-05-27</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Commerce, Justice, Science, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2016 </b></p> <p>Provides FY2016 appropriations to: the Department of Commerce; the Department of Justice (DOJ); science agencies, including the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) and the National Science Foundation (NSF); and several related agencies. </p> <p><i>Department of Commerce Appropriations Act, 2016 </i></p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Department of Commerce for the International Trade Administration, the Bureau of Industry and Security, the Economic Development Administration, the Minority Business Development Agency, Economics and Statistics Analysis, the Bureau of the Census, the National Telecommunications and Information Administration, the U.S Patent and Trademark Office, the National Institute of Standards and Technology, the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, and Departmental Management. </p> <p><i>Department of Justice Appropriations Act, 2016 </i></p> <p>Provides appropriations to DOJ for: General Administration; the U.S. Parole Commission; Legal Activities; the U.S. Marshals Service; the National Security Division; Interagency Law Enforcement; the Federal Bureau of Investigation; the Drug Enforcement Administration; the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives; and the Federal Prison System. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to DOJ for State and Local Law Enforcement Activities, including the Office on Violence Against Women, the Office of Justice Programs, and Community Oriented Policing Services (COPS). </p> <p><i>Science Appropriations Act, 2016 </i></p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Office of Science and Technology Policy, NASA, and the NSF. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to related agencies, including the Commission on Civil Rights, the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, the International Trade Commission, the Legal Services Corporation, the Marine Mammal Commission, the Office of the U.S. Trade Representative, and the State Justice Institute. </p> <p>Rescinds specified unobligated balances from prior appropriations to Commerce and DOJ. Sets forth permissible, restricted, and prohibited uses for funds provided by this and other appropriations Acts. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
