<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2281" measure-id="id114hr2281" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-12" update-date="2015-06-29">
<title>States' Education Reclamation Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2281v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-06-29">
<action-date>2015-05-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>States' Education Reclamation Act of 2015</b></p> <p>This bill abolishes the Department of Education (ED) and repeals any program for which it or the Secretary of Education has administrative responsibility.</p> <p>The Department of the Treasury (Treasury) shall provide grants to states, for FY2016-FY2024, for any: (1) elementary and secondary education purpose permitted by state law, and (2) postsecondary education purpose permitted by state law. The level of funding is set at the amount provided to states for federal elementary and secondary education programs and the amount provided for federal postsecondary education programs, respectively, for FY2012, minus the funding they were provided for education programs that this Act transfers to other federal agencies.</p> <p>States must contract for an annual audit of their expenditures or transfers of grant funds.</p> <p>Program administrative responsibility and delegation of authority are transferred as follows:</p> <ul> <li>ED's job training programs to the Department of Labor;</li> <li>each special education grant program under the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act to the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS);</li> <li>ED's Indian Education programs to the Department of the Interior;</li> <li>each Impact Aid program under the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to the Department of Defense; </li> <li>the Federal Pell Grant program and each federal student loan program to Treasury; and</li> <li> programs under the jurisdiction of the Institute of Education Sciences or the D.C. Opportunity Scholarship Program to HHS.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
