<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5752" measure-id="id114hr5752" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-07-13" update-date="2016-07-27">
<title>Pershing County Economic Development and Conservation Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5752v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-07-27">
<action-date>2016-07-13</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Pershing County Economic Development and Conservation Act</b></p> <p>This bill directs the Department of the Interior to conduct sales or exchanges of eligible lands in Pershing County, Nevada, identified as the &quot;Checkerboard Lands Resolution Area.&quot;</p> <p>Interior and the county shall jointly select which parcels of eligible land to offer for sale or acre-for-acre exchange. </p> <p>For purposes of acre-for-acre exchanges, Interior shall identify management priority areas within the Checkerboard Lands Resolution Area, including those considered to be:</p> <ul> <li> greater sage-grouse habitat;</li> <li> part of an identified wildlife corridor or designated critical habitat;</li> <li>of value for outdoor recreation or public access for hunting, fishing, and other recreational purposes;</li> <li>of significant cultural, historic, ecological, or scenic value; or</li> <li>of value for improving federal land management. </li> </ul> <p>The bill prescribes requirements for the disposition of proceeds from the sales of lands. </p> <p>Interior shall offer for sale and convey to specified qualified entities, for fair market value, the remaining U.S. right, title, and interest in certain lands and interests in the county. </p> <p>Interior shall convey to the county, without consideration, Unionville Cemetery. </p> <p>The bill designates specified federal land in Nevada as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System. </p> <p>The bill releases specified wilderness study areas from further review for designation as wilderness. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
