<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3334" measure-id="id114hr3334" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-07-29" update-date="2015-12-21">
<title>Families Flying Together Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3334v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-12-21">
<action-date>2015-07-29</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Families Flying Together Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>This bill directs the Department of Transportation to issue regulations directing each air carrier to: (1) establish a policy to ensure that a family that purchases tickets for a flight is seated together during that flight, and (2) make the policy available to the public on the air carrier's website. The bill defines "family" to mean a grouping of individuals that includes, at a minimum: (1) a child age 12 years or younger, and (2) an individual age 18 years or older who is responsible for accompanying that child.</p> <p>The bill makes it an unfair or deceptive practice for any ticket agent, air carrier, foreign air carrier, or other person offering to sell tickets for air transportation to fail to disclose, prior to an individual's purchase of more than one ticket for a covered flight that includes a ticket for a minor, a notification that: (1) it is not possible to assign two or more seats together on at least one of the flights selected,&nbsp;and (2) the individual may not be able to sit next to other members of his or her travel party even if he or she is traveling with a minor. The term "covered flight" is defined as a flight for which: (1) a purchaser of a ticket may specify an advance seat assignment, with or without the assessment of any charge or fee; and (2) two or more laterally adjacent seats are not available for advance assignment.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
