<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2534" measure-id="id114hr2534" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-21" update-date="2015-06-04">
<title>SCAN Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2534v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-06-04">
<action-date>2015-05-21</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Scan Containers Absolutely Now Act or the SCAN Act</b></p> <p> Amends the Security and Accountability For Every Port Act of 2006 to direct the Secretary of Homeland Security to: </p> <ul> <li> conduct a one-year pilot program at two domestic ports to evaluate the process of 100% scanning of cargo containers and its potential for use at all domestic ports, </li> <li> achieve a full-scale implementation of the program within one year after enactment of this Act, and </li> <li> evaluate and report on such program within one year after program completion.</li> </ul> <p>Requires the Secretary to: </p> <ul> <li> acquire the equipment necessary to conduct the pilot program, </li> <li> make information about the equipment available to domestic ports as part of the application process, and </li> <li> permit such equipment to remain with the selected ports upon completion of the program. </li> </ul> <p>Authorizes the Secretary to purchase or lease equipment for, as well as contract for performance of scanning of cargo under, the program.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
