<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5686" measure-id="id114hr5686" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-07-08" update-date="2016-08-25">
<title>Pink Tax Repeal Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5686v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-08-25">
<action-date>2016-07-08</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Pink Tax Repeal Act</b></p> <p>This bill prohibits the sale of substantially similar services or consumer products from the same manufacturer if they are priced differently based on the gender of the individuals to whom the products are marketed or intended or for whom the services are marketed, performed, or offered. </p> <p>A difference in coloring among consumer products shall not be construed as a substantial difference.</p> <p>Violations shall be treated as unfair or deceptive act or practice under the Federal Trade Commission Act.</p> <p>The Federal Trade Commission and state attorneys general are authorized to enforce against such violations.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
