<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2769" measure-id="id114hr2769" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-06-15" update-date="2015-09-21">
<title>Risk-Based Capital Study Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2769v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-09-21">
<action-date>2015-06-15</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Risk-Based Capital Study Act of 2015</b></p> <p>This bill directs the National Credit Union Administration (NCUA) to study the appropriate capital requirements for federal credit unions and state credit unions, including: </p> <ul> <li> whether the NCUA has the clear legal authority to prescribe separate risk-based capital thresholds for both &quot;adequately capitalized&quot; and &quot;well capitalized&quot; credit unions; </li> <li> a discussion of the differences between credit unions and other types of depository institutions and reasons why they should have similar or different risk-weights for their capital requirements; </li> <li>a discussion of the rationale behind the risk-weights assigned in the proposed NCUA rule &quot;Risk-Based Capital&quot;; and </li> <li> an analysis of the impact the proposed rule would have upon excess capital above the minimum level for a credit union to be &quot;well capitalized&quot; (a credit union's &quot;capital cushion&quot;), including the potential impact upon credit union lending and credit union examinations. </li> </ul> <p>A credit union may not be required to provide information regarding the capital standards sought in the NCUA study, but may provide it voluntarily. </p>  <p>The NCUA may not issue or implement any final rule or regulation governing risk-based capital (including the proposed rule) earlier than 120 days after it reports to Congress on the study. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
