<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3023" measure-id="id114hr3023" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-07-10" update-date="2016-04-19">
<title>To amend title 5, United States Code, to modify probationary periods with respect to positions within the competitive service and the Senior Executive Service, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3023v79" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-04-19">
<action-date>2016-03-23</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p>(Sec. 1) This bill requires the probationary period before an appointment in the competitive civil service or an initial appointment as a supervisor or manager becomes final to be: (1) with respect to any position that requires formal training, a period of two years beginning on the date that such training is completed; (2) with respect to any position that requires a license, a period of two years beginning on the date that such license is granted; and (3) with respect to any other position, at least two years. The probationary period for a preference eligible (i.e., a veteran)&nbsp;initially appointed to a position that exists as of 180 days after the enactment of this Act shall not be longer than the period that applies on such date. The probationary period for a preference eligible appointed to a position that does not exist on such date shall not be longer than the length of time the President establishes.</p> <p>Each agency must ensure that: (1) announcements of vacant positions and offers of appointment clearly state the terms and conditions of the probationary period,&nbsp;(2) individuals who are required to complete probationary periods receive timely notice of requirements to successfully complete the probationary period, and&nbsp;(3) certification of such successful completion is made.</p> <p>(Sec. 2) The bill increases from one to two years the probationary period after which an individual's appointment as a career appointee in the Senior Executive Service becomes final.</p> <p>(Sec. 3) The definition of "employee" for purposes of adverse action provisions is revised to mean an individual in the competitive service or in the excepted service who has completed at least two years (currently, one year) of current continuous service in the same or a similar position.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3023v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-12-21">
<action-date>2015-07-10</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill requires the probationary period before an appointment in the competitive civil service or an initial appointment as a supervisor or manager becomes final to be: (1) with respect to any position that requires formal training, a period of two years beginning on the date that such training is completed; (2) with respect to any position that requires a license, a period of two years beginning on the date that such license is granted; and (3) with respect to any other position, at least two years. The probationary period for a preference eligible (i.e., a veteran)&nbsp;initially appointed to a position that exists as of 180 days after the enactment of this Act shall not be longer than the period that applies on such date. The probationary period for a preference eligible appointed to a position that does not exist on such date shall not be longer than the length of time the President establishes.</p> <p>Each agency must ensure that: (1) announcements of vacant positions and offers of appointment clearly state the terms and conditions of the probationary period,&nbsp;(2) individuals who are required to complete probationary periods receive timely notice of requirements to successfully complete the probationary period, and&nbsp;(3) certification of such successful completion is made.</p> <p>The bill increases from one to two years the probationary period after which an individual's appointment as a career appointee in the Senior Executive Service becomes final.</p> <p>The definition of "employee" for purposes of adverse action provisions is revised to mean an individual in the competitive service or in the excepted service who has completed at least two years (currently, one year) of current continuous service in the same or a similar position.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
