<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="653" measure-id="id114hr653" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-02-02" update-date="2016-02-09">
<title>FOIA Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr653v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-02-09">
<action-date>2016-01-11</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>FOIA Oversight and Implementation Act of 2016 or the FOIA Act</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) to: </p> <ul> <li>require federal agencies to make information that is disclosable under such Act available to the public in an electronic, publicly accessible format; </li> <li>make available to the public copies of all releasable records under FOIA that have been requested three or more times or that inform the public of the operations and activities of the government; </li> <li>require agencies to provide the name, phone number, and email address of an agency employee who can provide current information about the status of a FOIA request;</li> <li>require the Office of Management and Budget to ensure the operation of a consolidated online request portal that allows a member of the public to submit a FOIA request for records from a single website; </li> <li>require agencies, at a minimum, to provide an email address at which FOIA requests are accepted and to publish such email address on the agency website; </li> <li>establish a presumption of openness in administering FOIA by prohibiting an agency from withholding information otherwise disclosable under FOIA unless the agency reasonably foresees that disclosure would cause identifiable harm to an interest protected by a FOIA exemption or if the disclosure is prohibited by law; </li> <li>require agencies to identify the statute that exempts a record from disclosure; </li> <li>exempt from disclosure under FOIA records or information that would adversely affect intelligence sources and methods that are protected by a FOIA exemption;</li> <li>prohibit agencies from denying requests from Congress for information based upon a FOIA exemption; </li> <li>limit the FOIA exemption for agency communications to 25 years after the creation of records and information and require agency disclosure of opinions that are controlling interpretations of law, final reports or memoranda solicited and used to make a final policy decision, and guidance documents used to respond to the public; and</li> <li>require mandatory awards of attorney fees and litigation costs to prevailing parties in FOIA proceedings.</li> </ul> <p>The bill expands the duties and reporting requirements of the Office of Government Information Services (OGIS). Requires the OGIS to: (1) identify categories of records that would be appropriate for proactive disclosure, (2) offer mediation services for disputed FOIA requests, (3) make its annual reports available in an electronic, publicly accessible format, and (4) hold annual public meetings.</p> <p>The bill:</p> <ul> <li>requires agencies that consult with any entity with substantial interests in the determination of a FOIA request to notify the consulted party of need to consult in writing and the consultation requester of specified information about the consultation process;</li> <li>prohibits agencies from assessing search or duplication fees if they have failed to comply with a statutory deadline for a FOIA request, with limited exceptions for unusual circumstances and FOIA requests of more than 3,000 pages; </li> <li>expands the role of agency Chief FOIA officers to require such officers to serve as the primary liaison between the OGIS and the Office of Information Policy;</li> <li>establishes a Chief FOIA Officers Council for developing recommendations to increase FOIA compliance; </li> <li>requires each agency to review its FOIA regulations within 180 days after the enactment of this Act and issue regulations on procedures for the disclosure of records under FOIA, for engaging in dispute resolution, and for engaging with the OGIS; and</li> <li>requires the Government Accountability Office to conduct, and report on, a study of the feasibility of requiring non-custodians to search for records to respond to FOIA requests. </li> </ul> <p>(Sec. 3) The bill requires the Inspector General of each federal agency to: (1) periodically review agency compliance with FOIA, including regarding the timely processing of requests, the assessment of fees and fee waivers, and the use of FOIA exemptions; and (2) make recommendations to each agency, including for disciplinary action. This review must be completed and recommendations made not less than once every two years. </p> <p>(Sec. 4) No additional funds are authorized to carry out the requirements of this Act.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr653v17" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-02-09">
<action-date>2016-01-07</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>FOIA Oversight and Implementation Act of 2015 or the FOIA Act</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) to: </p> <ul> <li>require federal agencies to make information that is disclosable under such Act available to the public in an electronic, publicly accessible format; </li> <li>make available to the public copies of all releasable records under FOIA that have been requested three or more times or that inform the public of the operations and activities of the government; </li> <li>require the Office of Management and Budget to ensure the operation of a consolidated online request portal that allows a member of the public to submit a FOIA request for records from a single website; </li> <li>require agencies to provide an email address at which FOIA requests are accepted and publish such email address on the agency website; </li> <li>establish a presumption of openness in administering FOIA by prohibiting an agency from withholding information otherwise disclosable under FOIA unless the agency reasonably foresees that disclosure would cause identifiable harm to an interest protected by a FOIA exemption or if the disclosure is prohibited by law;</li> <li>limit the FOIA exemption for agency communications to 25 years after the creation of a record and require agency disclosure of opinions that are controlling interpretations of law, final reports or memoranda solicited and used to make a final policy decision, and guidance documents used to respond to the public; and</li> <li>require mandatory awards of attorney fees and litigation costs to prevailing parties in FOIA proceedings.</li> </ul> <p>The bill expands the duties and reporting requirements of the Office of Government Information Services (OGIS). Requires the OGIS to: (1) offer mediation services for disputed FOIA requests, (2) make its annual reports available in an electronic, publicly accessible format, and (3) hold annual public meetings.</p> <p>The bill:</p> <ul> <li>prohibits agencies from assessing search or duplication fees if they have failed to comply with a statutory deadline for a FOIA request and did not submit a written notice to the FOIA requestor justifying the fees; </li> <li>expands the role of agency Chief FOIA officers to require such officers to serve as the primary liaison between the OGIS and the Office of Information Policy;</li> <li>establishes a Chief FOIA Officers Council for developing recommendations to increase FOIA compliance; and </li> <li>requires each agency to review its FOIA regulations within 180 days after the enactment of this Act and issue regulations on procedures for the disclosure of records under FOIA, for engaging in dispute resolution, and for engaging with the OGIS. </li> </ul> <p>(Sec. 3) The Inspector General of each federal agency must periodically review agency compliance with FOIA and make recommendations to each agency, including recommendations for disciplinary action. The bill makes the wrongful withholding of information under FOIA the basis for disciplinary action. </p> <p>(Sec. 4) No additional funds are authorized to carry out the requirements of this Act.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr653v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-03-10">
<action-date>2015-02-02</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>FOIA Oversight and Implementation Act of 2015 or the FOIA Act</strong></p> <p>This bill makes changes to the Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) to provide the public with greater access to information disclosable under such Act. </p> <p>The bill requires agencies, in administering FOIA, to: (1) make information disclosable under such Act available to the public in an electronic, publicly accessible format; and (2) make available to the public records of general interest that inform the public of the operations and activities of the government or that have been requested three or more times.</p> <p>The Office of Management and Budget is directed to ensure the operation of an online request portal that allows a member of the public to submit a FOIA request for records to any agency from a single website.</p> <p>The bill establishes a presumption of openness by prohibiting an agency from withholding information otherwise disclosable under FOIA unless: (1) the agency reasonably foresees that disclosure would cause specific identifiable harm to an interest protected by an exemption to FOIA, or (2) disclosure is prohibited by law. </p> <p>The duties of the Office of Government Information Services (OGIS) are expanded to require: (1) mediation services to resolve disputes between agencies and persons making FOIA requests; (2) annual reports on the activities of OGIS that are available in an electronic, publicly accessible format; and (3) annual public meetings on the review of agencies' FOIA policies, procedures, and compliance. </p> <p>The bill requires annual agency FOIA reports and the annual reports on FOIA of the Attorney General and the Director of the Office of Information Policy (OIP) to be made available in an electronic, publicly accessible format. </p> <p>Agencies are prohibited from assessing search or duplication fees if they have failed to comply with a statutory deadline for a FOIA response and did not submit a written notice to the requestor justifying the fees requested. </p> <p>The role of the Chief FOIA Officer at each agency is expanded to require officers to serve as the primary agency liaison between OGIS and OIP and to complete annual compliance determinations that review agency regulations, fee assessments, use of exemptions, dispute resolution services, and the timely processing of FOIA requests. </p> <p>The bill establishes a Chief FOIA Officers Council for developing recommendations for increasing compliance and efficiency, disseminating information about agency experiences, identifying initiatives to increase transparency and compliance, and promoting performance measures to ensure agency compliance with FOIA requirements.</p> <p>The Inspector General of each agency is required to: (1) periodically review compliance with FOIA requirements, including the timely processing of requests, assessment of fees and fee waivers, and the use of FOIA exemptions, and (2) make recommendations to the agency head, including recommendations for disciplinary action. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
