<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4666" measure-id="id114hr4666" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-03-02" update-date="2016-07-11">
<title>Protecting Students from Sexual and Violent Predators Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4666v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-07-11">
<action-date>2016-03-02</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Protecting Students from Sexual and Violent Predators Act</strong></p> <p>This bill requires a&nbsp;state or local educational agency (LEA) that receives funds under the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to: </p> <ul> <li>require, for each school employee, a criminal background check that includes a search of specified registries and repositories; </li> <li>prohibit the employment of an individual who refuses to consent to, or who makes a false statement in connection with, a background check or who has been convicted of&nbsp;one of&nbsp;specified crimes; </li> <li>require background checks to be periodically repeated or updated in accordance with state law or LEA policies; </li> <li>provide a school employee&nbsp;with a timely process to appeal the results of a background check; </li> <li>ensure that such policies and procedures are published on state and LEA websites; and </li> <li>allow an LEA to share the results of a school employee's&nbsp;recent background check with another LEA that is considering that individual for employment. </li></ul> <p></s /></p> <p></s /></p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
