<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2311" measure-id="id114hr2311" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-13" update-date="2015-05-21">
<title>Functional Gastrointestinal and Motility Disorders Research Enhancement Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2311v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-05-21">
<action-date>2015-05-13</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Functional Gastrointestinal and Motility Disorders Research Enhancement Act of 2015</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Public Health Service Act to require the National Institutes of Health to expand, intensify, and coordinate its activities with respect to functional gastrointestinal and motility disorders (FGIMDs), including by:</p> <ul> <li>expanding basic and clinical research into FGIMDs by implementing the research recommendations of the National Commission on Digestive Diseases,</li> <li>providing support for the establishment of centers of excellence on FGIMDs,</li> <li>supporting innovative approaches to educating health care providers and patients regarding strategies that improve patient-provider relationships and care,</li> <li>directing the National Institute of Diabetes and Digestive and Kidney Diseases (NIDDK) to provide the necessary funding for the continued expansion and advancement of the FGIMDs research portfolio, and</li> <li>directing NIDDK and the Eunice Kennedy Shriver National Institute of Child Health and Human Development to expand research into FGIMDs that impact children.</li> </ul> <p>The Department of Health and Human Services may engage in public awareness and education activities to increase understanding and recognition of FGIMDs.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
