<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5256" measure-id="id114hr5256" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-05-16" update-date="2016-08-12">
<title>Expanding DHS Overseas Passenger Security Screening and Vetting Operations Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5256v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-08-12">
<action-date>2016-05-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Expanding DHS Overseas Passenger Security Screening and Vetting Operations Act</strong></p> <p>This bill requires the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to report to Congress:</p> <ul> <li>a comprehensive five-year strategy for international programs or operations of U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP) or U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement that are targeted at vetting and screening persons seeking to enter the United States and in which DHS personnel and resources are deployed abroad; </li> <li>annually with the President's budget request for each fiscal year through FY2022, an implementation plan based on such strategy; </li> <li>a plan for expanding, within five years, the Visa Security Program in a risk-based manner, and a plan for deploying the Pre-Adjudicated Threat Recognition and Intelligence Operations Team program, to at least 50 U.S. diplomatic and consular posts that issue visas; and </li> <li>a plan for expanding participation in trusted traveler programs. </li></ul> <p>CBP shall increase the numbers of CBP officers and Agriculture Specialists for each of FY2017-FY2018. </p> <p>The bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to establish within CBP the Immigration Cooperation Program, under which CBP may cooperate with foreign authorities, air carriers, and security employees at foreign airports to identify persons who may be inadmissible to the United States or otherwise pose a risk to U.S. security.</p> <p>The Government Accountability Office shall review and report on the adequacy and appropriateness of the security screening process for each U.S. nonimmigrant visa category.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
