<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3159" measure-id="id114hr3159" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-07-22" update-date="2016-01-04">
<title>Kerrie Orozco Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3159v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-01-04">
<action-date>2015-07-22</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Kerrie Orozco Act</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to declare that the following persons may be naturalized upon compliance with all naturalization requirements, except that no prior residence or specified physical presence within the United States shall be required:</p> <ul> <li>a person who is the surviving spouse, child, or parent of a U.S. citizen who died as a result of injury or disease incurred in or aggravated by employment as a first responder; and</li> <li>in the case of such a surviving spouse, the person was living in marital union with the citizen spouse at the time of the citizen spouse's death. </li> </ul> <p>The Department of Homeland Security shall provide for the granting of posthumous citizenship at the time of death to a person who, while an alien or a noncitizen national of the United States, died as a result of injury or disease incurred or aggravated while serving as a first responder.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
