<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2563" measure-id="id114hr2563" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-21" update-date="2015-06-04">
<title>State and Local Predatory Towing Enforcement Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2563v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-06-04">
<action-date>2015-05-21</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>State and Local Predatory Towing Enforcement Act</b></p> <p> Waives federal preemption to allow states to regulate tow truck operations performed without the prior consent or authorization of the owner or operator of the towed motor vehicle.</p> <p>(Currently, states are allowed to regulate only the price of for-hire motor vehicle transportation by a tow truck, if such transportation is performed without the prior consent or authorization of the owner or operator of the motor vehicle.)</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
