<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4725" measure-id="id114hr4725" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-03-10" update-date="2016-11-03">
<title>Common Sense Savings Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4725v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-11-03">
<action-date>2016-03-10</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Common Sense Savings Act of 2016</strong></p> <p>This bill amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act (SSAct) to specify how a state must treat&nbsp;qualified lottery winnings and lump sum income for purposes of determining an individual's income-based eligibility for a state Medicaid program. Specifically, a state shall include such winnings or income as income received: (1) in the month in which it was received, if the amount is less than $60,000; (2) over a period of two months, if the amount is at least $60,000 but less than $70,000; (3) over a period of three months, if the amount is at least $70,000 but less than $80,000; and (4) over an additional one-month period for each increment of $10,000 received, not to exceed 120 months.</p> <p>Qualified lump sum income includes: (1) monetary winnings from gambling; (2) damages&nbsp;received&nbsp;in lump sums or periodic payments,&nbsp;excluding monthly payments, on account of causes of action other than those arising from personal physical injuries or sickness; and (3) income received as liquid assets from the estate of a deceased individual.</p> <p>In addition, the&nbsp;bill eliminates the enhanced Federal&nbsp;Medical Assistance Percentage (FMAP)&nbsp;with respect to the coverage of&nbsp;individuals who are inmates in public institutions.&nbsp;Under current law, the enhanced FMAP&nbsp;applies to coverage of individuals who are newly eligible for Medicaid under the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (PPACA).</p> <p>The bill also amends title XXI (Children's Health Insurance Program [CHIP]) of the SSAct to terminate increases to the enhanced FMAP as established by the PPACA with respect to CHIP.</p> <p>Under current law, federal Medicaid reimbursement to states is reduced in proportion to any impermissible state taxes collected from health care providers. The bill lowers a percentage threshold used to determine whether such taxes are impermissible. </p> <p>The bill terminates the Prevention and Public Health Fund.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
