<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4050" measure-id="id114hr4050" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-11-17" update-date="2016-02-12">
<title>Passenger Train Derailment Prevention Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4050v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-02-12">
<action-date>2015-11-17</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Passenger Train Derailment Prevention Act</strong></p> <p>This bill requires each railroad carrier on whose tracks an entity provides regularly scheduled intercity rail passenger transportation or commuter rail passenger transportation to submit to the Department of Transportation (DOT) a list identifying each curve, bridge, tunnel, or other location where the maximum authorized operating speed for such a passenger train is at least 20 miles per hour less than the maximum approach speed. DOT must provide such information, along with a list of any additional track locations that DOT identifies as dangerous, to specified congressional committees.</p> <p>DOT shall exercise its emergency authority to require:</p> <ul> <li>each such entity using a train equipped with an automatic train control system to modify such system to automatically slow down the train if it fails to comply with applicable maximum authorized speed limits at such locations,</li> <li> each such entity using a train not equipped with such system to provide that the train movement through such locations be made with a second qualified crew member in the cab of the controlling locomotive or with constant communication between the locomotive engineer and an additional crew member in the body of the train, and </li> <li> each such railroad carrier to install additional wayside signage along the carrier's tracks alerting engineers and conductors of the maximum authorized passenger train speed.</li> </ul> <p>DOT may exempt from these requirements any segment of track for which operations are governed by a certified positive train control system or equivalent safety technology.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
