<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4915" measure-id="id114hr4915" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-04-12" update-date="2016-07-18">
<title>Civil War Defenses of Washington National Historical Park Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4915v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-07-18">
<action-date>2016-04-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Civil War Defenses of Washington National Historical Park Act</b></p> <p> This bill designates as the Civil War Defenses of Washington National Historical Park the defenses constructed at the beginning of the Civil War in 1861 as a ring of fortifications in the District of Columbia, Maryland, and northern Virginia to protect the nation's capital. </p> <p> The park shall include all areas associated with the Civil War defenses of Washington currently owned by the federal government and under the administration of the National Park Service, including Battleground National Cemetery. </p> <p> Certain eligible sites and certain additional sites associated with the Civil War defenses of Washington may become affiliated with the park pursuant to a cooperative agreement under this bill. </p> <p> The Department of the Interior shall study and consider creative and cost-effective ways to facilitate how the storied history of the Civil War for both the North and the South, including the history of the defenses of Washington and the Shenandoah Valley Campaign of 1864, can be assembled, arrayed, and conveyed for the benefit of the public.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
