<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3320" measure-id="id114hr3320" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-07-29" update-date="2015-09-08">
<title>Timely Payment for Veterans' Medical Care Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3320v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-09-08">
<action-date>2015-07-29</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Timely Payment for Veterans' Medical Care Act</strong></p> <p>This bill authorizes the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to enter into contracts with an eligible entity to serve as an administrative contractor with respect to the performance of any or all of the following functions relating to providing medical care and hospital services in non-VA facilities: </p> <ul> <li>determining and making the payments required to be made to a non-VA facility;</li> <li>providing education and outreach to individuals enrolled in the patient enrollment system; </li> <li>providing consultative services to institutions, agencies, and other persons to enable them to maintain necessary fiscal records; </li> <li>communicating to non-VA facilities any information or instructions furnished to the administrative contractor by the VA; and </li> <li>performing functions relating to non-VA facility education, training, and technical assistance.</li> </ul> <p>An administrative contractor that performs such payment-related functions shall implement a contractor-wide information security program.</p> <p>The VA shall use claims payment error rates or similar methodology of administrative contractors in the processing or reviewing of claims in order to give such contractors an incentive to implement effective education and outreach programs for non-VA facilities.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
