<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3384" measure-id="id114hr3384" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-07-29" update-date="2016-06-27">
<title>Quiet Communities Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3384v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-06-27">
<action-date>2015-07-29</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Quiet Communities Act of 2015</b></p> <p>This bill requires the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to reestablish an Office of Noise Abatement and Control and reauthorizes the Office's activities through FY2020. </p> <p>The responsibilities of the Office must include: (1) promoting the development of effective state and local noise control programs, (2) carrying out a national noise control research program, (3) carrying out a national noise environmental assessment program, (4) establishing regional technical assistance centers to assist state and local noise control programs, (5) assessing the effectiveness of the Noise Control Act of 1972, and (6) conducting related outreach and educational activities. The Office must emphasize noise abatement approaches that rely on local and state activities, market incentives, and coordination with other agencies.</p> <p>Using funds made available to the Office, the EPA must carry out a study of airport noise. </p> <p>The bill amends the Noise Control Act of 1972 to expand the quiet communities grant program to include grants for establishing and implementing training programs on use of noise abatement equipment and implementing noise abatement plans.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
