<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5882" measure-id="id114hr5882" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-07-14" update-date="2016-08-25">
<title>Freedom Riders National Historical Park Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5882v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-08-25">
<action-date>2016-07-14</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Freedom Riders National Historical Park Act</b></p> <p>This bill establishes the Freedom Riders National Historical Park in Anniston, Alabama, for the purposes of: (1) arranging for an internationally significant place for public education focused on the Freedom Riders (civil rights activists who rode a Greyhound bus attacked and burned in Anniston on May 14, 1961), Civil Rights, and the burning of the Freedom Riders' bus; and (2) preserving such historical site for the heritage of that area and as a tourist destination. </p> <p>The park shall be located at 1031 Gurnee Avenue in downtown Anniston at the Greyhound Bus Station site where the attack began and includes the site of the original bus station.</p> <p>The Department of the Interior may acquire, by donation, transfer, or exchange only, additional buildings, assets, lands, and interests for addition to the park. </p> <p>Interior shall complete a general management plan for the park. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
