<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2490" measure-id="id114hr2490" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-21" update-date="2015-10-26">
<title>Bertie's Respect for National Cemeteries Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2490v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-10-26">
<action-date>2015-05-21</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Bertie's Respect for National Cemeteries Act</strong></p> <p>This bill requires the appropriate federal official to take every reasonable action, including by searching public records, to ensure that a person who will be interred in a cemetery in the National Cemetery Administration or in Arlington National Cemetery is not ineligible for such interment by reason of having been convicted of a federal or state capital crime or a tier III sex offense.</p> <p>The bill applies the requirement of the Alicia Dawn Koehl Respect for National Cemeteries Act for a written notice of a disqualifying felony conviction with respect to any interment or memorialization conducted, either before or after enactment of that Act.</p> <p>The Department of Veterans Affairs shall: (1) disinter the remains of George E. Siple from Indiantown Gap National Cemetery (Pennsylvania); (2) notify his next of kin of the impending disinterment; and (3) upon disinterment, relinquish the remains to the next of kin or, if the next of kin of record is unavailable, arrange for the appropriate disposition of the remains.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
