<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3894" measure-id="id114hr3894" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-11-03" update-date="2016-02-10">
<title>To amend title 10, United States Code, to require the prompt notification of State Child Protective Services by military and civilian personnel of the Department of Defense required by law to report suspected instances of child abuse and neglect.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3894v81" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-02-10">
<action-date>2016-02-09</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p>(Sec. 1) This bill directs a member of the Armed Forces, a civilian Department of Defense (DOD) employee, or a contractor employee working on a military installation who is required by federal regulation or state law to report known or suspected instances of child abuse and neglect to make the report directly to State Child Protective Services or another appropriate state agency in addition to the member's or employee's chain of command or any designated DOD point of contact. </p> <p>DOD shall ensure that such individuals receive appropriate training in accordance with state guidelines to improve their: (1) ability to recognize evidence of child abuse and neglect, and (2) understanding of mandatory reporting requirements.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3894v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-11-17">
<action-date>2015-11-03</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill directs a member of the Armed Forces, a civilian Department of Defense (DOD) employee, or a contractor employee working on a military installation who is required by federal regulation or state law to report known or suspected instances of child abuse and neglect to make the report directly to State Child Protective Services or another appropriate state agency in addition to the member's or employee's chain of command or any designated DOD point of contact. </p> <p>DOD shall ensure that such individuals receive appropriate training in accordance with state guidelines to improve their: (1) ability to recognize evidence of child abuse and neglect, and (2) understanding of mandatory reporting requirements.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
