<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1195" measure-id="id114hr1195" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-03-02" update-date="2015-04-29">
<title>Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection Advisory Boards Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1195v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-04-29">
<action-date>2015-04-22</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection Advisory Boards Act</b> </p> <p> (Sec. 2) Amends the Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010 to direct the Director of the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau (CFPB) to establish a Small Business Advisory Board to: (1) advise and consult with the CFPB in the exercise of its functions under the federal consumer financial laws regarding eligible financial products or services, and (2) provide information on evolving small business practices.</p> <p>Requires Board members to be representatives of small business concerns that:</p> <ul> <li> provide financial products or services for use by consumers primarily for personal, family, or household purposes, </li> <li> are service providers to covered persons; and </li> <li> use consumer financial products or services in financing the business activities of such small businesses.</li> </ul> <p>Requires the Director, in making such Board appointments, to include members representing minority-, women-, and veteran-owned small business concerns and their interests, without regard to party affiliation. </p> <p>Requires the Director to establish a Credit Union Advisory Council and a Community Bank Advisory Council to advise and consult with the CFPB on consumer financial products or services that impact credit unions and community banks, respectively.</p> <p> Directs the Director, in making appointments to the Councils, to include members representing credit unions and community banks predominantly serving traditionally underserved communities and populations and their interests, without regard to party affiliation.</p> <p>(Sec. 3) Prohibits the Director from requesting funds: (1) during FY 2020 in an amount that would exceed $655 million, and (2) during FY 2025 in an amount that would exceed $720 million.</p> <p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1195v79" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-04-07">
<action-date>2015-04-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.)</p> <p><b>Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection Advisory Boards Act</b> </p> <p> Amends the Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010 to direct the Director of the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau (CFPB) to establish a Small Business Advisory Board to: (1) advise and consult with the CFPB in the exercise of its functions under the federal consumer financial laws regarding eligible financial products or services, and (2) provide information on evolving small business practices.</p> <p>Requires such Board members to be representatives of small business concerns that:</p> <ul> <li> provide financial products or services for use by consumers primarily for personal, family, or household purposes, </li> <li> are service providers to covered persons; and </li> <li> use consumer financial products or services in financing the business activities of such small businesses.</li> </ul> <p>Encourages the Director, in making such Board appointments, to ensure the participation of minority- and women-owned small business concerns and their interests, without regard to party affiliation. </p> <p>Instructs the Director to establish a Credit Union Advisory Council and a Community Bank Advisory Council to advise and consult with the CFPB on consumer financial products or services that impact credit unions and community banks, respectively.</p> <p>Encourages the Director, in making appointments to such Councils, to ensure the participation of credit unions and community banks predominantly serving traditionally underserved communities and populations and their interests, without regard to party affiliation.</p> <p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1195v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-03-25">
<action-date>2015-03-02</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection Advisory Boards Act</b> </p> <p> Amends the Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010 to direct the Director of the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau (CFPB) to establish a Small Business Advisory Board to: (1) advise and consult with the CFPB in the exercise of its functions under the federal consumer financial laws regarding eligible financial products or services, and (2) provide information on evolving small business practices.</p> <p>Requires such Board members to be representatives of small business concerns that:</p> <ul> <li> provide financial products or services for use by consumers primarily for personal, family, or household purposes, </li> <li> are service providers to covered persons; and </li> <li> use consumer financial products or services in financing the business activities of such small businesses.</li> </ul> <p>Encourages the Director, in making such Board appointments, to ensure the participation of minority- and women-owned small business concerns and their interests, without regard to party affiliation. </p> <p>Instructs the Director to establish a Credit Union Advisory Council and a Community Bank Advisory Council to advise and consult with the CFPB on consumer financial products or services that impact credit unions and community banks, respectively.</p> <p>Encourages the Director, in making appointments to such Councils, to ensure the participation of credit unions and community banks predominantly serving traditionally underserved communities and populations and their interests, without regard to party affiliation.</p> <p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
