<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3481" measure-id="id114hr3481" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-09-10" update-date="2016-07-12">
<title>PRIDE Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3481v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-07-12">
<action-date>2015-09-10</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Police Reporting Information, Data, and Evidence Act of 2015 or the PRIDE Act</b></p> <p>This bill directs the Department of Justice (DOJ) to award grants to state and tribal governments to report information about, promote public awareness of, and train law enforcement personnel on shooting incidents and use-of-force incidents involving a law enforcement officer and a civilian.</p> <p>A grant-eligible state or tribal government must demonstrate that its law enforcement use-of-force policy is publicly available.</p> <p>DOJ must audit incident reports, determine grantees' compliance with information requirements, and publish a report that contains reported data.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
