<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3521" measure-id="id114hr3521" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-09-16" update-date="2016-07-19">
<title>Gulf Red Snapper Data Improvement Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3521v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-07-19">
<action-date>2015-09-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Gulf Red Snapper Data Improvement Act</b></p> <p>This bill requires the National Marine Fisheries Service Southeast Regional Office to award grants for data collection that is used in stock assessments for reef fish species in the Gulf of Mexico, including the red snapper. In awarding grants, the Office must seek to improve stock assessments through innovative approaches to data collection that incorporates data from peer-reviewed research involving academia, fishermen, and other fisheries sources.</p> <p>The Department of Commerce must: (1) seek to improve communications by the National Marine Fisheries Service with stakeholders regarding the reef fish species stock assessment processes and outcomes of those processes, and (2) develop a process for using data collected through cooperative research activities for those stock assessments.</p> <ul> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
