<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4409" measure-id="id114hr4409" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-02-01" update-date="2016-05-06">
<title>Made in America Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4409v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-05-06">
<action-date>2016-02-01</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Made in America Act of 2016</b></p> <p>This bill directs the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to establish labels that persons or businesses may use voluntarily to indicate to consumers the extent to which products introduced, delivered for introduction, sold, advertised, or offered for sale in commerce are of U.S. origin. </p> <p>The FTC must establish four categories of such labels, to be known as America Star labels, which may be used to designate products: (1) that satisfy the standard for an unqualified U.S. origin claim set forth by the FTC in the Enforcement Policy Statement on U.S. Origin Claims; or (2) for which not less than 90%, 80%, or 70% of the total cost of manufacturing is attributable to U.S. costs.</p> <p>The FTC must promulgate regulations for such labels and enforce such regulations under the Federal Trade Commission Act.</p> <p>The bill also preempts certain state law requirements relating to the use of &quot;Made in the U.S.A.&quot; or &quot;Made in America&quot; labels. The preemption provisions provide for: (1) the Violent Crime Control and Law Enforcement Act of 1994 to supersede state laws that impose more stringent requirements, and (2) FTC regulations under this bill to supersede state laws.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
