<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1307" measure-id="id114hr1307" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-03-04" update-date="2015-03-25">
<title>Global Free Internet Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1307v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-03-25">
<action-date>2015-03-04</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Global Free Internet Act of 2015</b></p> <p>Establishes a Task Force on the Global Internet to be hosted by the Department of Commerce.</p> <p>Requires the Task Force to develop and implement strategies in response to foreign and domestic government policies that: (1) unjustifiably or unreasonably burden or restrict international trade in Internet-related goods, services, and content; (2) mandate or prefer certain Internet-related technology standards; (3) impede the free flow of information on the Internet; or (4) otherwise threaten the open, global nature of the Internet, the interests of Internet users, and the United States in Internet-related international trade and discourse.</p> <p>Directs the Task Force to: (1)&nbsp;coordinate federal agencies' implementation of such strategies, and (2) consult and share timely information with the Internet Corporation for Assigned Names and Numbers and civil society policy groups.</p> <p>Instructs the U.S. Trade Representative to initiate investigations and consider imposing sanctions in accordance with the Trade Act of 1974 for any practices of a foreign government or international body identified as priority concerns.</p> <p>Directs the Federal Trade Commission and the Department of Justice to investigate whether U.S. antitrust laws are violated by identified practices or the related actions of nongovernmental entities. </p> <p>Requires the Task Force to report to Congress and the President regarding the sufficiency of existing multilateral and bilateral trade agreements in advancing a single open, global Internet. </p> <p>Instructs the Task Force to organize training of foreign and domestic government officials and national standard-setting and conformity assessment bodies, including coordination with nongovernmental international and domestic standards bodies.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
