<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2447" measure-id="id114hr2447" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-19" update-date="2015-11-16">
<title>To amend the Public Health Service Act to provide for an NIH research strategic plan.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2447v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-11-16">
<action-date>2015-05-19</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill amends the Public Health Service Act to require the National Institutes of Health (NIH) to develop and maintain a biomedical research strategic plan.</p> <p>The NIH must use the strategic plan to identify research opportunities and to develop individual strategic plans for each of the national research institutes and national centers. Strategic plans must identify strategic focus areas in a manner that considers the return on investment of biomedical research and contributes to expanding knowledge to improve the public's health. Strategic focus areas must include overarching Mission Priority Focus Areas, which serve the goal of preventing or eliminating the burden of a medical condition.</p> The NIH must: (1) ensure that rare and pediatric diseases and conditions remain a priority under the strategic plan, (2) publish the initial strategic plan within 270 days, (3) conduct progress reviews for each strategic focus area at least annually, and (4) update the strategic plan every five years.]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
