<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1838" measure-id="id114hr1838" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-04-16" update-date="2016-07-12">
<title>Clear Creek National Recreation Area and Conservation Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1838v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-07-12">
<action-date>2016-07-05</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Clear Creek National Recreation Area and Conservation Act</b></p> <p />(Sec. 3) This bill establishes the Clear Creek National Recreation Area in California to promote environmentally responsible off-highway vehicle recreation and support other public recreational uses, including hunting, hiking, and rock and gem collecting. <p>(Sec. 4) The Department of the Interior shall: </p> <ul> <li>prioritize environmentally responsible off-highway vehicle recreation and also facilitate hunting, hiking, gem collecting, and the use of motorized vehicles, mountain bikes, and horses; </li> <li>issue special recreation permits for motorized and nonmotorized events; and</li> <li>reopen the Clear Creek Management Area to such uses. </li> </ul> <p>Interior shall use the 2006 Clear Creek Management Area Travel Management Plan, as modified by this bill or by Interior, to incorporate natural resource protection information unavailable in 2006 as the basis for an interim management plan to govern off-highway vehicle recreation in the Recreation Area. </p> <p>Interior shall create a comprehensive management plan for the Recreation Area, which shall include:</p> <ul> <li>a hazards education program to inform people entering the Recreation Area of the asbestos-related risks associated with various activities within the recreation area, including off-highway vehicle recreation; and</li> <li>a user fee program for motorized vehicle use and guidelines for the use of the funds collected for the management and improvement of the recreation area. </li> </ul> <p>Interior may acquire by purchase from willing sellers, donation, or exchange:</p> <ul> <li>lands adjacent to the Recreation Area, and</li> <li>lands or interests in land to improve public safety in allowing access to the Recreation Area. </li> </ul> <p>Landowners must be given adequate access to inholdings within the Recreation Area. Private land adjacent to the Recreation Area to which there is no practicable access except through the recreation area shall be managed as an inholding. </p> <p>Nothing in this bill:</p> <ul> <li>creates a protective perimeter or buffer zone around the Recreation Area,</li> <li>constitutes a reservation by the United States of any water or water rights,</li> <li>limits hunting or fishing, or</li> <li>affects state authority to manage or regulated fish and resident wildlife. </li> </ul> <p>The use of motorized vehicles on public land in the Recreation Area shall be permitted only on roads, trails, and areas designated by the management plan. </p> <p> Livestock grazing shall be allowed to continue in certain parts of the Recreation Area. </p> <p>The bill withdraws all federal land within the Recreation Area from: (1) all forms of entry, appropriations, and disposal under the public land laws; (2) location, entry, and patenting under the mining laws; and (3) operation of the mineral leasing, mineral materials, and geothermal leasing laws. </p> <p>The National Oil and Hazardous Substances Pollution Contingency Plan shall not apply to Interior's management of asbestos exposure risks faced by the public when recreating within the Recreation Area. </p> <p>(Sec. 5) The bill designates approximately 21,000 acres of identified federal lands in Fresno and San Benito Counties, California, as the Joaquin Rocks Wilderness, and a component of the National Wilderness Preservation System. </p> <p>(Sec. 6) The bill also releases the San Benito Mountain Wilderness Study Area from specified requirements applicable to public lands subject to a wilderness review. </p> <p>(Sec. 7) No additional funds are authorized to carry out this bill's requirements, and those requirements shall be carried out using amounts otherwise authorized. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1838v17" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-07-12">
<action-date>2016-05-23</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Clear Creek National Recreation Area and Conservation Act</b></p> <p />(Sec. 3) This bill establishes the Clear Creek National Recreation Area in California to promote environmentally responsible off-highway vehicle recreation and support other public recreational uses, including hunting, hiking, and rock and gem collecting. <p>(Sec. 4) The Department of the Interior shall: </p> <ul> <li>prioritize environmentally responsible off-highway vehicle recreation and also facilitate hunting, hiking, gem collecting, and the use of motorized vehicles, mountain bikes, and horses; </li> <li>issue special recreation permits for motorized and nonmotorized events; and</li> <li>reopen the Clear Creek Management Area to such uses. </li> </ul> <p>Interior shall use the 2006 Clear Creek Management Area Travel Management Plan, as modified by this bill or by Interior, to incorporate natural resource protection information unavailable in 2006 as the basis for an interim management plan to govern off-highway vehicle recreation in the Recreation Area. </p> <p>Interior shall create a comprehensive management plan for the Recreation Area, which shall include:</p> <ul> <li>a hazards education program to inform people entering the Recreation Area of the asbestos-related risks associated with various activities within the recreation area, including off-highway vehicle recreation; and</li> <li>a user fee program for motorized vehicle use and guidelines for the use of the funds collected for the management and improvement of the recreation area. </li> </ul> <p>Interior may acquire by purchase from willing sellers, donation, or exchange:</p> <ul> <li>lands adjacent to the Recreation Area, and</li> <li>lands or interests in land to improve public safety in allowing access to the Recreation Area. </li> </ul> <p>Landowners must be given adequate access to inholdings within the Recreation Area. Private land adjacent to the Recreation Area to which there is no practicable access except through the recreation area shall be managed as an inholding. </p> <p>Nothing in this bill:</p> <ul> <li>creates a protective perimeter or buffer zone around the Recreation Area,</li> <li>constitutes a reservation by the United States of any water or water rights,</li> <li>limits hunting or fishing, or</li> <li>affects state authority to manage or regulated fish and resident wildlife. </li> </ul> <p>The use of motorized vehicles on public land in the Recreation Area shall be permitted only on roads, trails, and areas designated by the management plan. </p> <p> Livestock grazing shall be allowed to continue in certain parts of the Recreation Area. </p> <p>The bill withdraws all federal land within the Recreation Area from: (1) all forms of entry, appropriations, and disposal under the public land laws; (2) location, entry, and patenting under the mining laws; and (3) operation of the mineral leasing, mineral materials, and geothermal leasing laws. </p> <p>The National Oil and Hazardous Substances Pollution Contingency Plan shall not apply to Interior's management of asbestos exposure risks faced by the public when recreating within the Recreation Area. </p> <p>(Sec. 5) The bill designates approximately 21,000 acres of identified federal lands in Fresno and San Benito Counties, California, as the Joaquin Rocks Wilderness, and a component of the National Wilderness Preservation System. </p> <p>(Sec. 6) The bill also releases the San Benito Mountain Wilderness Study Area from specified requirements applicable to public lands subject to a wilderness review. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1838v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-07-12">
<action-date>2015-04-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Clear Creek National Recreation Area and Conservation Act</b></p> </p> Establishes the Clear Creek National Recreation Area in the state of California to promote environmentally responsible off-highway vehicle recreation and to support other public recreational uses, including hunting, hiking, and rock and gem collecting. <p>Instructs the Department of the Interior to use the 2005 Clear Creek Management Area Travel Management Plan as modified by this bill or by Interior to incorporate natural resource protection information unavailable in 2005 as the basis for an interim management plan to govern off-highway vehicle recreation in the Recreation Area. </p> <p>Requires Interior to create a comprehensive management plan for the Recreation Area within two years of the enactment of this bill. </p> <p>Requires landowners to be provided with adequate access to inholdings within the Recreation Area. </p> <p>Permits livestock grazing to continue in areas of the Recreation Area in which it is allowed as of the enactment of this bill. </p> <p>Designates approximately 21,000 acres of identified federal lands in Fresno and San Benito Counties, California, to be known as the Joaquin Rocks Wilderness, as wilderness and as a component of the National Wilderness Preservation System. </p> <p>Amends the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to add the Larious Canyon, San Carlos Creek, Cantua Creek, Picacho Creek, and White Creek and its tributaries as components of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System. </p> <p>Releases the San Benito Mountain Wilderness Study Area from specified requirements applicable to public lands subject to a wilderness review.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
