<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5222" measure-id="id114hr5222" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-05-12" update-date="2016-06-14">
<title>Iran Cyber Sanctions Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5222v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-06-14">
<action-date>2016-05-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Iran Cyber Sanctions Act of 2016</b></p> <p>This bill requires the President to report to Congress at least every 180 days regarding significant activities undermining cybersecurity conducted by persons on behalf of or at the direction of the government of Iran (including members of paramilitary organizations such as Ansar-e-Hezbollah and Basij-e Mostaz'afin) against the United States (including U.S. persons, entities, or federal, state, or local governments). The reports must: (1) identify persons that have knowingly facilitated, participated or assisted in, engaged in, directed, or provided material support for such activities; (2) describe their conduct; (3) assess the Iranian government's or other foreign governments' direction, facilitation, or material support in such activities; and (4) provide a strategy to counter efforts by persons to conduct such activities, which shall include engaging foreign governments to halt the capabilities of such persons.</p> <p>The President must include on the Office of Foreign Assets Control's specially designated nationals and blocked persons list persons who are: (1) identified in such reports; or (2) indicted by the Department of Justice in connection with such activities undermining U.S. cybersecurity. Under an exception, the President may exclude such a person from the list by submitting an explanation to Congress.</p> <p>The President must use Executive Order 13694 (relating to blocking the property of certain persons engaging in significant malicious cyber-enabled activities) to impose sanctions against persons included on such list.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
