<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1471" measure-id="id114hr1471" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-03-19" update-date="2016-04-05">
<title>FEMA Disaster Assistance Reform Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1471v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-04-05">
<action-date>2016-02-29</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>FEMA Disaster Assistance Reform Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>TITLE I--FEMA REAUTHORIZATION</p> <p>(Sec. 101) This bill reauthorizes the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) through FY2018. </p> <p>TITLE II--COMPREHENSIVE STUDY OF DISASTER COSTS AND LOSSES</p> <p>(Sec. 201) FEMA shall commence, through the National Advisory Council, a comprehensive study related to disaster costs and losses. The Council shall evaluate, and report on, disaster losses and costs and develop recommendations for reducing such losses and costs.</p> <p>TITLE III--STAFFORD ACT AND OTHER PROGRAMS </p> <p>(Sec. 301) The bill amends the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (Stafford Act) to: (1) continue the administration of the National Urban Search and Rescue Response System (USAR Response System), and (2) reauthorize the USAR Response System through FY2018.</p> <p>(Sec. 303) FEMA shall provide a plan for the development of consistent guidance to applicants on FEMA disaster funding, the maintenance of records and transfer of information, relieving administrative burdens, and the implementation of new technology tools during disaster response and recovery operations in the field. </p> <p>(Sec. 304) The bill amends the Stafford Act to raise the public assistance small projects threshold from $35,000 to $1 million. </p> <p>(Sec. 305) The bill amends the Stafford Act to establish fixed rates to reimburse states and local governments for direct and indirect administrative costs incurred to implement disaster recovery projects. </p> <p>(Sec. 306) Debts owed to the United States for disaster assistance may be waived if such assistance was distributed based on an error by FEMA, there was no fault on behalf of the debtor, and the collection of the debt would be against equity and good conscience. </p> <p>(Sec. 307) The statute of limitations for initiating a new administrative action to recover debts owed to the United States for disaster assistance is three years, unless there is evidence of civil or criminal fraud. </p> <p>(Sec. 308) FEMA shall: (1) provide technical assistance to common interest communities that provide essential services of a governmental nature, and (2) provide recommendations on how common areas of condominiums and housing cooperatives may be eligible for disaster assistance. </p> <p>(Sec. 309) FEMA shall give greater weight and consideration to severe localized impacts when making major disaster declaration recommendations to the President. </p> <p>(Sec. 310) A state shall be deemed to have met FEMA's proof of insurance requirements for an individual property owner when title to such property has been encumbered requiring the purchase and maintenance of insurance. </p> <p>(Sec. 311) FEMA shall not expand its statutory authorities as they related to floodplain management or mapping unless the requirement to do so is explicitly and specifically stated in statute. FEMA's authorities may not be construed to impute the privately-funded actions of private parties on private land to FEMA for the purpose of extending the requirement.</p> <p>(Sec. 312) FEMA shall be responsible for efforts to reduce the loss of life and property and to protect the Nation from an earthquake, tsunami, or a combined earthquake and tsunami event. </p> <p>(Sec. 313) The President shall establish a Federal Interagency Task Force to develop a comprehensive strategy and recommendations on preparation and planning for, mitigating against, responding to, recovering from, and more successfully adapting to an earthquake, tsunami, or a combined earthquake and tsunami event in the Cascadia Subduction Zone. </p> <p>The Task Force shall enter into an agreement with the National Academies for developing recommendations for a federal research strategy to advance scientific understanding of a Cascadia Subduction Zone earthquake and resulting tsunami preparedness. </p> <p>FEMA shall report to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure and the Senate Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs on the comprehensive strategy and recommendations on administrative actions to further the strategy. </p> <p>(Sec. 314) The President may provide hazard mitigation assistance in any area affected by a fire for which assistance was provided, whether or not a major disaster is declared. </p> <p>(Sec. 315) Recipients of hazard mitigation assistance under the Stafford Act may use such assistance to help reduce the risk of future damage, hardship, loss, or suffering in any area affected by a wildfire or earthquake hazards. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1471v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-08-26">
<action-date>2015-03-19</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>FEMA Disaster Assistance Reform Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>Authorizes appropriations for the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) for FY2016-FY2018 for management and administration.</p> <p> Directs FEMA, through the National Advisory Council, to undertake and report on a comprehensive study of disaster costs and losses.</p> <p> Amends the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to:</p> <ul> <li> authorize through FY2018 the NationalUrban Search and Rescue Response System and grants to implement the Emergency Management Assistance Compact; </li> <li>include public broadcasting facilities within the definition of "private nonprofit facility" for purposes of disaster assistance eligibility; </li> <li>establish a three-year statute of limitation for reclaiming disaster relief funds and for collecting debts related to disaster assistance;</li> <li> allow a waiver for the collection of certain disaster-related debts; </li> <li>increase the threshold for determining the eligibility of certain small projects for expedited disaster assistance payments;</li> <li>establish rates for reimbursing states and local governments for direct and indirect administrative costs incurred to implement disaster recovery projects; </li> <li>authorize the President, whether or not a major disaster is declared, to provide hazard mitigation assistance in any area affected by a fire; and </li> <li>allow recipients of hazard mitigation assistance to use such assistance for activities to reduce the risk of future damage, hardship, loss, or suffering in any area affected by a wildfire or earthquake hazards. <br /> </li> </ul> <p>Directs FEMA to: (1) study and report on physical testing standards for electric utility facilities, (2) report to specified congressional committees on agency plans to provide guidance to applicants for disaster assistance on FEMA disaster funding procedures and to maintain appropriate records during the lifecycle of a disaster, and (3) identify in its report new technologies to assist the disaster workforce during a disaster or emergency.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
