<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4586" measure-id="id114hr4586" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-02-23" update-date="2016-06-07">
<title>Lali's Law</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4586v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-06-07">
<action-date>2016-05-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the House on May 10, 2016. The summary of that version is repeated here.)</p> <p><b>Lali's Law</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Public Health Service Act to permit the Department of Health and Human Services to make grants to states that allow standing orders (documents that allow a person to acquire, dispense, or administer a prescription medication without a person-specific prescription) for opioid overdose reversal medication (e.g., naloxone). (Opioids are drugs with effects similar to opium, such as heroin and certain pain medications.)</p> <p>Grants may be used for:</p> <ul> <li> developing standing orders for opioid overdose reversal medication for pharmacies;</li> <li>encouraging pharmacies to dispense medication pursuant to such a standing order;</li> <li>implementing best practices for prescribing opioids, prescribing opioid overdose reversal medication with opioids, and discussing opioid overdose reversal medication with patients;</li> <li>developing training for prescribers to use in educating the public on administration of opioid overdose reversal medication; and</li> <li>educating the public on the availability and public health benefits of opioid overdose reversal medication.</li> </ul> <p>States must report on pharmacies that dispense opioid overdose reversal medication under a standing order and the number of pharmacists trained in educating the public on administration of opioid overdose reversal medication. </p> <p>(Sec. 3) As an offset, this bill reduces the authorization of appropriations for Centers for Disease Control and Prevention facilities.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4586v17" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-06-06">
<action-date>2016-05-10</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Lali's Law</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Public Health Service Act to permit the Department of Health and Human Services to make grants to states that allow standing orders (documents that allow a person to acquire, dispense, or administer a prescription medication without a person-specific prescription) for opioid overdose reversal medication (e.g., naloxone). (Opioids are drugs with effects similar to opium, such as heroin and certain pain medications.)</p> <p>Grants may be used for:</p> <ul> <li> developing standing orders for opioid overdose reversal medication for pharmacies;</li> <li>encouraging pharmacies to dispense medication pursuant to such a standing order;</li> <li>implementing best practices for prescribing opioids, prescribing opioid overdose reversal medication with opioids, and discussing opioid overdose reversal medication with patients;</li> <li>developing training for prescribers to use in educating the public on administration of opioid overdose reversal medication; and</li> <li>educating the public on the availability and public health benefits of opioid overdose reversal medication.</li> </ul> <p>States must report on pharmacies that dispense opioid overdose reversal medication under a standing order and the number of pharmacists trained in educating the public on administration of opioid overdose reversal medication. </p> <p>(Sec. 3) As an offset, this bill reduces the authorization of appropriations for Centers for Disease Control and Prevention facilities.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4586v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-06-03">
<action-date>2016-02-23</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Lali's Law</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Public Health Service Act to permit the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention to make grants to states that allow standing orders (documents that allow a person to acquire, dispense, or administer a prescription medication without a person-specific prescription) for opioid overdose reversal medication (e.g., naloxone). (Opioids are drugs with effects similar to opium, such as heroin and certain pain medications.)</p> <p>Grants may be used for:</p> <ul> <li> developing standing orders for opioid overdose reversal medication for pharmacies;</li> <li>encouraging pharmacies to dispense medication pursuant to such a standing order;</li> <li>implementing guidelines and best practices for prescribing opioids, prescribing opioid overdose reversal medication with opioids, and discussing opioid overdose reversal medication with patients;</li> <li>developing training for prescribers to use in educating the public on administration of opioid overdose reversal medication; and</li> <li>educating the public on the availability and public health benefits of opioid overdose reversal medication.</li> </ul> States must report on pharmacies that dispense opioid overdose reversal medication under a standing order and the number of pharmacists trained in educating the public on administration of opioid overdose reversal medication.]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
