<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2459" measure-id="id114hr2459" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-19" update-date="2015-11-16">
<title>Delivering Antimicrobial Transparency in Animals Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2459v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-11-16">
<action-date>2015-05-19</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Delivering Antimicrobial Transparency in Animals Act of 2015</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to revise reporting requirements for new animal drugs containing an antimicrobial.</p> <p>Certain live poultry dealers, swine contractors, and feed lot operators who purchase, contract, or manufacture animal feed containing a new antimicrobial animal drug must annually report to the Food and Drug Administration, by food-producing animal, the amount of drug per kilogram of feed, and the quantity of feed sold or distributed. Additional information must be provided for feed sold or distributed under a veterinary feed directive.</p> <p>The FDA may specify alternative reporting requirements to improve the accuracy of reports, lessen the burden of reporting, facilitate providing public summaries of reports, or improve the FDA's ability to use reports or the public's ability to use summaries.</p> <p>The FDA must publish summaries of these reports and reports from sponsors of new antimicrobial animal drugs, with data reported by antimicrobial drug class. Alternative reporting requirements are specified for antimicrobial drug classes with fewer than three new animal drugs.</p> <p>The FDA must increase collaboration and coordination with the Department of Agriculture to expand the collection of data on the use of antimicrobials on food-producing animals and to provide information for the Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service and Economic Research Service.</p> The Government Accountability Office must evaluate the voluntary approach used by the FDA to eliminate injudicious use of antimicrobial drugs in food-producing animals and the effectiveness of FDA data collection activities regarding antimicrobial resistance.]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
