<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4392" measure-id="id114hr4392" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-01-13" update-date="2016-05-04">
<title>To amend title 5, United States Code, to require that the Office of Personnel Management submit an annual report to Congress relating to the use of official time by Federal employees.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4392v17" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-05-04">
<action-date>2016-04-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(Sec. 1) This bill requires the Office of Personnel Management to submit an annual report to Congress on the use of official time by federal employees. The bill defines "official time" as any period of time granted to a federal employee to perform representational or consultative functions and during which the employee would otherwise be in a duty status.</p> <p>Each such report shall include, for each agency and for all agencies:</p> <ul> <li>the total amount of official time granted to employees;</li> <li>the average amount of official time expended per bargaining unit employee;</li> <li>the specific types of activities or purposes for which official time was granted and the impact which the granting of such official time had on agency operations;</li> <li>the total number of employees to whom official time was granted and, of that total, the number who were not engaged in any activities or purposes except those involving the use of official time; </li> <li>the total amount of compensation (including fringe benefits) afforded to employees in connection with activities or purposes for which they were granted official time; and</li> <li>a description of any room or space designated at the agency where official time activities will be conducted.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4392v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-02-26">
<action-date>2016-01-13</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill requires the Office of Personnel Management to submit an annual report to Congress on the use of official time by federal employees. The bill defines "official time" as any period of time granted to a federal employee to perform representational or consultative functions and during which the employee would otherwise be in a duty status.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
