<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4349" measure-id="id114hr4349" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-01-07" update-date="2016-02-19">
<title>Coordinating Crisis Care Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4349v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-02-19">
<action-date>2016-01-07</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Coordinating Crisis Care Act</b></p> <p>This bill requires the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration to award grants to states for real-time, Internet-based bed registries that provide information about beds in inpatient psychiatric facilities, crisis stabilization units, residential community mental health treatment facilities, and residential substance abuse treatment facilities to facilitate the identification of space for the temporary treatment of an individual in psychiatric or substance abuse crisis.</p> A bed registry must: (1) describe and provide contact information for every relevant facility in the state; (2) provide real-time information about the number of beds available at each facility and, for each available bed, provide the type of patient that may be admitted, the level of security provided, and any other information that may be necessary to identify an appropriate facility for an individual in crisis; and (3) allow specified users to search the registry for an appropriate and available bed for an individual in crisis.]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
