<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4480" measure-id="id114hr4480" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-02-04" update-date="2016-09-28">
<title>Albatross and Petrel Conservation Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4480v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-09-28">
<action-date>2016-02-04</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Albatross and Petrel Conservation Act</strong></p> <p>This bill authorizes the United States Fish and Wildlife Service (USFWS) and the National Marine Fisheries Service (NMFS) to promulgate regulations to implement and enforce the Agreement on the Conservation of Albatrosses and Petrels, done at Cape Town, South Africa, on February 2, 2001.</p> <p>This bill authorizes USFWS and NMFS to take action to conserve albatrosses and petrels, including to:</p> <ul> <li> reestablish albatrosses and petrels;</li> <li>prevent the introduction of, eradicate, or control invasive and nonnative species that have or may have an adverse effect on albatrosses and petrels; </li> <li>conserve, protect, and restore breeding sites; </li> <li>undertake measures for the conservation and protection of albatross and petrel habitat and other marine habitats that provide food for albatrosses and petrels; </li> <li>undertake scientific research to assess the effects of pollutants and marine debris on albatrosses and petrels; </li> <li>develop and implement measures to prevent, minimize, or mitigate the taking or disturbance of albatrosses and petrels in U.S. waters or by U.S. vessels; </li> <li>develop and undertake measures to minimize the bycatch of albatrosses and petrels; and </li> <li>share information on the conservation status of albatrosses and petrels, the threats facing albatrosses and petrels, and any actions taken under this bill.</li> </ul> <p>This bill prohibits the taking of an albatross or petrel without a permit, authorization, or exemption. USFWS, in consultation with NMFS, may authorize the taking of an albatross or petrel under exceptional circumstances or incidental to otherwise lawful activities. </p> <p>This bill gives the USFWS, the NMFS, and the Coast Guard authority to enforce this bill. </p> <p>This bill authorizes cooperation with other countries to achieve and maintain a favorable conservation status of albatrosses and petrels. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
