<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1730" measure-id="id114hr1730" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-03-26" update-date="2015-08-10">
<title>To amend the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act to provide that Alexander Creek, Alaska, is and shall be recognized as an eligible Native village under that Act, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1730v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-08-10">
<action-date>2015-03-26</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Amends the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act to recognize Alexander Creek, Alaska, as a Native village eligible for land and benefits under the Act. </p> <p>Requires Alexander Creek to file any amendments to its corporate charter in Alaska that are necessary to convert from a Native group to a Native Village Corporation. </p> <p>Directs the Secretary of the Interior to open negotiations with Alexander Creek to reach an agreement to settle Alexander Creek's aboriginal land claims and any other claims of such Native Village Corporation against the United States fairly and equitably.</p> <p>Requires Alexander Creek to notify each member of the Native village that: (1) all of them will cease to receive benefits from Cook Inlet Region Incorporated (CIRI) individually as at-large shareholders, and (2) all future resource payments from the Region will be made to the Village Corporation. Relieves CIRI from liability under any state, federal, or local law for damages related to that payment cessation. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
