<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="33" measure-id="id114hr33" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-01-06" update-date="2015-03-17">
<title>To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to ensure that emergency services volunteers are not taken into account as employees under the shared responsibility requirements contained in the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr33v49" currentChamber="BOTH" update-date="2015-03-17">
<action-date>2015-02-27</action-date>
<action-desc>Public Law</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was passed by the Senate on February 27, 2015. The summary of that version is repeated here.)</p> <p>This bill amends the Continuing Appropriations Resolution, 2015 to extend the continuing FY2015 appropriations for the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) at the current annual rate until the earlier of March 6, 2015, or enactment of DHS appropriations legislation for FY2015. The bill prevents a shutdown of DHS when funding under current law expires on February 27, 2015. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr33v35" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-03-17">
<action-date>2015-02-27</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed Senate amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill amends the Continuing Appropriations Resolution, 2015 to extend the continuing FY2015 appropriations for the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) at the current annual rate until the earlier of March 6, 2015, or enactment of DHS appropriations legislation for FY2015. The bill prevents a shutdown of DHS when funding under current law expires on February 27, 2015. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr33v81" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-01-14">
<action-date>2015-01-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.)</p> <p><strong>Protecting Volunteer Firefighters and Emergency Responders Act </strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to exclude services rendered by bona-fide volunteers providing firefighting and prevention services, emergency medical services, or ambulance services to a state or local government or a tax-exempt charitable organization from the category of services usually rendered by an employee of an applicable large employer subject to the mandate to provide minimum essential health care coverage under the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (PPACA), thus exempting such employers from PPACA requirements with respect to such volunteers.</p> <p>The bill defines &quot;bona fide volunteer&quot; as an employee of any government entity and any tax-exempt charitable organization whose only compensation is in the form of: (1) reimbursement for (or reasonable allowance for) reasonable expenses incurred in the performance of volunteer services, or (2) reasonable benefits (including length-of-service awards) and nominal fees customarily paid by similar entities for the services of volunteers. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr33v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-01-12">
<action-date>2015-01-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Protecting Volunteer Firefighters and Emergency Responders Act </strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to exclude services rendered by bona-fide volunteers providing firefighting and prevention services, emergency medical services, or ambulance services to a state or local government or a tax-exempt charitable organization from the category of services usually rendered by an employee of an applicable large employer subject to the mandate to provide minimum essential health care coverage under the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (PPACA), thus exempting such employers from PPACA requirements with respect to such volunteers.</p> <p>The bill defines &quot;bona fide volunteer&quot; as an employee of any government entity and any tax-exempt charitable organization whose only compensation is in the form of: (1) reimbursement for (or reasonable allowance for) reasonable expenses incurred in the performance of volunteer services, or (2) reasonable benefits (including length-of-service awards) and nominal fees customarily paid by similar entities for the services of volunteers. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
