<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1898" measure-id="id114hr1898" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-04-21" update-date="2016-08-23">
<title>America Competes Reauthorization Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1898v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-08-23">
<action-date>2015-04-21</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>America Competes Reauthorization Act of 2015</b></p> <p> Establishes, revises, and extends specified science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (STEM) programs, as well as education, research, and training programs. </p> <p>Authorizes appropriations for FY2016-FY2020 for: (1) the National Science Foundation (NSF), (2) the Department of Energy (DOE) for activities of the Office of Science, and (3) the Advanced Research Projects Agency-Energy (ARPA-E). </p> <p><em>International Science and Technology Cooperation Act of 2015</em></p> <p>Directs the Office of Science and Technology Policy (OSTP) to establish a body under the National Science and Technology Council to identify and coordinate international science and technology cooperation that can strengthen science and technology enterprise, improve economic and national security, and support foreign policy goals.</p> <p><em>National Nanotechnology Initiative Amendments Act of 2015</em></p> <p>Amends The 21st Century Nanotechnology Research and Development Act to expand reporting and other requirements for the National Nanotechnology Program, including a requirement for a triennial review of the Program. Expands the Program to include undergraduate education programs in science and engineering education, expanded research and development initiatives, and nanomanufacturing research.</p> <p><em>Engineering Biology Research and Development Act of 2015</em></p> <p>Directs the President to: (1) implement a National Engineering Biology Research and Development Program to advance societal well-being, national security, and economic productivity and competitiveness; and (2) designate an advisory committee on engineering biology research and development. </p> <p><em>STEM Opportunities Act of 2015</em></p> <p>Requires the OSTP to develop consistent federal policies for recipients of federal research awards who have caregiving responsibilities, including care for a newborn or newly adopted child, and consistent federal guidance to grant reviewers and program officers on best practices to minimize the effects of implicit bias based on gender, race, or ethnicity in the review of federal research grants. </p> <p>Requires the NSF to: (1) collect demographic data of STEM faculty and develop and disseminate guidance to universities to identify cultural and institutional barriers limiting the recruitment, retention, and achievement of women and minorities in research careers; and (2) award grants to institutions of higher educations to increase the recruitment, retention, and advancement of individuals from underrepresented minority groups in academic STEM careers.</p>                              <p><em>National Institute of Standards and Technology Authorization Act of 2015</em></p> <p>Authorizes appropriations for FY2016-FY2020 for the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) for: (1) scientific and technical research and services laboratory activities; (2) facilities construction and maintenance; and (3) industrial technology services activities.</p> <p><em>Department of Energy Office of Science Authorization Act of 2015</em></p> <p>Sets forth the mission of the DOE Office of Science as the delivery of scientific discoveries, capabilities, and major scientific tools to transform the understanding of nature and to advance the energy, economic, and national security of the United States. </p> <p>Establishes programs in the Office for basic energy sciences, biological and environmental research, advanced scientific computing research, fusion energy research, physics and nuclear physics research, and improvement of the infrastructure at Office of Science laboratories. <p><em>ARPA-E Reauthorization Act of 2015</em></p> <p>Directs DOE to make five-year (renewable) awards to consortia for establishing and operating Energy Innovation Hubs to conduct and support, whenever practicable at one centralized location, multidisciplinary, collaborative research, development, and demonstration of advanced energy technologies.</p> <p>Establishes in DOE the position of Under Secretary for Science and Energy and grants the Under Secretary special hiring authority for scientific, engineering, and personnel. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
