<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="347" measure-id="id114hr347" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-01-14" update-date="2015-01-29">
<title>Facilitating Access to Credit Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr347v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-01-29">
<action-date>2015-01-14</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Facilitating Access to Credit Act of 2015</b></p> <p> Amends the Credit Repair Organizations Act to exempt from its coverage any consumer reporting agency (or affiliate or subsidiary) described under the Fair Credit Reporting Act as: </p> <ul> <li>one that compiles and maintains files on consumers on a nationwide basis; or </li> <li>any person which, for monetary fees, dues, or on a cooperative nonprofit basis, regularly engages in whole or in part in the practice of assembling or evaluating consumer credit information or other information on consumers in order to furnish consumer reports to third parties, if the person is subject to supervision and examination by the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau.</li> </ul> <p>Preempts state law and regulations concerning a credit repair organization to the extent they would apply to consumer reporting agencies subject to this Act.</p> <p>Directs the Federal Trade Commission to study whether, in addition to these persons, any other person should be exempt from the Credit Repair Organizations Act.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
