<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3152" measure-id="id114hr3152" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-07-22" update-date="2015-08-17">
<title>Rural Broadband Initiative Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3152v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-08-17">
<action-date>2015-07-22</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Rural Broadband Initiative Act </b></p> <p>This bill amends the Rural Electrification Act of 1936 to establish an Office of Rural Broadband Initiatives at the Department of Agriculture (USDA) and and an Under Secretary for Rural Broadband Initiatives appointed by the President to head the Office. </p> <p>The Under Secretary is responsible for administering all rural broadband-related grant and loan programs previously administered by the Administrator of the Rural Utilities Service and must: </p> <ul> <li>conduct nationwide outreach to rural areas; </li> <li>foster the development of a comprehensive rural broadband strategic vision; </li> <li>plan coordination of federal resources for state, regional, and local governments to assist rural areas; </li> <li>assess all relevant technologies; </li> <li>serve as a single information source for and coordinate all federal rural broadband programs and services; and </li> <li>provide technical assistance to state, regional, and local governments. </li> </ul> <p>The Under Secretary must also: </p> <ul> <li> submit to the President and Congress a comprehensive rural broadband strategy;</li> <li>submit to Congress a plan to establish a Rural Broadband Advisory Panel; </li> <li>establish a web-based clearinghouse that describes options, opportunities, resources, successful public-private partnerships, funding sources, and technology tutorials; and</li> <li>revise the rules and qualification criteria for the loan and loan guarantee programs.</li> </ul> <p>USDA must report to Congress on the resources and staff necessary to carry out this bill, and the Government Accountability Office must review the report. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
