<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5607" measure-id="id114hr5607" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-06-28" update-date="2016-07-15">
<title>Enhancing Treasury's Anti-Terror Tools Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5607v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-07-15">
<action-date>2016-06-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Enhancing Treasury's Anti-Terror Tools Act </b></p> <p>This bill directs the Department of the Treasury to report to certain congressional committees on the employment by U.S embassies of full-time and temporary Treasury attaches and their role in advancing U.S. anti-terrorism financing interests, including money laundering and related illicit finance. </p> <p>The bill revises Treasury's authority to issue an order imposing recordkeeping and reporting requirements upon financial institutions and nonfinancial trade or business groups in certain geographic areas regarding transactions for the payment, receipt, or transfer of U.S. coins or currency (or other monetary instruments as Treasury may describe). Such an order may include all funds, not just U.S. coins or currency, involved in such transactions. </p> <p>Treasury shall study:</p> <ul> <li>the advisability and implications of transforming the Office of Terrorism and Financial Intelligence into a standalone bureau,</li> <li>the potential efficacy of requiring banking regulators to establish a pilot technical assistance program for depository institutions and credit unions that furnish account services to money services businesses serving individuals in Somalia, and</li> <li>the potential impact of allowing money services businesses to share their state examinations with depository institutions and credit unions. </li> </ul> <p>The bill expresses the sense of Congress that, to better integrate the intelligence community with anti-money laundering and counter-terrorist financing efforts, Treasury should work with finance ministry counterparts worldwide to spur the development of entities similar to its Office of Intelligence and Analysis. </p> <p>Treasury shall collect and make available electronically to federal agencies a unified stream of import and export data and similar currently collected information that would help federal detection and prevention of illicit finance. </p> <p>The National Security Act of 1947 is amended to add the Secretary of the Treasury to the National Security Council.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
