<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5260" measure-id="id114hr5260" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-05-17" update-date="2016-06-22">
<title>Equity and Inclusion Enforcement Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5260v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-06-22">
<action-date>2016-05-17</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Equity and Inclusion Enforcement Act</b></p> <p> This bill amends the Civil Rights Act of 1964 to allow private civil causes of action for disparate impact violations (to the same extent as intentional violations) of federal regulations of general applicability that prohibit discrimination on the ground of race, color, or national origin in programs or activities receiving federal financial assistance.</p> <p>Education programs that receive financial assistance authorized or extended by the Department of Education (ED) must designate at least one compliance coordinator to carry out these nondiscrimination responsibilities and to investigate complaints. </p> <p>The Department of Education Organization Act is amended to establish an ED-appointed Special Assistant for Equity and Inclusion within ED to: (1) promote, coordinate, and evaluate equity and inclusion programs, including the dissemination of information, technical assistance, and coordination of research activities; and (2) advise ED on matters relating to equity and inclusion.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
