<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3812" measure-id="id114hr3812" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-10-22" update-date="2015-12-02">
<title>Stop Outsourcing and Create American Jobs Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3812v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-12-02">
<action-date>2015-10-22</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Stop Outsourcing and Create American Jobs Act of 2015 </strong></p> <p>This bill directs the Department of the Treasury to develop and publish a list of countries that are tax havens for corporations. </p> <p>The bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to increase the penalties on corporations for: (1) underpayment of tax involving an undisclosed foreign financial asset located in a tax haven country; (2) reportable transaction understatements involving transactions in a tax haven country; and (3) fraud, tax evasion, or false statements involving transactions in a tax haven country.</p> <p>The bill: (1) grants a preference in the award of federal contracts to contractors who have not engaged in outsourcing, and (2) defines "outsourcing" as the laying off of a U.S. worker from a job and the hiring or contracting for the same job to be performed in a foreign country. </p> <p>Revenues generated by this Act must be set aside for the reduction of the public debt. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
