<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2952" measure-id="id114hr2952" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-07-07" update-date="2016-07-26">
<title>Improving Employment Outcomes of TANF Recipients Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2952v17" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-07-26">
<action-date>2016-06-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Improving Employment Outcomes of TANF Recipients</b> <b>Act</b></p> <p> (Sec. 2) This bill amends part A (Temporary Assistance for Needy Families) (TANF) of title IV of the Social Security Act to replace the current program of bonus grants for high performing states with a program requiring each state to collect and report information necessary to measure the state's level of performance for FY2018 and each ensuing fiscal year for each employment percentage, retention percentage, and earnings advancement measure for adults in unsubsidized employment after exiting the TANF program (indicators). The Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) shall use the information collected for FY2018 to establish the baseline level of performance of each state for each indicator.</p> <p>The state shall reach agreement with HHS: (1) on the requisite level of performance for each indicator for FY2019-FY2020; and (2) before FY2021 on the requisite level of performance for each indicator for that fiscal year. </p> <p>HHS shall revise the requisite levels of performance for a fiscal year and a state to reflect the actual economic conditions and characteristics of participants.</p> <p>HHS shall use an objective statistical model to make such performance level adjustments, and shall consult with the Department of Labor to develop a statistical adjustment model similar to one described in the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act.</p> <p>HHS shall also develop a template which each state shall use to report on outcomes achieved under the new program or any other state program funded with qualified state expenditures.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2952v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-09-17">
<action-date>2015-07-07</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Improving Employment Outcomes of TANF Recipients</b> Act</p> <p>This bill amends part A (Temporary Assistance for Needy Families) (TANF) of title IV of the Social Security Act to replace the current program of bonus grants for high performing states with a program requiring the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to make a grant to a state for each fiscal year that it achieves a requisite level of performance, under an agreement with HHS, indicated by the percentage of former TANF recipients who are in unsubsidized employment after exiting the TANF program.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
