<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3694" measure-id="id114hr3694" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-10-06" update-date="2016-08-23">
<title>Strategy To Oppose Predatory Organ Trafficking Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3694v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-08-23">
<action-date>2016-06-13</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Strategy To Oppose Predatory Organ Trafficking Act or the STOP Organ Trafficking Act</strong></p> <p> (Sec. 3) This bill expresses the sense of Congress that: </p> <ul> <li> kidnapping or coercion of individuals to extract their organs for profit contradicts the standards for ethical behavior upon which the United States has based its laws; </li> <li> illegal harvesting of organs from children is a violation of the chid's human rights and a breach of international medical ethical standards; </li> <li> illegal harvesting and trafficking of human organs violates the Universal Declaration of Human Rights; and </li> <li> establishing efficient national organ donation systems with strong enforcement mechanisms is the most effective way to combat trafficking of persons for the removal of their organs. </li> </ul> <p>(Sec. 4) It shall be U.S. policy to: (1) combat trafficking of persons for the removal of their organs, (2) promote the establishment of voluntary organ donation systems with effective enforcement mechanisms, and (3) promote the dignity and security of human life. </p> <p>(Sec. 5) The Passport Act of 1926 is amended to authorize the Department of State to refuse to issue a passport to, and revoke a previously issued passport from, a person convicted of trafficking in human organs who used a passport or otherwise crossed an international border in committing such offense.</p> <p>(Sec. 6) The Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 is amended to define &quot;trafficking of persons for the removal of their organs&quot; as the recruitment, transportation, transfer, harboring, or receipt of a person, either living or dead, for the purpose of removing one or more of the person's organs by: </p> <ul> <li>coercion, </li> <li>abduction, </li> <li>deception, </li> <li>fraud, </li> <li>abuse of power, or </li> <li> transfer of payments or benefits to achieve the consent of an individual having control over such person for the purpose of removing the person's organs.</li> </ul> <p> &quot;Organ&quot; means the human (including fetal) kidney, liver, heart, lung, pancreas, bone marrow, cornea, eye, bone, and skin or any subpart thereof and any other human organ specified by the Department of Health and Human Services. </p> <p>Trafficking of persons for the removal of their organs is included in the definition of "severe forms of trafficking in persons."</p> <p> The Interagency Task Force To Monitor and Combat Trafficking is tasked with collecting and organizing data from human rights officers at U.S. embassies on host country's laws against trafficking of persons for the removal of their organs and any instances of violations of such laws.</p> <p>(Sec. 7) The State Department shall report annually through 2024 to Congress regarding: (1) the trafficking of persons for the removal of their organs, and (2) preventive activities undertaken by the State Department and other countries. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3694v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-02-16">
<action-date>2015-10-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Strategy To Oppose Predatory Organ Trafficking Act or the STOP Organ Trafficking Act</strong></p> <p> This bill expresses the sense of Congress that: </p> <ul> <li> kidnapping or coercion of individuals to extract their organs for profit contradicts the standards for ethical behavior upon which the United States has based its laws; </li> <li> harvesting of organs from living children, regardless of the level of brain activity, is a violation of the human rights of the child and is a breach of internationally accepted medical ethical standards; </li> <li> illegal harvesting and trafficking of human organs violates the Universal Declaration of Human Rights; and </li> <li> efficient national organ donation systems with effective enforcement mechanisms that ensure voluntary organ donations are the most effective way to combat trafficking in human organs. </li> </ul> <p>The State Department Basic Authorities Act of 1956 is amended to prohibit the issuance of a passport to, and revoke a previously issued passport from, a person convicted of trafficking in human organs who used a passport or otherwise crossed an international border in committing such offense.</p> <p>The President is authorized to exercise specified authorities under the International Emergency Economic Powers Act in connection with the travel abroad by U.S. citizens to participate in any activity relating to human organ trafficking.</p> <p>The Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 is amended to include in the definition of "coercion" exploitation of a person through the promise of payments or benefits in order to compel or entice the person to consent to the removal of one or more of the person's organs for a transplant operation in a manner contrary to certain World Health Organization standards.</p> <p>"Trafficking in human organs" is defined as: </p> <ul> <li>the recruitment, transportation, transfer, harboring, or receipt of a person, either living or dead, for the purpose of removing one or more of the person's organs by coercion, abduction, deception, abuse of power, or transfer of payments or benefits; or </li> <li>the illicit transportation and transplantation of those organs in one or more other persons for profit or any other purpose. </li> </ul> <p>"Organ" is defined as the human (including fetal) kidney, liver, heart, lung, pancreas, bone marrow, cornea, eye, bone, and skin or any subpart thereof, and any other human organ or subpart (including that derived from a fetus) specified by the President. </p> <p>Trafficking in human organs is included in the definition of "severe forms of trafficking in persons."</p> <p> The Interagency Task Force To Monitor and Combat Trafficking is tasked with collecting and organizing data from human rights officers at U.S. embassies on host country's laws against trafficking in human organs and any instances of violations of such laws.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
