<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5631" measure-id="id114hr5631" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-07-06" update-date="2016-07-11">
<title>Iran Accountability Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5631v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-07-11">
<action-date>2016-07-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Iran Accountability Act of 2016</strong></p> <p>This bill prescribes requirements for mandatory sanctions with respect to: </p> <ul> <li>Iran's Revolutionary Guard Corps (IRGC), its agents, and persons or entities it owns; </li> <li>Mahan Air; </li> <li>Iran's support of terrorism and money laundering;</li> <li>Iran's human rights abuses; </li> <li>certain Iranian individuals, including the Supreme Leader of Iran and the President of Iran; </li> <li>persons who conduct transactions with or on behalf of certain Iranian individuals;</li> <li> persons that support or are involved in Iran's ballistic missile program; and </li> <li>financial institutions that engage in certain transactions on behalf of persons involved in human rights abuses or that export sensitive technology to Iran.</li> </ul> <p>The Department of the Treasury must establish and publish in the Federal Register an IRGC watch list.</p> <p>The bill prescribes prohibitions against Iran's access to the U.S. financial system.</p> <p>The bill authorizes the Department of State to provide assistance to individuals and entities working in Iran to promote the rule of law and economic opportunity. </p> <p>The Iran-Iraq Arms Non-Proliferation Act of 1992 is amended to cover ballistic missiles and related technology.</p> <p>The President is directed to: (1) designate within the State Department a Special Coordinator on Human Rights and Democracy in Iran; and (2) report on U.S. citizens, including dual citizens, detained by Iran or related groups. </p> <p>The bill requires Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty and the Voice of America to increase programing services to Iran.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
