<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="773" measure-id="id114hr773" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-02-05" update-date="2015-03-18">
<title>Transform Education in America through Choice Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr773v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-03-18">
<action-date>2015-02-05</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Transform Education in America through Choice Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to allow states to allocate school improvement grant funds among their local educational agencies (LEAs) on the basis of the number of children whose family income lies below the federal poverty level and who are enrolled in the public and state-accredited private schools within each LEA's geographic jurisdiction.</p> <p>Amends the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act to allow states that have established a program allowing the parents of disabled children to use public or private funds to send their children to a private school to use their allocation of special education funds to supplement those funds.</p> <p>Authorizes grants for the improvement of special education services to be used for the planning, design, and initial implementation (during a period of up to three years) of state programs that allow the parents of a disabled child to make a genuine independent choice of the appropriate public or private school.</p> <p>Sets forth requirements for those programs, including that they: (1) permit parents to receive state funds to pay some or all of the costs of their disabled child's attendance at the selected school, or (2) permit persons to receive a state tax credit for donations to an entity that provides funds to enable parents to pay some or all of the costs of their disabled child's attendance at that school.</p> <p>Repeals: (1) within one year or two years after this Act's enactment, specified provisions of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965, the Higher Education Act of 1965, the Rehabilitation Act of 1973, the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act, the America COMPETES Act, the American History and Civics Education Act of 2004, the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009, the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Improvement Act of 2006, and the Small Business Act; (2) within one year after this Act's enactment, the Erma Byrd Scholarship program; and (3) within three years after this Act's enactment, each competitive grant program administered by the Department of Education (ED), with specified exceptions.</p> <p>Requires ED, within one year after a program under this Act is repealed, to reduce the ED workforce by the number of full-time ED employee positions associated with such program.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
