<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1408" measure-id="id114hr1408" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-03-17" update-date="2015-07-22">
<title>Mortgage Servicing Asset Capital Requirements Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1408v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-07-22">
<action-date>2015-07-14</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Mortgage Servicing Asset Capital Requirements Act of 2015 </b></p> <p>This bill directs the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, and the National Credit Union Administration to study jointly the appropriate capital requirements for mortgage servicing assets for banking institutions.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1408v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-05-05">
<action-date>2015-03-17</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Mortgage Servicing Asset Capital Requirements Act of 2015 </b></p> <p> Directs the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, and the National Credit Union Administration (federal banking agencies) to study jointly the appropriate capital requirements for mortgage servicing assets for any banking institution other than an institution identified by the Financial Stability Board as a global systemically important bank.</p> <p>Prohibits regulations to implement the Global Regulatory Framework for More Resilient Banks and Banking Systems issued by the Basel Committee on Banking Supervision on December 16, 2010, as revised on June 1, 2011 (Basel III capital requirements), or the proposed rule of the National Credit Union Administration titled &quot;Risk-Based Capital&quot; with respect to mortgage servicing assets for nonsystemic banking institutions from taking effect until three months after the report on the study is issued to Congress. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
