<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3474" measure-id="id114hr3474" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-09-10" update-date="2016-07-13">
<title>Christopher's Law</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3474v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-07-13">
<action-date>2015-09-10</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Christopher Bryski Student Loan Protection Act or Christopher's Law</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Truth in Lending Act to require a private student loan lender to disclose clearly and conspicuously in writing a cosigner's obligations regarding a private student loan. The Consumer Financial Protection Bureau (CFPB) must publish a model form for such disclosure.</p> <p> The bill prohibits a private student loan lender from taking an adverse action against a borrower (e.g., placing a loan in default or accelerating a loan balance) upon a cosigner's death, disability, or bankruptcy. It also prohibits adverse actions against a cosigner for a borrower's death, disability, or bankruptcy. </p> <p> The CFPB must establish and a private student loan lender must disclose criteria for releasing a cosigner from a private student loan obligation.</p> <p>A private student loan lender must also: </p> <ul> <li> provide prompt notice of a cosigner's release; </li> <li>allow a borrower to designate a legal representative to make decisions upon the death or disability of such borrower; and <br /> </li> <li>ensure a borrower and cosigner receive comprehensive counseling on the terms, conditions, and responsibilities of a private student loan. </li> </ul> <p>Additionally, this bill amends title IV (Student Assistance) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to expand the required elements of entrance counseling for a federal student loan borrower to include: </p> <ul> <li>conditions for loan discharge upon the death or disability of a borrower,</li> <li>options for loan repayment and forgiveness upon the death or disability of a borrower or cosigner, and</li> <li>obligations of a borrower or cosigner upon the death or disability of a borrower.</li> </ul> <p>It requires clear and conspicuous disclosure of a student's option to designate a legal representative to make decisions about a federal student loan upon such student's death or disability. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
