<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2127" measure-id="id114hr2127" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-04-30" update-date="2015-08-28">
<title>Securing Expedited Screening Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2127v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-08-28">
<action-date>2015-07-27</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Securing Expedited Screening Act</b></p> <p>(Sec. 3) The Transportation Security Administration (TSA) of the Department of Homeland Security shall, within 180 days after enactment of this Act, limit access to expedited airport security screening at airport security checkpoints to only a passenger who:</p> <ul> <li>voluntarily submits biographic and biometric information for a security risk assessment and has an approved PreCheck program application;</li> <li>is traveling as air transportation security or a member of the Armed Forces, including any accompanying family member;</li> <li>is a member of a population designated by the TSA as known and low-risk and who may be issued a unique, known traveler number; or</li> <li>is 75 years or older, or 12 years or younger and traveling with a parent or guardian participating in the PreCheck program. </li> </ul> <p>The TSA may extend for one year implementation of the requirement for passengers who have been designated frequent fliers.</p> <p>The TSA may provide access to expedited airport security screening to additional passengers through an alternate method upon submission to Congress of an independent assessment of its security effectiveness.</p> <p>(Sec. 4) The TSA shall report annually to Congress certain information on passengers provided expedited security screening.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2127v17" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-08-28">
<action-date>2015-07-22</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Securing Expedited Screening Act</b></p> <p>(Sec. 3) The Transportation Security Administration (TSA) of the Department of Homeland Security shall, within 180 days after enactment of this Act, limit access to expedited airport security screening at airport security checkpoints to only a passenger who:</p> <ul> <li>voluntarily submits biographic and biometric information for a security risk assessment and has an approved PreCheck program application;</li> <li>is traveling as air transportation security or a member of the Armed Forces, including any accompanying family member;</li> <li>is a member of a population designated by the TSA as known and low-risk and who may be issued a unique, known traveler number; or</li> <li>is 75 years or older, or 12 years or younger and traveling with a parent or guardian participating in the PreCheck program. </li> </ul> <p>The TSA may extend for one year implementation of the requirement for passengers who have been designated frequent fliers.</p> <p>The TSA may provide access to expedited airport security screening to additional passengers through an alternate method upon submission to Congress of an independent assessment of its security effectiveness.</p> <p>(Sec. 4) The TSA shall report annually to Congress certain information on passengers provided expedited security screening.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2127v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-07-30">
<action-date>2015-04-30</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Securing Expedited Screening Act</b></p> <p>The Transportation Security Administration (TSA) of the Department of Homeland Security shall limit access to expedited airport security screening at airport security checkpoints to only a passenger who:</p> <ul> <li>voluntarily submits biographic and biometric information for a security risk assessment and has an approved PreCheck program application;</li> <li>is traveling as air transportation security or a member of the Armed Forces, including any accompanying family member;</li> <li>has been designated by the TSA as known and low-risk; or</li> <li>is 75 years or older, or 12 years or younger and traveling with a parent or guardian who is a participant in the PreCheck program. </li> </ul> <p>The TSA may provide access to expedited airport security screening to additional passengers through an alternate method upon submission to Congress of an independent assessment of its security effectiveness.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
