<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3398" measure-id="id114hr3398" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-07-29" update-date="2016-04-27">
<title>National Multimodal Freight Policy and Investment Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3398v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-04-27">
<action-date>2015-07-29</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>National Multimodal Freight Policy and Investment Act</b></p> <p>This bill directs the Department of Transportation (DOT) to:</p> <ul> <li>establish a national multimodal freight network, a national multimodal freight advisory committee, and a freight investment grant program; and</li> <li>develop a national multimodal freight strategic plan.</li> </ul>  <p>Each state receiving a freight investment grant shall also develop a freight investment plan and establish a state freight advisory committee.</p> <p>The bill establishes in DOT an Office of Freight Planning, Permitting, and Development.</p> <p>DOT shall establish a competitive capital grant program to provide financial assistance to states, metropolitan planning organizations, regional or local transportation authorities, tribal governments, and other entities for:</p> <ul> <li> shortline or regional railroad infrastructure improvement projects, and</li> <li>highway-rail vertical grade separation projects.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
