<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3754" measure-id="id114hr3754" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-10-09" update-date="2015-11-23">
<title>Halting Government Overreach Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3754v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-11-23">
<action-date>2015-10-09</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Halting Government Overreach Act of 2015</b></p> <p>This bill removes exceptions that prohibit a prevailing party other than the United States from being awarded fees and expenses incurred in a civil action (other than a tort action) brought by or against the United States, or in an agency adjudicatory proceeding, if the position of the United States was substantially justified or special circumstances make an award unjust. </p> <p>The fees and expenses may be awarded if the prevailing party has a direct and personal interest in the action because of an injury that gave rise to the action.</p> <p>The bill also removes requirements that make parties ineligible for such an award if their net worth exceeds a specified amount at the time the action was filed or the adjudication was initiated. Under the bill, parties may seek an award of fees and expenses regardless of their net worth.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
