<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1837" measure-id="id114hr1837" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-04-16" update-date="2015-05-04">
<title>Secure Delivery for America Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1837v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-05-04">
<action-date>2015-04-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Secure Delivery for America Act of 2015</b></p> <p>Declares that it is the policy of the United States Postal Service (USPS) to: (1) provide access to secure, convenient package delivery receptacles to the greatest number of postal patrons feasible; and (2) use the most cost-effective primary mode of mail delivery feasible. </p> <p>Directs USPS to: (1) provide a primary mode of mail delivery other than door delivery, with a preference for secure, centralized delivery, for new addresses established after September 30, 2016; and (2) implement a program to convert existing business addresses with door delivery to centralized delivery. </p> <p>Requires: (1) each USPS district office to identify residential addresses within its service area that are appropriate candidates for conversion to centralized, curbside, or sidewalk delivery; and (2) USPS to seek to voluntarily make such conversion.</p> <p>Requires the USPS, in making conversion determinations, to consider: (1) the impact of weather conditions, physical barriers, or any other factor on the feasibility of providing a primary mode of mail delivery other than door delivery; (2) whether the address is of historic value; and (3) population density and the concentration of poverty. </p> <p>Directs USPS to establish and maintain a waiver program for cases in which door delivery is necessary to avoid causing significant physical hardship or physical safety risks to a postal patron.</p> <p>Requires USPS to: (1) convert at least 1.5 million of the door delivery points extant on December 31, 2015, to centralized, curbside, or sidewalk delivery during each of FY2017-FY2026, with priority to voluntary conversions; (2) convert delivery points to centralized delivery to the greatest extent feasible and include secure package lockers co-located with mail receptacles at the centralized delivery point; (3) establish procedures to place centralized delivery points in locations that maximize delivery efficiency, ease of use for postal patrons, and respect for private property rights; and (4) provide for a voucher program under which USPS may defray costs associated with conversion that would otherwise be borne by postal patrons.</p> <p>Authorizes USPS to continue to provide door delivery for a fee to an address that received such delivery as of January 1, 2016, but was converted or scheduled to be converted to a different primary mode of mail delivery as a result of this Act's requirements.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
