<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1421" measure-id="id114hr1421" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-03-18" update-date="2015-04-01">
<title>Tyler Clementi Higher Education Anti-Harassment Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1421v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-04-01">
<action-date>2015-03-18</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Tyler Clementi Higher Education Anti-Harassment Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>Amends title IV (Student Assistance) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require each institution of higher education (IHE) participating in a title IV program (except a foreign school) to include in its annual security report a statement of policy regarding harassment that includes: (1) a prohibition of harassment of students by other students, faculty, and staff; (2) a description of its programs to prevent harassment; (3) a description of the procedures that students should follow if harassment occurs; and (4) a description of the procedures it will follow once an incident of harassment has been reported.</p> <p>Defines &quot;harassment&quot; to include certain conduct undertaken through technological means that limits a student's ability to benefit from the IHE's programs, or creates a hostile or abusive educational environment at the school.</p> <p>Authorizes the Secretary of Education to award competitive grants to IHEs to initiate, expand, or improve programs to: (1) prevent the harassment of students; (2) provide counseling or redress services to students who have been harassed or accused of subjecting other students to harassment; and (3) train students, faculty, or staff to prevent harassment or address harassment if it occurs.</p> <p>Directs the Secretary to publish a report of best practices for combating harassment at IHEs.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
