<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1296" measure-id="id114hr1296" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-03-04" update-date="2015-08-11">
<title>To amend the San Luis Rey Indian Water Rights Settlement Act to clarify certain settlement terms, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1296v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-08-11">
<action-date>2015-03-04</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill amends the San Luis Rey Indian Water Rights Settlement Act to approve and ratify all provisions of the settlement agreement dated January 30, 2015, and approved by the La Jolla, Rincon, San Pasqual, Pauma, and Pala Bands of Mission Indians (California), the San Luis Rey River Indian Water Authority, the City of Escondido, California, the Vista Irrigation District, and the United States. </p> <p>The Departments of the Interior and Justice are authorized to execute the agreement and any amendments approved by the parties as necessary to make it consistent with such Act. (However, such execution shall not constitute a major federal action under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969.) Interior is authorized to take steps necessary to implement the agreement and such Act. </p> <p>The Bands will continue to possess federally reserved rights and other water rights held in trust by the United States. In any proceeding involving the assertion, enforcement, or defense of such rights, the United States shall not be a required party and and any decision by the United States regarding participation in any such proceeding shall not be subject to judicial review or give rise to any claim for relief against the United States. </p> <p>Congress confirms that the benefits to allottees in the agreement are equitable and fully satisfy their water rights. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
