<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5374" measure-id="id114hr5374" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-05-27" update-date="2016-10-06">
<title>Bring Small Businesses Back Tax Reform Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5374v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-10-06">
<action-date>2016-05-27</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Bring Small Businesses Back Tax Reform Act </b></p> <p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to establish new maximum individual tax rates for qualified business income that does not exceed $1 million (i.e., small business income). The maximum rates are: (1) 10% of such income not exceeding $150,000, and (2) 20% for income that exceeds $150,000 and is not more than $1 million. </p> <p>The rates apply to up to $1 million of qualified business income that is: (1) gross earnings derived by an individual from any active trade or business carried on by the individual, excluding deductions attributable to the trade or business; and (2) the taxpayer's distributive or pro rata share of pass-through income from entities such as a partnership or S corporation. Qualified business income does not include capital gains, interest, dividends, or royalties. </p> <p>For taxpayers that are not a corporation or a partnership with a corporation as a partner, the bill repeals the annual limitation on the election to deduct certain depreciable business assets. </p> <p>The bill also permits certain small businesses whose average gross receipts do not exceed $25 million (currently, $5 million) to use the cash accounting method without limitations and exempts such businesses from inventory rules. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
