<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3736" measure-id="id114hr3736" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-10-09" update-date="2015-10-28">
<title>Clatsop-Nehalem Restoration Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3736v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-10-28">
<action-date>2015-10-09</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Clatsop-Nehalem Restoration Act</b></p> <p>This bill extends federal recognition to the Clatsop-Nehalem Confederated Tribes of Oregon.</p> <p>Rights and privileges of the tribe and its members under any federal treaty, executive order, agreement, statute, or other federal authority that may have been diminished or lost under the Act approved August 13, 1954 are restored. That Act no longer applies to the tribe and its members. </p> <p>The tribe and its members are eligible to receive all federal services and benefits furnished to federally recognized Indian tribes, without regard to the existence of a reservation. Members of the tribe residing in Tillamook and Clatsop Counties in Oregon are deemed to be residing on or near a reservation. </p> <p>No hunting, fishing, or trapping rights of the tribe or of any member are granted or restored.</p> <p>Lands in Tillamook County, Oregon may not be held in trust for the tribe.</p> <p>An Interim Council is established as the governing body of the tribe until the tribal governing body convenes. The Department of the Interior must hold an election to elect the members of the Interim Council.</p> <p>The membership roll of the tribe is established and opened. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
