<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3653" measure-id="id114hr3653" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-09-30" update-date="2016-07-20">
<title>Help Find the Missing Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3653v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-07-20">
<action-date>2015-09-30</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Billy's Law or the Help Find the Missing Act</b></p> <p>This bill authorizes the Department of Justice (DOJ), through the National Institute of Justice, to maintain public databases, known as the National Missing and Unidentified Persons System (NamUs), of missing persons and unidentified remains.</p> <p>It requires DOJ to facilitate information sharing between the NamUs databases and the National Crime Information Center (NCIC) database. DOJ must update the online data entry format to allow criminal justice agencies, medical examiners, and coroners to simultaneously submit information to NamUs and NCIC. DOJ must also promulgate rules that protect confidential, private, and law enforcement sensitive information. </p> <p>The bill amends the Crime Control Act of 1990 to require a law enforcement agency that submits a missing child report to NCIC to also submit such missing child report to NamUs.</p> <p>It directs DOJ to establish a program to award matching grants to law enforcement agencies, coroners, and medical examiners to facilitate information reporting to the NCIC database and NamUs databases to help locate missing persons and identify unidentified remains.</p> <p>DOJ must report: (1) to medical examiners, coroners, and law enforcement agencies on best practices for data collection and analysis; and (2) to Congress on the status of the NCIC database and NamUs databases. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
