<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2939" measure-id="id114hr2939" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-06-25" update-date="2015-08-26">
<title>Enforce Existing Gun Laws Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2939v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-08-26">
<action-date>2015-06-25</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Enforce Existing Gun Laws Act </b></p> <p>This bill amends several appropriations laws to remove limitations on the authority of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives to conduct activities related to the administration of federal firearms laws. </p> <p>The amended appropriations laws include: </p> <ul> <li> the Consolidated and Further Continuing Appropriations Act, 2012; </li> <li>the Consolidated and Further Continuing Appropriations Act, 2013; </li> <li>the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2010; </li> <li>the Omnibus Appropriations Act, 2009; </li> <li> the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2008; </li> <li>the Science, State, Justice, Commerce, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2006; </li> <li>the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2005; and</li> <li>the Consolidated Appropriations Resolution, 2003. </li> </ul> <p>The bill removes provisions from these laws that: </p> <ul> <li>prohibit the consolidation or centralization within the Department of Justice of firearms acquisition and disposition records maintained by federal firearms licensees; </li> <li>prohibit the imposition of a requirement that firearms dealers conduct a physical inventory; </li> <li>require instant background check records to be destroyed within 24 hours; </li> <li>limit the use of firearms tracing data; </li> <li>limit the processing of Freedom of Information Act requests in connection with arson or explosive incidents or firearm traces; </li> <li>limit denials of applications to import &quot;curios or relics&quot; firearms, parts, or ammunition; and </li> <li>prohibit denials of federal firearms licenses due to lack of business activity. </li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
