<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5185" measure-id="id114hr5185" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-05-10" update-date="2016-08-18">
<title>To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for disclosure for charity employees and board members previously implicated in terror finance.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5185v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-08-18">
<action-date>2016-05-10</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to require tax-exempt organizations to disclose details regarding employees and board members involved in terror finance activities. </p> <p>An organization applying for tax-exempt status must disclose in its application the names and addresses of any officer, director, trustee, or highly compensated employee who, at any time prior to the date of the application, was: </p> <ul> <li>a member or employee of an organization: (1) named on the Department of the Treasury's Designated Charities and Potential Fundraising Front Organizations for FTOs (Foreign Terrorist Organizations) list, or (2) with property that has been blocked pending investigation by Treasury's Office of Foreign Assets Control; </li> <li> an unindicted coconspirator with respect to a terror finance scheme of an organization described above, or </li> <li> an employee of any charity found liable for civil damages due to an act of international terrorism. </li> </ul> <p>In lieu of the disclosure, the organization may include a statement indicating that no officer, director, trustee, or highly compensated employee of the organization (or individual with similar powers and responsibilities) meets the criteria described above. </p> <p>Tax-exempt organizations must also include either the required disclosure or the statement in annual tax returns filed after the enactment of this bill. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
