<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2494" measure-id="id114hr2494" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-21" update-date="2016-08-17">
<title>Eliminate, Neutralize, and Disrupt Wildlife Trafficking Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2494v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-08-17">
<action-date>2015-11-02</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Global Anti-Poaching Act</b></p> <p>This bill addresses the illegal trade in endangered and threatened wildlife and their related parts and products.</p> <p>(Sec 3) The Department of State, the U.S. Agency for International Development, the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, and other appropriate agencies are urged to: (1) support strengthening existing wildlife enforcement networks and establishing new networks in other appropriate regions, and (2) promote the professionalization of the wildlife law enforcement sector and professional ranger training in partner countries.</p> <p>(Sec 5) For the next five years, the State Department must provide to Congress an annual list of each foreign country that is a major source, transit point, or consumer of wildlife trafficking products. The report must designate each country listed in the report that has failed to demonstrably make substantial efforts to adhere to its obligations under international agreements relating to endangered or threatened species. The State Department may withhold certain foreign aid from a designated country and must notify each such country that it is subject to the withholding of assistance.</p> <p>The bill amends the Sudan Peace Act by repealing a requirement for the State Department to report annually on the conflict in Sudan.</p> <p>(Sec. 6) The bill urges the United States to continue providing defense articles (not including significant military equipment), defense services, and related training to appropriate security forces of African countries for countering wildlife trafficking and poaching.</p> <p>(Sec. 7) The State Department is included in the certification process under the Pelly Amendment to the Fishermen's Protective Act of 1967. The Pelly Amendment authorizes the President to embargo wildlife products when the Department of the Interior or of Commerce certifies that a country is engaging in trade or certain actions that diminishes the effectiveness of an international agreement for the conservation of endangered or threatened species.</p> <p>(Sec. 8) The bill applies provisions of the federal criminal code concerning money laundering and racketeering to wildlife trafficking violations of the Endangered Species Act of 1973, the African Elephant Conservation Act, and the Rhinoceros and Tiger Conservation Act of 1994, if the endangered or threatened species, products, items, or substances involved in the violation and relevant conduct have a total value of more than $10,000. The amounts generated from penalties for those wildlife violations must be used for the benefit and conservation of impacted species.</p> <p>(Sec. 9) The bill urges the State Department to dedicate resources to: (1) conduct monitoring and evaluation of wildlife trafficking programs consistent with the Department's January 2015 Evaluation Policy; (2) publish program information on wildlife trafficking programs on the website, ForeignAssistance.gov; and (3) develop and implement a learning agenda to improve the performance and impact of wildlife trafficking programs and to share best practices among executive agencies. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2494v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-06-07">
<action-date>2015-05-21</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Global Anti-Poaching Act</b></p> <p>This bill addresses the illegal trade in endangered and threatened wildlife and their related parts and products.</p> <p>The Department of State, the U.S. Agency for International Development, the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, and other appropriate agencies are urged to: (1) support strengthening existing wildlife enforcement networks and establishing new networks in other appropriate regions, and (2) promote the professionalization of the wildlife law enforcement sector and professional ranger training in partner countries.</p> <p> The State Department: (1) must provide to Congress an annual list of each foreign country that is a major source, transit point, or consumer of wildlife trafficking products; and (2) may withhold certain assistance from countries that have failed to adhere to their obligations under international agreements relating to endangered or threatened species.</p> <p>The President may provide defense articles, services, and related training to security forces of African countries to counter wildlife trafficking and poaching. If a unit of a security force has been found to engage in wildlife trafficking or poaching, the President may not provide such assistance unless the President determines that the government of the country is taking steps to hold the security unit accountable and prevent trafficking and poaching. </p>  <p>The bill amends the federal criminal code to make wildlife trafficking violations of the Endangered Species Act of 1973, the African Elephant Conservation Act, and the Rhinoceros and Tiger Conservation Act of 1994 predicate offenses for racketeering and money laundering prosecutions, if such violations involve more than $10,000. Fines and forfeitures from such violations must be transferred to the Multinational Species Conservation Fund and used for the benefit of the species impacted by the violation. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
