<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3510" measure-id="id114hr3510" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-09-15" update-date="2015-10-09">
<title>Department of Homeland Security Cybersecurity Strategy Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3510v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-10-09">
<action-date>2015-10-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Department of Homeland Security Cybersecurity Strategy Act of 2015</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to require the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to develop a cybersecurity strategy that includes: (1) strategic and operational goals and priorities to execute the full range of DHS's cybersecurity responsibilities; and (2) information on programs, policies, and activities in furtherance of the cybersecurity functions of the national cybersecurity and communications integration center (NCCIC), investigations capabilities, research and development, and engagement with international partners.</p> <p>In developing the strategy, DHS must consider: (1) the cybersecurity strategy published in November 2011 for governmental and nongovernmental entities involved in homeland security, including federal, state, local, and tribal government officials, private sector representatives, academics, and other policy experts; (2) the Department of Homeland Security Fiscal Years 2014-2018 Strategic Plan; and (3) the most recent Quadrennial Homeland Security Review.</p> <p>The strategy must include the roles and responsibilities of DHS components and offices.</p> <p>DHS must also issue an implementation plan that includes strategic objectives, projected timelines, costs for tasks, and evaluation metrics. </p> <p>DHS must submit the strategy and implementation plan to Congress. </p> <p>The bill prohibits the strategy from being construed as permitting DHS to engage in monitoring, surveillance, exfiltration, or other collection activities to track an individual's personally identifiable information.</p> <p>The bill also prohibits DHS from changing the location or reporting structure of the National Protection and Programs Directorate without prior authorization from Congress.</p> <p>For purposes of the NCCIC, the bill redefines "incident" to include occurrences that actually or imminently jeopardize, without lawful authority, an information system, thereby replacing a standard that currently includes a violation or imminent threat of violation of law, security policies, security procedures, or acceptable use policies.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3510v17" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-10-07">
<action-date>2015-10-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Department of Homeland Security Cybersecurity Strategy Act of 2015</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to require the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to develop a cybersecurity strategy that includes: (1) strategic and operational goals and priorities to execute the full range of DHS's cybersecurity responsibilities; and (2) information on programs, policies, and activities in furtherance of the cybersecurity functions of the national cybersecurity and communications integration center (NCCIC), investigations capabilities, research and development, and engagement with international partners.</p> <p>In developing the strategy, DHS must consider: (1) the cybersecurity strategy published in November 2011 for governmental and nongovernmental entities involved in homeland security, including federal, state, local, and tribal government officials, private sector representatives, academics, and other policy experts; (2) the Department of Homeland Security Fiscal Years 2014-2018 Strategic Plan; and (3) the most recent Quadrennial Homeland Security Review.</p> <p>The strategy must include the roles and responsibilities of DHS components and offices.</p> <p>DHS must also issue an implementation plan that includes strategic objectives, projected timelines, costs for tasks, and evaluation metrics. </p> <p>DHS must submit the strategy and implementation plan to Congress. Congressional authorization is required for any reorganization of DHS components or offices.</p> <p>The bill prohibits the strategy from being construed as permitting DHS to engage in monitoring, surveillance, exfiltration, or other collection activities to track an individual's personally identifiable information.</p> <p>For purposes of the NCCIC, the bill redefines &quot;incident&quot; to include occurrences that actually or imminently jeopardize, without lawful authority, an information system, thereby replacing a standard that currently includes a violation or imminent threat of violation of law, security policies, security procedures, or acceptable use policies.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3510v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-10-07">
<action-date>2015-09-15</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Department of Homeland Security Cybersecurity Strategy Act of 2015</b></p> <p>This bill requires the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to develop a cybersecurity strategy that includes: (1) strategic and operational goals and priorities to execute the full range of DHS's cybersecurity responsibilities; and (2) information on programs, policies, and activities in furtherance of the cybersecurity functions of the national cybersecurity and communications integration center (NCCIC), investigations capabilities, research and development, and engagement with international partners.</p> <p>The strategy must include the roles and responsibilities of DHS components and offices. </p> <p>Congressional authorization is required for any reorganization of such components or offices.</p> <p>For purposes of the NCCIC, the bill redefines &quot;incident&quot; to include occurrences that actually or imminently jeopardize, without lawful authority, an information system, thereby replacing a standard that currently includes a violation or imminent threat of violation of law, security policies, security procedures, or acceptable use policies.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
