<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3956" measure-id="id114hr3956" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-11-05" update-date="2016-08-02">
<title>VA Health Center Management Stability and Improvement Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3956v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-08-02">
<action-date>2016-05-23</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>VA Health Center Management Stability and Improvement Act</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 3) This bill directs the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to: (1) develop and implement a plan to hire highly qualified directors for each VA medical center that lacks a permanent director, and (2) prioritize such hiring for the medical centers that have been without a permanent director for the longest periods. The plan shall include: (1) a hiring deadline; (2) identification of possible hiring impediments; and (3) identification of opportunities to promote and train candidates from within the VA for senior executive positions, including medical center directors. </p> <p>(Sec. 4) The VA shall ensure that the director of each VA medical facility annually certifies that the facility is in full compliance with all provisions of law and regulations relating to scheduling appointments for veterans hospital care and medical services. The VA may not waive any applicable provision of such laws or regulations. </p> <p>If unable to make such certification, the director shall provide the VA with an explanation of noncompliance and a description of compliance actions being taken. If a director does not make a certification for any year, each covered official may not receive specified awards or bonuses during the subsequent year. A covered official is the: (1) director, (2) chief of staff, (3) associate director, (4) associate director for patient care, and (5) deputy chief of staff. </p> <p>(Sec. 5) The VA shall ensure that its directives and policies apply uniformly to each VA office or facility. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3956v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-11-10">
<action-date>2015-11-05</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>VA Health Center Management Stability and Improvement Act</strong></p> <p>This bill directs the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to develop and implement a plan to hire a director for each VA medical center without a permanent director. </p> <p>Hiring priority shall be given to medical centers that have not had a permanent director for the longest periods.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
