<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2121" measure-id="id114hr2121" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-04-29" update-date="2016-07-22">
<title>SAFE Transitional Licensing Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2121v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-07-22">
<action-date>2016-05-23</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(Sec. 1) This bill amends the S.A.F.E. Mortgage Licensing Act of 2008 (Act) to state that, upon employment by a state-licensed mortgage company, an individual who is a registered loan originator shall be deemed to have temporary authority to act as one in an application state for a specified period if the individual:</p> <ul> <li>has not had an application for a loan originator license denied, or had such a license revoked or suspended in any governmental jurisdiction;</li> <li>has not been subject to or served with a cease and desist order in any governmental jurisdiction;</li> <li>has not been convicted of a felony that would preclude licensure under the law of the application state;</li> <li>has applied to be a state-licensed originator in the application state; and</li> <li>was registered in the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry as a loan originator during the 12-month period preceding the date of the required information.</li> </ul> <p>A state-licensed loan originator shall also be deemed to have temporary authority to act as a loan originator in an application state for a specified period if the loan originator: (1) meets certain requirements; (2) is employed by a state-licensed mortgage company in the application state; and (3) was licensed in another state during the 30-day period before submitting the information required in connection with the application to the application state.</p> <p>Any person employing an individual deemed to have such temporary authority to act as a loan originator in an application state, and any such individual who engages in residential mortgage loan activities, shall be subject to the requirements of the Act and to state law to the same extent as if such individual was a loan originator licensed by the application state.</p> <p>(Sec. 2) The exemption from civil liability of the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau (CFPB), any state official or agency, or any organization serving as the administrator of the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry (or a CFPB-established system), or any officer or employee of any such entity, by reason of a good faith action or omission while acting within the scope of office or employment that relates to the collection, furnishing, or dissemination of information concerning persons applying for licensing or registration as loan originators shall be limited to any such activities involving only information concerning applicants using the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2121v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-06-22">
<action-date>2015-04-29</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>SAFE Transitional Licensing Act of 2015 </b></p> <p>This bill amends the S.A.F.E. Mortgage Licensing Act of 2008 to provide a temporary license of 120 days for registered loan originators: (1) moving from a financial institution to a state-licensed non-bank originator, or (2) moving interstate to a state-licensed loan originator in another state.</p> <p>Any person registering a registered loan originator with the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry shall be subject to this Act and to applicable state law to the same extent as if that registered loan originator was licensed and registered as a state-licensed loan originator.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
