<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5806" measure-id="id114hr5806" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-07-14" update-date="2016-08-04">
<title>Do Your Job Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5806v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-08-04">
<action-date>2016-07-14</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Do Your Job Act </b></p> <p>This bill amends the rules of the Senate and the House of Representatives to prohibit a recess or adjournment longer than 24 hours until Congress agrees to a budget resolution that establishes a balanced budget no later than FY2026. </p> <p>The bill also amends the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 to create points of order against resolutions providing for: (1) the adjournment of the House for more than three days during August until the House has approved all of the annual appropriation bills, or (2) the adjournment of either the House or the Senate for more than three days between October 1 and the duration of the session of Congress until all of the annual appropriation bills have been presented to the President. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
