<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2653" measure-id="id114hr2653" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-06-04" update-date="2016-02-19">
<title>American Health Care Reform Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2653v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-02-19">
<action-date>2015-06-04</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>American Health Care Reform Act of 2015</b></p> <p>This bill repeals the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act and the health care provisions of the Health Care and Education Reconciliation Act of 2010, effective January 1, 2016. Provisions amended by repealed provisions are restored.</p> <p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow an income tax standard deduction for health insurance.</p> <p>Provisions regarding health savings accounts (HSAs) are revised, including to raise contribution limits and to expand the products and services that may be paid for using an HSA.</p> <p>Group health plans may vary premiums and cost-sharing based on participation in a wellness program.</p> <p>This bill amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to provide grants to states for high risk health insurance pools.</p> <p>Individual health insurance coverage is governed by the laws of the state designated by the health insurance issuer.</p> <p>This bill amends title XI (General Provisions) of the Social Security Act to require the Center for Medicare and Medicaid Services to publish Medicare claims and payment data.</p> <p>This bill amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) to provide for association health plans, which are group health plans sponsored by certain business associations.</p> <p>Veterans with certain service-related disabilities or who have been awarded a medal of honor must be provided access to medical services though specified entities other than the Department of Veterans Affairs.</p> <p>HHS must publish clinical practice guidelines. Independent medical review panels must review health care lawsuits in which the defendant alleges adherence to clinical practice guidelines.</p> <p>Federal courts have jurisdiction over health care lawsuits.</p> This bill amends the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 to revise non-security discretionary spending limits. <div> <div> </div> </div>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
