<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="64" measure-id="id114hr64" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-01-06" update-date="2015-01-12">
<title>Candace's Law</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr64v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-01-12">
<action-date>2015-01-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Domestic Violence Enhanced Penalty Act of 2015</b> or <b>Candace's Law</b></p> <p> Directs a state to provide by law enhanced sentencing requirements for persons convicted of committing, or attempting to commit, an act of domestic violence in the presence of minor children.</p> <p>Prohibits a state that fails within two years to implement this Act substantially from receiving 20% of the funds that would otherwise be allocated to it for the fiscal year under the Violence Against Women Act of 2000.</p> <p>Allows for reasonable alternative procedures or accommodations for compliance by a state that is unable to implement this Act substantially because of a conflict with the state constitution.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
