<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2925" measure-id="id114hr2925" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-06-25" update-date="2015-09-09">
<title>Santa Cruz Valley National Heritage Area Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2925v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-09-09">
<action-date>2015-06-25</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Santa Cruz Valley National Heritage Area Act</b></p> <p> Establishes the Santa Cruz Valley National Heritage Area in Arizona. Requires the Santa Cruz Valley Heritage Alliance, Inc. as the local coordinating entity for the Area, to prepare and submit a management plan for it. </p> <p>Requires the management plan to:</p> <ul> <li>inventory the natural, historical, cultural, educational, scenic, and recreational resources of the Area related to its national importance, as well as the themes that ought to be protected, enhanced, interpreted, managed, funded, and developed; and</li> <li>recommend policies and strategies for resource management.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
