<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3091" measure-id="id114hr3091" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-07-16" update-date="2015-09-22">
<title>Missing Alzheimer's Disease Patient Alert Program Reauthorization Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3091v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-09-22">
<action-date>2015-07-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Missing Alzheimer's Disease Patient Alert Program Reauthorization Act of 2015</strong></p> <p> Amends the Violent Crime Control and Law Enforcement Act of 1994 to revise provisions concerning the Missing Alzheimer's Disease Patient Alert Program to direct the Attorney General: (1) through the Bureau of Justice Assistance and in consultation with the Department of Health and Human Services, to award competitive grants to nonprofit organizations to assist in paying for the costs of planning, designing, establishing, and operating locally based, proactive programs to protect and locate missing patients with Alzheimer's disease and related dementias; and (2) in awarding grants, to give preference to national nonprofit organizations that have experience working with patients with Alzheimer's disease and related dementias and their families. </p> <p>Authorizes appropriations for such grants for FY2016-FY2020.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
