<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3728" measure-id="id114hr3728" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-10-08" update-date="2015-10-15">
<title>To amend the Iran Threat Reduction and Syria Human Rights Act of 2012 to modify the requirement to impose sanctions with respect to the provision of specialized financial messaging services to the Central Bank of Iran and other sanctioned Iranian financial institutions, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3728v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-10-15">
<action-date>2015-10-08</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p> This bill changes the current discretionary authority to a requirement that the President impose sanctions under the Iran Threat Reduction and Syria Human Rights Act of 2012 with respect to the provision of specialized financial messaging services to the Central Bank of Iran and other sanctioned Iranian financial institutions. This requirement may not be waived.</p> <p>Sanctions are expanded to include, in the case of an alien who is a senior executive or member of the board of directors of a person that provides such messaging services, visa denial and exclusion from the United States, and revocation of any visa or other documentation.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
