<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4508" measure-id="id114hr4508" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-02-09" update-date="2016-02-17">
<title>Fair Wage Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4508v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-02-17">
<action-date>2016-02-09</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Fair Wage Act</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to increase the federal minimum wage for employees to:</p> <ul> <li>$8.00 an hour 30 days after this Act's enactment date or January 1, 2017, whichever date is earlier;</li> <li>$9.00 an hour, one year after the date the $8.00 an hour wage takes effect;</li> <li>$10.00 an hour, after two years;</li> <li>$11.00 an hour, after three years; </li> <li>$12.00 an hour, after four years;</li> <li>$13.00 an hour, after five years;</li> <li>$14.00 an hour, after six years;</li> <li>$15.00 an hour, after seven years; and </li> <li>the amount determined by the Department of Labor (based on increases in the Consumer Price Index) eight years after such date and annually thereafter. </li> </ul> <p>The bill directs Labor, 60 days before any increase in the minimum wage, to publish it in the Federal Register and on Labor's website. </p> <p>The bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow an employer who pays at least $1 more per hour than the federal minimum wage, but not more than $15 per hour, a credit against the employment tax equal to 6.2% of wages paid by such employer during the calendar year.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
