<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3630" measure-id="id114hr3630" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-09-28" update-date="2016-07-25">
<title>PUGET SOS Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3630v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-07-25">
<action-date>2015-09-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Promoting United Government Efforts to Save Our Sound Act or the PUGET SOS Act</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (commonly known as the Clean Water Act) to provide for the coordination of federal Puget Sound recovery efforts with state, local and tribal recovery efforts, including by establishing: </p> <ul> <li> conditions for approval by the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) of the Comprehensive Conservation Management Plan for the Puget Sound region;</li> <li> a Puget Sound Recovery National Program Office within the EPA;</li> <li>a Puget Sound Federal Leadership Task Force;</li> <li>a Save America's Puget Sound Fund in the Department of the Treasury for certain Puget Sound recovery and protection efforts that are included in the Puget Sound Partnership's Action Agenda; and </li> <li>reporting requirements on the status of Puget Sound's recovery.</li> </ul> <p>The Puget Sound is an estuary in the Pacific Ocean off the coast of Washington.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
