<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5877" measure-id="id114hr5877" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-07-14" update-date="2016-09-21">
<title>United States-Israel Advanced Research Partnership Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5877v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-09-21">
<action-date>2016-07-14</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>United States-Israel Advanced Research Partnership Act of 2016</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 and the United States-Israel Strategic Partnership Act of 2014 to allow the Department of Homeland Security (DHS), in coordination with the Department of State, to enter cooperative programs with Israel to enhance capabilities in cybersecurity through:</p> <ul> <li>the international cooperation program established by DHS's Under Secretary for Science and Technology to enter into cooperative research activities with foreign partner governments that are allies in the global war on terrorism, and </li> <li> the Homeland Security Advanced Research Projects Agency (HSARPA).</li> </ul> <p>The pilot project designation is removed from the HSARPA's cooperative research programs with Israel for border, maritime, and aviation security; explosives detection; and emergency services.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
