<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2399" measure-id="id114hr2399" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-18" update-date="2015-08-17">
<title>Wildlife and Hunting Heritage Conservation Council Advisory Committee Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2399v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-08-17">
<action-date>2015-05-18</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Wildlife and Hunting Heritage Conservation Council Advisory Committee Act </b></p> <p>This bill amends the Fish and Wildlife Coordination Act to establish the Wildlife and Hunting Heritage Conservation Council Advisory Committee to advise the Department of the Interior and the Department of Agriculture on wildlife and habitat conservation, hunting, and recreational shooting. </p> <p>The Advisory Committee must advise the departments on policies or programs related to: </p> <ul> <li>implementing Executive Order No. 13443: Facilitation of Hunting Heritage and Wildlife Conservation; </li> <li>conserving and restoring wetlands, agricultural lands, grasslands, forest, and rangeland habitats;</li> <li>promoting opportunities for and access to hunting and shooting sports on federal lands; </li> <li>recruiting and retaining new hunters and shooters;</li> <li>increasing public awareness of the importance of wildlife conservation and the benefits of recreational hunting and shooting; and </li> <li>encouraging coordination among the public, the hunting and shooting sports community, wildlife conservation groups, states, tribes, and the federal government. </li> </ul> <p>The bill also specifies requirements for membership, meetings, pay and expenses, administrative support, and annual reports to Congress. The Advisory Committee is exempt from the Federal Advisory Committee Act. </p> <p>The bill abolishes the existing Wildlife and Hunting Heritage Conservation Council, effective on the date of the first meeting of the Advisory Committee established by this bill. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
