<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2173" measure-id="id114hr2173" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-04-30" update-date="2015-06-26">
<title>Redistricting Reform Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2173v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-06-26">
<action-date>2015-04-30</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Redistricting Reform Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>Prohibits a state that has been redistricted after an apportionment from being redistricted again until after the next apportionment of Representatives, unless the state is ordered by a court to conduct a subsequent redistricting in order to comply with the U.S. Constitution or enforce the Voting Rights Act of 1965. </p> <p>Requires such redistricting to be conducted in accordance with the plan developed and enacted into law by the independent redistricting commission established in the state or, if such a plan is not enacted into law, with the redistricting plan developed and enacted into law by a three-judge panel of the U.S. District Court for the District of Columbia. </p> <p>Sets forth provisions relating to: (1) the establishment by a nonpartisan agency of a state independent redistricting commission (including requirements for holding each of its meetings in public and maintaining a public Internet site); (2) the development and publication of a preliminary redistricting plan and the holding of at least three public hearings on such plan; (3) the enactment of a redistricting plan, under specified conditions, by a three-judge panel of the U.S. District Court for the District of Columbia; (4) redistricting conducted under a federal court order; and (5) Election Assistance Commission payments to states for carrying out redistricting. </p> <p>Authorizes the Department of Justice to bring a civil action to enforce this Act, which shall be given expedited consideration </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
