<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1445" measure-id="id114hr1445" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-03-18" update-date="2015-04-02">
<title>LAND Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1445v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-04-02">
<action-date>2015-03-18</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Land Acquisition to cut National Debt Act or LAND Act</b></p> <p> Bars the Department of the Interior from using federal funding to purchase land resulting in a net increase of land acreage being under the jurisdiction of the National Park Service, the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, or the Bureau of Land Management unless the federal budget is balanced for the year in which such land would be purchased. </p> <p>Makes such prohibition inapplicable to: (1) lands purchased with funding made available through the sale of Federal Migratory Bird Hunting and Conservation Stamps, and (2) easements acquired by Interior to facilitate the management of federal lands. </p> <p>Bars the Department of Agriculture (USDA) from using federal funding to purchase land resulting in a net increase of land acreage included in the National Forest System unless the federal budget is balanced for the year in which that land would be purchased. Makes such prohibition inapplicable to easements acquired by the USDA to facilitate the management of federal lands.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
