<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4956" measure-id="id114hr4956" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-04-15" update-date="2016-06-17">
<title>End Executive Overreach Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4956v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-06-17">
<action-date>2016-04-15</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>End Executive Overreach Act</strong></p> <p>This bill prohibits, until January 21, 2017, the use of federal funds, fees, or resources to implement an executive order issued on or after the enactment of this bill.</p> <p>The bill prohibits any agency, until such date, from making or finalizing:</p> <ul> <li>a major rule (a rule that is likely to result in an annual effect on the economy of $100 million or more); </li> <li>a rule that may raise novel legal or policy issues arising out of legal mandates, the President's priorities, or the principles set forth in Executive Order 12866 (which requires that significant regulatory actions be submitted for review by the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs of the Office of Management and Budget); or </li> <li>a rule that may create a serious inconsistency or otherwise interfere with an action taken or planned by another agency. </li></ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
