<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3535" measure-id="id114hr3535" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-09-17" update-date="2016-04-25">
<title>Alice Cogswell and Anne Sullivan Macy Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3535v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-04-25">
<action-date>2015-09-17</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p class="MsoNormal"></p> <p class="MsoNormal"><strong>Alice Cogswell and Anne Sullivan Macy Act </strong></p> <p class="MsoNormal"><strong></strong></p> <p class="MsoNormal"><strong></strong></p> <p class="MsoNormal"><strong></strong>This bill amends the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act to require a state to identify, evaluate, and provide special education and related services to children who have visual or hearing disabilities (or both) and also are, or may be, classified in another disability category. A state must ensure that it has enough qualified personnel to serve children who have such disabilities and that a full continuum of alternative placements is available to meet the needs of disabled children for special education and related services.</p> <p class="MsoNormal"></p> <p class="MsoNormal"></p> <p class="MsoNormal">The individualized education program for each child that is either (or both) visually or hearing impaired must include specified components and must provide the child with instruction that meets the child's unique learning needs. Similarly, the individualized family service plan for an infant or toddler with a hearing disability must include specified components.</p> <p class="MsoNormal"></p> <p class="MsoNormal"></p> <p class="MsoNormal">A states' closure of a special school serving deaf or blind children shall count as a reduction of its financial support for special education and related services for purposes of the prohibition against reducing state financial support for such services from one fiscal year to the next.</p> <p class="MsoNormal"></p> <p class="MsoNormal"></p> <p class="MsoNormal">The bill also: (1) authorizes grants for training special education personnel, to be used in preparing individuals to become qualified teachers and early intervention specialists for children with hearing disabilities; and (2) establishes within the Department of Education the Anne Sullivan Macy Center on Visual Disability and Educational Excellence to better support students with visual disabilities.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
