<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3743" measure-id="id114hr3743" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-10-09" update-date="2015-11-23">
<title>SERVER Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3743v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-11-23">
<action-date>2015-10-09</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Securing Every Relevant and Vital Electronic Record Act of 2015 or the SERVER Act</strong></p> <p>This bill prohibits the&nbsp;Secretary of a cabinet-level&nbsp;executive department from maintaining a private email server to conduct&nbsp;official government business.&nbsp;The Inspector General of each such department shall ensure compliance with such prohibition.&nbsp; A Secretary who violates such prohibition is subject to a fine and/or prison term and shall forfeit his or her office and be disqualified from holding any U.S. government office. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
