<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1308" measure-id="id114hr1308" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-03-04" update-date="2015-03-17">
<title>Economy in Motion: The National Multimodal and Sustainable Freight Infrastructure Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1308v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-03-17">
<action-date>2015-03-04</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Economy in Motion: The National Multimodal and Sustainable Freight Infrastructure Act</b></p> <p> Directs the Secretary of Transportation to: (1) establish a Multimodal Freight Funding Formula Program to distribute funds to states, and a National Freight Infrastructure Competitive Grant Program to make grants to entities for projects, to improve the efficiency and reliability of freight movement in the United States; (2) establish a multimodal national freight network to accomplish the goals of the national freight policy, including increasing the productivity and efficiency of the national freight system and improving its safety, security, and resilience; (3) develop, maintain, and post on the public website of the Department of Transportation a national freight strategic plan that includes an assessment of the condition and performance of the national freight system; and (4) develop and improve tools to support an outcome-oriented, performance-based approach to evaluate proposed freight-related and other transportation projects.</p> <p>Amends the Moving Ahead for Progress in the 21st Century Act (or&nbsp;MAP-21)&nbsp;to: (1) expand the membership and duties of state freight advisory committees; and&nbsp;(2) require state freight plans to include strategies and goals to decrease greenhouse gas emissions, local air pollution, water runoff, and wildlife habitat loss.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p> <p>Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) impose a 1% excise tax upon taxable ground transportation of property (i.e., transportation by freight rail or truck trailer and semitrailer chassis and bodies, suitable for use with a trailer or semitrailer with a gross vehicle weight of 26,000 pounds or more), and (2) deposit such tax revenues into a Freight Trust Fund (established by this Act) to finance the Multimodal Freight Funding Formula Program and the National Freight Infrastructure Competitive Grant Program. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
