<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3496" measure-id="id114hr3496" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-09-11" update-date="2015-10-13">
<title>GO PACK Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3496v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-10-13">
<action-date>2015-09-11</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Granting Our People the Ability to Cheer Kickoff Act of 2015 or the GO PACK Act of 2015</b></p> <p>Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to require a cable operator or satellite carrier to provide to certain subscribers in specified Wisconsin counties who elect to receive a television network: (1) retransmission of the signal of any local network station that such operator or carrier is otherwise required to retransmit; (2) an in-state, adjacent-market network station retransmission; or (3) both such retransmissions. Subjects satellite carriers to such requirements only to the extent that such retransmissions are technically feasible. </p> <p>Defines &quot;in-state, adjacent-market network station retransmission&quot; as the secondary transmission by a cable operator or satellite carrier of the primary transmission of any network station whose community of license is located: (1) in a subscriber's state, and (2) in a local market that is adjacent to the subscriber's local market.</p> <p>Provides for this Act to apply, with respect to such an in-state, adjacent-market network station retransmission to a subscriber, to specified Wisconsin counties (Barron, Burnett, Dunn, Pierce, Polk, St. Croix, and Washburn) that are not in the local market of any television broadcast station that is affiliated with the same network and whose community of license is located in the subscriber's state.</p> <p>Exempts in-state, adjacent-market network station retransmissions in such counties from: (1) retransmission consent requirements that prohibit cable operators from retransmitting broadcast stations without the authority of the originating station, and (2) statutory licensing limitations under federal copyright laws concerning satellite retransmissions to unserved households and secondary transmissions of distant signals.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
