<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5419" measure-id="id114hr5419" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-06-09" update-date="2016-09-02">
<title>Credit Union Examination Reform Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5419v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-09-02">
<action-date>2016-06-09</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Credit Union Examination Reform Act of 2016</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Federal Credit Union Act to permit an examination to be carried out only once every 18 months of a federal credit union or an insured credit union that:</p> <ul> <li> has total assets of less than $1 billion;</li> <li> is well capitalized (or adequately capitalized, in the case of an insured credit union);</li> <li> was found in its most recent examination to be well managed, with a composite rating (under the Uniform Financial Institutions Rating System) of 1, in the case of a credit union that has total assets of more than $200 million, or 1 or 2, in the case of a credit union that has total assets of $200 million or less; and</li> <li> is not currently subject to a formal enforcement proceeding or order by the National Credit Union Administration (NCUA).</li> </ul> <p>Such limitation shall not apply if the NCUA determines that such a credit union: (1) should be examined more often because of safety and soundness concerns, or (2) has violated the law.</p> <p> The NCUA shall issue a report on how this bill affects its budget.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
