<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1073" measure-id="id114hr1073" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-02-25" update-date="2015-11-25">
<title>CIPA</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1073v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-11-25">
<action-date>2015-11-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the House on August 4, 2015. The summary of that version is repeated here.)</p> <p><strong>Critical Infrastructure Protection Act or CIPA</strong></p> <p> (Sec. 2) Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to define &quot;EMP&quot; to mean: (1) an electromagnetic pulse caused by intentional means, including acts of terrorism; and (2) a geomagnetic disturbance caused by solar storms or other naturally occurring phenomena.</p> <p>Directs DHS to: (1) include in national planning frameworks the threat of EMP events; and (2) conduct outreach to educate owners and operators of critical infrastructure, emergency planners, and emergency response providers of the threat of EMP events.</p> <p>Directs DHS to conduct research and development to mitigate the consequences of EMP events, including: (1) an objective scientific analysis of the risks to critical infrastructures from a range of EMP events; (2) determination of the critical national security assets and vital civic utilities and infrastructures that are at risk from EMP events; (3) an evaluation of emergency planning and response technologies that would address the findings and recommendations of experts, including those of the Commission to Assess the Threat to the United States from Electromagnetic Pulse Attack; (4) an analysis of available technology options to improve the resiliency of critical infrastructure to EMP; and (5) the restoration and recovery capabilities of critical infrastructure under differing levels of damage and disruption from various EMP events.</p> <p>Includes among the responsibilities of DHS relating to intelligence and analysis and infrastructure protection, to prepare and submit to specified congressional committees: (1) a recommended strategy to protect and prepare the critical infrastructure of the American homeland against EMP events, and (2) biennial updates on the status of such strategy. </p> <p>Requires DHS to report within 180 days after enactment of this Act on the progress made in meeting, and on an estimated date for completing, the requirements set forth under this Act. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1073v17" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-11-13">
<action-date>2015-08-04</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Critical Infrastructure Protection Act or CIPA</strong></p> <p> (Sec. 2) Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to define &quot;EMP&quot; to mean: (1) an electromagnetic pulse caused by intentional means, including acts of terrorism; and (2) a geomagnetic disturbance caused by solar storms or other naturally occurring phenomena.</p> <p>Directs DHS to: (1) include in national planning frameworks the threat of EMP events; and (2) conduct outreach to educate owners and operators of critical infrastructure, emergency planners, and emergency response providers of the threat of EMP events.</p> <p>Directs DHS to conduct research and development to mitigate the consequences of EMP events, including: (1) an objective scientific analysis of the risks to critical infrastructures from a range of EMP events; (2) determination of the critical national security assets and vital civic utilities and infrastructures that are at risk from EMP events; (3) an evaluation of emergency planning and response technologies that would address the findings and recommendations of experts, including those of the Commission to Assess the Threat to the United States from Electromagnetic Pulse Attack; (4) an analysis of available technology options to improve the resiliency of critical infrastructure to EMP; and (5) the restoration and recovery capabilities of critical infrastructure under differing levels of damage and disruption from various EMP events.</p> <p>Includes among the responsibilities of DHS relating to intelligence and analysis and infrastructure protection, to prepare and submit to specified congressional committees: (1) a recommended strategy to protect and prepare the critical infrastructure of the American homeland against EMP events, and (2) biennial updates on the status of such strategy. </p> <p>Requires DHS to report within 180 days after enactment of this Act on the progress made in meeting, and on an estimated date for completing, the requirements set forth under this Act.</p>  <p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1073v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-06-03">
<action-date>2015-02-25</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Critical Infrastructure Protection Act or CIPA</strong></p> <p> Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to require the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to: (1) include EM threats in national planning scenarios; and (2) conduct a campaign to proactively educate owners and operators of critical infrastructure, emergency planners, and emergency responders at all levels of government about EM threats. Defines &quot;EM threat&quot; to mean an electromagnetic pulse caused by: (1) a nuclear or non-nuclear device, including by an act of terrorism; or (2) a geomagnetic disturbance or other naturally occurring phenomenon.</p> <p>Directs DHS to conduct research and development to mitigate the consequences of EM threats, including: (1) an objective scientific analysis of the risks to critical infrastructures from a range of EM threats; (2) determination of the critical national security assets and vital civic utilities and infrastructures that are at risk from EM threats; (3) an evaluation of emergency planning and response technologies that would address the findings and recommendations of experts, including those of the Commission to Assess the Threat to the United States from Electromagnetic Pulse Attack; (4) an analysis of available technology options to improve the resiliency of critical infrastructure to EM threats; and (5) the restoration and recovery capabilities of critical infrastructure under differing levels of damage and disruption from various EM threats.</p> <p>Includes among the responsibilities of DHS, relating to intelligence and analysis and infrastructure protection, to prepare and submit to specified congressional committees: (1) a comprehensive plan to protect and prepare the critical infrastructure of the American homeland against EM threats, including from acts of terrorism; and (2) biennial updates of such plan. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
