<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3592" measure-id="id114hr3592" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-09-22" update-date="2016-02-08">
<title>To establish a pilot program to reduce the number of vehicles owned by certain Federal departments and increase the use of ride-sharing services.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3592v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-02-08">
<action-date>2015-09-22</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill directs the Departments of Agriculture, the Interior, and Energy to each establish a pilot program to: (1) reduce the inventory of light vehicles owned by the department by 10% for each of the 5 fiscal years beginning after the expiration of the 1-year period starting on the date of enactment of this Act, and (2) increase the department's use of commercial ride-sharing companies.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
