<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3353" measure-id="id114hr3353" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-07-29" update-date="2016-06-27">
<title>To amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to limit attorney fees and penalties in citizen suits, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3353v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-06-27">
<action-date>2015-07-29</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (commonly known as the Clean Water Act) to limit the amount that may be awarded for the costs of litigation in citizen suits. An award of litigation costs may not exceed: (1) an amount that is proportional to the number of successful claims included in the complaint, or (2) the amount of monetary penalties.</p> <p>The award of litigation costs must be based on the prevailing rates in the local market area where the violation occurred for the kind and quality of the services furnished. </p> <p>Citizen suits may not be commenced if the Environmental Protection Agency or a state has commenced and is diligently prosecuting a civil or criminal action through the issuance of a compliance order.</p> <p>The bill provides for certain affirmative defenses for a person who may be liable for the unlawful discharge of a pollutant under the Clean Water Act.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
