<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3763" measure-id="id114hr3763" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-10-20" update-date="2016-04-15">
<title>Surface Transportation Reauthorization and Reform Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3763v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-04-15">
<action-date>2015-10-20</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Surface Transportation Reauthorization and Reform Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>This bill authorizes appropriations out of the Highway Trust Fund (HTF) (other than the Mass Transit Account) for FY2016-FY2021 for certain core federal-aid highway and related programs, prescribing obligation ceilings for federal-aid highway and highway safety construction programs.</p> <p>The bill revises and prescribes requirements for:</p> <ul> <li>surface transportation programs; and</li> <li>minimum penalties for repeat offenders for driving while intoxicated or under the influence, including mandatory ignition interlock systems.</li> </ul> <p>The Transportation Infrastructure Finance and Innovation Act of 1998 is amended to extend for the same period the state infrastructure bank program.</p> <p><em>Federal Public Transportation Act of 2015</em></p> <p>The bill revises and prescribes requirements, as well as authorizes appropriations from the HTF Mass Transit Account, for certain public transportation grant programs, and reauthorizes:</p> <ul> <li>National Highway Traffic Safety Administration safety programs,</li> <li>(for FY2016) the motor carrier safety assistance grant program, and</li> <li>Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration (FMCSA) Financial Assistance Programs.</li> </ul> <p>The Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users is amended to reauthorize FMCSA grant programs for FY2016.</p> <p><em>Transportation for Tomorrow Act of 2015</em></p> <p>The bill reauthorizes for FY2016-FY2021 the highway research and development program and certain innovative programs, and abolishes the Office of Intermodalism of the Department of Transportation (DOT).</p> <p><em>Hazardous Materials Transportation Safety Improvement Act of 2015</em></p> <p>The bill reauthorizes for the same period hazardous materials (hazmat) transportation safety projects.</p> <p>DOT may make certain expenditures during the same period, including an amount for hazmat training grants, from the Hazardous Materials Emergency Preparedness Fund. </p> <p><i>Positive Train Control Enforcement and Implementation Act of 2015</i></p> <p>The bill extends deadlines and modifies requirements for Class I, Class II, and Class III railroad carriers as well as providers of intercity or commuter rail passenger transportation to implement positive train control systems.</p> <p>The bill revises requirements for the National Multimodal Freight Network.</p> <p>DOT shall establish:</p> <ul> <li> a National Surface Transportation and Innovative Finance Bureau, and </li> <li>a Council on Credit and Finance.</li> </ul> <p>The Dingell-Johnson Sport Fish Restoration Act is amended to authorize appropriations from the Sport Fish Restoration and Boating Trust Fund for the same period for certain allocations of funds to states for:</p> <ul> <li>fish restoration and management projects,</li> <li>boating infrastructure improvement projects, </li> <li>Coast Guard (CG) administration, and</li> <li>CG administrative expenses for state recreational boating safety and national recreational boating programs.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
