<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3383" measure-id="id114hr3383" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-07-29" update-date="2015-10-26">
<title>Child Performers Protection Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3383v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-10-26">
<action-date>2015-07-29</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Child Performers Protection Act of 2015</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to revise the application of child labor requirements and prohibitions with respect to child performers to specify new limitations on the number of hours such children may be employed at the place of employment.</p> <p>An employer or contractor may not: (1) employ any child performer unless a trust meeting specified requirements has been established on the child performer's behalf and the employer has obtained the account number of the trust account or other proof of its existence; or (2) compensate a child performer in any form besides cash wages, exclusive of board, lodging, or facilities.</p> <p>Any employment or contracting of a child performer that is not in accordance with such limitations and requirements shall be treated as oppressive labor.</p> <p>Certain work hour restrictions shall not apply to child performers employed in a live theatrical production.</p>  <p>Any individual in a supervisory role with respect to a child performer shall be liable for unlawful discrimination on the basis of sex against a child performer whether or not the individual is employed by or contracted by a covered employer or contractor.</p> <p>Any child performer aggrieved by unlawful harassment on the basis of sex, or the performer's parent or guardian, may bring a civil action in any federal court of competent jurisdiction to recover equitable relief and compensatory and punitive damages, costs, and attorneys fees.</p> <p>The employer of an individual who is alleged to have engaged in unlawful harassment on the basis of sex against a child performer shall conduct an internal review of its policies and procedures for protecting child performers and ensuring appropriate compliance with the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
