<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3151" measure-id="id114hr3151" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-07-22" update-date="2015-09-03">
<title>Arrest Statistics Reporting Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3151v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-09-03">
<action-date>2015-07-22</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Arrest Statistics Reporting Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>This bill requires U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement to publish annually and make publicly available a report that includes for each person arrested during the preceding year, and for whom a request was submitted to the Law Enforcement Support Center or any potential matches forwarded under the information sharing program between the Department of Justice and the Department of Homeland Security, the following information: </p> <ul> <li>the person's nationality and immigration status, and </li> <li>the offense for which the person was arrested. </li> </ul> <p>The Federal Bureau of Investigation shall: </p> <ul> <li>revise the Uniform Crime Reports to require that each arrest report shall include such published arrest information, and </li> <li>publish a summary of the data which shall include a table containing the National Crime Information Center offense codes and the corresponding occurrences for each nationality and immigration status category.</li></ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
