<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="931" measure-id="id114hr931" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-02-12" update-date="2015-07-15">
<title>HEAL Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr931v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-07-15">
<action-date>2015-02-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Helping Effective Antibiotics Last Act of 2015 or the HEAL Act</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to allow the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) to approve an antibacterial drug or biological product that is intended to treat a serious or life-threatening condition only for treating a well-defined population of patients. To be approved, the antibacterial product must produce superior outcomes over available therapies in the well-defined patient population.</p> <p>A product approved by this pathway must include in its prescribing information the population of patients expected to benefit from using the product and the method for identifying members of that population. The FDA must require each product to have a risk evaluation and mitigation strategy.</p> <p>The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention must monitor changes to bacterial drug resistance and changes to patient outcomes caused by bacterial drug resistance.</p> <p>Upon approval of antibacterial products, the FDA must identify susceptibility test interpretive criteria (the drug concentrations where a type of bacteria is categorized as susceptible, intermediate, or resistant) and update the criteria as needed based upon evidence of changes in patient outcomes. </p> <p>To be eligible for an exclusivity period extension, a qualified infectious disease product must be demonstrated to produce superior outcomes over available therapies.</p> The FDA must issue guidance on the development of target product profiles for antibacterial drugs.]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
