<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5233" measure-id="id114hr5233" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-05-13" update-date="2016-09-22">
<title>Clarifying Congressional Intent in Providing for DC Home Rule Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5233v81" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-09-22">
<action-date>2016-05-25</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The expanded summary of the House reported version is repeated here.)</p> <p><b>Clarifying Congressional Intent in Providing for DC Home Rule Act of 2016</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill repeals the Local Budget Autonomy Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Law 19-321) and restores previous law as though the Act had never been enacted.</p> <p>(Sec. 3) The District of Columbia Home Rule Act is amended to declare that nothing in it shall be construed as creating a continuing appropriation of the General Fund of the District.</p> <p>All funds provided for the District of Columbia shall be appropriated on an annual fiscal year basis through the federal appropriations process.</p> <p>The District of Columbia Code is amended to declare that nothing in it shall be construed as authorizing the District of Columbia to make any change in law, regulation, or basic procedure and practice relating to the respective roles of Congress, the President, the Office of Management and Budget, and the Government Accountability Office in the preparation, review, submission, examination, authorization, and appropriation of the total budget of the District of Columbia government.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5233v79" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-09-22">
<action-date>2016-05-23</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p><b>Clarifying Congressional Intent in Providing for DC Home Rule Act of 2016</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill repeals the Local Budget Autonomy Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Law 19-321) and restores previous law as though the Act had never been enacted.</p> <p>(Sec. 3) The District of Columbia Home Rule Act is amended to declare that nothing in it shall be construed as creating a continuing appropriation of the General Fund of the District.</p> <p>All funds provided for the District of Columbia shall be appropriated on an annual fiscal year basis through the federal appropriations process.</p> <p>The District of Columbia Code is amended to declare that nothing in it shall be construed as authorizing the District of Columbia to make any change in law, regulation, or basic procedure and practice relating to the respective roles of Congress, the President, the Office of Management and Budget, and the Government Accountability Office in the preparation, review, submission, examination, authorization, and appropriation of the total budget of the District of Columbia government.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5233v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-05-17">
<action-date>2016-05-13</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Clarifying Congressional Intent in Providing for DC Home Rule Act of 2016</b></p> <p>This bill repeals the Local Budget Autonomy Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Law 19-321), and restores previous law as though the Act had never been enacted.</p> <p>The District of Columbia Home Rule Act is amended to declare that nothing in it shall be construed as creating a continuing appropriation of the General Fund of the District.</p> <p>All funds provided for the District of Columbia shall be appropriated on an annual fiscal year basis through the federal appropriations process.</p> <p>The District of Columbia Code is amended to declare that nothing in it shall be construed as authorizing the District of Columbia to make any change in law, regulation, or basic procedure and practice relating to the respective roles of the Congress, the President, the federal Office of Management and Budget, and the Government Accountability Office in the preparation, review, submission, examination, authorization, and appropriation of the total budget of the District of Columbia government.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
