<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4427" measure-id="id114hr4427" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-02-02" update-date="2016-06-03">
<title>To amend section 203 of the Federal Power Act.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4427v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-06-03">
<action-date>2016-03-14</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill amends the Federal Power Act with respect to the prohibition regarding mergers or consolidations by a public utility. Any merger or consolidation of a public utility whose value exceeds $10 million must first be authorized by the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC).</p> <p>In addition, FERC is required to promulgate a rule within 180 days that mandates any public utility seeking to merge or consolidate to notify FERC, within 30 days of transaction consummation, if the value of such merger or consolidation exceeds $1 million but is less than $10 million.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4427v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-03-14">
<action-date>2016-02-02</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill amends the Federal Power Act with respect to the prohibition against direct or indirect merger or consolidation by a public utility of its facilities (or any part of them) with those of any other person, by any means whatsoever, without first having secured the authorization of the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission.</p> <p>This prohibition shall apply only to facilities (or any part of them) whose value exceeds $10 million.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
