<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="832" measure-id="id114hr832" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-02-10" update-date="2015-03-18">
<title>Veterans Employment and Training Service Longitudinal Study Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr832v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-03-18">
<action-date>2015-02-10</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Veterans Employment and Training Service Longitudinal Study Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>Directs the Secretary of Labor to enter into a contract with a non-governmental entity to conduct a longitudinal study of a statistically valid sample of each of the following groups of individuals over a period of at least five years: (1) veterans who have received intensive job counseling, training, and placement services; (2) veterans who did not receive intensive services but who otherwise received services; and (3) veterans who did not seek or receive services.</p> <p>Requires the study to include the collection of specified information for each individual who participates in the study, including:</p> <ul> <li>the average number of months served on active duty,</li> <li>the distribution of disability ratings,</li> <li>unemployment benefits received,</li> <li>the average number of months employed and average individual and household annual income,</li> <li>employment status,</li> <li>whether the individual believes that any service received helped the individual to become employed,</li> <li>use of educational assistance,</li> <li>participation in a vocational rehabilitation program,</li> <li>conditions of discharge or release from the Armed Forces, and</li> <li>demographic information.</li> </ul> <p>Directs the Secretary to submit annual reports on the outcomes of the study that include any information the Secretary determines is necessary to determine long-term outcomes of the individuals in such groups.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
