<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2568" measure-id="id114hr2568" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-22" update-date="2016-01-13">
<title>Fair Medical Audits Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2568v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-01-13">
<action-date>2015-05-22</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p class="MsoNormal"><b>Fair Medical Audits Act of 2015</b></p> <p>This bill amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to modify requirements related to the identification and recovery of overpayments under Medicare.</p> <p>A contract between the the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS) and a recovery audit contractor must require the contractor to provide a health care provider with: (1) specified identifying, legal, and logistical information; (2) an identification of any errors or underpayments discovered in the audit; and (3) a description of how any requested overpayment amount was calculated. Standards for extrapolation when used to determine overpayment amounts are established. CMS must require a contractor to give a provider at least 90 days' notice of identified code over-utilization and to reimburse a provider for the cost of producing certain documentation. The retrospective audit period is limited to two (rather than four) years. </p> <p>Recovery audit contractors must have staff with knowledge and experience related to clinical licensure and medical records, claims, and codes. A contractor that has excessive overturned determinations shall be subject to administrative penalty and, under specified circumstances, liable for attorneys' fees. </p> <p>In the case of a provider seeking reconsideration of an overpayment determination, CMS may not recoup the overpayment until a decision has been rendered at the third level of appeal by an Administrative Law Judge. A recoupment based on a decision that is reversed on appeal must be returned to the provider within 30 days.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
