<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4245" measure-id="id114hr4245" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-12-11" update-date="2016-11-04">
<title>To exempt exportation of certain echinoderms and mollusks from licensing requirements under the Endangered Species Act of 1973.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4245v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-11-04">
<action-date>2016-09-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(Sec. 1) This bill: (1) exempts exporters of sea urchins, sea cucumbers, squid, octopus, and cuttlefish that are designated as food for humans or animals or taken for recreational purposes from licensing requirements; and (2) requires the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service to amend regulations concerning transporting wildlife to clarify that those sea urchins, sea cucumbers, squid, octopus, and cuttlefish are fishery products exempt from the export permission requirements under the Endangered Species Act of 1973. Thus, those exporters will be exempted from: (1) inspections to ensure shipments of those fishery products do not contain endangered or threatened species, and (2) related inspection fees.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4245v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-09-06">
<action-date>2015-12-11</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill exempts importers and exporters of sea urchins and sea cucumbers that are designated as food for humans or animals or taken for recreational purposes from licensing requirements. Thus, those importers and exporters will be exempted from: (1) inspections to ensure shipments of those sea urchins and sea cucumbers do not contain endangered or threatened species, and (2) related inspection fees.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
