<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="38" measure-id="id114hr38" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-01-06" update-date="2015-01-14">
<title>Preventing Executive Overreach on Immigration Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr38v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-01-14">
<action-date>2015-01-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Preventing Executive Overreach on Immigration Act of 2015</strong></p> <p> Prohibits the executive branch of the government from: </p> <ul> <li>exempting or deferring from removal, by executive order, regulation, or any other means, categories of aliens considered under the immigration laws to be unlawfully present in the United States; </li> <li>treating such aliens as if they were lawfully present or had a lawful immigration status; or </li> <li>treating them other than as unauthorized aliens. </li> </ul> <p>States that such prohibition shall not apply: </p> <ul> <li>to the extent prohibited by the Constitution; </li> <li>upon the request of federal, state, or local law enforcement agencies for purposes of maintaining aliens in the United States to be tried for crimes or to be trial witnesses; or </li> <li>for humanitarian purposes where the aliens are at imminent risk of serious bodily harm or death. </li> </ul> <p>Declares that any executive branch action intending to circumvent the objectives of this Act shall be null and void and without legal effect. </p> <p>States that this Act shall take effect as if enacted on November 20, 2014, and shall apply to requests submitted on or after that date for: (1) work authorization; or (2) exemption from, or deferral of, removal.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
