<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2978" measure-id="id114hr2978" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-07-08" update-date="2015-08-18">
<title>Thirteenth Amendment Commemorative Coin Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2978v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-08-18">
<action-date>2015-07-08</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Thirteenth Amendment Commemorative Coin Act</b></p> <p>Directs the Department of the Treasury to mint and issue the following coins in commemoration of the sesquicentennial anniversary of the passage of the Thirteenth Amendment to the Constitution:</p> <ul> <li>up to 250,000 $50 bi-metallic platinum and gold coins,</li> <li>up to 250,000 $20 gold coins, and</li> <li> up to 500,000 $1 silver coins.</li> </ul> <p>Requires such coins to be considered legal tender and numismatic items.</p> <p>Permits Treasury to issue such coins only during the one-year period beginning January 1 of the issuance year, except that sales may be initiated, without issuance, before such date.</p> <p>Requires specified surcharges that Treasury receives from the sale of such coins to be paid to the Smithsonian National Museum of African American History and Culture.</p> <p>Directs Treasury to ensure that: (1) the minting and issuing of such coins will not result in any net cost to the U.S. government; and (2) no funds, including applicable surcharges, are disbursed to the Museum until the total cost of designing and issuing all such coins is recovered by the Treasury.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
