<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1678" measure-id="id114hr1678" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-03-26" update-date="2015-05-04">
<title>National Positioning, Navigation, and Timing Resilience and Security Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1678v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-05-04">
<action-date>2015-03-26</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>National Positioning, Navigation, and Timing Resilience and Security Act of 2015</b></p> <p>Directs the Department of Defense to provide for the establishment of a reliable land-based positioning, navigation, and timing system to complement and back up the global positioning system (GPS) to ensure the availability of uncorrupted or non-degraded signals for military and civilian users if GPS signals are corrupted, degraded, unreliable, or otherwise unavailable.</p> <p>Requires the system to: (1) be wireless, terrestrial, and wide-area; (2) provide a precise, high-power 100 kilohertz signal; (3) be able to penetrate underground and inside buildings; (4) take advantage of existing, unused government long-range navigation system (LORAN) infrastructure and work in concert with enhanced long-range navigation systems (eLORAN); and (5) incorporate private sector expertise. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
