<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2028" measure-id="id114hr2028" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-04-24" update-date="2016-06-03">
<title>Energy and Water Development and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2028v35" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-06-03">
<action-date>2016-05-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed Senate amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Highlights: </b></p> <p>The Energy and Water Development and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2017 provides FY2017 appropriations for:</p> <ul> <li> the civil works projects of the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers; </li> <li>the Department of the Interior's Bureau of Reclamation and Central Utah Project; </li> <li>the Department of Energy (DOE); and</li> <li>several independent agencies, including the Nuclear Regulatory Commission. </li> </ul> <p>The bill increases overall FY2017 Energy and Water Development funding above FY2016 levels. The bill includes increases for both DOE and the Army Corps of Engineers, while funding the Department of the Interior's Bureau of Reclamation at the FY2016 level. </p> <p>Within the DOE budget, the bill increases funding for Science and the National Nuclear Security Administration. </p> <p>The bill does not include FY2017 funding for Nuclear Waste Disposal. It authorizes DOE to conduct a pilot program with private sector partners to provide interim storage for spent nuclear fuel and high-level radioactive waste. </p> <p>Also included in the bill is a provision restricting the Corps of Engineers from advancing regulations changing the definition of &quot;fill material&quot; or &quot;discharge of fill material&quot; under the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (commonly known as the Clean Water Act). </p> <p><b>Full Summary: </b></p> <p><b>Energy and Water Development and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2017 </b></p> <p>TITLE I--CORPS OF ENGINEERS--CIVIL </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers for authorized civil functions pertaining to rivers and harbors, flood and storm damage reduction, shore protection, aquatic ecosystem restoration, and related efforts. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Corps of Engineers for: </p> <ul> <li> Investigations; </li> <li>Construction; </li> <li> Mississippi River and Tributaries, including flood damage reduction projects in the Mississippi River alluvial valley below Cape Girardeau, Missouri; </li> <li> Operation and Maintenance; </li> <li> the Regulatory Program pertaining to navigable waters and wetlands; </li> <li> the Formerly Utilized Sites Remedial Action Program for clean-up of early atomic energy program contamination; </li> <li> Flood Control and Coastal Emergencies, including hurricanes, floods, and other natural disasters; </li> <li> Expenses necessary for the supervision and general administration of the civil works program; and </li> <li> the Office of the Assistant Secretary of the Army for Civil Works. </li> </ul> <p>(Sec. 101) Establishes reprogramming guidelines and requirements for funds provided in this title. Prohibits the availability of funds for obligation or expenditure through reprogramming that would: (1) create, initiate, or eliminate a program, project, or activity; (2) increase funds or personnel for any program, project, or activity for which funds are either denied or restricted by this bill; (3) reduce funds that are directed to be used for a specific purpose by this bill; or (4) reprogram funds for specific projects, programs, or activities by more than specified amounts. </p> <p>Specifies exceptions and requires the Corps of Engineers to submit a report to Congress establishing the baseline for application of reprogramming and transfer authorities for the current fiscal year. </p> <p>Prohibits funds provided by this title from being used for a contract that commits funds beyond the amounts appropriated for that program, project, or activity that remain unobligated. Includes exception for funds made available through reprogramming. </p> <p>(Sec. 102) Permits the Corps of Engineers to transfer to the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service up to $5.4 million in Operation and Maintenance funds to mitigate for fisheries lost due to Corps of Engineers civil works projects. </p> <p>(Sec. 103) Prohibits the Corps of Engineers from using funds to develop, adopt, implement, administer, or enforce any change to regulations in effect on October 1, 2012, pertaining to the definitions of &quot;fill material&quot; or &quot;discharge of fill material&quot; for the purposes of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (commonly known as the Clean Water Act). </p> <p>(Sec. 104) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used for open lake disposal of dredged sediment in Lake Erie unless the disposal meets the water and environmental standards of a state's water permitting agency and is consistent with a state's Coastal Zone Management Plan. Requires the Corps of Engineers to maintain its funding obligations for upland placement of dredged material with cost sharing if the standard is not met. </p> <p>(Sec. 105) Prohibits funds provided by this title from being used for the acquisition of certain welded shipboard anchor and mooring chains unless they are manufactured in the United States. </p> <p>(Sec. 106) Requires specified Operation and Maintenance funds to be used for Upper Missouri River Basin flood and drought monitoring. </p> <p>(Sec. 107) Amends the Water Resources Development Act of 2007 to require the Corps of Engineers to take regional impacts and effects into account when conducting a study of harbor and navigation improvements and recommending projects. </p> <p>TITLE II--DEPARTMENT OF THE INTERIOR </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Department of the Interior for the Central Utah Project. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Bureau of Reclamation for: </p> <ul> <li> Water and Related Resources, </li> <li> the Central Valley Project Restoration Fund, </li> <li> California Bay-Delta Restoration, and </li> <li> Policy and Administration. </li> </ul> <p>Permits appropriations to the Bureau of Reclamation to be used for purchasing replacements for up to five passenger motor vehicles.</p> <p> (Sec. 201) Prohibits funds provided in this title for Water and Related Resources from being used for a reprogramming that would: (1) create, initiate, or eliminate a program, project, or activity; (2) increase funds for any program, project, or activity for which funds have been denied or restricted by this bill; (3) restart or resume any program, project, or activity for which funds are not provided in this bill unless prior approval is received from Congress; or (4) transfer funds in excess of specified limits or in violation of specified requirements without the approval of Congress. </p> <p>Requires the Bureau of Reclamation to submit quarterly reports to Congress detailing funds that have been reprogrammed. </p> <p>(Sec. 202) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to determine the final point of discharge for the interceptor drain for the San Luis Unit until Interior and California develop a plan to minimize any detrimental effect of the San Luis drainage waters. Requires the plan to conform to California water quality standards as approved by the Environmental Protection Agency.</p> <p> Directs Interior to classify the costs of the Kesterson Reservoir Cleanup Program and the San Joaquin Valley Drainage Program as either reimbursable or nonreimbursable and collected until fully repaid pursuant to specified alternative repayment plans. </p> <p>Requires future federal obligations of funds regarding drainage service or drainage studies for the San Luis Unit to be fully reimbursable by San Luis Unit beneficiaries of the service or studies. </p> <p>(Sec. 203) Amends the Calfed Bay-Delta Authorization Act to extend the authorization through 2019. </p> <p>(Sec. 204) Amends the Secure Water Act of 2009 to increase the authorization of appropriations for grants and cooperative agreements for water management improvement and to require a portion of the funds to be used for pilot projects to increase Colorado River System water in Lake Mead and the initial units of Colorado River Storage Project reservoirs</p> <p>(Sec. 205) Amends the Energy and Water Development and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2016 to extend the deadline for the completion of a feasibility study relating to the Sites Reservoir in Colusa County, California. </p> <p>(Sec. 206) Permits Interior to: (1) enter into an agreement with the National Academy of Sciences for a study of the effectiveness and environmental impact of salt cedar control efforts in increasing water supplies, restoring riparian habitat, and improving flood management; and (2) prepare a plan for the removal of salt cedar from all federal land in the Lower Colorado River basin based on the study. </p> <p>TITLE III--DEPARTMENT OF ENERGY </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Department of Energy (DOE) for Energy Programs, including: </p> <ul> <li> Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy, </li> <li> Electricity Delivery and Energy Reliability, </li> <li> Nuclear Energy, </li> <li> Fossil Energy Research and Development, </li> <li> Naval Petroleum and Oil Shale Reserves, </li> <li> the Strategic Petroleum Reserve (SPR), </li> <li> the Northeast Home Heating Oil Reserve, </li> <li> the Energy Information Administration, </li> <li> Non-Defense Environmental Cleanup, </li> <li> the Uranium Enrichment Decontamination and Decommissioning Fund, </li> <li> Science, </li> <li> the Advanced Research Projects Agency-Energy, </li> <li> the Office of Indian Energy, </li> <li>the Tribal Energy Loan Guarantee Program, </li> <li> the Title 17 Innovative Technology Loan Guarantee Loan Program, </li> <li> the Advanced Technology Vehicles Manufacturing Loan Program, </li> <li> Departmental Administration, and </li> <li> the Office of the Inspector General. </li> </ul> <p>Provides appropriations for the Atomic Energy Defense Activities of the National Nuclear Security Administration (NNSA), including for: </p> <ul> <li> Weapons Activities, </li> <li>Defense Nuclear Nonproliferation, </li> <li> Naval Reactors, and </li> <li> Federal Salaries and Expenses. </li> </ul> <p>Provides appropriations for Environmental and Other Defense Activities, including: </p> <ul> <li>Defense Environmental Cleanup, </li> <li>Defense Uranium Enrichment Decontamination and Decommissioning, and </li> <li> Other Defense Activities. </li> </ul> <p>Provides appropriations for the Power Marketing Administrations, including: </p> <ul> <li> the Bonneville Power Administration Fund; </li> <li> Southeastern Power Administration Operation and Maintenance; </li> <li> Southwestern Power Administration Operation and Maintenance; </li> <li> Western Area Power Administration Operation and Maintenance, Construction, and Rehabilitation; and </li> <li> the Falcon and Amistad Operating and Maintenance Fund. </li> </ul> <p>Provides appropriations for the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission. </p> <p>(Sec. 301) Prohibits the use of funds provided in this title for programs, projects, or activities that have not been funded by Congress. </p> <p>Prohibits specified grants, contracts, allocations, and agreements unless Congress is notified in advance. </p> <p>Prohibits funds from being used for certain multiyear Department of Energy--Energy Programs activities unless specified conditions are met and Congress is notified. </p> <p>Establishes requirements and restrictions for the reprogramming of funds provided in this title.</p> <p> Permits unexpended balances of prior appropriations provided for activities in this bill to be transferred and merged with appropriations accounts established in this bill. </p> <p>(Sec. 302) Rescinds specified unobligated balances from various DOE accounts. </p> <p>(Sec. 303) Deems funds appropriated by this bill for intelligence activities to be specifically authorized by Congress during FY2017 until the enactment of the Intelligence Authorization Act for FY2017. </p> <p>(Sec. 304) Prohibits funds provided by this tile from being used to construct specified high-hazard nuclear facilities unless independent oversight is conducted by the Office of Independent Enterprise Assessments to ensure compliance with nuclear safety requirements. </p> <p>(Sec. 305) Prohibits funds provided by this title from being used to approve certain critical decisions for construction projects exceeding $100 million until a separate independent cost estimate has been developed. </p> <p>(Sec. 306) Authorizes DOE to conduct a pilot program with private sector partners to license, construct, and operate one or more storage facilities to provide interim storage for spent nuclear fuel and high-level radioactive waste. Permits the Nuclear Waste Fund to be used for this purpose, subject to appropriations. </p> <p>(Sec. 307) Requires the Western Area Power Administration to report to Congress on the uses of certain termination clauses in power contracts. </p> <p>TITLE IV--INDEPENDENT AGENCIES </p> <p>Provides appropriations for independent agencies, including: </p> <ul> <li> the Appalachian Regional Commission, </li> <li> the Defense Nuclear Facilities Safety Board, </li> <li> the Delta Regional Authority, </li> <li> the Denali Commission, </li> <li> the Northern Border Regional Commission, </li> <li> the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC), and </li> <li> the Nuclear Waste Technical Review Board. </li> </ul> <p>(Sec. 401) Permits the NRC to reprogram funds provided by this title if Congress is notified in advance regarding any proposed reprogramming that would change any program funding level by more than $500,000 or 10 percent, whichever is less. Permits the NRC to waive the notification requirement if compliance would pose a substantial risk to human health, the environment, welfare, or national security. </p> <p>Prohibits NRC funds from being used for a reprogramming that increases funds or personnel for any program, project, or activity for which funds are denied or restricted by this bill. </p> <p>Requires the NRC to submit a monthly report to Congress that includes total budget authority, unobligated balances, and unliquidated obligations for each program, project, or activity. </p> <p>TITLE V--GENERAL PROVISIONS </p> <p>(Sec. 501) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to influence congressional action on any legislation or appropriation matters pending before Congress. </p> <p>(Sec. 502) Prohibits transfers of funds made available in title III (Department of Energy) of this bill except pursuant to specified authorities for transferring funds or providing goods and services to another entity of the U.S. government. </p> <p>Requires agencies that utilize transfer authority to provide a semiannual report to Congress detailing the transfer authority used, including the amounts transferred and the purposes for which they were transferred. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2028v01" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-09-11">
<action-date>2015-05-21</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to Senate amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Highlights: </b></p> <p>The Energy and Water Development and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2016 provides FY2016 appropriations for the civil works projects of the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers; the Department of the Interior's Bureau of Reclamation and Central Utah Project; the Department of Energy (DOE); and several independent agencies, including the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC) and the Appalachian Regional Commission. </p> <p>The bill increases overall FY2016 Energy and Water Development funding above FY2015 levels and includes increases for DOE and the Department of the Interior's Bureau of Reclamation.</p> <p>For the Army Corps of Engineers, the bill increases base appropriations compared to FY2015 levels and includes a rescission of unobligated prior year balances. If the rescission is taken into account, the net appropriation is below FY2015 levels. </p> <p>Within the DOE budget, the bill </p> <ul> <li>increases funding above FY2015 levels for Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy, Electricity Delivery and Energy Reliability, Nuclear Energy, Fossil Energy Research and Development, Advanced Research Projects Agency-Energy, the National Nuclear Security Administration, Defense Environmental Cleanup, Science, and Defense Uranium Enrichment Decontamination and Decommissioning; and </li> <li>decreases funding below FY2015 levels for Non-Defense Environmental Cleanup and the Uranium Enrichment Decontamination and Decommissioning Fund.</li> </ul> <p>The bill does not include FY2016 funding for Nuclear Waste Disposal and funds the Power Marketing Administrations at the FY2015 level. </p> <p>The bill authorizes DOE to conduct a pilot program with private sector partners to provide interim storage for spent nuclear fuel and high-level radioactive waste. </p> <p>Also included in the bill is a provision restricting the Corps of Engineers from advancing regulations changing the definition of &quot;fill material&quot; under the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (commonly known as the Clean Water Act). </p> <p><b>Full Summary: </b></p> <p><b>Energy and Water Development and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2016 </b></p> <p> Provides FY2016 appropriations for energy and water development and related agencies.</p> <p>TITLE I--CORPS OF ENGINEERS--CIVIL </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers for authorized civil functions pertaining to rivers and harbors, flood and storm damage reduction, shore protection, aquatic ecosystem restoration, and related efforts. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Corps of Engineers for: (1) Investigations; (2) Construction; (3) Mississippi River and Tributaries, including flood damage reduction projects in the Mississippi River alluvial valley below Cape Girardeau, Missouri; (4) Operation and Maintenance; (5) the Regulatory Program pertaining to navigable waters and wetlands; (6) the Formerly Utilized Sites Remedial Action Program for clean-up of early atomic energy program contamination; (7) Flood Control and Coastal Emergencies, including hurricanes, floods, and other natural disasters; (8) Expenses necessary for the supervision and general administration of the civil works program; and (9) the Office of the Assistant Secretary of the Army for Civil Works. </p> <p>(Sec. 101) Establishes reprogramming guidelines and requirements for funds provided in this title. Prohibits the availability of funds for obligation or expenditure through reprogramming that would: (1) create, initiate, or eliminate a program, project, or activity; (2) increase funds or personnel for any program, project, or activity for which funds are either denied or restricted by this bill; (3) reduce funds that are directed to be used for a specific purpose by this bill; or (4) reprogram funds for specific projects, programs, or activities by more than specified amounts. </p> <p>Specifies exceptions and requires the Corps of Engineers to submit a report to Congress establishing the baseline for application of reprogramming and transfer authorities for the current fiscal year. </p> <p>(Sec. 102) Rescinds $128 million in unobligated balances from prior appropriations for water resources efforts in the Corps of Engineers--Civil Department of the Army--Construction account. </p> <p>(Sec. 103) Permits up to $4.7 million in Operation and Maintenance funds to be transferred to the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service to mitigate for fisheries lost due to Corps of Engineers projects. </p> <p>(Sec. 104) Prohibits the Corps of Engineers from using funds to develop, adopt, implement, administer, or enforce any change to regulations in effect on October 1, 2012, pertaining to the definitions of &quot;fill material&quot; or &quot;discharge of fill material&quot; for the purposes of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (commonly known as the Clean Water Act). </p> <p>(Sec. 105) Requires the Corps of Engineers to execute an agreement that transfers the Ten Mile Creek Water Preserve Area Critical Restoration Project to the South Florida Water Management District and requires the District to operate the project as an environmental restoration project to provide water storage and treatment options. Deauthorizes the project upon execution of the transfer agreement. </p> <p>(Sec. 106) Amends the Water Resources Development Act of 2007 to increase the length of time that the Corps of Engineers is responsible for the long-term maintenance and repair of the Lowell Creek Tunnel in Seward, Alaska until an alternative method of flood diversion is constructed and operational. </p> <p>(Sec. 107) Prohibits federal, contributed, or other non-federal funds from being used to reallocate or to study the reallocation of water within the Alabama-Coosa-Tallapoosa river basin, until the Corps of Engineers has executed a partnering agreement with Alabama and Georgia. </p> <p>TITLE II--DEPARTMENT OF THE INTERIOR </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Department of the Interior for the Central Utah Project; and the Bureau of Reclamation, including for Water and Related Resources, the Central Valley Project Restoration Fund, California Bay-Delta Restoration, and Policy and Administration. </p> <p>Permits appropriations to the Bureau of Reclamation to be used for purchasing replacements for up to five passenger motor vehicles. </p> <p>(Sec. 201) Prohibits funds provided in this title from being used for a reprogramming that would: (1) create, initiate, or eliminate a program, project, or activity; (2) increase funds for any program, project, or activity for which funds have been denied or restricted by this bill; (3) restart or resume any program, project, or activity for which funds are not provided in this bill unless prior approval is received from Congress or (4) transfer funds in excess of specified limits or in violation of specified requirements without the approval of Congress. </p> <p>Requires the Bureau of Reclamation to submit quarterly reports to Congress detailing funds that have been reprogrammed. </p> <p>(Sec. 202) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to determine the final point of discharge for the interceptor drain for the San Luis Unit until Interior and California develop a plan to minimize any detrimental effect of the San Luis drainage waters. Requires the plan to conform to California water quality standards as approved by the EPA. </p> <p>Directs Interior to classify the costs of the Kesterson Reservoir Cleanup Program and the San Joaquin Valley Drainage Program as either reimbursable or nonreimbursable and collected until fully repaid pursuant to specified alternative repayment plans. </p> <p>Requires future federal obligations of funds regarding drainage service or drainage studies for the San Luis Unit to be fully reimbursable by San Luis Unit beneficiaries of the service or studies. </p> <p>(Sec. 203) Amends the Secure Water Act of 2009 to increase the authorization of appropriations for grants and cooperative agreements for water management improvement from $300 million to $500 million. </p> <p>(Sec. 204) Amends the Calfed Bay-Delta Authorization Act to extend the authorization through 2020. </p> <p>(Sec. 205) Amends the Reclamation Safety of Dams Act of 1978 to authorize Interior to conduct construction projects under the Act with benefits that include, but are not limited to additional conservation storage capacity. (Under current law, construction under the Act is limited to dam safety and does not include providing additional conservation storage capacity.) </p> <p>(Sec. 206) Amends the Reclamation Safety of Dams Act of 1978 to increase: (1) the authorization of appropriations for construction under the Act, and (2) the limitation on appropriations that may be used to modify an existing dam. Requires Interior to notify Congress prior to obligating modification expenditures exceeding specified amounts. </p> <p>(Sec. 207) Sets forth deadlines for Interior to complete specified feasibility studies required by the Water Supply, Reliability, and Environmental Improvement Act for water storage projects in California. </p> <p>(Sec. 208) Permits funds provided by this bill for California Bay-Delta Restoration to be used to deliver water to the Trinity River above the minimum requirements of the Trinity Record of Decision or to supplement flows in the Klamath River. </p> <p>(Sec. 209) Permits funds provided by this bill for the Central Valley Project Restoration Fund to be used for all authorized activities necessary to supplement or enhance the instream flow requirements in California that are mandated by the Endangered Species Act of 1973 and the Central Valley Project Improvement Act </p> <p>TITLE III--DEPARTMENT OF ENERGY </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Department of Energy (DOE) for Energy Programs, including: </p> <ul> <li>Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy, </li> <li>Electricity Delivery and Energy Reliability,</li> <li>Nuclear Energy, </li> <li>Fossil Energy Research and Development, </li> <li>Naval Petroleum and Oil Shale Reserves, </li> <li>Strategic Petroleum Reserve (SPR), </li> <li>Northeast Home Heating Oil Reserve, </li> <li>Energy Information Administration, </li> <li>Non-Defense Environmental Cleanup, </li> <li>Uranium Enrichment Decontamination and Decommissioning Fund, </li> <li>Science, </li> <li>Advanced Research Projects Agency-Energy,</li> <li>Title 17 Innovative Technology Loan Guarantee Loan Program, </li> <li>Advanced Technology Vehicles Manufacturing Loan Program, </li> <li>Departmental Administration, and </li> <li>the Office of the Inspector General. </li> </ul> <p>Provides appropriations to DOE for Atomic Energy Defense Activities of the National Nuclear Security Administration, including for Weapons Activities, Defense Nuclear Nonproliferation, Naval Reactors, and Federal Salaries and Expenses. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to DOE for Environmental and Other Defense Activities for Defense Environmental Cleanup, Defense Uranium Enrichment Decontamination and Decommissioning, and Other Defense Activities. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to DOE for the Power Marketing Administrations, including (1) the Bonneville Power Administration Fund; (2) Southeastern Power Administration Operation and Maintenance; (3) Southwestern Power Administration Operation and Maintenance; (4) Western Area Power Administration Operation and Maintenance, Construction, and Rehabilitation; and (5) the Falcon and Amistad Operating and Maintenance Fund. </p> <p>Provides appropriations for the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission. </p> <p>(Sec. 301) Prohibits the use of funds provided in this title for programs, projects, or activities that have not been funded by Congress. Prohibits specified grants, contracts, allocations, and agreements unless Congress is notified in advance. Prohibits funds from being used for certain multiyear Department of Energy--Energy Programs activities unless specified conditions are met and Congress is notified. Establishes requirements and restrictions for the reprogramming of funds provided in this title. </p> <p>(Sec. 302) Permits unexpended balances of prior appropriations provided for activities in this bill to be transferred and merged with appropriations accounts established in this bill. </p> <p>(Sec. 303) Deems funds appropriated by this Act for intelligence activities to be specifically authorized by Congress during FY2016 until the enactment of the Intelligence Authorization Act for FY2016. </p> <p>(Sec. 304) Prohibits the use of funds made available in this title to construct specified high-hazard nuclear facilities unless independent oversight is conducted by the Office of Independent Enterprise Assessments to ensure compliance with nuclear safety requirements. </p> <p>(Sec. 305) Prohibits the use of funds provided in this title to approve certain critical decisions for construction projects exceeding $100 million until a separate independent cost estimate has been developed. </p> <p>(Sec. 306) Authorizes DOE to conduct a pilot program with private sector partners to license, construct, and operate one or more storage facilities to provide interim storage for spent nuclear fuel and high-level radioactive waste. Permits the Nuclear Waste Fund to be used for this purpose, subject to appropriations. </p> <p>(Sec. 307) Prohibits funds from being used to carry out a drawdown and sale or exchange of petroleum products from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve (SPR) unless DOE notifies Congress in advance. Specifies requirements for the notification DOE submits to Congress. </p> <p>Prohibits DOE from establishing any new regional petroleum product reserve unless funding is explicitly requested in advance and approved by Congress. </p> <p>(Sec. 308) Rescinds specified unobligated balances that were appropriated to DOE for Energy Programs and the Power Marketing Administrations for FY2005-FY2010.</p> <p>(Sec. 309) Rescinds specified unobligated balances previously appropriated to DOE for the National Nuclear Security Administration. </p> <p>(Sec. 310) Permits up to $50 million of the funds provided to the National Nuclear Security Administration for Weapons Activities to be reprogrammed for Domestic Uranium Enrichment. </p> <p>(Sec. 311) Permits DOD to: (1) enter into contracts to store spent nuclear fuel and high-level radioactive waste to which DOE holds the title or has a contract to accept title, and (2) enter into new contracts or modify existing contracts to accept title for high-level radioactive waste or spent nuclear fuel. </p> <p>Provides that delivery and acceptance by DOE of any spent fuel or waste for storage under this section shall constitute a transfer of title to DOE. </p> <p>(Sec. 312) Provides that specified requirements regarding the management of information technology projects and authorities of Chief Information Officers over the projects do not apply to Federal Funded Research and Development Centers sponsored by DOE. </p> <p>TITLE IV--INDEPENDENT AGENCIES </p> <p>Provides appropriations to: (1) the Appalachian Regional Commission, (2) the Defense Nuclear Facilities Safety Board, (3) the Delta Regional Authority, (4) the Denali Commission, (5) the Northern Border Regional Commission, (6) the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC), and (7) the Nuclear Waste Technical Review Board. </p> <p>(Sec. 401) Permits the NRC to reprogram funds provided by this title if Congress is notified in advance regarding any proposed reprogramming that would change any program funding level by more than $500,000 or 10 percent, whichever is less. Permits the NRC to waive the notification requirement if compliance would pose a substantial risk to human health, the environment, welfare, or national security. </p> <p>Prohibits NRC funds from being used for a reprogramming that increases funds or personnel for any program, project, or activity for which funds are denied or restricted by this bill. </p> <p>Requires the NRC to submit a monthly report to Congress that includes total budget authority, unobligated balances, and unliquidated obligations for each program, project, or activity. </p> <p>(Sec. 402) Requires the NRC to comply with specified internal procedures when responding to congressional requests for information. </p> <p>(Sec. 403) Amends the Omnibus Consolidated and Emergency Supplemental Appropriations Act, 1999 to permit the interest from the Trans-Alaska Pipeline Liability Fund that is deposited into the Oil Spill Liability Trust Fund and transferred to the Denali Commission to be used for the construction and repair of barge mooring points and barge landing sites to facilitate pumping fuel from fuel transport barges into bulk fuel storage tanks.</p> <p>TITLE V--GENERAL PROVISIONS </p> <p>(Sec. 501) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to influence congressional action on any legislation or appropriation matters pending before Congress. </p> <p>(Sec. 502) Prohibits transfers of funds made available in title III (Department of Energy) of this bill except pursuant to specified authorities for transferring funds or providing goods and services to another entity of the U.S. government. </p> <p>Requires agencies that utilize transfer authority to provide a semiannual report to Congress detailing the transfer authority used, including the amounts transferred and the purposes for which they were transferred. </p> <p>(Sec. 503) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used for Executive Order No. 13690 (Establishing a Federal Flood Risk Management Standard and a Process for Further Soliciting and Considering Stakeholder Input). </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2028v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-08-17">
<action-date>2015-05-01</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Highlights: </b></p> <p>The Energy and Water Development and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2016 provides FY2016 appropriations for the civil works projects of the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers, the Department of the Interior's Bureau of Reclamation and Central Utah Project; the Department of Energy (DOE); and several independent agencies, including the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC) and the Appalachian Regional Commission. </p> <p>The bill increases overall FY2016 Energy and Water Development funding above FY2015 levels and includes increases for both the Army Corps of Engineers and DOE. </p> <p>Within the DOE budget, the bill: </p> <ul> <li>increases funding above FY2015 levels for Electricity Delivery and Energy Reliability, Nuclear Energy, Nuclear Waste Disposal, Fossil Energy Research and Development, the Strategic Petroleum Reserve, Science, the National Nuclear Security Administration, and Defense Environmental cleanup; and </li> <li>decreases funding below FY2015 levels for Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy and Non-Defense Environmental Clean-Up. </li> </ul> <p>The bill decreases funding below FY2015 levels for the Department of the Interior's Bureau of Reclamation. </p> <p>Also included in the bill are provisions affecting policies on issues such as the definition of waters protected under the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (commonly known as the Clean Water Act), the definition of fill material under the Clean Water Act, the use of firearms by individuals at Army Corps of Engineers water resources development projects, the Yucca Mountain nuclear waste repository in Nevada, and the implementation of the National Ocean Policy. </p> <p><b>Full Summary: </b></p> <p><b>Energy and Water Development and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2016 </b></p> <p> Provides FY2016 appropriations for energy and water development and related agencies.</p> <p>TITLE I--CORPS OF ENGINEERS--CIVIL </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers for authorized civil functions pertaining to rivers and harbors, flood and storm damage reduction, shore protection, aquatic ecosystem restoration, and related efforts. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Corps of Engineers for: (1) Investigations; (2) Construction; (3) Mississippi River and Tributaries, including flood damage reduction projects in the Mississippi River alluvial valley below Cape Girardeau, Missouri; (4) Operation and Maintenance; (5) the Regulatory Program pertaining to navigable waters and wetlands; (6) the Formerly Utilized Sites Remedial Action Program for clean-up of early atomic energy program contamination; (7) Flood Control and Coastal Emergencies, including hurricanes, floods, and other natural disasters; (8) Expenses necessary for the supervision and general administration of the civil works program; and (9) the Office of the Assistant Secretary of the Army for Civil Works. </p> <p>(Sec. 101) Establishes reprogramming guidelines and requirements for funds provided in this title. Prohibits the availability of funds for obligation or expenditure through reprogramming that would: (1) create, initiate, or eliminate a program, project, or activity; (2) increase funds or personnel for any program, project, or activity for which funds are either denied or restricted by this bill; (3) reduce funds that are directed to be used for a specific purpose by this bill; or (4) increase or reduce funds for specific projects, programs, or activities by more than $2 million or 10%, whichever is less. </p> <p>Specifies exceptions and requires the Corps of Engineers to submit quarterly reports to Congress detailing all funds that have been reprogrammed. </p> <p>(Sec. 102) Prohibits funds provided by this title from being used for a contract that commits funds beyond the amounts appropriated for that program, project, or activity that remain unobligated. Includes exception for funds made available through reprogramming pursuant to section 101. </p> <p>(Sec. 103) Permits up to $4.7 million in Operation and Maintenance funds to be transferred to the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service to mitigate for fisheries lost due to Corps of Engineers projects. </p> <p>(Sec. 104) Prohibits the Corps of Engineers from using funds to develop, adopt, implement, administer, or enforce any change to regulations in effect on October 1, 2012, pertaining to the definitions of &quot;fill material&quot; or &quot;discharge of fill material&quot; for the purposes of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (commonly known as the Clean Water Act). </p> <p>(Sec. 105) Prohibits funds from being used to develop, adopt, implement, administer, or enforce any change to the regulations and guidance in effect on October 1, 2012, pertaining to the definition of waters under the jurisdiction of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (commonly known as the Clean Water Act) including provisions of specified rules pertaining to the jurisdiction. </p> <p>(Sec. 106) Prohibits funds made available by this bill from being used to require a permit for the discharge of dredged or fill material under the Clean Water Act for specified agricultural activities. </p> <p>(Sec. 107) Permits individuals to possess firearms at Corps of Engineers water resources development projects if: (1) the individual is not otherwise prohibited by law from possessing the firearm; and (2) the possession of the firearm complies with the law of the state in which the project is located. (The Corps of Engineers currently prohibits private individuals from possessing firearms and other weapons at the projects unless the weapons are being used for hunting, at authorized shooting ranges, or with written permission of the Corps District Commander.) </p> <p>(Sec. 108) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used for an open lake placement of dredged material originating from Lake Erie or tributaries, unless it is approved under a state water quality certification. </p> <p>TITLE II--DEPARTMENT OF THE INTERIOR </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Department of the Interior for the Central Utah Project; and the Bureau of Reclamation, including for Water and Related Resources, the Central Valley Project Restoration Fund, California Bay-Delta Restoration, and Policy and Administration. </p> <p>Permits appropriations to the Bureau of Reclamation to be used for purchasing replacements for up to five passenger motor vehicles. </p> <p>(Sec. 201) Prohibits funds provided in this title from being used for a reprogramming that would: (1) create, initiate, or eliminate a program, project, or activity; (2) increase funds for any program, project, or activity for which funds have been denied or restricted by this bill; (3) restart or resume any program, project, or activity for which funds are not provided in this bill unless prior approval is received from Congress or (4) transfer funds in excess of specified limits or in violation of specified requirements without the approval of Congress. </p> <p>(Sec. 202) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to determine the final point of discharge for the interceptor drain for the San Luis Unit until Interior and California develop a plan to minimize any detrimental effect of the San Luis drainage waters. Requires the plan to conform to California water quality standards as approved by the EPA. </p> <p>Directs Interior to classify the costs of the Kesterson Reservoir Cleanup Program and the San Joaquin Valley Drainage Program as either reimbursable or nonreimbursable and collected until fully repaid pursuant to specified alternative repayment plans. </p> <p>Requires future federal obligations of funds regarding drainage service or drainage studies for the San Luis Unit to be fully reimbursable by San Luis Unit beneficiaries of the service or studies. </p> <p>(Sec. 203) Sets forth deadlines for Interior to complete specified feasibility studies required by the Water Supply, Reliability, and Environmental Improvement Act for water storage projects in California. </p> <p>TITLE III--DEPARTMENT OF ENERGY </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Department of Energy (DOE) for Energy Programs, including: </p> <ul> <li>Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy, </li> <li>Electricity Delivery and Energy Reliability,</li> <li>Nuclear Energy, </li> <li>Fossil Energy Research and Development, </li> <li>Naval Petroleum and Oil Shale Reserves, </li> <li>Strategic Petroleum Reserve (SPR), </li> <li>Northeast Home Heating Oil Reserve, </li> <li>Energy Information Administration, </li> <li>Non-Defense Environmental Cleanup, </li> <li>Uranium Enrichment Decontamination and Decommissioning Fund, </li> <li>Science, </li> <li>Nuclear Waste Disposal, </li> <li>Advanced Research Projects Agency-Energy (ARPA-E), </li> <li>Title 17 Innovative Technology Loan Guarantee Loan Program, </li> <li>Advanced Technology Vehicles Manufacturing Loan Program, </li> <li>Departmental Administration, and </li> <li>the Office of the Inspector General. </li> </ul> <p>Provides appropriations to DOE for Atomic Energy Defense Activities of the National Nuclear Security Administration, including for Weapons Activities, Defense Nuclear Nonproliferation, Naval Reactors, and Federal Salaries and Expenses. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to DOE for Environmental and Other Defense Activities for Defense Environmental Cleanup, Defense Uranium Enrichment Decontamination and Decommissioning, and Other Defense Activities. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to DOE for the Power Marketing Administrations, including (1) the Bonneville Power Administration Fund; (2) Southeastern Power Administration Operation and Maintenance; (3) Southwestern Power Administration Operation and Maintenance; (4) Western Area Power Administration Operation and Maintenance, Construction, and Rehabilitation; and (5) the Falcon and Amistad Operating and Maintenance Fund. </p> <p>Provides appropriations for the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission. </p> <p>(Sec. 301) Prohibits the use of funds provided in this title for programs, projects, or activities that have not been funded by Congress. Prohibits specified grants, contracts, allocations, and agreements unless Congress is notified in advance. Prohibits funds from being used for certain multiyear DOE--Energy Programs activities unless specified conditions are met and Congress is notified. Establishes requirements and restrictions for the reprogramming of funds provided in this title. </p> <p>(Sec. 302) Permits unexpended balances of prior appropriations provided for activities in this bill to be transferred and merged with appropriations accounts established in this bill. </p> <p>(Sec. 303) Deems funds appropriated by this Act for intelligence activities to be specifically authorized by Congress during FY2016 until the enactment of the Intelligence Authorization Act for FY2016. </p> <p>(Sec. 304) Prohibits the use of funds made available in this title to construct specified high-hazard nuclear facilities unless independent oversight is conducted by the Office of Independent Enterprise Assessments to ensure compliance with nuclear safety requirements. </p> <p>(Sec. 305) Prohibits the use of funds provided in this title to approve certain critical decisions for construction projects exceeding $100 million until a separate independent cost estimate has been developed. </p> <p>(Sec. 306) Prohibits funds made available for Department of Energy--Energy Programs--Science from being used for any multiyear contract, grant, cooperative agreement, or other transaction agreement of $1 million or less unless the agreement is funded for the full period of performance anticipated at the time of award. </p> <p>(Sec. 307) Prohibits Defense Nuclear Nonproliferation funds from being used for contracts with or agreements for federal assistance to the Russian Federation. Permits DOE to waive the prohibition if the activity is in the national security interests of the United States and a report justifying the waiver is submitted to Congress. </p> <p>(Sec. 308) Prohibits funds from being used to carry out a drawdown and sale or exchange of petroleum products from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve (SPR) unless DOE notifies Congress in advance. Specifies requirements for the notification DOE submits to Congress. </p> <p>Prohibits DOE from establishing any new regional petroleum product reserve unless funding is explicitly requested in advance and approved by Congress. </p> <p>(Sec. 309) Permits up to $50 million of the funds provided to the National Nuclear Security Administration for Weapons Activities to be reprogrammed for Domestic Uranium Enrichment. </p> <p>(Sec. 310) Rescinds specified unobligated balances that were appropriated to DOE for FY2005-FY2010. </p> <p>TITLE IV--INDEPENDENT AGENCIES </p> <p>Provides appropriations to: (1) the Appalachian Regional Commission, (2) the Defense Nuclear Facilities Safety Board, (3) the Delta Regional Authority, (4) the Denali Commission, (5) the Northern Border Regional Commission, (6) the Southeast Crescent Regional Commission, (7) the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC), (8) the Nuclear Waste Technical Review Board, and (9) the Office of the Federal Coordinator for Alaska Natural Gas Transportation Projects. </p> <p>(Sec. 401) Requires the NRC to comply with specified internal procedures when responding to congressional requests for information. </p> <p>TITLE V--GENERAL PROVISIONS </p> <p>(Sec. 501) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to influence congressional action on any legislation or appropriation matters pending before Congress. </p> <p>(Sec. 502) Prohibits transfers of funds made available in title III (Department of Energy) of this bill except pursuant to specified authorities for transferring funds or providing goods and services to another entity of the U.S. government. </p> <p>Requires agencies that utilize transfer authority to provide a semiannual report to Congress detailing the transfer authority used, including the amounts transferred and the purposes for which they were transferred. </p> <p>(Sec. 503) Prohibits the use of funds to contravene Executive Order No. 12898 of February 11, 1994 (Federal Actions to Address Environmental Justice in Minority Populations and Low-Income Populations). </p> <p>(Sec. 504) Prohibits the use of funds provided by this bill: (1) to conduct closure of adjudicatory functions, technical review, or support activities associated with the Yucca Mountain (Nevada) geologic repository license application; or (2) for actions that irrevocably remove the possibility that Yucca Mountain may be a repository option in the future. </p> <p>(Sec. 505) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used for further implementation of the coastal and marine spatial planning and ecosystem-based management components of the National Ocean Policy developed under Executive Order 13547 (Stewardship of the Ocean, Our Coasts, and the Great Lakes.) </p> <p>(Sec. 506) Establishes a spending reduction account for the amount by which the subcommittee's allocation under section 302(b) of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 exceeds the amount of proposed new budget authority in the bill. Specifies that the amount is $0. (Under the Rules of the House of Representatives, any savings included in the spending reduction account are not available for further appropriation during consideration of the bill.)</p> <p>(Sec. 507) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to transform the National Energy Technology Laboratory into a government-owned, contractor-operated laboratory, or to consolidate or close the facility. </p> <p>(Sec. 508) Prohibits Defense Nuclear Nonproliferation funds provided by this bill from being used for new contracts or agreements for assistance to the Islamic Republic of Iran except for those requiring Iran to cease the pursuit, acquisition, and development of nuclear weapons technology. </p> <p>(Sec. 509) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to lease or purchase new light duty vehicles for any executive fleet or for an agency's fleet inventory, except in accordance with Presidential Memorandum--Federal Fleet Performance, dated May 24, 2011. </p> <p>(Sec. 510) Prohibits DOE from using funds provided by this bill for the proposed rule entitled &quot;Standards Ceiling Fans and Ceiling Fan Light Kits.&quot; </p> <p>(Sec. 511) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used in contravention of provisions of the Water Resources Reform and Development Act of 2014 and the Water Resources Development Act of 1986 related to funding from the Harbor Maintenance Trust Fund. </p> <p>(Sec. 512) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used for the Cape Wind Energy Project on the Outer Continental Shelf off Massachusetts in Nantucket Sound.</p> <p>(Sec. 513) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to implement or enforce certain regulations and statutory provisions establishing energy conservation standards for incandescent lamps. </p> <p>(Sec. 514) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used for Executive Order No. 13690 (Establishing a Federal Flood Risk Management Standard and a Process for Further Soliciting and Considering Stakeholder Input). </p> <p>(Sec. 515) Prohibits funds provided by this bill for Department of Energy--Energy Programs--Science from being used in contravention of the Department of Energy Organization Act. </p> <p>(Sec. 516) Prohibits DOD from using funds provided by this bill to purchase a certain anchor and mooring chain unless it is procured from a manufacturer that is part of the national technology and industrial base. </p> <p>(Sec. 517) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used for the removal of any federally owned or operated dam. </p> <p>(Sec. 518) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used for a contract with companies convicted, indicted, or charged with certain crimes or that have more than $3,000 in delinquent taxes within a three-year period surrounding the contract. </p> <p>(Sec. 519) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used for DOE's proposed rule entitled &quot;Energy Conservation Program for Consumer Products: Energy Conservation Standards for Residential Furnaces.&quot; </p> <p>(Sec. 520) Prohibits the Corps of Engineers from using funds provided by this bill to continue the study of the Missouri River and its tributaries, authorized by the Water Resources Development Act of 2007 to determine actions required to mitigate losses of aquatic and terrestrial habitat, recover federally listed endangered species, and restore the ecosystem to prevent further declines among other native species. </p> <p>(Sec. 521) Decreases funds provided by this bill for DOE's Departmental Administration account by $2.5 million and appropriates the funds to the Army Corps of Engineers Investigations account. </p> <p>(Sec. 522) Prohibits DOE from using fund provided by this bill to apply the report entitled &quot;Life Cycle Greenhouse Gas Perspective on Exporting Liquefied Natural Gas from the United States&quot; in any public interest determination by the Federal Power Commission authorizing the import or export of natural gas under section 3 of the Natural Gas Act. </p> <p>(Sec. 523) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used for DOE's Climate Model Development and Validation program. </p> <p>(Sec. 524) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to purchase water to supplement or enhance the instream flow requirements in California that are mandated under the Endangered Species Act of 1973, the Central Valley Project Improvement Act, or the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969. </p> <p>(Sec. 525) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to limit exemptions in the Clean Water Act for the discharge of dredged or fill material from certain agricultural activities by requiring that the activities be established or ongoing in order to receive an exemption. </p> <p>(Sec. 526) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to deliver water to the Trinity River above the minimum requirements of the Trinity Record of Decision or to supplement flows in the Klamath River. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2028v79" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-05-27">
<action-date>2015-04-24</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p><b>Highlights: </b></p> <p>The Energy and Water Development and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2016 provides FY2016 appropriations for the civil works projects of the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers, the Department of the Interior's Bureau of Reclamation and Central Utah Project; the Department of Energy (DOE); and several independent agencies, including the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC) and the Appalachian Regional Commission. </p> <p>The bill increases overall FY2016 Energy and Water Development funding above FY2015 levels and includes increases for both the Army Corps of Engineers and DOE. </p> <p>Within the DOE budget, the bill: </p> <ul> <li>increases funding above FY2015 levels for Electricity Delivery and Energy Reliability, Nuclear Energy, Nuclear Waste Disposal, Fossil Energy Research and Development, the Strategic Petroleum Reserve, Science, the National Nuclear Security Administration, and Defense Environmental cleanup; and </li> <li>decreases funding below FY2015 levels for Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy and Non-Defense Environmental Clean-Up. </li> </ul> <p>The bill decreases funding below FY2015 levels for the Department of the Interior's Bureau of Reclamation. </p> <p>Also included in the bill are provisions affecting policies on issues such as the definition of waters protected under the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (commonly known as the Clean Water Act), the definition of fill material under the Clean Water Act, the use of firearms by individuals at Army Corps of Engineers water resources development projects, the Yucca Mountain nuclear waste repository in Nevada, and the implementation of the National Ocean Policy. </p> <p><b>Full Summary: </b></p> <p><b>Energy and Water Development and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2016 </b></p> <p> Provides FY2016 appropriations for energy and water development and related agencies.</p> <p>TITLE I--CORPS OF ENGINEERS--CIVIL </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers for authorized civil functions pertaining to rivers and harbors, flood and storm damage reduction, shore protection, aquatic ecosystem restoration, and related efforts. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Corps of Engineers for: (1) Investigations; (2) Construction; (3) Mississippi River and Tributaries, including flood damage reduction projects in the Mississippi River alluvial valley below Cape Girardeau, Missouri; (4) Operation and Maintenance; (5) the Regulatory Program pertaining to navigable waters and wetlands; (6) the Formerly Utilized Sites Remedial Action Program for clean-up of early atomic energy program contamination; (7) Flood Control and Coastal Emergencies, including hurricanes, floods, and other natural disasters; (8) Expenses necessary for the supervision and general administration of the civil works program; and (9) the Office of the Assistant Secretary of the Army for Civil Works. </p> <p>(Sec. 101) Establishes reprogramming guidelines and requirements for funds provided in this title. Prohibits the availability of funds for obligation or expenditure through reprogramming that would: (1) create, initiate, or eliminate a program, project, or activity; (2) increase funds or personnel for any program, project, or activity for which funds are either denied or restricted by this bill; (3) reduce funds that are directed to be used for a specific purpose by this bill; or (4) increase or reduce funds for specific projects, programs, or activities by more than $2 million or 10%, whichever is less. </p> <p>Specifies exceptions and requires the Corps of Engineers to submit quarterly reports to Congress detailing all funds that have been reprogrammed. </p> <p>(Sec. 102) Prohibits funds provided by this title from being used for a contract that commits funds beyond the amounts appropriated for that program, project, or activity that remain unobligated. Includes exception for funds made available through reprogramming pursuant to section 101. </p> <p>(Sec. 103) Permits up to $4.7 million in Operation and Maintenance funds to be transferred to the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service to mitigate for fisheries lost due to Corps of Engineers projects. </p> <p>(Sec. 104) Prohibits the Corps of Engineers from using funds to develop, adopt, implement, administer, or enforce any change to regulations in effect on October 1, 2012, pertaining to the definitions of &quot;fill material&quot; or &quot;discharge of fill material&quot; for the purposes of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (commonly known as the Clean Water Act). </p> <p>(Sec. 105) Prohibits funds from being used to develop, adopt, implement, administer, or enforce any change to the regulations and guidance in effect on October 1, 2012, pertaining to the definition of waters under the jurisdiction of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (commonly known as the Clean Water Act) including provisions of specified rules pertaining to the jurisdiction. </p> <p>(Sec. 106) Prohibits funds made available by this bill from being used to require a permit for the discharge of dredged or fill material under the Clean Water Act for specified agricultural activities. </p> <p>(Sec. 107) Permits individuals to possess firearms at Corps of Engineers water resources development projects if: (1) the individual is not otherwise prohibited by law from possessing the firearm; and (2) the possession of the firearm complies with the law of the state in which the project is located. (The Corps of Engineers currently prohibits private individuals from possessing firearms and other weapons at the projects unless the weapons are being used for hunting, at authorized shooting ranges, or with written permission of the Corps District Commander.) </p> <p>(Sec. 108) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used for an open lake placement of dredged material originating from Lake Erie or tributaries, unless it is approved under a state water quality certification. </p> <p>TITLE II--DEPARTMENT OF THE INTERIOR </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Department of the Interior for the Central Utah Project; and the Bureau of Reclamation, including for Water and Related Resources, the Central Valley Project Restoration Fund, California Bay-Delta Restoration, and Policy and Administration. </p> <p>Permits appropriations to the Bureau of Reclamation to be used for purchasing replacements for up to five passenger motor vehicles. </p> <p>(Sec. 201) Prohibits funds provided in this title from being used for a reprogramming that would: (1) create, initiate, or eliminate a program, project, or activity; (2) increase funds for any program, project, or activity for which funds have been denied or restricted by this bill; (3) restart or resume any program, project, or activity for which funds are not provided in this bill unless prior approval is received from Congress or (4) transfer funds in excess of specified limits or in violation of specified requirements without the approval of Congress. </p> <p>(Sec. 202) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to determine the final point of discharge for the interceptor drain for the San Luis Unit until Interior and California develop a plan to minimize any detrimental effect of the San Luis drainage waters. Requires the plan to conform to California water quality standards as approved by the EPA. </p> <p>Directs Interior to classify the costs of the Kesterson Reservoir Cleanup Program and the San Joaquin Valley Drainage Program as either reimbursable or nonreimbursable and collected until fully repaid pursuant to specified alternative repayment plans. </p> <p>Requires future federal obligations of funds regarding drainage service or drainage studies for the San Luis Unit to be fully reimbursable by San Luis Unit beneficiaries of the service or studies. </p> <p>(Sec. 203) Sets forth deadlines for Interior to complete specified feasibility studies required by the Water Supply, Reliability, and Environmental Improvement Act for water storage projects in California. </p> <p>TITLE III--DEPARTMENT OF ENERGY </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Department of Energy (DOE) for Energy Programs, including: </p> <ul> <li>Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy, </li> <li>Electricity Delivery and Energy Reliability,</li> <li>Nuclear Energy, </li> <li>Fossil Energy Research and Development, </li> <li>Naval Petroleum and Oil Shale Reserves, </li> <li>Strategic Petroleum Reserve (SPR), </li> <li>Northeast Home Heating Oil Reserve, </li> <li>Energy Information Administration, </li> <li>Non-Defense Environmental Cleanup, </li> <li>Uranium Enrichment Decontamination and Decommissioning Fund, </li> <li>Science, </li> <li>Nuclear Waste Disposal, </li> <li>Advanced Research Projects Agency-Energy (ARPA-E), </li> <li>Title 17 Innovative Technology Loan Guarantee Loan Program, </li> <li>Advanced Technology Vehicles Manufacturing Loan Program, </li> <li>Departmental Administration, and </li> <li>the Office of the Inspector General. </li> </ul> <p>Provides appropriations to DOE for Atomic Energy Defense Activities of the National Nuclear Security Administration, including for Weapons Activities, Defense Nuclear Nonproliferation, Naval Reactors, and Federal Salaries and Expenses. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to DOE for Environmental and Other Defense Activities for Defense Environmental Cleanup, Defense Uranium Enrichment Decontamination and Decommissioning, and Other Defense Activities. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to DOE for the Power Marketing Administrations, including (1) the Bonneville Power Administration Fund; (2) Southeastern Power Administration Operation and Maintenance; (3) Southwestern Power Administration Operation and Maintenance; (4) Western Area Power Administration Operation and Maintenance, Construction, and Rehabilitation; and (5) the Falcon and Amistad Operating and Maintenance Fund. </p> <p>Provides appropriations for the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission. </p> <p>(Sec. 301) Prohibits the use of funds provided in this title for programs, projects, or activities that have not been funded by Congress. Prohibits specified grants, contracts, allocations, and agreements unless Congress is notified in advance. Prohibits funds from being used for certain multiyear DOE, Energy Programs activities unless specified conditions are met and Congress is notified. Establishes requirements and restrictions for the reprogramming of funds provided in this title. </p> <p>(Sec. 302) Permits unexpended balances of prior appropriations provided for activities in this bill to be transferred and merged with appropriations accounts established in this bill. </p> <p>(Sec. 303) Deems funds appropriated by this Act for intelligence activities to be specifically authorized by Congress during FY2016 until the enactment of the Intelligence Authorization Act for FY2016. </p> <p>(Sec. 304) Prohibits the use of funds made available in this title to construct specified high-hazard nuclear facilities unless independent oversight is conducted by the Office of Independent Enterprise Assessments to ensure compliance with nuclear safety requirements. </p> <p>(Sec. 305) Prohibits the use of funds provided in this title to approve certain critical decisions for construction projects exceeding $100 million until a separate independent cost estimate has been developed. </p> <p>(Sec. 306) Prohibits funds made available for Department of Energy, Energy Programs, Science from being used for any multiyear contract, grant, cooperative agreement, or other transaction agreement of $1 million or less unless the agreement is funded for the full period of performance anticipated at the time of award. </p> <p>(Sec. 307) Prohibits Defense Nuclear Nonproliferation funds from being used for contracts with or agreements for federal assistance to the Russian Federation. Permits DOE to waive the prohibition if the activity is in the national security interests of the United States and a report justifying the waiver is submitted to Congress. </p> <p>(Sec. 308) Prohibits funds from being used to carry out a drawdown and sale or exchange of petroleum products from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve (SPR) unless DOE notifies Congress in advance. Specifies requirements for the notification DOE submits to Congress. </p> <p>Prohibits DOE from establishing any new regional petroleum product reserve unless funding is explicitly requested in advance and approved by Congress. </p> <p>(Sec. 309) Permits up to $50 million of the funds provided to the National Nuclear Security Administration for Weapons Activities to be reprogrammed for Domestic Uranium Enrichment. </p> <p>(Sec. 310) Rescinds specified unobligated balances that were appropriated to DOE for FY2005-FY2010. </p> <p>TITLE IV--INDEPENDENT AGENCIES </p> <p>Provides appropriations to: (1) the Appalachian Regional Commission, (2) the Defense Nuclear Facilities Safety Board, (3) the Delta Regional Authority, (4) the Denali Commission, (5) the Northern Border Regional Commission, (6) the Southeast Crescent Regional Commission, (7) the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC), (8) the Nuclear Waste Technical Review Board, and (9) the Office of the Federal Coordinator for Alaska Natural Gas Transportation Projects. </p> <p>(Sec. 401) Requires the NRC to comply with specified internal procedures when responding to congressional requests for information. </p> <p>TITLE V--GENERAL PROVISIONS </p> <p>(Sec. 501) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to influence congressional action on any legislation or appropriation matters pending before Congress. </p> <p>(Sec. 502) Prohibits transfers of funds made available in title III (Department of Energy) of this bill except pursuant to specified authorities for transferring funds or providing goods and services to another entity of the U.S. government. </p> <p>Requires agencies that utilize transfer authority to provide a semiannual report to Congress detailing the transfer authority used, including the amounts transferred and the purposes for which they were transferred. </p> <p>(Sec. 503) Prohibits the use of funds to contravene Executive Order No. 12898 of February 11, 1994 (Federal Actions to Address Environmental Justice in Minority Populations and Low-Income Populations). </p> <p>(Sec. 504) Prohibits the use of funds provided by this bill: (1) to conduct closure of adjudicatory functions, technical review, or support activities associated with the Yucca Mountain (Nevada) geologic repository license application; or (2) for actions that irrevocably remove the possibility that Yucca Mountain may be a repository option in the future. </p> <p>(Sec. 505) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used for further implementation of the coastal and marine spatial planning and ecosystem-based management components of the National Ocean Policy developed under Executive Order 13547 (Stewardship of the Ocean, Our Coasts, and the Great Lakes.) </p> <p>(Sec. 506) Establishes a spending reduction account for the amount by which the subcommittee's allocation under section 302(b) of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 exceeds the amount of proposed new budget authority in the bill. Specifies that the amount is $0. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2028v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-05-15">
<action-date>2015-04-24</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Energy and Water Development and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2016 </b></p> <p>Provides FY2016 appropriations for U.S. Army Corps of Engineers civil works projects, the Department of the Interior's Bureau of Reclamation, the Department of Energy (DOE), and independent agencies such as the Nuclear Regulatory Commission. </p> <p>Provides appropriations for U.S. Army Corps of Engineers civil works projects, including for Investigations, Construction, Mississippi River and Tributaries, Operation and Maintenance, the Regulatory Program, the Formerly Utilized Sites Remedial Action Program, Flood Control and Coastal Emergencies, Expenses, and the Office of the Assistant Secretary of the Army for Civil Works. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Department of the Interior for the Central Utah Project, and to the Bureau of Reclamation, including Water and Related Resources, the Central Valley Project Restoration Fund, California Bay-Delta Restoration, and Policy and Administration. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to DOE for Energy Programs, including Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy, Electricity Delivery and Energy Reliability, Nuclear Energy, Fossil Energy Research and Development, Naval Petroleum and Oil Shale Reserves, the Strategic Petroleum Reserve, the Northeast Home Heating Oil Reserve, the Energy Information Administration, Non-Defense Environmental Cleanup, the Uranium Enrichment Decontamination and Decommissioning Fund, Science, Nuclear Waste Disposal, the Advanced Research Projects Agency-Energy, the Title 17 Innovative Technology Loan Guarantee Program, the Advanced Technology Vehicles Manufacturing Loan Program, Departmental Administration, and the Office of the Inspector General. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to DOE for the Atomic Energy Defense Activities of the National Nuclear Security Administration, including Weapons Activities, Defense Nuclear Nonproliferation, Naval Reactors, and Federal Salaries and Expenses. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to DOE for Environmental and Other Defense Activities, including Defense Environmental Cleanup, Defense Uranium Enrichment Decontamination and Decommissioning, and Other Defense Activities. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to DOE for the Power Marketing Administrations, including the Bonneville Power Administration, the Southeastern Power Administration, the Southwestern Power Administration, and the Western Area Power Administration. </p> <p>Rescinds specified amounts previously appropriated to the Department of Energy. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to other independent agencies, including the Appalachian Regional Commission, the Defense Nuclear Facilities Safety Board, the Delta Regional Authority, the Denali Commission, the Northern Border Regional Commission, the Southeast Crescent Regional Commission, the Nuclear Regulatory Commission, the Nuclear Waste Technical Review Board, and the Office of the Federal Coordinator for Alaska Natural Gas Transportation Projects. </p> <p>Sets forth permissible, restricted, and prohibited uses for funds provided by this and other appropriations Acts. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
