<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3762" measure-id="id114hr3762" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-10-16" update-date="2015-12-11">
<title>Restoring Americans' Healthcare Freedom Reconciliation Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3762v35" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-12-11">
<action-date>2015-12-03</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed Senate amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>TITLE I--HEALTH, EDUCATION, LABOR, AND PENSIONS</p> <p>(Sec. 101) This bill amends the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (PPACA) to terminate the Prevention and Public Health Fund, which provides for investment in prevention and public health programs to improve health and restrain the rate of growth in health care costs. Unobligated funds are rescinded.</p> <p>(Sec. 102) Funding for community health centers is increased.</p> <p>(Sec. 103) Certain funding for U.S. territories that establish health insurance exchanges is no longer available after 2017. </p> <p>(Sec. 104) The Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) may not collect fees or make payments under the transitional reinsurance program.</p> <p>(Sec. 105) This bill makes appropriations for FY2016 and FY2017 for HHS to award grants to states to address substance abuse or to respond to urgent mental health needs.</p> <p>TITLE II--FINANCE</p> <p>(Sec. 201) This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to require individuals to pay back the full amount of advance payments in excess of their premium assistance tax credit. (Currently, there is a limit on the amount of excess an individual must pay back.)</p> <p>(Sec. 202) Provisions relating to the premium assistance tax credit, reduced cost-sharing, and eligibility determinations for these subsidies are repealed on December 31, 2017.</p> <p>(Sec. 203) The small employer health insurance tax credit does not apply after 2017. (This credit is for certain employers who make contributions toward employee health coverage purchased through a health insurance exchange.) </p> <p>(Sec. 204) The penalty for individuals who do not maintain minimum essential health care coverage is eliminated.</p> <p>(Sec. 205) Large employers are no longer required to make shared responsibility payments.</p> <p>(Sec. 206) For one year, this bill restricts the availability of federal funding to a state for payments to an entity (e.g., Planned Parenthood Federation of America) that:</p> <ul> <li>is a 501(c)(3) tax-exempt organization;</li> <li>is an essential community provider primarily engaged in family planning services and reproductive health;</li> <li>provides for abortions other than abortions in cases of rape or incest, or where a physical condition endangers a woman's life unless an abortion is performed; and</li> <li>received a total of more than $350 million under Medicaid in FY2014, including payments to affiliates, subsidiaries, successors, or clinics.</li> </ul> <p>(Sec. 207) This bill amends part A (General Provisions) of title XI of the Social Security Act (SSAct) to require the additional payments to U.S. territories for Medicaid under the Health Care and Education Reconciliation Act of 2010 to be made by the end of FY2017 instead of the end of FY2019.</p> <p>This bill amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the SSAct to end the expansion of Medicaid under PPACA on December 31, 2017.</p> <p>After 2017, hospitals may no longer elect to provide Medicaid services to individuals during a presumptive eligibility period.</p> <p>States must maintain Medicaid eligibility standards for individuals under 19 years old through FY2017 instead of through FY2019.</p> <p>The federal medical assistance percentage (FMAP, the federal matching rate for Medicaid expenditures) for U.S. territories is 50% after 2017 (currently, the FMAP is 55%).</p> <p>The increased FMAP for childless adults and home and community-based attendant services under PPACA ends December 31, 2017.</p> <p>After 2017, states may no longer elect to provide certain individuals with a presumptive eligibility period for Medicaid.</p> <p>Medicaid benchmark plans are no longer required to provide minimum essential health benefits after 2017.</p> <p>After 2017, states are no longer required to operate a website for Medicaid enrollment that is linked to the state's health benefit exchange and Children's Health Insurance program (CHIP).</p> <p>(Sec. 208) Medicaid allotments for disproportionate share hospitals are increased.</p> <p>(Sec. 209) The excise tax on high cost employer-sponsored health coverage (popularly known as the &quot;Cadillac tax&quot;) does not apply after 2017.</p> <p>(Sec. 210) Health savings accounts (HSAs), Archer medical savings accounts (MSAs), health flexible spending arrangements (HFSAs), and health reimbursement arrangements may be used to pay for over-the-counter medications.</p> <p>(Sec. 211) This bill lowers the tax on distributions from HSAs and Archer MSAs that are not used for medical expenses.</p> <p>(Sec. 212) Salary reduction contributions to an HFSA under a cafeteria plan are no longer limited.</p> <p>(Sec. 213) The annual fee on manufacturers and importers of brand name prescription drugs is eliminated.</p> <p>(Sec. 214) The excise tax on medical devices is eliminated.</p> <p>(Sec. 215) The annual fee on health insurers is eliminated.</p> <p>(Sec. 216) Medical costs are allowed as a tax deduction regardless of whether the costs are taken into account when determining the amount of the subsidy for an employer-sponsored retiree prescription drug plan under Medicare part D (Voluntary Prescription Drug Benefit Program).</p> <p>(Sec. 217) A tax deduction is allowed for medical expenses in excess of 7.5% (currently, 10%) of adjusted gross income.</p> <p>(Sec. 218) The additional Medicare tax on income above a certain threshold is eliminated.</p> <p>(Sec. 219) The indoor tanning services tax is eliminated.</p> <p>(Sec. 220) The net investment income tax is eliminated.</p> <p>(Sec. 221) A health insurer is allowed a tax deduction for the full amount of an employee's compensation. (Currently, there is a limit on the amount of an employee's compensation that a health insurer may deduct.)</p> <p>(Sec. 222) Provisions relating to the economic substance doctrine are repealed. (The economic substance doctrine treats a transaction as having economic substance if it has a purpose other than reducing income taxes. Currently, there are penalties for claiming tax benefits for transactions without economic substance.)</p> <p>(Sec. 223) Funds are transferred from the Department of the Treasury to the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3762v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-12-11">
<action-date>2015-10-23</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Restoring Americans&rsquo; Healthcare Freedom Reconciliation Act of 2015</b></p> <p>TITLE I--COMMITTEE ON ENERGY AND COMMERCE</p> <p>(Sec. 101) This bill amends the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (PPACA) to terminate the Prevention and Public Health Fund, which provides for investment in prevention and public health programs to improve health and help restrain the rate of growth in health care costs. Unobligated funds are rescinded.</p> <p>(Sec. 102) For one year, no federal funds may be made available to a state for direct payments, or payments through a managed care organization, to an entity (e.g., Planned Parenthood Federation of America) that:</p> <ul> <li>is a 501(c)(3) tax-exempt organization;</li> <li>is an essential community provider primarily engaged in family planning services and reproductive health;</li> <li>provides for abortions other than abortions in cases of rape or incest, or where a physical condition endangers a woman's life unless an abortion is performed; and</li> <li>received a total of more than $350 million under Medicaid in FY2014, including payments to affiliates, subsidiaries, successors, or clinics.</li> </ul> <p>(Sec. 103) Funding for community health centers is increased.</p> <p>TITLE II--COMMITTEE ON WAYS AND MEANS</p> <p>(Sec. 201) This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to eliminate the requirement for individuals to maintain minimum essential health care coverage and the requirement for certain large employers to make shared responsibility payments, effective after December 31, 2014.</p> <p>(Sec. 203) The excise tax on medical devices is repealed.</p> <p>(Sec. 204) The excise tax on high cost employer-sponsored health coverage (popularly known as the &ldquo;Cadillac tax&rdquo;) is repealed after December 31, 2017. After 2014, W-2 forms no longer need to include the cost of employer-sponsored coverage.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3762v79" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-12-11">
<action-date>2015-10-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Restoring Americans&rsquo; Healthcare Freedom Reconciliation Act of 2015</b></p> <p>TITLE I--COMMITTEE ON EDUCATION AND THE WORKFORCE</p> <p>(Sec. 101) This bill amends the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to repeal the requirement that certain employers automatically enroll their employees in a health plan.</p> <p>TITLE II--COMMITTEE ON ENERGY AND COMMERCE</p> <p>(Sec. 201) This bill amends the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (PPACA) to terminate the Prevention and Public Health Fund, which provides for investment in prevention and public health programs to improve health and help restrain the rate of growth in health care costs. Unobligated funds are rescinded.</p> <p>(Sec. 202) For one year, no federal funds may be made available to a state for payments to an entity (e.g., Planned Parenthood Federation of America) that:</p> <ul> <li>is a 501(c)(3) tax-exempt organization;</li> <li>is an essential community provider primarily engaged in family planning services and reproductive health;</li> <li>provides for elective abortions; and</li> <li>received a total of more than $350 million under Medicaid in FY2014, including payments to affiliates, subsidiaries, successors, or clinics.</li> </ul> <p>(Sec. 203) Funding for community health centers is increased.</p> <p>TITLE III--COMMITTEE ON WAYS AND MEANS</p> <p>Subtitle A--Revenue Provisions</p> <p>(Sec. 301) This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to eliminate the requirement for individuals to maintain minimum essential health care coverage and the requirement for certain large employers to make shared responsibility payments, effective after December 31, 2014.</p> <p>(Sec. 303) The excise tax on medical devices is repealed.</p> <p>(Sec. 304) The excise tax on high cost employer-sponsored health coverage (popularly known as the &ldquo;Cadillac tax&rdquo;) is repealed after December 31, 2017. After 2014, W-2 forms no longer need to include the cost of employer-sponsored coverage.</p> <p>Subtitle B--Repeal of Independent Payment Advisory Board</p> (Sec. 311) The Independent Medicare Advisory Board is terminated, effective as of enactment of PPACA.]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3762v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-12-11">
<action-date>2015-10-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Restoring Americans&rsquo; Healthcare Freedom Reconciliation Act of 2015</b></p> <p> This bill amends the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to repeal the requirement that certain employers automatically enroll their employees in a health plan. <p>This bill amends the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (PPACA) to terminate the Prevention and Public Health Fund, which provides for investment in prevention and public health programs to improve health and help restrain the rate of growth in health care costs. Unobligated funds are rescinded.</p> <p>For one year, no federal funds may be made available to a state for payments to an entity (e.g., Planned Parenthood Federation of America) that:</p> <ul> <li>is a 501(c)(3) tax-exempt organization;</li> <li>is an essential community provider primarily engaged in family planning services and reproductive health;</li> <li>provides for elective abortions; and</li> <li>received a total of more than $350 million under Medicaid in FY2014, including payments to affiliates, subsidiaries, successors, or clinics.</li> </ul> <p>Funding for community health centers is increased.</p> <p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to eliminate the requirement for individuals to maintain minimum essential health care coverage and the requirement for certain large employers to make shared responsibility payments, effective after December 31, 2014.</p> <p>The excise tax on medical devices is repealed.</p> <p>The excise tax on high cost employer-sponsored health coverage (popularly known as the &ldquo;Cadillac tax&rdquo;) is repealed after December 31, 2017. After 2014, W-2 forms no longer need to include the cost of employer-sponsored coverage.</p> The Independent Medicare Advisory Board is terminated, effective as of enactment of PPACA.]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
