<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1254" measure-id="id114hr1254" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-03-04" update-date="2015-03-20">
<title>Recidivism Clarification Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1254v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-03-20">
<action-date>2015-03-04</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Recidivism Clarification Act of 2015</b></p> <p> Amends the federal criminal code, with respect to additional penalties for using or carrying a firearm in the commission of a crime of violence or drug trafficking crime, to: (1) modify the penalty to require an additional prison term of not more than 5 years, not more than 7 years if the firearm is brandished, and not more than 10 years if the firearm is discharged (currently, not less than 5, 7, or 10 years respectively); (2) allow a prison term for any term of years (currently, minimum mandatory term of 25 years) for a person who has a prior conviction that has become final; (3) require an additional prison term of not more than 15 years (currently, not less than 15 years) for using, carrying, or possessing armor piercing ammunition during the commission of a crime of violence or drug trafficking crime; and (4) eliminate the death penalty for cases in which the use of such ammunition results in a death. </p> <p>Makes this Act applicable to conduct engaged in and sentences imposed before, on, or after the date of this Act's enactment.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
