<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2829" measure-id="id114hr2829" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-06-18" update-date="2015-11-16">
<title>Free Market Healthcare Restoration and Coverage Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2829v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-11-16">
<action-date>2015-06-18</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Free Market Healthcare Restoration and Coverage Act of 2015</b></p> <p>This bill repeals the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (PPACA) and the health care provisions of the Health Care and Education Reconciliation Act of 2010, effective May 31, 2017. Provisions amended by the repealed provisions are restored.</p> <p>PPACA and the Internal Revenue Code are amended to repeal the requirements for individuals to maintain minimum essential coverage and for large employers to pay penalties if a full-time employee: (1) must wait longer than 60 days to enroll in an employer-sponsored health plan, or (2) receives a premium assistance tax credit or reduced cost-sharing. Coverage reporting requirements for providers and large employers are also repealed. These amendments are applied as if the repealed provisions had not been enacted.</p> <p>Individuals enrolled in a health plan purchased through the federal health insurance exchange at the time of enactment of this Act who are ineligible for a premium assistance tax credit solely as a result of a determination by the Supreme Court in <i>King v. Burwell</i> are eligible for the tax credit. This applies to coverage months beginning after December 2013.</p> <p>Group health coverage in which an individual was enrolled for any period after enactment of PPACA (March 23, 2010) is a grandfathered health plan under PPACA and is exempt from some coverage requirements.</p> <p>Essential health benefits are defined by states. This amendment takes effect as if included in PPACA.</p> <p>The budgetary effects of this bill must not be entered on the PAYGO scorecards maintained by the Office of Management and Budget.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
