<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4096" measure-id="id114hr4096" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-11-19" update-date="2016-05-02">
<title>Investor Clarity and Bank Parity Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4096v81" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-05-02">
<action-date>2016-04-26</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p><b>Investor Clarity and Bank Parity Act</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956 to permit a hedge fund or private equity fund to share the same name, or a variation of the same name, as a banking entity that is an investment advisor to the hedge fund or private equity fund, if: </p> <ul> <li>the investment advisor is not an insured depository institution, a company that controls an insured depository institution, or a company treated as a bank holding company for purposes of the International Banking Act of 1978 relating to nonbanking activities of foreign banks;</li> <li>the investment advisor does not share the same name, or a variation of it, as an insured depository institution, a company that controls an insured depository institution, or a company treated as a bank holding company for the specified purposes of the International Banking Act of 1978; and </li> <li>the name does not contain the word &quot;bank.&quot;</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4096v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-03-21">
<action-date>2015-11-19</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Investor Clarity and Bank Parity Act</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956 to permit a hedge fund or private equity fund to share the same name, or a variation of the same name, as a banking entity that is an investment advisor to the hedge fund or private equity fund, if: </p> <ul> <li>the investment advisor is not an insured depository institution, a company that controls an insured depository institution, or a company treated as a bank holding company for purposes of the International Banking Act of 1978 relating to nonbanking activities of foreign banks;</li> <li>the investment advisor does not share the same name, or a variation of it, as an insured depository institution, a company that controls an insured depository institution, or a company treated as a bank holding company for the specified purposes of the International Banking Act of 1978; and </li> <li>the name does not contain the word &quot;bank.&quot;</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
