<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1820" measure-id="id114hr1820" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-04-15" update-date="2015-04-28">
<title>To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to retire coal preference right lease applications for which the Secretary has made an affirmative commercial quantities determination, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1820v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-04-28">
<action-date>2015-04-15</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to retire any coal preference right lease application for which an affirmative commercial quantities determination has been made, by issuing bidding rights in exchange for relinquishment of the application, including payment to the relevant state of 50% of the dollar amount of any bidding right subsequently used in lieu of any monetary payment of a bonus in a coal lease sale or of rental or royalty under a federal coal lease.</p> <p>Requires the Secretary to make such payments from revenues received under federal mineral leases. </p> <p>Declares such bidding rights to be fully transferable to any other person. </p> <p>Terminates a bidding right five years from its date of issue, not counting any period in which exercise of the bidding right is precluded by temporary injunctive relief granted under, or administrative, legislative, or judicial suspension of, the federal coal leasing program. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
