<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1833" measure-id="id114hr1833" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-04-16" update-date="2015-04-30">
<title>FAFSA for All Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1833v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-04-30">
<action-date>2015-04-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>FAFSA for All Act</strong></p> <p>Amends title IV (Student Assistance) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to direct the Secretary of Education to include on the same website that is used to provide students with the electronic version of the Free Application for Federal Student Aid (FAFSA) questions to determine, for title IV eligibility purposes, whether:</p> <ul> <li> a dependent student is a citizen, national, or permanent resident of the United States or is here for other than a temporary purpose with the intention of becoming a citizen or permanent resident; and</li> <li>the parents of a dependent student have a valid social security number.</li> </ul> <p>Requires that website to also include:</p> <ul> <li>detailed guidance on how dependent students who satisfy those immigration requirements but whose parents do not have a valid social security number may obtain student assistance under title IV, and</li> <li>an online tool that allows those students to upload the documents they need to receive such assistance.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
