<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4268" measure-id="id114hr4268" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-12-16" update-date="2016-03-01">
<title>Castner Range National Monument Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4268v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-03-01">
<action-date>2015-12-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Castner Range National Monument Act</b></p> <p>This bill establishes the Castner Range National Monument in Texas.</p> <p>The Department of the Interior shall continue to provide historical and adequate access to private inholdings within the Monument's exterior boundaries. </p> <p>Interior shall:</p> <ul> <li>manage the Monument in a manner to conserve, protect, and enhance its natural resources and values; and</li> <li>develop a comprehensive management plan for the Monument's protection and management. </li> </ul> <p>Interior shall also establish a Castner Range National Monument Advisory Council to advise Interior with respect to the preparation and implementation of the management plan. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
