<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5625" measure-id="id114hr5625" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-07-05" update-date="2016-09-27">
<title>Modernizing Government Travel Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5625v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-09-27">
<action-date>2016-09-22</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the House on September 20, 2016. The summary of that version is repeated here.)</p> <p><strong>Modernizing Government Travel Act</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill requires the General Services Administration (GSA) to prescribe regulations to provide for the reimbursement of federal employees traveling on official business for the use of a transportation network company or innovative mobility technology. The Administrative Office of the United States Courts shall prescribe such regulations with respect to judicial branch employees.</p> <p>An "innovative mobility technology company" is an entity that applies technology to expand and enhance available transportation choices, better manage demand for transportation services, and provide alternatives to driving alone.</p> <p>A "transportation network company" is an entity that uses a digital network to connect riders to drivers affiliated with such entity in order for a driver to provide transportation services to a rider.</p> <p>(Sec. 3) The bill revises the reporting requirements regarding payments pertaining to official travel.</p> <p>By November 31 of each year, each agency shall submit to the GSA, in a format prescribed by it and approved by the Office of Management and Budget (OMB), an analysis of the total costs of transportation service by type and the total number of trips utilizing each transportation type for purposes of official travel.</p> <p>The GSA shall make the data submitted publicly available upon receipt.</p> <p>By January 31 of each year, the GSA shall submit to the OMB and to specified congressional committees: (1) an analysis of the data submitted for specified agencies (as listed under a provision regarding the establishment of agency Chief Financial Officers), and (2) a description of any new regulations promulgated or changes to existing regulations authorized. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5625v17" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-09-22">
<action-date>2016-09-20</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Modernizing Government Travel Act</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill requires the General Services Administration (GSA) to prescribe regulations to provide for the reimbursement of federal employees traveling on official business for the use of a transportation network company or innovative mobility technology. The Administrative Office of the United States Courts shall prescribe such regulations with respect to judicial branch employees.</p> <p>An "innovative mobility technology company" is an entity that applies technology to expand and enhance available transportation choices, better manage demand for transportation services, and provide alternatives to driving alone.</p> <p>A "transportation network company" is an entity that uses a digital network to connect riders to drivers affiliated with such entity in order for a driver to provide transportation services to a rider.</p> <p>(Sec. 3) The bill revises the reporting requirements regarding payments pertaining to official travel.</p> <p>By November 31 of each year, each agency shall submit to the GSA, in a format prescribed by it and approved by the Office of Management and Budget (OMB), an analysis of the total costs of transportation service by type and the total number of trips utilizing each transportation type for purposes of official travel.</p> <p>The GSA shall make the data submitted publicly available upon receipt.</p> <p>By January 31 of each year, the GSA shall submit to the OMB and to specified congressional committees: (1) an analysis of the data submitted for specified agencies (as listed under a provision regarding the establishment of agency Chief Financial Officers), and (2) a description of any new regulations promulgated or changes to existing regulations authorized.</p> <ul> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5625v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-09-20">
<action-date>2016-07-05</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Modernizing Government Travel Act</strong></p> <p>This bill requires the General Services Administration (GSA) to: (1) prescribe regulations to provide for the reimbursement of federal employees traveling on official business for the use of a transportation network company or innovative mobility technology, and (2) report on government savings resulting from such use. The Administrative Office of the United States Courts shall prescribe such regulations with respect to judicial branch employees.</p> <p>An &quot;innovative mobility technology company&quot; is an entity that utilizes innovative mobility technologies to provide alternatives to driving alone, including car-share, bike-share, carpool or vanpool, multimodal fare payment system, and app-based mobility providers.</p> <p>A &quot;transportation network company&quot;: (1) is an entity that uses a digital network to connect riders to drivers affiliated with such entity in order for the driver to transport the rider using the driver's personal vehicle to a point chosen by the rider; and (2) does not include a shared expense carpool, a vanpool arrangement, or any other arrangement or service in which the driver receives a fee that does not exceed the driver's cost associated with providing the ride.</p>  <ul> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
