<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="805" measure-id="id114hr805" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-02-05" update-date="2015-06-25">
<title>DOTCOM Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr805v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-06-25">
<action-date>2015-06-23</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Domain Openness Through Continued Oversight Matters Act of 2015 or the DOTCOM Act of 2015</b></p> <p>Prohibits the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Communications and Information from permitting the National Telecommunications and Information Administration's (NTIA's) role in the performance of the Internet Assigned Numbers Authority (IANA) functions to cease until 30 legislative days after the Assistant Secretary&nbsp;submits to Congress a report that contains: (1) the proposal relating to the transition of the NTIA's stewardship of the IANA functions that was developed in a process convened by the Internet Corporation for Assigned Names and Numbers (ICANN) at the request of the NTIA, and (2) the following required certifications by the Assistant Secretary. </p> <p>Requires the Assistant Secretary to certify that: (1) such proposal supports and enhances the multistakeholder model of Internet governance, maintains the security, stability, and resiliency of the Internet domain name system, meets the needs of global customers and partners of the IANA services, maintains the openness of the Internet, and does not replace the role of the NTIA with a government-led or intergovernmental organization solution; and (2) the required changes to ICANN's bylaws contained in the final report of ICANN's Cross Community Working Group on Enhancing ICANN Accountability and the changes to ICANN's bylaws required by ICANN's IANA Stewardship Transition Coordination Group have been adopted.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr805v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-02-23">
<action-date>2015-02-05</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Domain Openness Through Continued Oversight Matters Act of 2015 or the DOTCOM Act of 2015</b></p> <p>Prohibits the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Communications and Information from relinquishing or agreeing to any proposal relating to the relinquishment of the responsibility of the National Telecommunications and Information Administration (NTIA) over Internet domain name system functions until the Government Accountability Office (GAO), within one year after the NTIA receives a relinquishment proposal developed in a process convened by the Internet Corporation for Assigned Names and Numbers at the request of the NTIA, submits a report to Congress regarding the NTIA's role with respect to the system. </p> <p>Requires the GAO's report to include: (1) advantages and disadvantages of such a relinquishment of the NTIA's responsibility; (2) any principles or criteria that the NTIA sets for relinquishment proposals, as well as an analysis of each proposal received by the NTIA; (3) the processes used by the NTIA and any other federal agencies for evaluating proposals; (4) any national security or network security concerns; and (5) a definition of &quot;multistakeholder model&quot; as used by the NTIA with respect to Internet policymaking and governance.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
