<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2684" measure-id="id114hr2684" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-06-04" update-date="2015-08-03">
<title>Alabama-Coushatta Tribe of Texas Equal and Fair Opportunity Settlement Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2684v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-08-03">
<action-date>2015-06-04</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Alabama-Coushatta Tribe of Texas Equal and Fair Opportunity Settlement Act</b></p> <p> This bill amends the Alabama-Coushatta Tribes of Texas Restoration Act to repeal the prohibition against gaming activities by the Alabama-Coushatta Tribe of Texas on its lands if those gaming activities are prohibited by Texas law. </p> <p>The United States and the Tribe must execute and file in each applicable court a motion for dismissal of any pending claim arising out of or relating to any interest in the aboriginal lands of the Tribe. </p> <p>Any claim by or on behalf of the Tribe, or any predecessor in interest or any of its members, against the United States, Texas, or any landowner, which is based on any interest in or right involving any land or natural resources regarding the aboriginal lands, is hereby extinguished.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
