<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1656" measure-id="id114hr1656" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-03-26" update-date="2015-10-29">
<title>Secret Service Improvements Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1656v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-10-29">
<action-date>2015-07-27</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Secret Service Improvements Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends the federal criminal code to: (1) subject the appointment of the Director of the U.S. Secret Service to the advice and consent of the Senate; (2) prohibit knowingly causing any object to enter any restricted building or grounds so that such object impedes or disrupts the orderly conduct of government business or official functions; and (3) prohibit knowingly and willfully threatening to kill, kidnap, or inflict bodily harm upon former Vice Presidents, their spouses, and their children who are under age 16.</p> <p>(Sec. 5) The Director must increase the annual number of training hours for Secret Service officers and agents. </p> <p>(Sec. 6) The Director is authorized to: (1) construct facilities at the Rowley Training Center necessary to improve the training of officers of the U.S. Secret Service Uniformed Division and agents of the Secret Service, and (2) hire not fewer than 200 additional officers for such Division and 85 additional agents for the Secret Service Presidential Protective Detail.</p> <p>(Sec. 8) The Director shall devise and adopt improved procedures for: (1) evaluating vulnerabilities in White House security and threats to persons protected by the Secret Service, including threats posed by unmanned aerial systems or explosive devices; and (2) evaluating the ways technology may be used to improve White House security and the response to threats to persons protected by the Service.</p> <p>(Sec. 10) The Director is required to evaluate the practicability of equipping agents and officers with weapons other than those currently provided, including nonlethal weapons.</p> <p>(Sec. 11) Provisions of the Presidential Protection Assistance Act of 1976 requiring expenditures above a specified amount by the Secret Service for securing any non-governmental property in addition to the one non-governmental property designated by each protectee to be approved by the House and Senate Appropriations Committees are replaced with provisions requiring the Secret Service to notify such Committees of any such expenditures.</p> <p>(Sec. 12) Subject to the oversight of the Office of Chief Counsel of the Secret Service, the Director shall establish an Ethics Program Office to administer the provisions of the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 and to provide increased training to Secret Service employees.</p> <p>(Sec. 13) This section expresses the sense of Congress that an assessment made by the Secretary of Homeland Security or the Director regarding physical security of the White House and attendant grounds should be accorded substantial deference by the National Capital Planning Commission, the Commission of Fine Arts, and any other relevant entities.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1656v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-06-23">
<action-date>2015-03-26</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Secret Service Improvements Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>Amends the federal criminal code to: (1) subject the appointment of the Director of the U.S. Secret Service to the advice and consent of the Senate; (2) prohibit knowingly causing any object to enter any restricted building or grounds so that such object impedes or disrupts the orderly conduct of government business or official functions; and (3) include former Vice Presidents and members of their immediate families within the prohibition against threatening former Presidents and their families.</p> <p>Requires the Director to increase the annual number of hours spent training by Secret Service officers and agents. </p> <p>Authorizes the Director to: (1) construct facilities at the Rowley Training Center necessary to improve the training of officers of the U.S. Secret Service Uniformed Division and agents of the Secret Service Presidential Protective Detail, and (2) hire not fewer than 200 additional officers for the Division and 80 additional agents for the Detail.</p> <p>Requires the Director to devise and adopt improved procedures for: (1) evaluating vulnerabilities in White House security and threats to persons protected by the Secret Service, including threats posed by unmanned aerial systems or explosive devices; and (2) evaluating the ways technology may be used to improve White House security and the response to threats to persons protected by the Service. </p> <p>Requires the Director to evaluate the practicability of equipping agents and officers with weapons other than those currently provided, including nonlethal weapons.</p> <p>Expresses the sense of Congress that an assessment made by the Secretary of Homeland Security or the Director regarding physical security of the White House and attendant grounds should be accorded substantial deference by the National Capital Planning Commission, the Commission of Fine Arts, and any other relevant entities.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
