<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2498" measure-id="id114hr2498" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-21" update-date="2015-08-17">
<title>Budget Integrity Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2498v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-08-17">
<action-date>2015-05-21</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Budget Integrity Act </b></p> <p>This bill amends the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 to require the Congressional Budget Office (CBO) to prepare long-term cost estimates for reported legislation with a gross budgetary impact of at least 0.25% of gross domestic product in either of the next two 10-year periods. </p> <p>The bill also creates a point of order against considering legislation in the House or the Senate that would cause a net increase in on-budget deficits above $5 billion in either of the two periods. </p> <p>The CBO and the Office of Management and Budget must issue long-term budget projections that cover 40 years. The Government Accountability Office must report on the effects of long-term debt. </p> <p>The bill amends the Rules of the House of Representatives to deem the House to have passed any necessary changes to the statutory debt limit upon adoption of the budget resolution. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
