<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4858" measure-id="id114hr4858" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-03-23" update-date="2016-07-07">
<title>To provide a declaration of nonnavigability for the central Delaware River, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4858v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-07-07">
<action-date>2016-03-23</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill declares the following portions of the Delaware River in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, bounded by the former bulkhead and pierhead lines that were established by the Secretary of War and successors, to be nonnavigable waters of the United States unless the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers finds that there are substantive objections:</p> <ul> <li>Piers 70 South through 38 South, encompassing an area bounded by the southern line of Moore Street extended to the northern line of Catherine Street extended; and</li> <li>Piers 24 North through 72 North, encompassing an area bounded by the southern line of Callowhill Street extended to the northern line of East Fletcher Street extended.</li> </ul> <p>The Army Corps of Engineers shall make such public interest determination separately for each proposed project to be undertaken within the boundaries described, using reasonable discretion, within 150 days of the date of submission of appropriate plans for such project. </p> <p>This bill's declaration shall apply only to those parts of the areas described that are or will be bulkheaded and filled or otherwise occupied by permanent structures, including marina and recreation facilities.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
