<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2060" measure-id="id114hr2060" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-04-28" update-date="2015-05-27">
<title>United States-Mexico Economic Partnership Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2060v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-05-27">
<action-date>2015-04-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>United States-Mexico Economic Partnership Act</strong></p> <p>This bill authorizes the President to expand U.S.-Mexico academic exchange programs at the secondary, post-secondary, and post-graduate levels. </p> <p>It is the sense of Congress that such programs should reflect the goals of the 100,000 Strong in the Americas Initiative and should seek to double the number of students studying in each other's country within five years. </p> <p>Priority should be given to strengthening ties between communities and academic institutions in those portions of the United States and Mexico that are within 100 kilometers of the international boundary between those countries (covered region). </p> <p>The President is authorized to establish programs to support cooperation, training, and mentoring of entrepreneurs in the covered region.</p> <p>It is the sense of Congress that such programs should seek to provide not less than 100 grants of not more than $25,000 each for program participants. </p> <p>The President is authorized to promote U.S.-Mexico energy infrastructure coordination and cooperation through programs to support vocational-level education, internships, and exchanges between the two countries, particularly in the region in which the Eagle Ford Shale is located and in proximity to the covered region. </p> <p>It is the sense of Congress that such programs should seek to provide education, internships, and exchanges for at least 1,000 program participants. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
