<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="307" measure-id="id114hr307" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-01-13" update-date="2015-01-23">
<title>Buyback Our Safety Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr307v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-01-23">
<action-date>2015-01-13</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Buyback Our Safety Act</strong></p> <p>Directs the Assistant Attorney General for the Office of Justice Programs of the Department of Justice to establish a gun buyback program under which the Assistant Attorney General may make grants to assist in funding gun buyback programs carried out by state, local, and Indian tribal law enforcement agencies.</p> <p>Conditions such a grant on the law enforcement agency providing assurances that: (1) it will adequately advertise the program to the public, (2) such program will be administered by law enforcement personnel, (3) all guns received will remain in the possession of law enforcement personnel, (4) adequate safeguards will be established and followed to prevent fraud, (5) the agency will have in place a process to test on site a gun purchased before payment is provided, and (6) an adequate process will be in place to destroy all guns received. Requires the agency to certify that it will match all federal funds provided with an equal amount of cash or in-kind goods or services from other non-federal sources.</p> <p>Directs the Assistant Attorney General to enter into an arrangement with the National Academy of Sciences to: (1) develop standards for identifying, and to identify, guns that are the most likely to be used in violent crimes; and (2) establish a pricing scale for purchasing such guns through gun buyback programs. Authorizes the Assistant Attorney General to waive all or part of the matching funds requirement for a program that provides for obtaining only such guns.</p> <p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
