<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2909" measure-id="id114hr2909" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-06-25" update-date="2015-12-15">
<title>Protecting Firefighters and Promoting Innovation Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2909v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-12-15">
<action-date>2015-06-25</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Protecting Firefighters and Promoting Innovation Act</strong></p> <p>This bill directs the President to establish an interagency working group to study the use of unmanned aircraft systems for wildland firefighting.</p> <p>The working group shall:</p> <ul> <li>develop standards and best practices for the use of unmanned aircraft systems for wildland firefighting to assist in fire suppression, to provide real-time updates for firefighters, and to reduce the risk of firefighter fatalities due to wildland firefighting and related aircraft accidents;</li> <li>identify opportunities to use existing federal unmanned aircraft systems to lower the costs of the use of unmanned aircraft systems for wildland firefighting;</li> <li>with respect to the use of unmanned aircraft systems for wildland firefighting, assess opportunities to improve interagency coordination, the efficacy of current technology, and the potential efficacy of emerging technology; </li> <li>assess the implications for the Fourth Amendment of any standards, best practices, or recommendations under this Act with respect to the use of unmanned aircraft systems; and</li> <li> report to Congress and to the National Wildfire Coordinating Group on the results of its work.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
