<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4629" measure-id="id114hr4629" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-02-25" update-date="2016-03-22">
<title>Muscogee Nation of Florida Federal Recognition Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4629v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-03-22">
<action-date>2016-02-25</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Muscogee Nation of Florida Federal Recognition Act</b></p> <p>This bill extends federal recognition to the Muscogee Nation of Florida, which makes its members eligible for the services and benefits provided to members of federally recognized Indian tribes.</p> <p> The service area of the tribe, for the purpose of delivering federal services to members, is the community of Bruce in Walton County, Florida, and an area in Florida in which members reside that is bordered on the west by the Escambia River and on the east by the St. Marks River. </p> <p>The constitution and bylaws of the tribe must be the constitution and bylaws of the tribe's Tribal Council dated January 21, 2001, including amendments. The Department of the Interior, upon receipt of a written request of the Tribal Council, must hold a referendum for members to adopt a new constitution and bylaws.</p> <p>The role and duties of the Tribal Council are specified. </p> <p>The membership roll of the tribe must be determined in accordance with the membership criteria established by the ordinance of the tribe numbered 04-01-100 and dated February 7, 2004. </p> <p>Interior may take land into trust on behalf of the tribe.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
