<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4312" measure-id="id114hr4312" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-12-18" update-date="2016-01-07">
<title>Iran's Revolutionary Guard Corps Sanctions Implementation and Review Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4312v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-01-07">
<action-date>2015-12-18</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Iran's Revolutionary Guard Corps Sanctions Implementation and Review Act</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Iran Threat Reduction and Syrian Human Rights Act of 2012 to require the President to block and prohibit all transactions in property and property interests of a foreign person that knowingly supports or conducts certain transactions with Iran's Revolutionary Guard Corps (IRGC) or other sanctioned persons if that property and those property interests are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a U.S. person.</p> <p>The President may issue licenses to U.S. persons to engage in such property transactions with an otherwise blocked foreign person. </p> <p>The Government Accountability Office (GAO) shall report annually to the President and Congress on all foreign persons not currently subject to such sanctions that, within the preceding three years, have been reported to have conducted transactions or have provided material support to the IRGC or any of its agents or affiliates. </p> <p> The President shall: </p> <ul> <li>review an identified foreign person to determine whether there is sufficient evidence to impose sanctions; and </li> <li>if so, include that person on the list of specially designated nationals and blocked persons maintained by the Office of Foreign Assets Control of the Department of the Treasury and impose sanctions. </li> </ul> <p>The Securities Exchange Act of 1934 is amended to require securities issuers to report to the Securities and Exchange Commission any financial transactions with a foreign person identified in the most recent GAO report before the commencement of the transaction or dealing.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
