<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5392" measure-id="id114hr5392" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-06-07" update-date="2016-10-04">
<title>No Veterans Crisis Line Call Should Go Unanswered Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5392v81" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-10-04">
<action-date>2016-09-26</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p><strong>No Veterans Crisis Line Call Should Go Unanswered Act</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill directs the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to develop a quality assurance document for carrying out the toll-free Veterans Crisis Line (VCL), which shall: (1) outline performance indicators and objectives to improve the VCL, including at backup call centers; (2) include time frames to meet such indicators and objectives; and (3) be consistent with guidance issued by the Office of Management and Budget. </p> <p>The VA shall develop a plan to ensure that each telephone call, text message, and other communications received by the VCL, including at backup call centers, is answered in a timely manner by a person, consistent with the guidance established by the American Association of Suicidology. The plan shall include guidelines for periodic VCL testing. </p> <p> The VA shall submit the document and plan within 180 days.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5392v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-08-19">
<action-date>2016-06-07</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>No Veterans Crisis Line Call Should Go Unanswered Act</strong></p> <p>This bill directs the Department of Veterans Affairs to develop: </p> <ul> <li>a quality assurance document for carrying out the toll-free Veterans Crisis Line (VCL), including at backup call centers; and </li> <li>a plan to ensure that each telephone call, text message, and other communications received by the VCL, including at backup call centers, is answered in a timely manner by a person, consistent with the guidance established by the American Association of Suicidology.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
