<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5678" measure-id="id114hr5678" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-07-07" update-date="2016-10-13">
<title>Stop Iran From Smuggling Weapons to Terrorists Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5678v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-10-13">
<action-date>2016-07-07</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Stop Iran From Smuggling Weapons to Terrorists Act</strong></p> <p>This bill authorizes the Department of Defense (DOD) to provide training to: (1) the national military or other security forces of Israel, Bahrain, Saudi Arabia, the United Arab Emirates, Oman, Kuwait, and Qatar that have among their functional responsibilities maritime security missions; and (2) ministry, agency, and headquarters level organizations for such forces. </p> <p>Such assistance and training may be referred to as the Counter Iran Maritime Initiative.</p> <p>Such training: (1) may include the provision of de minimis equipment, supplies, and small-scale military construction; and (2) shall include the promotion of human rights and respect for legitimate civilian authority.</p> <p>It is the sense of Congress that DOD should seek payments from such countries to offset training costs. DOD shall negotiate a training cost-sharing agreement with a recipient country that covers at least 50% of related costs.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
