<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3978" measure-id="id114hr3978" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-11-05" update-date="2015-11-13">
<title>Ensuring Fair Access to Veterans Healthcare Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3978v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-11-13">
<action-date>2015-11-05</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Ensuring Fair Access to Veterans Healthcare Act</strong></p> <p>This bill establishes in the Veterans Health Administration an Office of the Ombudsman, which shall:</p> <ul> <li>investigate and resolve complaints made by or on behalf of patients receiving medical care or hospital services at a Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) medical facility (covered patients) that relate to action, inaction, or decisions made by VA employees that may adversely affect such patients; </li> <li>assist covered patients in finding patient advocates, veterans service organizations, or other similar entities to advocate for their health, safety, welfare, and rights;</li> <li>ensure that covered patients have regular and timely access to Office services; </li> <li>administer the reporting system provided for by this Act; and </li> <li>provide training to local ombudsmen and volunteers. </li> </ul> <p>The Office shall establish a reporting system to collect and analyze complaint data in order to determine how to resolve significant VA medical facility problems.</p> <p>Each VA medical facility shall have a local ombudsman responsible for carrying out the duties of the Office at such location. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
