<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1301" measure-id="id114hr1301" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-03-04" update-date="2016-10-13">
<title>Amateur Radio Parity Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1301v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-10-13">
<action-date>2016-09-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the House on September 9, 2016. The summary of that version is repeated here.)</p> <p><b>Amateur Radio Parity Act of 2016</b></p> <p><strong></strong></p> <p>(Sec. 3) This bill directs the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to amend station antenna structure regulations to prohibit a private land use restriction from applying to amateur radio stations if the restriction:</p> <ul> <li>precludes communications in an amateur radio service, </li> <li>fails to permit a licensee of amateur radio service to install and maintain an effective outdoor antenna on property under its exclusive use or control, or </li> <li>is not the minimum practicable restriction to accomplish the lawful purposes of a community association seeking to enforce the restriction. </li></ul> <p>Before installing an outdoor antenna, however, an amateur radio licensee must obtain a community association's prior approval. A community association may: (1) prohibit installations on common property not under the exclusive control of the licensee, and (2) establish installation rules for amateur radio antennas and support structures.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1301v17" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-10-13">
<action-date>2016-09-09</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Amateur Radio Parity Act of 2016</b></p> <p><strong></strong></p> <p>(Sec. 3) This bill directs the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to amend station antenna structure regulations to prohibit a private land use restriction from applying to amateur radio stations if the restriction:</p> <ul> <li> precludes communications in an amateur radio service, </li> <li>fails to permit a licensee of amateur radio service to install and maintain an effective outdoor antenna on property under its exclusive use or control, or </li> <li>is not the minimum practicable restriction to accomplish the lawful purposes of a community association seeking to enforce the restriction.</li> </ul> <p>Before installing an outdoor antenna, however, an amateur radio licensee must obtain a community association's prior approval. A community association may: (1) prohibit installations on common property not under the exclusive control of the licensee, and (2) establish installation rules for amateur radio antennas and support structures.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1301v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-03-19">
<action-date>2015-03-04</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Amateur Radio Parity Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>Directs the Federal Communications Commission to amend regulations concerning the height and dimensions of station antenna structures to prohibit a private land use restriction from applying to amateur service communications if the restriction precludes such communications, fails to accommodate such communications, or does not constitute the minimum practicable restriction to accomplish the legitimate purpose of the private entity seeking to enforce the restriction.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
