<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5677" measure-id="id114hr5677" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-07-07" update-date="2016-10-13">
<title>U.S.-Israel Partnership to Hold Iran Accountable Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5677v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-10-13">
<action-date>2016-07-07</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>U.S.-Israel Partnership to Hold Iran Accountable Act</strong></p> <p>This bill authorizes the Department of State to establish a joint commission with Israel to address Iranian compliance with the Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action (JCPOA).</p> <p>The commission should: </p> <ul> <li>support professional dialogues to detect and respond to JCPOA violations by Iran; </li> <li>coordinate subcabinet level political discussions on contingency responses to such violations and responses to Iran's destabilizing, non-nuclear activities, including missile launches, support for terrorism, and human rights violations; and </li> <li>coordinate technical discussions among the State Department, the Department of the Treasury, the Department of Energy, and counterpart Israeli ministries on technical aspects of JCPOA implementation.</li> </ul> <p>The bill expresses the sense of Congress that: </p> <ul> <li>Israeli officials who are counterparts to specified U.S. officials should be appointed as commission members; </li> <li>the President should ensure commission participation by senior officials in the Executive Office of the President and counterparts in the Office of the Prime Minister of Israel; and </li> <li>the Department of Defense should conduct joint military planning with Israel based on commission-identified contingency scenarios, such as responding to the detection of a covert Iranian enrichment facility, new Iranian weaponization efforts, or other clear indicators that Iran has begun a nuclear weapon breakout.</li></ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
