<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1392" measure-id="id114hr1392" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-03-17" update-date="2015-03-20">
<title>FOCUS Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1392v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-03-20">
<action-date>2015-03-17</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Fighting Occupied Cell Use So Everyone Drives More Safely Act of 2015 or the FOCUS Act of 2015</b></p> <p>This bill directs the Secretary of Transportation to withhold 25% of a state's apportionment of certain federal-aid highway funds for a fiscal year if the state has not enacted and is not enforcing a law that:</p> <ul> <li>prohibits an operator of a moving motor vehicle from using a communication device, except in the event of an emergency, if the operator is under age 21, and using a hand-held communication device if that operator is 21 or older; and</li> <li>requires, upon conviction of a violation of such prohibition, the imposition of penalties similar to those for conviction of the offense of driving while intoxicated or driving under the influence.</li> </ul> <p>&quot;Communication device&quot; means a mobile telephone or other portable electronic communication device with which a user engages in a call or writes, sends, or reads a message, or plays a game or watches a video.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
