<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2235" measure-id="id114hr2235" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-05" update-date="2016-07-07">
<title>National Mitigation Fisheries Coordination Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2235v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-07-07">
<action-date>2015-05-05</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>National Mitigation Fisheries Coordination Act</b></p> <p>This bill directs the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service (USFWS) to impose a charge for conducting mitigation fishery activities in connection with federal water resources development projects carried out by water development agencies (the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers, the Bureau of Reclamation, or the Tennessee Valley Authority). The agencies must pay the charge in accordance with a fishery mitigation plan developed and approved by the USFWS Director and the agency head.</p> <p>"Mitigation fishery activities" are the rearing and stocking of native and nonnative fish to replace or maintain fishery resources or harvest levels lost as a result of a project, including project planning, population assessment and evaluation, genetic monitoring, broodstock development, and fish health sampling.</p> <p> USFWS's charges must be reasonably related to expenditures necessary to: (1) operate, maintain, and rehabilitate certain USFWS-owned and -operated mitigation fishery facilities, hatcheries, and health centers; and (2) conduct mitigation fishery activities, including expenditures for personnel, transportation, utilities, contractual services, fish feed, supplies, equipment, routine maintenance, deferred maintenance, fish eggs, technical support, fish health, management and administration, planning, outreach and education, and hatchery product evaluations.</p> <p>The bill lists the applicable mitigation fishery facilities in Arkansas, Georgia, Kentucky, Missouri, Montana, North Dakota, Pennsylvania, South Dakota, Tennessee, Utah, West Virginia, Wisconsin, and Wyoming.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
