<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2426" measure-id="id114hr2426" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-19" update-date="2015-11-16">
<title>To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act with respect to easing regulatory burden with respect to certain class I and class II devices.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2426v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-11-16">
<action-date>2015-05-19</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to require the Food and Drug Administration (FDA), not later than 120 days after enactment of the 21st Century Cures Act (H.R. 6, a bill introduced on May 19, 2015), to identify types of class I medical devices (devices that do not need special controls to assure their safety and effectiveness) for which a report is no longer needed prior to marketing to provide reasonable assurance of safety and effectiveness. (Currently, a report is needed for a class I device only if the device is of substantial importance in preventing impairment of human health or if it presents a potential unreasonable risk of illness or injury.)</p> Not later than 180 days after enactment of the 21st Century Cures Act, the FDA must publish a list of types of class II medical devices (devices that need special controls to assure their safety and effectiveness) for which a report is no longer needed prior to marketing to provide reasonable assurance of safety and effectiveness. (Currently, such a list must be published each time the FDA exempts a type of class II device from the reporting requirement.) The public comment period for such an exemption is extended to 60 days.]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
