<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2442" measure-id="id114hr2442" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-19" update-date="2015-06-17">
<title>Supplemental Security Income Restoration Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2442v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-06-17">
<action-date>2015-05-19</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Supplemental Security Income Restoration Act of 2015 </b></p> <p> Amends title XVI (Supplemental Security Income) (SSI) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to increase from $240 to $1,344 (increased for inflation each calendar year after 2016) the first amount of general income per year excluded in determining SSI program eligibility.</p> <p>Increases from $780 to $4,368 (similarly increased) the first amount of earned income similarly excluded (including for a blind or disabled individual or spouse under age 65).</p> <p>Sets at: (1) $15,000 in calendar year 2016 (increased for inflation) the resource limit for couples, and (2) $10,000 in calendar year 2016 (similarly increased) the resource limit for individuals without a spouse.</p> <p>Prescribes an inflation adjustment in benefits in any calendar year after 2016.</p> <p>Removes support and maintenance furnished in kind from determination of unearned income.</p> <p>Repeals the administrative penalty which renders individuals (and spouses) ineligible for SSI for a certain period of time if after the look-back date (usually 36 months preceding their application for SSI) they dispose of their resources for less than market value.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
