<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2750" measure-id="id114hr2750" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-06-12" update-date="2015-08-31">
<title>Improved Security Vetting for Aviation Workers Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2750v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-08-31">
<action-date>2015-07-27</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Improved Security Vetting for Aviation Workers Act of 2015</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 todirect the Transportation Security Administration (TSA) of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS), by December 31, 2015, in coordination with the DHS Assistant Secretary for Policy, to request from the Director of National Intelligence access to additional data from the Terrorist Identities Datamart Environment data and any or other terrorism-related information to improve the effectiveness of TSA's credential vetting program for individuals with unescorted access to sensitive areas of airports.</p> <p>The TSA, by the same deadline, shall: </p> <ul> <li>issue guidance for Transportation Security Inspectors to review annually airport badging office procedures for applicants seeking access to sensitive airport areas, including a comprehensive review of applicants' Criminal History Records Check and work authorization documentation during the course of an inspection;</li> <li>issue guidance to airports requiring that all federalized airport badging authorities place an expiration date on airport credentials commensurate with the period of time during which an individual is lawfully authorized to work in the United States; and</li> <li>review the denial of credentials owing to an applicants's lawful status in order to identify airports with specific weaknesses and coordinate with them to address such weaknesses. </li></ul> <p>The TSA may conduct a Rap Back Service pilot program, in coordination with the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI), to determine the feasibility of full implementation of a service through which the TSA would be notified of a change in status of an individual holding a valid credential granting unescorted access to sensitive airport areas across eligible TSA-regulated populations. (The FBI Rap Back Service notifies authorized agencies of criminal, and, in limited cases, civil activity of individuals that occurs after the initial processing and retention of criminal or civil transactions.)</p> <p>Certain pilot program procedures are prescribed regarding notification only of a change with respect to a disqualifying offense under the credential vetting program.</p> <p>(Sec. 3) The TSA, within 60 days after enactment of this Act, shall report to Congress on the status of plans to conduct the Rap Back Service pilot program.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2750v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-08-31">
<action-date>2015-06-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Improved Security Vetting for Aviation Workers Act of 2015</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 todirect the Transportation Security Administration (TSA) of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to coordinate with DHS and the Interagency Policy Committee of the Office of the President to determine whether TSA should receive additional Terrorist Identities Datamart Environment data or other terrorism related category codes to assist in its credential vetting program for individuals with access to sensitive areas of airports.</p> <p>The TSA shall: </p> <ul> <li>issue guidance for Transportation Security Inspectors to review annually airport badging office procedures for applicants seeking access to sensitive airport areas, including a comprehensive review of applicants' Criminal History Records Check and work authorization documentation during the course of an inspection;</li> <li>coordinate with DHS to conduct a Rap Back Service pilot program to determine the feasibility of its implementation across eligible TSA-regulated populations;</li> <li>issue guidance to airports requiring that all federalized airport badging authorities place an expiration date on airport credentials commensurate to the time which an individual is lawfully authorized to work in the United States; and</li> <li>review the denial of credentials due to an applicants's lawful status in order to identify airports with specific weaknesses and coordinate with them to address such weaknesses.</li> </ul> <p>The TSA shall coordinate with DHS and consult with the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) to conduct a pilot program of the Rap Back Service to determine the feasibility of its full implementation across eligible TSA-regulated populations. (The FBI Rap Back Service provides authorized agencies with notification of criminal, and, in limited cases, civil activity of individuals that occurs after the initial processing and retention of criminal or civil transactions.)</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
