<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3410" measure-id="id114hr3410" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-07-29" update-date="2015-09-02">
<title>Rural Economic Vitalization Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3410v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-09-02">
<action-date>2015-07-29</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Rural Economic Vitalization Act </b></p> <p>This bill authorizes the voluntary waiver of permits or leases for grazing on federal lands managed by the Department of Agriculture or the Department of the Interior. </p> <p>If a permit or lease is waived by a permittee or lessee, the appropriate department must: </p> <ul> <li>accept and terminate the permit or lease, </li> <li>refrain from issuing any new grazing permit or lease within the grazing allotment covered by the permit or lease, and </li> <li>ensure a permanent end to livestock grazing on the allotment covered by the permit or lease. </li> </ul> <p>If an allotment covered by a waiver is also covered by another permit or lease that is not waived, the department must reduce the level of commercial livestock grazing on the allotment to reflect the waiver. </p> <p>The departments must not accept more than 100 grazing permits and leases per year, in the aggregate, under this authority. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
