<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4608" measure-id="id114hr4608" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-02-24" update-date="2016-03-29">
<title>Savings Accounts for a Variable Economy for Small Businesses Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4608v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-03-29">
<action-date>2016-02-24</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>SAVE for Small Businesses Act or the Savings Accounts for a Variable Economy for Small Businesses Act </strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) provide for tax-exempt small business savings accounts, and (2) allow tax deductible contributions to such accounts of not more than 10% of the gross profits of an eligible small business (a business employing an average of 50 or fewer full-time employees) for the preceding taxable year. </p> <p>The bill excludes qualified distributions from such accounts from gross income for income tax purposes. A &quot;qualified distribution&quot; is: (1) any amount that is distributed from a small business savings account during a specified period of economic hardship, and (2) the distribution of which is certified as being part of a plan that provides for the reinvestment of such distribution for the funding of worker hiring or financial stabilization for the purposes of job retention or creation. </p> <p>The Secretary of the Treasury shall: (1) establish minimum standards for small business savings accounts that seek to minimize fees and risk of loss of principal, and (2) ensure a range of investment risk options available to account beneficiaries. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
