<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1065" measure-id="id114hr1065" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-02-25" update-date="2015-05-21">
<title>POST Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1065v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-05-21">
<action-date>2015-02-25</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>POST Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>Directs states receiving funds under specified Bureau of Justice Assistance grant programs (whether characterized as the Edward Byrne Memorial State and Local Law Enforcement Assistance Programs, the Local Government Law Enforcement Block Grants Program, the Edward Byrne Memorial Justice Assistance Grant Program, or otherwise), after a specified compliance period, to require all individuals enrolled in an academy of a law enforcement agency of the state and all law enforcement officers of the state to fulfill a training session on sensitivity each fiscal year, including training on ethnic and racial bias, cultural diversity, and police interaction with the disabled, mentally ill, and new immigrants. Requires an eight-hour session for individuals attending an academy and a four-hour session for all other law enforcement officers.</p> <p>Subjects any state that fails to comply with such requirement to a reduction of up to 20% of the funds that would otherwise be allocated to such state for a fiscal year for such grant programs, at the discretion of the Attorney General. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
