<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4492" measure-id="id114hr4492" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-02-08" update-date="2016-06-02">
<title>Sound of Freedom Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4492v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-06-02">
<action-date>2016-02-08</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Sound of Freedom Act</strong></p> <p>This bill states that it shall be Department of Defense (DOD) policy that flyovers of public events in support of community relations activities may only be flown as part of an approved training mission at no additional expense to the federal government.</p> <p>The Adjutant General of a state in which an Army National Guard or Air National Guard unit is based shall be the approval authority for all Air National Guard and Army National Guard flyovers in that state, including any flyover request in any civilian domain at a non-aviation related event.</p> <p>DOD shall maintain records of flyover requests and approvals in a publicly accessible database updated annually. </p> <p>&quot;Flyover&quot; means aviation support: </p> <ul> <li>in which a straight and level flight limited to one pass by a single military aircraft, or by a single formation of four or fewer military aircraft of the same type, from the same military department over a predetermined point on the ground at a specific time;</li> <li>that does not involve aerobatics or demonstrations; and</li> <li>that uses bank angles of up to 90 degrees if required to improve spectator visibility of the aircraft.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
