<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3557" measure-id="id114hr3557" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-09-18" update-date="2016-04-20">
<title>FSOC Transparency and Accountability Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3557v79" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-04-20">
<action-date>2016-04-19</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p><b>FSOC Transparency and Accountability Act</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Financial Stability Act of 2010 to repeal the nonapplicability of the Federal Advisory Committee Act (FACA) to the Financial Stability Oversight Council (thus applying FACA to the Council).</p> <p>The Council is declared an agency for purposes of the &quot;Government in the Sunshine Act&quot; (and its open meeting requirements).</p> <p> The voting profile of Council members is revised to cite the following member agencies as each having collectively one vote: (1) the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, (2) the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC), (3) the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC), (4) the Commodity Futures Trading Commission (CFTC), and (5) the National Credit Union Administration (NCUA) Board.</p> <p>Such member agencies shall: (1) determine their Council vote by using the voting process normally applicable to votes by their members, and (2) cast the one collective Council vote by the agency head. </p> <p>A Council member may select to have one or more individuals on the member's staff attend a meeting of the Council, including any meeting of representatives of the member agencies other than the members themselves.</p> <p> All Council meetings shall be open to attendance and participation by members of specified congressional committees, including any meeting of representatives of the member agencies other than the members themselves. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3557v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-09-28">
<action-date>2015-09-18</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>FSOC Transparency and Accountability Act</b></p> <p>Amends the Financial Stability Act of 2010 to repeal the nonapplicability of the Federal Advisory Committee Act (FACA) to the Financial Stability Oversight Council (thus applying FACA to the Council).</p> <p>Declares the Council an agency for purposes of the &quot;Government in the Sunshine Act&quot; (and its open meeting requirements).</p> <p> Revises the voting profile of Council members to single out the following member agencies as each having collectively one vote: (1) the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, (2) the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC), (3) the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC), (4) the Commodity Futures Trading Commission (CFTC), and (5) the National Credit Union Administration (NCUA) Board.</p> <p>Directs these member agencies to: (1) determine their Council vote by using the voting process normally applicable to votes by their members, and (2) cast the one collective Council vote by the agency head. </p> <p>Permits any Council member to select to have one or more individuals on the member's staff attend a meeting of the Council, including any meeting of representatives of the member agencies other than the members themselves.</p> <p>Requires all Council meetings to be open to attendance and participation by members of specified congressional committees, including any meeting of representatives of the member agencies other than the members themselves. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
