<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3595" measure-id="id114hr3595" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-09-24" update-date="2015-09-30">
<title>Increased Authorizations for the Denver VA Medical Center Construction Project Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3595v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-09-30">
<action-date>2015-09-24</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Increased Authorizations for the Denver VA Medical Center Construction Project Act</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Construction Authorization and Choice Improvement Act to increase the amount authorized for the replacement of the existing Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) Medical Center in Denver, Colorado. </p> <p>In the case of any super construction project (expenditures exceeding $100 million) the VA shall enter into an agreement with an appropriate non-VA federal entity to provide full project management services for the super construction project, including management over the project design, acquisition, construction, and contract changes. </p> <p>The Veterans Access, Choice, and Accountability Act of 2014 is amended to reduce the aggregate amount of specified VA awards and bonuses for FY2016. (Existing award levels are maintained for each of FY2017-FY2024.)</p> <p>The VA shall reduce the retirement annuity benefits of a senior executive employee who: (1) is convicted of a felony that influenced the individual's performance while employed in the senior executive position, and (2) is afforded notice and an opportunity for a hearing conducted by another federal department or agency.</p> <p>The VA may issue an order directing a VA employee to repay in full or in part any award or bonus if: (1) the VA determines such repayment appropriate pursuant to specified regulations, and (2) the employee is afforded notice and an opportunity for a hearing conducted by another federal department or agency.</p> <p>A VA decision regarding a repayment is final and not subject to review by other federal agencies or courts.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
