<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3502" measure-id="id114hr3502" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-09-11" update-date="2015-12-04">
<title>Tribal Nutrition Improvement Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3502v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-12-04">
<action-date>2015-09-11</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Tribal Nutrition Improvement Act of 2015</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Richard B. Russell National School Act to allow an Indian tribe to assume, from a nearby local educational agency (LEA) and in lieu of a state,&nbsp;responsibility for administration of the school breakfast program, the school lunch program, the child and adult care food program, or the summer food service program for children.&nbsp;The Department of Agriculture (USDA)&nbsp;must identify, for optional use in&nbsp;LEAs on or near Indian reservations, alternatives to current program requirements related to the daily counting of meals by category, the use of annual applications to determine program eligibility, and the use of universal meal service. USDA&nbsp;may implement such alternatives, as limited by the bill, as well as&nbsp;further test them in demonstration projects.</p> <p>The bill also amends the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 to require USDA to&nbsp;increase the amount of administrative funds paid to an Indian tribe that agrees to assume responsibility for the administration of one of the aforementioned food programs.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
