<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4402" measure-id="id114hr4402" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-02-01" update-date="2016-03-02">
<title>Foreign Fighter Review Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4402v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-03-02">
<action-date>2016-02-23</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Foreign Fighter Review Act of 2016 </strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill directs the President, through the Department of Homeland Security (DHS), to initiate a review of known instances since 2011 in which a person has traveled or attempted to travel to a conflict zone in Iraq or Syria from the United States to join or provide material support or resources to a terrorist organization. </p> <p> Such review shall: </p> <ul> <li> include relevant information held by the U.S. government related to each instance; </li> <li> ascertain factors that may have undermined efforts to prevent such travel, including the timely identification of suspects, information sharing, intervention, and interdiction; and </li> <li> identify lessons learned and areas for improvement to prevent additional travel by such persons to a conflict zone in Iraq or Syria, or other terrorist safe havens abroad, to join or provide material support or resources to a terrorist organization.</li> </ul> <p>DHS shall submit to Congress the results of such review, which may include information on travel routes of greatest concern.</p> <p>No additional funds are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4402v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-02-02">
<action-date>2016-02-01</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Foreign Fighter Review Act of 2016</strong></p> <p>This bill directs the President, through the Department of Homeland Security, to initiate a review of known instances since 2011 in which a person has traveled or attempted to travel to a conflict zone in Iraq or Syria from the United States to join or provide material support or resources to a terrorist organization.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
