<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="985" measure-id="id114hr985" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-02-13" update-date="2016-07-27">
<title>Concrete Masonry Products Research, Education, and Promotion Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr985v17" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-07-27">
<action-date>2016-07-08</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Concrete Masonry Products Research, Education, and Promotion Act of 2015</b></p> <p> (Sec. 4) This bill directs the Department of Commerce to issue orders applicable to manufacturers of concrete masonry products.</p> <p> An order regarding the generic research, education, and promotion about concrete masonry products may be: <ul> <li>proposed by Commerce at any time; or</li> <li>requested (and submitted to Commerce) by an existing national organization of concrete masonry product manufacturers or any person that may be affected by the issuance of such an order.</li> </ul> <p> (Sec. 5) Any such order shall provide for establishment of a Concrete Masonry Products Board to carry out a program of generic promotion, research, and education regarding concrete masonry products.</p> <p>The board may not engage in any action, nor use any funds received under this bill, to:</p> <ul> <li> influence legislation, elections, or governmental action;</li> <li> engage in any conflict of interest;</li> <li>engage in advertising that is false or misleading; or </li> <li>engage in any promotion, research, or education that would be disparaging to other construction materials, or any promotion or project that would benefit any individual manufacturer.</li> </ul> <p>Manufacturers and importers shall maintain, and make available for inspection, specified records.</p> <p>(Sec. 6) Any such order must also require that quarterly assessments be paid by manufacturers for any concrete masonry products manufactured at least 180 days before remittance of the assessment to the board.</p> <p>The bill establishes an initial assessment rate of $0.01 per concrete masonry unit sold. The board may increase or decrease such rate but any change may not exceed $0.01 per unit, and be made no more than once per year. The maximum rate shall be $0.05 per unit.</p> <p>The board may make specified investments of collected assessments.</p> <p>At least 50% of the assessments (less administrative expenses) paid by a manufacturer shall be used to support research, education, and promotion programs and projects in support of the manufacturer's geographic region. The bill divides the states into five specified regions, whose composition Commerce may adjust on the board's recommendation.</p> <p>(Sec. 7) During the 60-day period preceding the proposed effective date of an order, Commerce shall conduct a referendum for order approval, according to specified procedures, among the manufacturers required to pay assessments under it.</p> <p>(Sec. 8) The bill prescribes requirements for petition and review of an order, including order enforcement through U.S. district courts. Commerce may assess a civil penalty on any person willfully violating such an order or regulation.</p> <p>(Sec. 10) Commerce may also conduct appropriate investigations to administer this bill (with power of subpoena).</p> <p>(Sec. 11) Commerce must suspend or terminate any order, or a provision of an order, that obstructs or does not tend to effectuate the purposes of this bill, or that is not favored by a majority of all votes cast in a referendum.</p> <p>(Sec. 15) Funds appropriated to carry out this bill may not be used for the board's payment of expenses or expenditures in administering the order.</p> <p>(Sec. 16) The Government Accountability Office shall study how the board spends assessments collected, the impact of board activities, and other matters relating to the demand for concrete masonry products.</p> <p>(Sec. 17) Commerce shall examine the appropriateness and effectiveness of applying the commodity check-off program model to a nonagricultural industry. (A commodity check-off program collects funds through a checkoff mechanism from producers of a particular agricultural commodity and uses them to promote and do research on that particular commodity.)</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr985v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-07-28">
<action-date>2015-02-13</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Concrete Masonry Products Research, Education, and Promotion Act of 2015</b></p> <p>This bill directs the Secretary of Commerce to issue orders applicable to manufacturers of concrete masonry products. Any such order must provide for the establishment of a Concrete Masonry Products Board to carry out a program of promotion, research, and information regarding concrete masonry products. Manufacturers and importers shall maintain, and make available, specified records. </p> <p>An order must also provide that assessments be paid by concrete masonry product manufacturers with respect to concrete masonry products manufactured and marketed in the United States. Assessment rates are specified. At least 50% of the assessments paid by a manufacturer must be used to support research, education, and promotion plans and projects in support of the geographic region of the manufacturer. During the 60-day period preceding the proposed effective date of an order, the Secretary shall conduct a referendum for order approval among the manufacturers required to pay assessments under it. Referendum procedures are outlined.</p> <p>The bill allows petition and review of an order, and order enforcement through U.S. district courts. The Secretary: (1) may conduct appropriate investigations in order to administer this Act (with power of subpoena); and (2) must suspend or terminate any order or provision that obstructs or does not tend to effectuate the purposes of this Act, or that is not favored by persons voting in a referendum.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
