<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5301" measure-id="id114hr5301" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-05-19" update-date="2016-07-07">
<title>Seller Finance Enhancement Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5301v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-07-07">
<action-date>2016-05-19</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Seller Finance Enhancement Act</b></p> <p> This bill amends the S.A.F.E. Mortgage Licensing Act of 2008 to exempt from certain licensing and registration requirements any person (other than a depository institution) who: (1) originates not more than 24 residential mortgage loans in a 12-month period, and (2) only originates residential mortgage loans for property owned by that person.</p> <p>For determining whether a residential mortgage loan meets minimum standards, the Truth in Lending Act is amended to prohibit the application to loans originated by such a person certain Consumer Financial Protection Bureau guidelines and regulations relating to ratios of total monthly debt to monthly income.</p> <p> The Department of Housing and Urban Development and the Department of the Treasury shall study:</p> <ul> <li>the number of homes bought for under $150,000 or 60% of the median home value in a given community, whichever is lower, in the United States by utilizing seller financing;</li> <li>the number of such homes sold by licensed mortgage brokers; </li> <li>the potential number of such homes which could be sold but are not, because seller financiers are unwilling, or from a practical standpoint unable, to comply with mortgage broker rules; and</li> <li>the potential benefit to home values and wealth creation if more homes are able to be sold utilizing seller finance.</li> </ul> <p> <p> <p> <p> <p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
