<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2381" measure-id="id114hr2381" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-15" update-date="2015-06-22">
<title>Racial Profiling Prevention Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2381v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-06-22">
<action-date>2015-05-15</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Racial Profiling Prevention Act</b></p> <p>Directs the Department of Transportation (DOT) to make a grant to a state that: (1) has enacted and is enforcing a law that prohibits a state or local law enforcement officer from using the race or ethnicity (racial profiling) of the driver or passengers in making routine or spontaneous law enforcement decisions, such as ordinary traffic stops on federal-aid highways; and (2) allows and maintains public inspection statistical information for each motor vehicle stop made by a law enforcement officer on a federal-aid highway regarding the race and ethnicity of the driver and any passengers. Requires grant-receiving states to provide assurances to DOT that they are undertaking activities to comply with such requirements.</p> <p>Requires a state to use such grants for the costs of: (1) collecting, maintaining, and evaluating the results of data on traffic stops; and (2) activities to comply with the requirements of this Act.</p> <p>Declares that nothing in this Act shall alter the manner in which a state or local law enforcement officer considers race or ethnicity whenever there is trustworthy information that links persons of a particular race or ethnicity to an identified criminal incident, scheme, or organization.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
