<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4421" measure-id="id114hr4421" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-02-01" update-date="2016-05-06">
<title>Colonel Charles Young Congressional Gold Medal Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4421v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-05-06">
<action-date>2016-02-01</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Colonel Charles Young Congressional Gold Medal Act</strong></p> <p>This bill directs the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President pro tempore of the Senate to make appropriate arrangements for the presentation, on behalf of Congress, of a gold medal to Colonel Charles Young in recognition of his pioneering U.S. Army career during exceptionally challenging times. </p> <p>Following its award, the medal shall be given to the National Afro-American Museum and Cultural Center in Wilberforce, Ohio.</p> <p>It is the sense of Congress that the National Afro-American Museum and Cultural Center should make the gold medal received available for display or loan so that it may be displayed elsewhere, particularly at other locations associated with Colonel Young's life.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
