<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5341" measure-id="id114hr5341" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-05-26" update-date="2016-08-15">
<title>To amend title 5, United States Code, to provide for recalculation of basic annuity benefits for certain air traffic controllers, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5341v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-08-15">
<action-date>2016-05-26</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill: (1) provides that calculation of the basic annuity benefits for an air traffic controller with at least five years of service actively engaged in the separation and control of air traffic shall include service as a first or second level supervisor of such a controller, (2) makes such change effective retroactive to December 12, 2003, and (3) provides for a lump sum payment to each affected annuitant equal to the additional total benefit amount such annuitant would have received had such change been in effect on such date. </p> <ul> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
