<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2220" measure-id="id114hr2220" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-01" update-date="2016-06-27">
<title>Marine and Hydrokinetic Renewable Energy Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2220v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-06-27">
<action-date>2015-05-01</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Marine and Hydrokinetic Renewable Energy Act of 2015</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007 to revise and reauthorize through FY2019 the program of research, development, demonstration, and commercial application to expand marine and hydrokinetic renewable energy production. The program must give priority to fostering accelerated research, development, and commercialization of technology.</p> <p>The meaning of "marine and hydrokinetic renewable energy&quot; is expanded to include all forms of energy, not just electricity, from: (1) waves, tides, and currents in oceans, estuaries, and tidal areas; (2) free flowing water in rivers, lakes, and streams; (3) free flowing water in man-made channels; and (4) differentials in ocean temperature (ocean thermal energy conversion).</p> <p>National Marine Renewable Energy Research, Development, and Demonstration Centers must support in-water testing and demonstration of marine and hydrokinetic renewable energy technologies, including facilities capable of testing: (1) marine and hydrokinetic renewable energy systems of various technology readiness levels and scales, (2) a variety of technologies in multiple test berths at a single location, and (3) arrays of technology devices. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
