<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3878" measure-id="id114hr3878" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-11-02" update-date="2015-12-31">
<title>Strengthening Cybersecurity Information Sharing and Coordination in Our Ports Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3878v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-12-31">
<action-date>2015-12-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Strengthening Cybersecurity Information Sharing and Coordination in Our Ports Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill requires the Department of&nbsp;Homeland Security (DHS) to implement, and evaluate at least every two years, a maritime cybersecurity risk assessment model to evaluate current and future cybersecurity risks. The model must be consistent with the National Institute of Standards and Technology Framework for Improving Critical Infrastructure Cybersecurity and any updates pursuant to the Cybersecurity Enhancement Act of 2014.</p> <p>DHS must also: (1) seek to ensure participation of at least one information sharing and analysis organization representing the maritime community in the National Cybersecurity and Communications Integration Center (NCCIC); (2) establish guidelines for voluntary reporting of maritime-related cybersecurity risks and incidents to the NCCIC and other appropriate federal agencies; and (3) request the National Maritime Security Advisory Committee to report and make recommendations to DHS regarding the enhancement of cybersecurity information sharing between relevant federal agencies and state, local, and tribal governments, public safety and emergency response agencies, law enforcement and security organizations, the maritime industry, port owners and operators, and terminal owners and operators.</p> <p>(Sec. 3) The Coast Guard must: (1) direct Area Maritime Security Advisory Committees to facilitate the sharing of cybersecurity risks and incidents to address port-specific cybersecurity risks, including, possibly, by establishing a working group of members of such committees to address port-specific cybersecurity vulnerabilities; and (2) require area maritime security plans and facility security plans to include a mitigation plan to prevent, manage, and respond to cybersecurity risks.</p> <p>(Sec. 4) DHS's vulnerability assessments of facilities and vessels that may be involved in a transportation security incident must identify weaknesses in cybersecurity. Owners or operators of such vessels or facilities must include provisions regarding prevention, management, and response to cybersecurity risks in their security plans for deterring such incidents. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3878v18" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-12-31">
<action-date>2015-12-15</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House amended, Part I</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Strengthening Cybersecurity Information Sharing and Coordination in Our Ports Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill requires the Department of&nbsp;Homeland Security (DHS) to implement, and evaluate at least every two years, a maritime cybersecurity risk assessment model to evaluate current and future cybersecurity risks. The model must be consistent with the National Institute of Standards and Technology Framework for Improving Critical Infrastructure Cybersecurity and any updates pursuant to the Cybersecurity Enhancement Act of 2014.</p> <p>DHS must also: (1) seek to ensure participation of at least one information sharing and analysis organization representing the maritime community in the National Cybersecurity and Communications Integration Center (NCCIC); (2) establish guidelines for voluntary reporting of maritime-related cybersecurity risks and incidents to the NCCIC and other appropriate federal agencies; and (3) request the National Maritime Security Advisory Committee to report and make recommendations to DHS regarding the enhancement of cybersecurity information sharing between relevant federal agencies and state, local, and tribal governments, public safety and emergency response agencies, law enforcement and security organizations, the maritime industry, port owners and operators, and terminal owners and operators.</p> <p>(Sec. 3) The Coast Guard must: (1) direct Area Maritime Security Advisory Committees to facilitate the sharing of cybersecurity risks and incidents to address port-specific cybersecurity risks, including, possibly, by establishing a working group of members of such committees to address port-specific cybersecurity vulnerabilities; and (2) require area maritime security plans and facility security plans to include a mitigation plan to prevent, manage, and respond to cybersecurity risks.</p> <p>(Sec. 4) DHS's vulnerability assessments of facilities and vessels that may be involved in a transportation security incident must identify weaknesses in cybersecurity. Owners or operators of such vessels or facilities must include cybersecurity provisions in their security plans for deterring such incidents. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3878v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-12-10">
<action-date>2015-11-02</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Strengthening Cybersecurity Information Sharing and Coordination in Our Ports Act of 2015</strong></p> This bill requires the Department of&nbsp;Homeland Security (DHS) to seek to enhance cybersecurity situational awareness and information sharing between and with maritime security stakeholders from federal, state, local, and tribal governments, public safety and emergency response agencies, law enforcement and security organizations, maritime industry participants, port owners and operators, and maritime terminal owners and operators. <p>DHS must: (1)&nbsp;consult with the Coast Guard to enhance participation by the Maritime Information Sharing and Analysis Center in the National Cybersecurity and Communications Integration Center; and (2) request that the National Maritime Security Advisory Committee report and make recommendations to DHS on methods to enhance cybersecurity and information sharing between such stakeholders, including the establishment of a council to facilitate national-level sharing of security information and coordination of strategies to mitigate cybersecurity risks in the maritime sector.</p> The Coast Guard must direct captains of designated ports to establish a working group of members of Area Maritime Security Advisory Committees to facilitate the sharing of information about, and development of plans to address, port-specific cybersecurity vulnerabilities. <p>The Coast Guard must also require that Area Maritime Security Plans and facility security plans approved after enactment of this Act&nbsp;include mitigation measures to prevent, manage, and respond to cyber threats and vulnerabilities.</p> <p>DHS must ensure that maritime security risk assessments include cybersecurity risks to ports and the maritime border of the United States. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
