<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3718" measure-id="id114hr3718" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-10-08" update-date="2016-05-23">
<title>Preventing and Reducing Improper Medicare and Medicaid Expenditures to Restore Integrity to Benefits Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3718v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-05-23">
<action-date>2015-10-08</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Preventing and Reducing Improper Medicare and Medicaid Expenditures to Restore Integrity to Benefits Act of 2015</b></p> <p>This bill amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to make several changes related to the prevention of Medicaid fraud.</p> <p>With respect to the Medicaid Integrity Program (MIP), the bill: (1) specifies that program appropriations&nbsp;may cover costs of equipment, travel, training, and salaries and benefits; and (2) allows the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) flexibility in determining the number of additional staff necessary to carry out the program. (MIP is a federal program aimed at preventing and reducing provider fraud, waste, and abuse in the Medicaid program.)</p> <p>Under current law, HHS may contract with Medicare administrative contractors (MACs), which are&nbsp;private&nbsp;insurers that process Medicare claims within&nbsp;specified geographic jurisdictions. The bill&nbsp;requires HHS to provide specified incentives for MACs to reduce improper payment error rates within their jurisdictions.</p> <p>The bill establishes criminal penalties of up to 10 years imprisonment and up to $500,000 in fines for illegally purchasing or distributing Medicare, Medicaid, or Children's Health Insurance Program (CHIP) beneficiary identification or billing privileges.</p> <p>The bill increases the scope of the Medicare-Medicaid Data Match Program (Medi-Medi Program), an existing program through which contractors and participating&nbsp;governmental agencies collaboratively analyze&nbsp;Medicare and Medicaid billing trends. HHS must establish a plan to encourage states to participate in the Medi-Medi Program. </p> <p>HHS shall develop and implement a plan to allow states to access relevant data on improper or fraudulent payments made under the Medicare program on behalf of individuals dually eligible for both Medicare and Medicaid.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
