<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2602" measure-id="id114hr2602" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-06-02" update-date="2015-09-29">
<title>Prioritizing Online Threat Enforcement Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2602v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-09-29">
<action-date>2015-06-02</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Prioritizing Online Threat Enforcement Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>Directs the Attorney General to ensure: </p> <ul> <li> that there are at least 10 additional operational agents of the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) designated to support the Criminal Division of the Department of Justice (DOJ) in the investigation and coordination of cybercrimes against persons;</li> <li> that each office of a U.S. Attorney designates at least one Assistant U.S. Attorney as responsible for investigating and prosecuting cybercrimes against persons; and</li> <li> the implementation of a regular and comprehensive training program to train FBI agents in the investigation and prosecution of, and the enforcement of laws related to, cybercrimes against persons, including relevant forensic training related to investigating and prosecuting such crimes.</li> </ul> <p>Makes additional funding available to the FBI, the Attorney General, and DOJ's Criminal Division for FY2016-FY2020 to: (1) hire and train law enforcement officers to investigate cybercrimes against person and assist in the prosecution of such crimes; and (2) enable relevant DOJ units to procure advanced tools of forensic science and expert computer forensic assistance to investigate, prosecute, and study such crimes.</p> <p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
