<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5167" measure-id="id114hr5167" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-05-06" update-date="2016-08-18">
<title>Technologies for Energy Security Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5167v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-08-18">
<action-date>2016-05-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Technologies for Energy Security Act </b></p> <p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to extend and modify the tax credits for residential energy efficient property and investments in energy property. </p> <p>The bill modifies the tax credit for residential energy efficient property to extend through 2021 the credits for expenditures for fuel cell property, small wind energy property, and geothermal heat pump property. For each extended credit, the bill phases out the current credit rate of 30% of expenditures by reducing it to 26% or 22%, depending on the date that the property is placed in service.</p> <p>The bill extends the tax credit for investments in energy property for the following property with construction that begins before January 1, 2022: </p> <ul> <li> fiber-optic solar energy property, </li> <li>fuel cell property, </li> <li> microturbine property, </li> <li> combined heat and power system property, </li> <li> small wind energy property, and </li> <li> thermal energy property. </li> </ul> <p>The bill phases out the current credit rate of 30% for investments in fuel cell property, small wind energy property, and fiber-optic solar energy property by reducing it to 26% or 22%, depending on the date that the property is placed in service. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
