<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="783" measure-id="id114hr783" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-02-05" update-date="2015-06-11">
<title>Zero Tolerance for FGM Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr783v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-06-11">
<action-date>2015-02-05</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Zero Tolerance for FGM Act of 2015</b></p> <p>This bill requires the Department of Health and Human Services to report on the development and implementation of a strategy that:</p> <ul> <li>ensures individuals who encounter minors at risk of female genital mutilation (FGM) are fully prepared to take action to prevent the practice;</li> <li>ensures individuals subjected to FGM can seek necessary services;</li> <li>provides for updating Centers for Disease Control and Prevention estimates of the prevalence of FGM or female circumcision; and</li> <li>provides for a public awareness campaign, so that the public understands how to help individuals at risk of FGM and address the needs of individuals subjected to FGM.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
