<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4697" measure-id="id114hr4697" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-03-03" update-date="2016-03-22">
<title>Prevent Drug Addiction Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4697v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-03-22">
<action-date>2016-03-03</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Prevent Drug Addiction Act of 2016</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration (SAMHSA) to award grants for consumer education about opioid addiction. (Opioids are drugs with effects similar to opium, such as heroin or certain prescription painkillers.)</p> <p>This bill amends the Controlled Substances Act to require medical practitioners to be trained in the treatment of opioid-dependent patients, pain management, and early detection of opioid addiction before they can be registered by the Drug Enforcement Administration to dispense opioids.</p> <p>Opioid treatment programs that close on any day must make arrangements for each patient to receive treatment during the closure, as necessary.</p> <p>A report must be submitted to SAMHSA for each individual who dies while receiving treatment in an opioid treatment program. In states receiving funding for controlled substance monitoring programs, deaths where an opioid drug is detected in the body must be reported to SAMHSA.</p> <p>The National Center for Health Statistics of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention must establish a National Opioid Death Registry to track opioid-related deaths.</p> <p>The Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality must develop and apply prescription drug addiction prevention and treatment quality measures.</p> <p>This bill amends part D (Voluntary Prescription Drug Benefit Program) of title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to allow prescription drug plan (PDP) sponsors to limit the access of certain beneficiaries to addictive drugs. PDP sponsors must have a utilization management tool to prevent drug addiction.</p> Medicare Drug Integrity Contractors may accept prescription and medical records to determine whether a beneficiary is at risk for prescription drug addiction.]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
