<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4744" measure-id="id114hr4744" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-03-15" update-date="2016-09-15">
<title>SAFETY Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4744v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-09-15">
<action-date>2016-03-15</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Safe Academic Facilities and Environments for Tribal Youth Act or the SAFETY Act</b></p> <p>This bill directs the Department of the Interior to carry out a Tribal School Construction Demonstration Program to award grants to Indian tribes for the construction of replacement tribal schools. The program provides additional funding and opportunities for tribes to construct schools. Tribes on the Interior priority list for construction of tribal schools receive the highest priority for a grant under this program.</p> <p>This bill amends the Tribally Controlled Colleges and Universities Assistance Act of 1978 to revise the grant program for construction at tribal colleges and universities. The bill eliminates the requirements for Interior to identify the need for construction and tribal colleges and universities to provide matching funds. Restrictions on grant amounts and the use of constructed facilities are removed.</p> <p>This bill amends the Housing Act of 1949 to authorize the Department of Agriculture to award grants to Indian tribes, tribal organizations, and tribal housing entities for the construction or renovation of housing in rural areas for educators at Indian schools and schools where at least 25% of the students are Indian.</p> <p>The Bureau of Indian Education and the Office of Management and Budget must develop a 10-year plan to bring up to good condition certain Bureau of Indian Education school facilities.</p> The Government Accountability Office must report on Impact Aid for construction provided to local education agencies impacted by military dependent children and children who reside on Indian lands.]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
