<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1643" measure-id="id114hr1643" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-03-26" update-date="2015-04-08">
<title>Digital Goods and Services Tax Fairness Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1643v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-04-08">
<action-date>2015-03-26</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Digital Goods and Services Tax Fairness Act of 2015</strong> </p> <p>Prohibits a state or local jurisdiction from imposing multiple or discriminatory taxes on the sale or use of a digital good or service delivered or transferred electronically to a customer. Excludes from the definition of "digital service" a service that is predominantly attributable to the direct, contemporaneous expenditure of live human effort, skill, or expertise, a telecommunications service, an ancillary service, an Internet access service, an audio or video programming service, or a hotel intermediary service.</p> <p>Restricts taxation of a digital good or service to taxation by a state or local jurisdiction whose territorial limits encompass a customer tax address, as defined by this Act. Makes the seller of digital goods or services responsible for obtaining and maintaining such address. Provides for the taxation of digital goods and services transactions that are aggregated and not separately stated.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
