<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5859" measure-id="id114hr5859" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-07-14" update-date="2016-09-26">
<title>Community Counterterrorism Preparedness Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5859v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-09-26">
<action-date>2016-09-21</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the House on September 9, 2016. The summary of that version is repeated here.)</p> <p><strong>Community Counterterrorism Preparedness Act</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to require the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to carry out a grant program for emergency response providers to prevent, prepare for, and respond to the most likely terrorist attack scenarios, including active shooters against major metropolitan areas.</p> <p>DHS shall provide to eligible applicants: (1) unclassified information on such scenarios, and (2) information on training and exercises best practices. Recipients may use grants to conduct training and exercises consistent with preventing, preparing for, and responding to such scenarios.</p> <p>Emergency response providers in jurisdictions that are currently receiving, or that previously received, funding under the Urban Area Security Initiative may apply for such a grant. </p> <p>Eligible applicants receiving funding under the program may include in funded activities neighboring jurisdictions that would be likely to provide mutual aid in response to terrorist attack scenarios.</p> <p>Grant applications must include a description of how the applicant will work with community partners such as schools, places of worship, and businesses when conducting permitted activities.</p> <p>DHS shall make funds provided under this bill available for use by a grant recipient for a period of at least 24 months.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5859v17" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-09-20">
<action-date>2016-09-19</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Community Counterterrorism Preparedness Act</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to require the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to carry out a grant program for emergency response providers to prevent, prepare for, and respond to the most likely terrorist attack scenarios, including active shooters against major metropolitan areas.</p> <p>DHS shall provide to eligible applicants: (1) unclassified information on such scenarios, and (2) information on training and exercises best practices. Recipients may use grants to conduct training and exercises consistent with preventing, preparing for, and responding to such scenarios.</p> <p>Emergency response providers in jurisdictions that are currently receiving, or that previously received, funding under the Urban Area Security Initiative may apply for such a grant. </p> <p>Eligible applicants receiving funding under the program may include in funded activities neighboring jurisdictions that would be likely to provide mutual aid in response to terrorist attack scenarios.</p> <p>Grant applications must include a description of how the applicant will work with community partners such as schools, places of worship, and businesses when conducting permitted activities.</p>  <p>DHS shall make funds provided under this bill available for use by a grant recipient for a period of at least 24 months.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5859v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-09-20">
<action-date>2016-07-14</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Community Counterterrorism Preparedness Act</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to require the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to carry out a grant program for emergency response providers to prevent, prepare for, and respond to the most likely terrorist attack scenarios, including active shooters against major metropolitan areas.</p> <p>Emergency response providers and jurisdictions that are currently receiving, or that previously received, funding under the Urban Area Security Initiative may apply for such a grant.</p> <p>Recipients may use grants to conduct training and exercises consistent with preventing, preparing for, and responding to such scenarios.</p> <p>DHS shall make funds provided under this bill available for use by a grant recipient for a period of at least 24 months.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
