<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3753" measure-id="id114hr3753" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-10-09" update-date="2015-12-08">
<title>Debt Ceiling Alternative Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3753v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-12-08">
<action-date>2015-10-09</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Debt Ceiling Alternative Act </b></p> <p>This bill establishes requirements for prioritizing obligations and selling federal assets if the federal debt reaches the statutory limit. </p> <p>If the Department of the Treasury estimates that the debt will reach the limit during a quarter, the President must ensure that the amount deposited in the Treasury from selling federal assets, disposing of real property, and rescinding unobligated balances is sufficient to prevent the debt from reaching the limit. </p> <p>To comply with this bill, the President may order the sale of assets, including:</p> <ul> <li>mortgages and real estate held by the Federal National Mortgage Association (Fannie Mae) and the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation (Freddie Mac), and</li> <li>mortgage-backed securities held by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System or any federal reserve bank. </li> </ul> <p>The Office of the Management and Budget must establish a Federal Real Property Disposal Pilot Program, under which real property that is not meeting federal government needs may be disposed of using expedited procedures. </p> <p>If a federal budget deficit exists in 2015 and no later than July 16, 2016, the President may rescind any unobligated balances of funds provided before FY2010. </p> <p>If the debt reaches the statutory limit, the Department of the Treasury may issue additional obligations solely to pay the principal and interest on debt held by the public and the Social Security trust funds. Obligations issued under this authority are exempt from the debt limit. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
