<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3376" measure-id="id114hr3376" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-07-29" update-date="2016-03-16">
<title>To authorize States to carry out bridge construction, maintenance, repair, and replacement projects using previously allocated surface transportation funds that are identified as being excess or inactive, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3376v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-03-16">
<action-date>2015-07-29</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill authorizes the Department of Transportation to permit states to carry out bridge projects using previously allocated funds that have been identified as being excess or inactive. The projects may include operational improvements, capital and operating costs, environmental measures, and transportation control measures. The funds will remain available for three years after the year in which this bill is enacted. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
