<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="178" measure-id="id114hr178" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-01-06" update-date="2015-01-14">
<title>Terrorist Denaturalization and Passport Revocation Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr178v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-01-14">
<action-date>2015-01-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p> <strong>Terrorist Denaturalization and Passport Revocation Act </strong></p> <p> Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to include among the grounds for loss of U.S. nationality by a native-born or naturalized citizen: </p> <ul> <li>taking an oath or making a declaration of allegiance to a foreign terrorist organization after attaining the age of 18; </li> <li> entering or serving in the armed forces of a foreign state that harbors a foreign terrorist organization; </li> <li>accepting, serving in, or performing the duties of any office, post, or employment in a foreign terrorist organization after attaining the age of 18; </li> <li>accepting, serving in, or performing the duties of any office, post, or employment in a foreign terrorist organization after attaining the age of 18 for which an oath or declaration of allegiance is required; or </li> <li>accepting, serving in, or performing the duties of any office, post, or employment in a foreign terrorist organization after attaining the age of 18 if the position requires knowing engagement in hostilities against U.S. military or civilian personnel.</li> </ul> <p>Amends the Passport Act of 1926 to prohibit, with a discretionary exception for emergency or humanitarian reasons, the Secretary of State from issuing a passport or passport card to an individual who is a member of a foreign terrorist organization engaged in hostilities against the United States or its allies. </p> <p>Directs the Secretary to revoke a passport or passport card previously issued to any such individual.</p> <p>Authorizes the Secretary, before revocation, to: (1) limit a previously issued passport or passport card only for return travel to the United States, or (2) issue a limited passport or passport card that only permits return travel to the United States.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
