<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1789" measure-id="id114hr1789" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-04-14" update-date="2015-04-20">
<title>Tank Car Safety and Security Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1789v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-04-20">
<action-date>2015-04-14</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Tank Car Safety and Security Act of 2015 </b></p> <p> Directs the Secretary of Transportation (DOT) to revise federal regulations regarding DOT-111 tank cars used to move flammable liquids to: (1) improve tank car design standards for new cars to include an outer steel jacket around it and thermal protection, full-height head shields, and high-flow capacity pressure relief valves; and (2) require additional safety upgrades to tank cars built after October 2011 by including installation of such valves and design modifications to prevent bottom outlets from opening in case of accident.</p> <p>Directs the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration to issue regulations to require that all rail safety coordinators ensure that no tank car containing crude oil is left unattended during any period that it is being transferred between railroad carriers or between a railroad carrier and a shipper.</p> <p>Directs the Secretary to submit to Congress a plan to phase out older-model DOT-111 tank cars that are not retrofitted to meet the new federal requirements.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
