<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4339" measure-id="id114hr4339" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-01-06" update-date="2016-02-09">
<title>Improving Small Business Advocacy Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4339v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-02-09">
<action-date>2016-01-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Improving Small Business Advocacy Act of 2016</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Small Business Act to declare that the exclusive duties of a Business Opportunity Specialist reporting to the senior official (or designee) appointed by the Small Business Administration (SBA) with certain SBA loan responsibilities, including the procurement program for small business concerns owned and controlled by service-disabled veterans and the Historically Underutilized Business Zone (HUBZone) program, shall be to implement specified SBA loan programs, and complete other duties related to contracting programs.</p> <p>Such duties shall include: </p> <ul> <li>performing specified functions with respect to small business concerns eligible to receive federal contracts and subcontracts;</li> <li>reviewing and monitoring compliance with mentor-protege agreements;</li> <li>representing the interests of the SBA and small business concerns in the award, modification, and administration of contracts and subcontracts awarded pursuant to the Act; and</li> <li>reporting fraud or abuse.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
