<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3731" measure-id="id114hr3731" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-10-09" update-date="2016-06-06">
<title>RaD Fund Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3731v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-06-06">
<action-date>2015-10-09</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Rare Disease Fund Act or the RaD Fund Act</b></p> <p>This bill requires the National Institutes of Health (NIH) to organize the Rare Disease Therapeutics Corporation to purchase rights to, fund the development of, and sell ownership interests in drugs, biological products, and medical devices for rare diseases.</p> <p>The NIH must sell stock in the corporation to investors as soon as practicable. The corporation and the NIH may enter into an agreement under which the NIH maintains an ownership interest in the corporation in exchange for providing the corporation with intellectual property or other assistance. The corporation is prohibited from paying dividends on its stock.</p> <p>The corporation must sell its interest in a rare disease therapy prior to the therapy entering large-scale clinical trials.</p> <p>The corporation must issue bonds guaranteed by the United States and may issue bonds backed by the corporation. For purposes of securities laws, the securities of the corporation are not issued or guaranteed by the federal government.</p> The bill establishes within the NIH the Rare Disease Therapeutics Corporation Science Advisory Council to advise the corporation on the purchase, sale, and development of rare disease therapies.]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
