<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3394" measure-id="id114hr3394" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-07-29" update-date="2016-11-03">
<title>CAPTIVE Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3394v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-11-03">
<action-date>2016-07-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Clarifying Amendment to Provide Terrorism Victims Equity Act or the CAPTIVE Act</b></p> <p> (Sec. 2) This bill amends the Terrorism Risk Insurance Act of 2002 to allow a person's court-awarded judgment against a terrorist party that is based on an act of terrorism to be satisfied with assets that the United States has seized or frozen from that terrorist party under the Foreign Narcotics Kingpin Designation Act. Under current law, assets seized or frozen under the Trading with the Enemy Act or the International Emergency Economic Powers Act are the only assets seized or frozen by the United States that may be used to satisfy such a person's judgment against a terrorist party. </p> <p>The bill also narrows the categories of &quot;persons&quot; who may satisfy their judgments against terrorist parties with such seized or frozen assets to natural persons who, at the time the act of terrorism was committed upon which the judgment was obtained, were: </p> <ul> <li>U.S. nationals; </li> <li>members of the U.S. Armed Forces; or </li> <li>otherwise employees of the federal government, or of a federal contractor, acting within the scope of employment. </li> </ul> <p>If a person described is deceased, the personal representative of the estate of that deceased person shall count as the person. </p> <p>(Sec. 3) The bill applies retroactively to judgments entered before its enactment.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3394v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-09-18">
<action-date>2015-07-29</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p> <b>Clarifying Amendment to Provide Terrorism Victims Equity Act or the CAPTIVE Act</b></p> <p>Amends the Terrorism Risk Insurance Act of 2002 to subject the blocked assets of a terrorist party to execution or attachment in aid of execution in order to satisfy a judgment based upon an act of terrorism, regardless of whether the terrorist party ceases to be a terrorist party after judgment is entered.</p> <p>Redefines a blocked asset to include any asset seized or frozen by the United States under the Foreign Narcotics Kingpin Designation Act. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
