<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3465" measure-id="id114hr3465" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-09-09" update-date="2016-01-21">
<title>Public-Private Partnership Infrastructure Investment Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3465v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-01-21">
<action-date>2015-09-09</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Public-Private Partnership Infrastructure Investment Act</strong> </p> <p>This bill requires the senior procurement executive of the Department of Transportation to enhance the services of the Office of Contracts and Procurement by: (1) working with modal agencies, states, and other grant recipients on implementing design-bid-build, design-build, and public-private partnerships (P3) procurement best practices, including model contracts; and (2) developing suggested best practices to encourage standardizing state P3 authorities and practices, including fair and balanced assumptions made in the calculations, consistency on unsolicited bids, non-compete clauses, and other major elements. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
