<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5177" measure-id="id114hr5177" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-05-10" update-date="2016-08-05">
<title>National Mitigation Investment Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5177v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-08-05">
<action-date>2016-05-10</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>National Mitigation Investment Act</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to authorize the President to increase the maximum total of contributions for a major disaster by an amount equal to 4% of the estimated aggregate amount of grants to be made under such Act if, at the time of a declaration of a major disaster, the affected state has in effect and is actively enforcing an approved state building code.</p> <p>To be eligible for such increased federal contributions, a state must submit its building code to the President for approval. The President shall approve such a code upon determining that it: (1) is consistent with the most recent version of a nationally recognized model building code; (2) has been adopted by the state within six years of the most recent version of such nationally recognized code; and (3) uses the nationally recognized code as a minimum standard. </p> <p>The Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) shall set appropriate standards for the periodic update, resubmittal, and approval of previously approved state building codes.</p> <p>Recipients may use hazard mitigation assistance received under such Act to conduct activities to help reduce the risk of future damage, hardship, loss, or suffering in any area affected by a flood.</p> <p>States and local governments may use technical and financial assistance received under such Act to implement predisaster hazard mitigation measures to establish and operate a building department and carry out enforcement activities to implement an approved state building code. In determining whether to provide such assistance, the President shall take into account the extent to which a state or local government is carrying out activities to implement an approved state building code.</p> <p>The National Advisory Council shall commence a comprehensive study to evaluate disaster costs and losses and develop recommendations for reducing them. </p> <p>FEMA shall conduct a pilot program to award grants to state, local, and tribal governments to aid and encourage the adoption and active enforcement of nationally recognized model building codes, state building codes, and related mitigation measures.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
