<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4120" measure-id="id114hr4120" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-11-19" update-date="2016-07-19">
<title>Head Start Improvement Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4120v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-07-19">
<action-date>2015-11-19</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Head Start Improvement Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Head Start Act to replace the existing Head Start program with block grants to states and Indian tribes for prekindergarten (pre-K) education. </p> <p>Instead of providing direct financial assistance to Head Start agencies, the Department of Education (ED) shall allot block grant funds for pre-K education among eligible states and Indian tribes in accordance with&nbsp;their relative proportions of children, age five and younger, from low-income households.&nbsp;Grant recipients&nbsp;shall use the grant funds to: (1)&nbsp;award subgrants to eligible entities&nbsp;that provide&nbsp;pre-K education programs; (2) administer such programs; and (3) provide technical assistance, oversight, monitoring, research, and training.</p> <p>Under current law, ED is authorized to designate, monitor, and establish standards for&nbsp;Head Start agencies. The bill instead shifts&nbsp;pre-K program oversight and control&nbsp;to states and Indian tribes, which&nbsp;shall have full flexibility to use grant funds to finance the pre-K programs of&nbsp;their choice.&nbsp;In addition,&nbsp;grant recipients may use grant funds to establish portable voucher systems that allow costs to be paid&nbsp;for attendance at&nbsp;private pre-K education programs.</p> <p>Under current law, federal financial assistance for a Head Start program&nbsp;is generally limited to&nbsp;80% of total program costs. The bill maintains this&nbsp;limitation by&nbsp;requiring grant recipients to provide matching funds equal to 20% of the grant amount.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
