<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2171" measure-id="id114hr2171" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-04-30" update-date="2015-06-25">
<title>Owyhee Wilderness Areas Boundary Modifications Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2171v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-06-25">
<action-date>2015-04-30</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Owyhee Wilderness Areas Boundary Modifications Act </b></p> <p>Adjusts the boundaries of the North Fork Owyhee Wilderness, the Owyhee River Wilderness, and the Pole Creek Wilderness in Idaho to exclude certain land.</p> <p>Amends the Omnibus Public Land Management Act of 2009 to allow motor vehicles to continue to be used for livestock monitoring, herding, and gathering in the Big Jacks Creek Wilderness, Bruneau-Jarbidge Rivers Wilderness, Little Jacks Creek Wilderness, North Fork Owyhee Wilderness, Owyhee River Wilderness, and Pole Creek Wilderness.</p> <p>Requires the Department of the Interior to: (1) report to Congress on all livestock grazing management activities that were authorized in such wilderness areas on the day before they were designated as wilderness, and (2) use the report to assist in the management of livestock grazing in those areas. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
