<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4158" measure-id="id114hr4158" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-12-02" update-date="2016-07-26">
<title>RISE Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4158v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-07-26">
<action-date>2015-12-02</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Restoring Investment in ATB Student Education Act or the RISE Act</b></p> <p>This bill amends title IV (Student Assistance) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to modify the federal student aid eligibility requirements for students who are not high school graduates. </p> <p>Currently, a student without a high school diploma or homeschool credential is eligible to receive federal student aid if such student is enrolled in a career pathway program and demonstrates an ability to benefit from an institution's education or training program. </p> <p>This bill eliminates enrollment in a career pathway program as a federal student aid eligibility requirement. A student without a high school diploma or homeschool credential is eligible to receive federal student aid by demonstrating an ability to benefit from an institution's education or training program. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
