<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2231" measure-id="id114hr2231" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-01" update-date="2015-07-07">
<title>Public Housing Tenant Protection and Reinvestment Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2231v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-07-07">
<action-date>2015-05-01</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Public Housing Tenant Protection and Reinvestment Act of 2015</b></p> <p><i>Public Housing One-for-One Replacement and Tenant Protection Act of 2015</i></p> <p> Amends the United States Housing Act of 1937 with respect to: (1) demolition, disposition, or both pursuant to conversion of any public housing unit; and (2) the taking of public housing units through the use of eminent domain.</p> <p>Exempts from specified requirements for demolition and disposition of public housing any public housing projects removed from a public housing agency (PHA) inventory under the program for conversion of demolished or distressed public housing dwelling units to tenant-based assistance.</p> <p>Excludes real property containing dwelling units in public housing from federal regulations of the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) or any substantially similar regulations, with respect to:</p> <ul> <li> certain real estate; and</li> <li> implementing HUD requirements for demolition or disposition of public housing projects, and conversion of public housing to tenant-based assistance.</li> </ul> <p> <i>Public Housing Preservation and Rehabilitation Act of 2015</i></p> <p>Reauthorizes for FY2016-FY2025 the public housing Capital and Operating Funds.</p> <p>Authorizes HUD to guarantee notes or other obligations issued by PHAs to finance: (1) the rehabilitation of PHA public housing; (2) the modernization of such housing through energy efficiency improvements; or (3) the construction, rehabilitation, purchase, or conversion of public housing units to replace any demolished, disposed of, or converted.</p> <p>Prescribes requirements for PHAs that utilize housing tax credits under the Internal Revenue Code for rental housing units.</p> <p>Removes a specified limitation on the use of amounts from the Capital Fund or Operation Fund by a PHA to construct new public housing units. </p> <p><i>Choice Neighborhoods Initiative Act of 2015</i></p> <p> Requires HUD to make competitive grants to local governments, PHAs, or nonprofit entities owning a major housing project to implement transformational programs in eligible neighborhoods with a concentration of extreme poverty and severely distressed housing.</p> <p><i>Together We Care Act of 2015</i></p> <p> Requires HUD to establish a competitive grant pilot program for eligible entities to train public housing residents as home health aides and as providers of home-based health services for residents of public housing or federally-assisted rental housing who are elderly, disabled, or both.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
