<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3888" measure-id="id114hr3888" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-11-03" update-date="2016-05-16">
<title>Blair Holt's Firearm Licensing and Record of Sale Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3888v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-05-16">
<action-date>2015-11-03</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Blair Holt's Firearm Licensing and Record of Sale Act of 2015</b></p> <p>This bill amends the federal criminal code to prohibit a person from possessing a firearm without a valid license. </p> <p>It prohibits transferring or receiving a handgun or a semiautomatic firearm that can accept a detachable ammunition feeding device unless the recipient presents a valid, verified firearms license and the dealer records a tracking authorization number. It prescribes firearms transfer reporting and record keeping requirements. DOJ must establish and maintain a federal record of sale system. <p>Additionally, it prohibits: (1) transferring a firearm to any person other than a licensee, unless the transfer is processed through a licensed dealer in accordance with national instant criminal background check system requirements, with exceptions; (2) a licensed manufacturer or dealer from failing to comply with reporting and record keeping requirements of this Act; (3) failing to report the loss or theft of the firearm to DOJ within 72 hours; (4) failing to report to DOJ an address change within 60 days; or (5) keeping a loaded firearm, or an unloaded firearm and ammunition for the firearm, knowingly or recklessly disregarding the risk that a child is capable of gaining access, if a child uses the firearm and causes death or serious bodily injury. <p>It prescribes criminal penalties for violations of firearms provisions. <p>DOJ must: (1) establish and maintain a firearm injury information clearinghouse, (2) conduct continuing studies and investigations of firearm-related deaths and injuries, (3) collect and maintain current production and sales figures of each licensed manufacturer, and (4) study the efficacy of smart gun technology (i.e., technology that prevents an unauthorized person from using a firearm) in the prevention of unintended deaths. <p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
