<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5099" measure-id="id114hr5099" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-04-28" update-date="2016-08-09">
<title>To establish a pilot program on partnership agreements to construct new facilities for the Department of Veterans Affairs.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5099v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-08-09">
<action-date>2016-04-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill authorizes the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to carry out a program under which it may enter into up to five partnership arrangements with a non-federal entity to conduct one or more: </p> <ul> <li>super construction projects (those for the construction, alteration, or acquisition of a medical facility involving a total expenditure of more than $100 million);</li> <li>major construction projects (those for the construction, alteration, or acquisition of a medical facility involving a total expenditure of more than $10 million, but not including an acquisition by exchange); or </li> <li>major construction projects to construct a new cemetery or to develop additional gravesites or columbarium niches at an existing cemetery. </li> </ul> <p>The selected projects may be ones for which: </p> <ul> <li>Congress has appropriated partial funding or the VA has identified a need for the project by listing it on the Major Construction Strategic Capital Investment Planning priority list, and </li> <li>a non-federal entity has entered or is willing to enter into a formal agreement with the VA to independently finance and/or donate acceptable project funds at no additional government cost. </li> </ul> <p>One of the non-federal entity partnership agreements shall be a project to design, finance, and construct a new ambulatory care center in Omaha, Nebraska. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
