<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2938" measure-id="id114hr2938" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-06-25" update-date="2015-08-27">
<title>National Design Services Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2938v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-08-27">
<action-date>2015-06-25</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>National Design Services Act of 2015</b></p> <p>Amends the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 to authorize the Department of Housing and Urban Development to establish a loan repayment program for eligible architects who provide certain design services on behalf of a Community Design Center (a non-profit organization operated and managed by a licensed architect that conducts research and provides design services for community development projects).</p> <p>Requires an eligible architect, in order to participate in the loan repayment program, to enter into a written contract with the Department that contains:</p> <ul> <li> an agreement under which: (1) the architect agrees to provide eligible design services on behalf of a Community Design Center for at least one year, and (2) the Department agrees to pay the principal and interest of the architect's qualifying educational loans for the period of time the architect provides such services;</li> <li>a provision that any U.S. financial obligation arising out of the contract, and any obligation of the architect, is contingent upon appropriations for the loan repayment program; and</li> <li>a statement of the damages to which the United States is entitled if the eligible architect breaches the contract.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
