<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5098" measure-id="id114hr5098" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-04-28" update-date="2016-05-25">
<title>FTC REPORTS Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5098v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-05-25">
<action-date>2016-04-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>FTC Robust Elderly Protections and Organizational Requirements to Track Scams Act or the FTC REPORTS Act</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Federal Trade Commission Act to require the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to publish and submit to Congress annually: (1) the FTC's plan for the next calendar year, and (2) a report on FTC enforcement actions involving allegations of fraud targeting individuals who are 65 or older during the previous year. </p> <p>The FTC's annual plan must describe:</p> <ul> <li> its projected activities, priorities, rulemakings, guidelines, restructuring plans, and projects;</li> <li>how its activities combat fraud against individuals who are 65 or older; and</li> <li>the projected dates and timelines for such activities. </li> </ul> <p>The FTC's annual report about enforcement actions involving allegations of fraud targeting individuals who are 65 or older during the previous year must include:</p> <ul> <li> a description of each FTC enforcement action involving allegations of fraud against such individuals;</li> <li>the disposition of such enforcement actions, broken down by category; and </li> <li>the proportion of enforcement actions involving allegations of fraud against such individuals as a percentage of all enforcement actions relating to unfair or deceptive acts or practices in or affecting commerce brought by the FTC.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
