<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3855" measure-id="id114hr3855" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-10-28" update-date="2015-12-10">
<title>Taxpayer Receipt Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3855v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-12-10">
<action-date>2015-10-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Taxpayer Receipt Act</strong> </p> <p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to require the Department of the Treasury to provide every taxpayer who files an individual income tax return for any taxable year an itemized tax receipt showing: (1) the proportionate allocation of the taxpayer's payment in such year among major expenditure categories of the federal budget (e.g., social security, national defense, Medicare and other federal health programs, low-income assistance programs, unemployment benefits, net interest on the federal debt, and other federal programs); and (2) the amount of the federal debt at the end of the fiscal year and the amount of additional borrowing by the federal government in such fiscal year for each legal U.S. resident.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
