<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5387" measure-id="id114hr5387" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-06-07" update-date="2016-09-28">
<title>Special Global Partnership with India Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5387v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-09-28">
<action-date>2016-06-07</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Special Global Partnership with India Act of 2016</strong></p> <p>This bill directs the President to take specified actions to advance the U.S.-India relationship, which shall include: (1) strategic, commercial, and defense dialogues; (2) development of advanced technology programs, including cyber security cooperation; and (3) enhanced scientific and military cooperation. </p> <p>The Department of Defense may enter into pilot programs to enhance India's capabilities in: (1) border, maritime, and aviation security; (2) explosives detection; (3) humanitarian and disaster management; and (4) counterterrorism.</p> <p>The President, with prior congressional notice, may make India temporarily eligible for certain defense services and articles under the Arms Export Control Act.</p> <p>The President shall make India eligible for the strategic trade authorization exemption from having to obtain certain export control licensees.</p> <p>The President may provide assistance to India to promote: (1) economic growth, (2) public health, (3) infrastructure development, (4) urban energy infrastructure, (5) military education and training, (6) educational exchanges, (7) joint development initiatives in third countries, and (8) banking access. </p> <p>The bill expresses the sense of Congress regarding: (1) India's entry into the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation regional economic forum, (2) U.S.-India negotiations to finalize a bilateral investment treaty, and (3) India's full implementation of the Civilian Nuclear Cooperation Initiative. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
