<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3617" measure-id="id114hr3617" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-09-25" update-date="2015-10-01">
<title>IMAGE Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3617v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-10-01">
<action-date>2015-09-25</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Improving All Government Efficiency Act of 2015 or the IMAGE Act of 2015 </strong></p> <p>This bill directs the Office of Management and Budget to coordinate with the heads of relevant federal departments or agencies to: (1) use available administrative authority to eliminate, consolidate, or streamline programs and agencies with duplicative and overlapping missions as identified in specified Government Accountability Office reports released between 2013 and 2015; (2) identify and report to Congress any legislative changes required to further eliminate, consolidate, or streamline duplicative or overlapping missions identified in such reports; (3) estimate the total cost savings from such activities; and (4) rescind from amounts made available to such departments and agencies the total estimated cost savings.</p> <p>The bill imposes a monetary penalty on any department or agency that does not meet the requirements of this Act before September 30, 2015.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
