<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2682" measure-id="id114hr2682" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-06-04" update-date="2015-06-09">
<title>Fighting for American Jobs Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2682v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-06-09">
<action-date>2015-06-04</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Fighting for American Jobs Act of 2015</b></p> <p> Directs each federal agency that provides contracts, grants, loans, or loan guarantees to businesses to require, as a condition of such assistance, that such businesses provide annually information on: </p> <ul> <li> the number of employees employed in the United States and its territories and possessions and the number employed outside the United States, as well as wage information on U.S. employees; and </li> <li> the percentage of the workforce that has been laid off or forced to resign during the preceding year. Prohibits, until the situation is corrected, subsequent federal assistance to businesses that lay off a greater percentage of workers in the United States and its territories and possessions than in other countries.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
