<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4596" measure-id="id114hr4596" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-02-24" update-date="2016-03-30">
<title>Small Business Broadband Deployment Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4596v81" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-03-30">
<action-date>2016-03-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the House on March 7, 2016. The summary of that version is repeated here.)</p> <p><b>Small Business Broadband Deployment Act</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill exempts for five years any small business broadband Internet access service provider with no more than 250,000 subscribers from the enhancements to the transparency rule of the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) under which any person engaged in the provision of broadband Internet access service must disclose publicly accurate information regarding the network management practices, performance, and commercial terms of its broadband Internet access services sufficient for:</p> <ul> <li>consumers to make informed choices regarding their use; and</li> <li>content, application, service, and device providers to develop, market, and maintain Internet offerings.</li> </ul> <p> The FCC shall report to specified congressional committees, within 180 days after enactment of this Act, its recommendations (together with supporting data) on whether:</p> <ul> <li>this exception should be made permanent, and</li> <li>the definition of &quot;small business&quot; for these purposes should be modified. </li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4596v17" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-03-09">
<action-date>2016-03-07</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Small Business Broadband Deployment Act</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill exempts for five years any small business broadband Internet access service provider with no more than 250,000 subscribers from the enhancements to the transparency rule of the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) under which any person engaged in the provision of broadband Internet access service must disclose publicly accurate information regarding the network management practices, performance, and commercial terms of its broadband Internet access services sufficient for:</p> <ul> <li>consumers to make informed choices regarding their use; and</li> <li>content, application, service, and device providers to develop, market, and maintain Internet offerings.</li> </ul> <p> The FCC shall report to specified congressional committees, within 180 days after enactment of this Act, its recommendations (together with supporting data) on whether:</p> <ul> <li>this exception should be made permanent, and</li> <li>the definition of &quot;small business&quot; for these purposes should be modified.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4596v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-03-01">
<action-date>2016-02-24</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Small Business Broadband Deployment Act</b></p> <p>This bill exempts small businesses from the enhancements to the transparency rule of the Federal Communications Commission under which any person engaged in the provision of broadband Internet access service must disclose publicly accurate information regarding the network management practices, performance, and commercial terms of its broadband Internet access services sufficient for:</p> <ul> <li>consumers to make informed choices regarding their use; and</li> <li>content, application, service, and device providers to develop, market, and maintain Internet offerings.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
