<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3921" measure-id="id114hr3921" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-11-04" update-date="2016-03-25">
<title>Hedge Fund Sunshine Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3921v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-03-25">
<action-date>2015-11-04</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Hedge Fund Sunshine Act of 2015</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to require that hedge funds send specified information to both the issuer of a security and each exchange where the security is rated within five (instead of 10) days of acquiring 1% (instead of 5%) of the beneficial ownership of an equity security, and also to file specified information required by the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC).</p> <p> For purposes of determining such beneficial ownership, a hedge fund shall include any equity security with respect to which it owns a derivative instrument that includes the opportunity to profit or share in any profit derived from an increase in the value of such equity security.</p> <p>In addition, a hedge fund must file a quarterly report with the SEC if it: (1) has $100 million or more in assets under management, and (2) is the beneficial owner of more than 1% of a class of any security.</p>  <p>The SEC shall make all reports received under this Act publicly available on its website.</p> </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
