<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4187" measure-id="id114hr4187" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-12-08" update-date="2016-01-12">
<title>Secure and Protect Americans' Data Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4187v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-01-12">
<action-date>2015-12-08</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Secure and Protect Americans' Data Act</b></p> <p>This bill requires the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to promulgate regulations requiring entities regulated by the FTC, common carriers, and nonprofit organizations to establish information security practices for the treatment and protection of personal information. </p> <p>At least annually, such entities must evaluate their consumer privacy programs to make any appropriate adjustments for changing technologies, threats or vulnerabilities, or business arrangements. </p> <p>The bill sets forth special procedures for information brokers to: (1) submit security policies to the FTC, (2) provide for post-breach audits, and (3) establish procedures for individuals to review and correct inaccuracies in their personal information. In lieu of procedures that allow individuals to dispute information, an information broker may provide individuals a means of expressing a preference not to have their information used for marketing purposes. </p> <p>The bill prohibits information brokers from obtaining or disclosing personal information by false pretenses.</p> <p>Within 10 days following discovery of a security breach, entities must notify:</p> <ul> <li>the FTC;</li> <li>the Federal Bureau of Investigation; </li> <li>the U.S. Secret Service; </li> <li>for common carriers, the Federal Communications Commission (FCC); and </li> <li> attorneys general of affected states. </ul> <p>Within 30 days following a breach, entities must notify individuals who are U.S. citizens or residents whose personal information was, or is reasonably believed to have been, acquired or accessed by an unauthorized person, or used for an unauthorized purpose.</p> <p>If an entity is required to notify more than 5,000 individuals, the entity must also notify major consumer reporting agencies. An entity must provide notices in print and broadcast media if the affected residents of a state exceed 5,000. </p> <p>Notices must include information on affected individuals' entitlement to consumer credit reports or credit monitoring services.</p> <p>The bill exempts entities from notification requirements if the data is unusable, unreadable, or indecipherable.</p> <p>Entities complying with other federal laws that require substantially similar information security procedures or breach notifications are deemed to be in compliance with the FTC's procedures or the notification requirements of this Act.</p> <p>Enforcement authority is provided to the FTC and states. States may obtain civil penalties for certain violations.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
