<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2009" measure-id="id114hr2009" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-04-23" update-date="2015-07-01">
<title>Pascua Yaqui Tribe Land Conveyance Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2009v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-07-01">
<action-date>2015-04-23</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Pascua Yaqui Tribe Land Conveyance Act of 2015</b> <p>Declares that, in the event that the Tuscon Unified School District No. 1 conveys to the United States all of its interest in and to approximately 39.65 acres of land depicted as Parcel A on the map titled &quot;PYT Land Department/2015/BLM Congressional Bill,&quot; that parcel shall be accepted by the United States and held in trust for the benefit of the Pascua Yaqui Tribe of Arizona as part of its reservation. <p>Requires that all interest of the United States in and to approximately 13.24 acres of federal lands generally depicted on the map as Parcel B be conveyed to the District by patent without reservation of rights by the United States. <p>Waives and gives up all U.S. reversionary interest in and to the approximately 27.50 acres of the land generally depicted on the map as Parcel C. Deems those lands to be held by the District free and clear of any U.S. claims. <p> <p>Prohibits gaming on the lands taken into trust pursuant to this Act. <p>Prohibits the forfeiture or abandonment of any water rights that are appurtenant to such lands.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
