<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1291" measure-id="id114hr1291" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-03-04" update-date="2015-04-30">
<title>Highway-Rail Grade Crossing Safety Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1291v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-04-30">
<action-date>2015-03-04</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Highway-Rail Grade Crossing Safety Act of 2015 </b></p> <p>This bill authorizes appropriations for FY2016-FY2019 for the highway safety improvement program, with $50 million set aside for each fiscal year for the Railway-Highway Crossings Program.</p> <p>The limitation to three states per year is eliminated, so all states now become eligible for the award of Highway-Rail Grade Crossing Safety improvement grants to develop or continue enhanced public education and awareness activities, in combination with targeted law enforcement, to reduce traffic law violations at highway-rail grade crossings, as well as to prevent and reduce injuries and fatalities along railroad rights-of-way. The limitation on grant amounts awarded to a state is increased from $250,000 to $2.5 million.</p>  <p>Eligibility requirements are revised for the award of capital grants to states under the rail line relocation and improvement program.</p> <p>Increased appropriations under the Rail Safety Improvement Act of 2008 are authorized for FY2016-FY2019 for the Federal Railroad Administration (FRA) to make grants to the Operation Lifesaver program. </p> <p>The FRA shall hire:</p> <ul> <li> 16 full-time grade crossing safety managers to work with state and local officials to identify safety improvements to highway-rail grade crossings; and </li> <li>8 trespass prevention managers to work with local governments, schools, businesses, and railroads to develop site-specific mitigation plans.</li> </ul>  <p>The Secretary of Transportation shall study the feasibility of requiring railroad carriers to provide additional means for the public to report problems at highway-rail grade crossings, including via the Internet and text messaging.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
