<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3857" measure-id="id114hr3857" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-10-29" update-date="2016-03-25">
<title>To require the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System and the Financial Stability Oversight Council to carry out certain requirements under the Financial Stability Act of 2010 before making any new determination under section 113 of such Act, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3857v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-03-25">
<action-date>2015-10-29</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill prohibits the Financial Stability Oversight Council from determining under the Financial Stability Act of 2010 that certain nonbank financial companies shall be supervised by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System and subject to prudential standards until 90 days after:</p> <ul> <li> the Board establishes prudential standards for nonbank financial companies,</li> <li> the Board promulgates criteria for exempting certain types or classes of U.S. or foreign nonbank financial companies from supervision, </li> <li>the Council reevaluates within calendar year 2016 each such determination and rescinds any of them if the nonbank financial company in question no longer meets specified standards, and</li> <li>the Council reports to certain congressional committees its reasons for not rescinding any determination.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
