<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3768" measure-id="id114hr3768" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-10-20" update-date="2015-12-28">
<title>SES TRUST Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3768v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-12-28">
<action-date>2015-10-20</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Senior Executive Service Taking Responsibility for Unilateral Station Transfers Act or the SES TRUST Act</strong></p> <p>This bill directs the appointing authority for each agency to periodically determine the annual rate of basic pay for each Senior Executive Service (SES) position within such agency. Any senior executive who transfers or otherwise moves to an SES position with the same or any other agency shall receive the rate of pay applicable to that position.</p> <p>The Office of Personnel Management (OPM) must review any decision to reassign a senior executive to another SES position, within 30 days after such reassignment, to ensure that the decision was not based on an impermissible reason (defined as any reason other than performance of the senior executive or interests in the efficiency of the SES). If OPM determines that the reassignment was based on an impermissible reason, and the rate of basic pay applicable to such other position is lower than the rate provided under the previous position, the senior executive shall retain the higher rate of pay.</p> <p>The bill requires the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to submit, semiannually, a report on covered senior executives who transfer from one SES position to another within the VA, including a justification for any increase or decrease in pay, and information on any incentives or relocation expenses, received by such person.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
