<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3654" measure-id="id114hr3654" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-09-30" update-date="2016-01-28">
<title>Combat Terrorist Use of Social Media Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3654v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-01-28">
<action-date>2015-12-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Combat Terrorist Use of Social Media Act of 2015</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill requires the President to transmit to Congress a report on U.S. strategy to combat terrorists' and terrorist organizations' use of social media. </p> <p>The report must include: </p> <ul> <li>an evaluation of the role social media plays in radicalization in the United States and elsewhere; </li> <li>an analysis of how terrorists and terrorist organizations are using social media; </li> <li>recommendations to improve the federal government's efforts to disrupt and counter the use of social media by terrorists and terrorist organizations;</li> <li>an analysis of how social media is being used for counter-radicalization and counter-propaganda purposes, irrespective of whether such efforts are made by the federal government;</li> <li>an assessment of the value to law enforcement of terrorists' social media posts; and</li> <li>an overview of training available to law enforcement and intelligence personnel to combat terrorists' use of social media and recommendations for improving or expanding existing training opportunities.</li> </ul> <p>(Sec. 3) The President must also transmit to Congress a comprehensive strategy to counter terrorists' and terrorist organizations' use of social media, as committed to in the President's 2011 Strategic Implementation Plan for Empowering Local Partners to Prevent Violent Extremism in the United States. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3654v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-11-16">
<action-date>2015-09-30</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Combat Terrorist Use of Social Media Act of 2015</b></p> <p>This bill requires the President to transmit to Congress a report on U.S. strategy to combat terrorists' and terrorist organizations' use of social media. The report must include: (1) an evaluation of the role social media plays in radicalization in the United States and elsewhere, (2) an analysis of how terrorists and terrorist organizations are using social media, (3) recommendations to improve the federal government's efforts to disrupt and counter the use of social media by terrorists and terrorist organizations, (4) a classified assessment of the intelligence value of terrorists' social media posts, and (5) a classified overview of training available to law enforcement and intelligence personnel to combat terrorists' use of social media and recommendations for improving or expanding existing training opportunities. </p> <p>The President must also transmit to Congress: (1) a policy that enhances the exchange of information and dialogue between the federal government and social media companies as it relates to the use of social media platforms by terrorists; and (2) a comprehensive strategy to counter terrorists' and terrorist organizations' use of social media, as committed to in the President's 2011 Strategic Implementation Plan for Empowering Local Partners to Prevent Violent Extremism in the United States. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
