<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5445" measure-id="id114hr5445" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-06-10" update-date="2016-10-12">
<title>Health Care Security Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5445v17" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-10-12">
<action-date>2016-06-17</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Health Care Security Act of 2016</b></p> <p> This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to modify the rules for health savings accounts (HSAs) with respect to catch-up contributions for married couples, medical expenses incurred before an HSA is established, and contribution limits. </p> <p>(Sec. 2) If both spouses of a married couple have family coverage under a high deductible health plan, each spouse may make catch-up contributions to the same HSA. (Catch-up contributions are additional contributions which individuals who are at least 55 years of age may make to an HSA.)</p> <p>(Sec. 3) If an HSA is established within 60 days of the beginning of coverage under a high deductible health plan, any distribution from the HSA used to pay a qualified medical expense incurred during that 60-day period after the health coverage began is excludible from gross income. (Under current law, the medical expense must be incurred on or after the date that the HSA is established.) </p> <p>(Sec. 4) The bill increases the maximum contribution limits for HSAs to equal the maximum for the sum of the annual deductible and out-of-pocket expenses that may be required to be paid for covered benefits under a high deductible health plan. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5445v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-10-12">
<action-date>2016-06-10</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to modify the rules for health savings accounts (HSAs) with respect to catch-up contributions for married couples, medical expenses incurred before an HSA is established, and contribution limits. </p> <p> If both spouses of a married couple have family coverage under a high deductible health plan, each spouse may make catch-up contributions to the same HSA. (Catch-up contributions are additional contributions which individuals who are at least 55 years of age may make to an HSA.)</p> <p> If an HSA is established within 60 days of the beginning of coverage under a high deductible health plan, any distribution from the HSA used to pay a qualified medical expense incurred during that 60-day period after the health coverage began is excludible from gross income. (Under current law, the medical expense must be incurred on or after the date that the HSA is established.) </p> <p>The bill increases the maximum contribution limits for HSAs to equal the maximum for the sum of the annual deductible and out-of-pocket expenses that may be required to be paid for covered benefits under a high deductible health plan. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
