<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2243" measure-id="id114hr2243" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-08" update-date="2015-12-01">
<title>Equity in Government Compensation Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2243v18" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-12-01">
<action-date>2015-11-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House amended, Part I</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Equity in Government Compensation Act of 2015 </b></p> <p>(Sec. 3) This bill requires the Director of the Federal Housing Finance Agency to: (1) suspend immediately the compensation packages approved for 2015 for the chief executive officers of the Federal National Mortgage Association (Fannie Mae) and the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation (Freddie Mac) (government-sponsored enterprises or GSEs); and (2) establish, in lieu of such packages, the compensation and benefits for each such officer at the same level in effect as of January 1, 2015. </p> <p>Such compensation and benefits may not thereafter be increased.</p> <p>This requirement may not be construed to affect the applicability to the chief executive officer of each GSE of the prohibition against receiving bonuses during any period of conservatorship on or after April 4, 2012.</p> <p>(Sec. 4) Any executive officer affected by this Act shall not be considered a federal employee.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2243v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-06-15">
<action-date>2015-05-08</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Equity in Government Compensation Act of 2015 </b></p> <p> Requires the Director of the Federal Housing Finance Agency to: (1) suspend immediately the compensation packages approved for 2015 for the executive officers of the Federal National Mortgage Association (Fannie Mae) and the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation (Freddie Mac) (government-sponsored enterprises or GSEs); and (2) establish, in lieu of such packages, a compensation system for such officers in accordance with the rates of pay for positions in the Executive Schedule and the Senior Executive Service of the federal government.</p> <p>Establishes requirements for determining compensation rates for GSE employees according to the General Schedule for federal civil service employees.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
