<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5316" measure-id="id114hr5316" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-05-24" update-date="2016-06-06">
<title>Healthy Soils and Rangelands Solutions Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5316v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-06-06">
<action-date>2016-05-24</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Healthy Soils and Rangelands Solutions Act</b></p> <p>This bill directs the Department of the Interior, through the Bureau of Land Management, to establish a Carbon Sequestration Pilot Program to make grants to owners or operators of qualified public lands, universities, nongovernmental organizations, or Indian tribes for projects for sequestering carbon through:</p> <ul> <li>grazing practices,</li> <li>restoring degraded qualified public lands,</li> <li>application of compost on qualified public lands, or</li> <li>using biochar (carbonized biomass) as an amendment on qualified public lands. </li> </ul> <p>Interior shall establish a science advisory board to furnish analysis and recommendations regarding: </p> <ul> <li> the selection of such eligible entities and activities to receive grants based on the best available science, and </li> <li>appropriate monitoring requirements to quantify project performance and communicate results. </li> </ul> <p>Interior shall make grants, through a challenge competition, to eligible entities for projects to carry out innovative approaches to eligible activities. </p> <p>Interior: </p> <ul> <li>may furnish technical assistance for eligible activities, and </li> <li>shall expand outreach and education respecting carbon sequestration and best practices related to those activities. </li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
