<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4843" measure-id="id114hr4843" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-03-23" update-date="2016-05-23">
<title>Infant Plan of Safe Care Improvement Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4843v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-05-23">
<action-date>2016-05-11</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Infant Plan of Safe Care Improvement Act </b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Child Abuse Prevention and Treatment Act to require the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), through the national clearinghouse for information relating to child abuse, to maintain and disseminate information about the requirements and best practices relating to the development of plans of safe care for infants born affected by illegal substance abuse, withdrawal symptoms, or a Fetal Alcohol Spectrum Disorder.</p> <p>(Sec. 3) A state plan submitted to HHS for a grant to improve its child protective services system must certify that it has a state law or statewide program relating to child abuse and neglect that includes a plan of safe care for such an infant to ensure its safety and well-being following release from the care of healthcare providers. </p> <p>The state plan of safe care shall: (1) address the health and substance use disorder treatment needs of the infant and affected family or caregiver; and (2) specify the development and implementation by the state of monitoring systems regarding the implementation of such plans to determine whether and in what manner local entities are providing, in accordance with state requirements, referrals to and delivery of appropriate services for the infant and affected family or caregiver.</p> <p>(Sec. 4) Annual state data reports shall include the total number of such infants for whom a plan of safe care was developed, and for whom referrals are made for appropriate services, including services for the affected family or caregiver.</p> <p>(Sec. 5) HHS shall monitor the compliance of each grant-receiving state with applicable current law requirements, including required state policies and procedures regarding care of such infants.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4843v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-04-28">
<action-date>2016-03-23</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Improving Safe Care for the Prevention of Infant Abuse and Neglect Act </b></p> <p>This bill amends the Child Abuse Prevention and Treatment Act to require the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), through the national clearinghouse for information relating to child abuse, to maintain and disseminate information about the best practices relating to the development of plans of safe care for infants born affected by illegal substance abuse, withdrawal symptoms, or a Fetal Alcohol Spectrum Disorder.</p> <p>A state plan submitted to HHS for a grant to improve its child protective services system must certify that it has a state law or statewide program relating to child abuse and neglect that includes a plan of safe care for such an infant to ensure its safety and well-being following release from the care of healthcare providers.</p> <p>Annual state data reports shall include the total number of such infants for whom a plan of safe care was developed, and for whom referrals are made for appropriate services, including services for the affected family or caregiver.</p> <p>HHS shall monitor the compliance of each grant-receiving state with applicable current law requirements, including required state policies and procedures regarding care of such infants.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
