<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5663" measure-id="id114hr5663" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-07-07" update-date="2016-11-02">
<title>Four C's for Careers Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5663v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-11-02">
<action-date>2016-07-07</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Critical Thinking, Collaboration, Communication, and Creativity for Careers Act or the Four C's for Careers Act</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 to revise requirements for the local use of funds received by eligible recipients under the Act to support their career and technical education programs. </p> <p>The bill requires such funds to be used by eligible recipients to support career and technical education programs that:</p> <ul> <li>train career guidance and academic counselors to use labor market information in assisting students with postsecondary education and career planning; and </li> <li>support public-private partnerships designed to provide students with the credentials and skills required to secure employment in relevant fields; and </li> <li>if determined appropriate by the local educational agency, support programs that coordinate and integrate academic and career and technical education content and specified work-based learning opportunities.</li> </ul> <p>Funds may be used to assess resources required for promoting greater engagement and coordination with business and industry.</p> <p>An eligible agency, with input from eligible recipients, may identify in its state plan, the acquisition of critical thinking, collaboration, communication, and creativity skills as additional indicators of performance for the career and technical education activities authorized under the Act. </p> <p>State plans shall describe how eligible agencies will improve the critical thinking, communications, collaboration, and creativity skills of the students participating in their career and technical education programs.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
