<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3638" measure-id="id114hr3638" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-09-29" update-date="2015-11-16">
<title>Family Telephone Connection Protection Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3638v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-11-16">
<action-date>2015-09-29</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Family Telephone Connection Protection Act of 2015</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Communications Act of 1934 to direct the Federal Communications Commission to adopt regulations on the use of inmate telephone and video services that enable persons incarcerated in correctional institutions to originate calls at payphones, telephones, or video kiosks designated for the personal use of prisoners.</p> <p>The regulations must: (1) prescribe a maximum uniform per-minute rate and service connection or other per-call rate, (2) prescribe variable maximum rates depending on factors such as carrier costs and the size of the correctional facility, (3) require providers of inmate telephone and video service to offer both collect calling and prepaid debit account services, (4) prohibit or limit the payment of commissions by such providers to administrators of correctional facilities based upon the revenue of the service, (5) require such administrators to allow more than one service provider at a facility so that prisoners have a choice, and (6) prohibit or substantially limit any ancillary fees that are in addition to the per-minute rate and connection charge. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
