<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1563" measure-id="id114hr1563" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-03-24" update-date="2015-04-27">
<title>Federal Employee Tax Accountability Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1563v28" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-04-27">
<action-date>2015-04-14</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House without amendment, Part I</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p><strong>Federal Employee Tax Accountability Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) Makes any individual who has a seriously delinquent tax debt ineligible for federal employment or to continue serving as a federal employee. Defines "seriously delinquent tax debt" as a&nbsp; federal tax liability assessed by the Internal Revenue Service and collectible by levy or court proceeding, except a tax debt: (1) that is being paid in a timely manner under an approved installment payment agreement or an offer-in-compromise, (2) for which a collection due process hearing has been requested or pending, (3) for which a continuous levy has been issued or agreed to by an applicant for employment, or (4) with respect to which such a levy is released because it has been determined to be an economic hardship to the taxpayer. </p> <p>Requires each federal agency to: (1) ensure that applicants for employment certify that they do not have a seriously delinquent tax debt, (2) review public records to determine if a notice of lien has been filed against an employee or applicant, and (3) restrict access to and use of information obtained under this Act.</p> <p>Authorizes an agency, if a tax lien against a federal employee or applicant for federal employment is discovered in a public record, to: (1) request such employee or applicant to execute and submit a form authorizing the Department of the Treasury to disclose to an agency head information describing whether the employee or applicant has a seriously delinquent tax debt, has willfully failed to file a required tax return, or has understated tax liability, and (2) request that Treasury disclose information authorized to be disclosed. </p> <p>Authorizes the head of an agency to take personnel actions against an agency employee who willfully failed to file a required tax return or willfully understated federal tax liability. </p> <p>Requires the Office of Personnel Management to: (1) promulgate regulations to carry out this Act that provide federal employees and applicants for employment with all due process rights and that allow, in a situation involving financial hardship, an employee with a seriously delinquent tax debt to continue employment; and (2) report to Congress annually on the number of exemptions granted for financial hardship. Grants federal employees or applicants for federal employment 180 days to demonstrate that their tax debts are exempt from classification as a seriously delinquent tax debt under this Act. </p> <p>(Sec. 3) Makes this Act effective nine months after its enactment date.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1563v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-04-14">
<action-date>2015-03-24</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Federal Employee Tax Accountability Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>Makes any individual who has a seriously delinquent tax debt ineligible for federal employment or to continue serving as a federal employee. Defines "seriously delinquent tax debt" as a&nbsp; federal tax liability assessed by the Internal Revenue Service and collectible by levy or court proceeding, except a tax debt: (1) that is being paid in a timely manner under an approved installment payment agreement or an offer-in-compromise, (2) for which a collection due process hearing has been requested or pending, (3) for which a continuous levy has been issued or agreed to by an applicant for employment, or (4) with respect to which such a levy is released because it has been determined to be an economic hardship to the taxpayer. </p> <p>Requires each federal agency to: (1) ensure that applicants for employment certify that they do not have a seriously delinquent tax debt, (2) review public records to determine if a notice of lien has been filed against an employee or applicant, and (3) restrict access to and use of information obtained under this Act.</p> <p>Authorizes an agency, if a tax lien against a federal employee or applicant for federal employment is discovered in a public record, to: (1) request such employee or applicant to execute and submit a form authorizing the Department of the Treasury to disclose to an agency head information describing whether the employee or applicant has a seriously delinquent tax debt, has willfully failed to file a required tax return, or has understated tax liability, and (2) request that Treasury disclose information authorized to be disclosed. </p> <p>Authorizes the head of an agency to take personnel actions against an agency employee who willfully failed to file a required tax return or willfully understated federal tax liability. </p> <p>Requires the Office of Personnel Management to: (1) promulgate regulations to carry out this Act that provide federal employees and applicants for employment with all due process rights and that allow, in a situation involving financial hardship, an employee with a seriously delinquent tax debt to continue employment; and (2) report to Congress annually on the number of exemptions granted for financial hardship. Grants federal employees or applicants for federal employment 180 days to demonstrate that their tax debts are exempt from classification as a seriously delinquent tax debt under this Act. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
