<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5367" measure-id="id114hr5367" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-05-26" update-date="2016-06-06">
<title>Seniors' Security Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5367v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-06-06">
<action-date>2016-05-26</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Seniors Security Act of 2016</b></p> <p> This bill amends title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) (OASDI) of the Social Security Act (SSAct) to require the computation of cost-of-living adjustments to use the Consumer Price Index for Elderly Consumers (CPI-E).</p> <p>The Bureau of Labor Statistics of the Department of Labor shall prepare and publish the CPI-E for each calendar month.</p> <p> The CPI-E shall also be used for cost-of-living adjustments for federal civilian employee annuities and for the retired and retainer pay of members of the armed forces.</p> <p> SSAct title XVIII (Medicare) is amended to prohibit any increases in Medicare part B premiums for calendar years beginning with 2017 to the extent they would exceed 30% of the difference between the amount of benefits payable to an individual for that December and the amount of benefits payable for that November (both amounts determined before the deduction of a premium). This change shall allow premium increases of up to 30% of that difference.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
