<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4790" measure-id="id114hr4790" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-03-17" update-date="2016-04-04">
<title>Recreation Not Red-Tape Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4790v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-04-04">
<action-date>2016-03-17</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Recreation Not Red-Tape Act</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Federal Lands Recreation Enhancement Act to require the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) and the Forest Service to adopt a consistent and uniform special recreation permitting process with respect to outfitters and guides. </p> <p>The Department of the Interior and the Department of Agriculture (USDA) shall sell National Parks and Federal Recreational Lands Passes entrance and recreation fees through federal websites. </p> <p>Interior and USDA should:</p> <ul> <li>work with the Department of Defense and the Department of Veterans Affairs to ensure that veterans have access to outdoor programs, and</li> <li>increase programs focused on improving education about and access to outdoor recreation opportunities on public lands for individuals age 55 or older. </li> </ul> <p>Interior and USDA shall make available, free of charge, a certain quantity of America the Beautiful passes for use by specified schools or their students and their families. </p> <p>Interior and USDA shall study the overall impact that recreation on federal recreational land and water has on the U.S. economy and labor market. </p> <p>The Forest Service, BLM, and National Park Service may develop respective management plans for extending the recreation season or increasing recreation use during the offseason. </p> <p>The Forest Service and BLM shall include metrics on recreation use in specified evaluations of lands under their jurisdictions. </p> <p>The Army Corps of Engineers, the Bureau of Reclamation, and the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission shall consider how land and water management decisions can enhance recreation opportunities and the recreation economy. </p> <p>The bill amends the Omnibus Parks and Public Lands Management Act of 1996 to prescribe requirements for deposit, administration, and distribution of revenues collected from rental charges for certain ski area permits issued on National Forest System lands.</p>   <p>The bill establishes: (1) a National Recreation Area System, (2) a private sector volunteer enhancement program, and (3) a priority trail maintenance program. </p> <p>Interior and USDA shall establish an interagency trail management plan under which federal land management agencies shall coordinate so that trails that cross jurisdictional boundaries between those agencies are uniformly managed and maintained.</p> <p>The Public Lands Corps Act of 1993 is amended to conform to this Act.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
