<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5251" measure-id="id114hr5251" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-05-16" update-date="2016-05-20">
<title>Healthy Homes Tax Credit Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5251v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-05-20">
<action-date>2016-05-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Healthy Homes Tax Credit Act </strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow new tax credits for 50% of: (1) lead hazard reduction activity costs, (2) radon hazard reduction activity costs, and (3) asbestos hazard reduction activity costs. These costs must be incurred with respect to an eligible dwelling and the credit for such costs is generally limited to $5,000 for any eligible dwelling in any taxable year, reduced by costs taken into account in previous taxable years. </p> <p>The bill defines an "eligible dwelling" generally as a dwelling unit that is: (1) placed in service before 1950; (2) located in the United States; and (3) a house, apartment, condominium, mobile home, boat, or similar property, but not a unit used exclusively as a hotel, motel, inn, or similar establishment. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
