<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4291" measure-id="id114hr4291" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-12-18" update-date="2016-01-07">
<title>SAFER Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4291v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-01-07">
<action-date>2015-12-18</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Secure Accountability for Emigres and Refugees Act of 2015 or the SAFER Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>This bill requires that, before the U.S. refugee admission of a covered alien, the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) shall ensure that such person: </p> <ul> <li>has passed a lie detector test; </li> <li>has submitted to DHS biometric identification information, including DNA, which DHS has compared against all relevant databases and determined that the person has no known history of terrorist activity; and </li> <li>does not pose a threat to U.S. national security based on a background check that includes a review of the person's Internet interactions, including social media services. </li> </ul> <p>&quot;Covered alien&quot; means an alien applying for U.S. refugee admission who: (1) is a national of Iraq or Syria, (2) has no nationality and whose last habitual residence was in Iraq or Syria, or (3) has been present in Iraq or Syria at any time on or after March 1, 2011.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
