<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5111" measure-id="id114hr5111" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-04-28" update-date="2016-10-04">
<title>Consumer Review Fairness Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5111v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-10-04">
<action-date>2016-09-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the House on September 9, 2016. The summary of that version is repeated here.)</p> <p><b>Consumer Review Fairness Act of 2016</b></p> (Sec. 2) This bill makes a provision of a form contract void from the inception if it: (1) prohibits or restricts an individual who is a party to such a contract from engaging in written, oral, or pictorial reviews, or other similar performance assessments or analyses of, including by electronic means, the goods, services, or conduct of a person that is also a party to the contract; (2) imposes penalties or fees against individuals who engage in such communications; or (3) transfers or requires the individual to transfer intellectual property rights in review or feedback content (with the exception of a nonexclusive license to use the content) in any otherwise lawful communications about such person or the goods or services provided by such person. <p>A &quot;form contract&quot; is a contract with standardized terms: (1) used by a person in the course of selling or leasing the person's goods or services, and (2) imposed on an individual without a meaningful opportunity to negotiate the standardized terms. The definition excludes an employer-employee or independent contractor contract.</p> <p>The standards under which provisions of a form contract are considered void under this bill shall not be construed to affect:</p> <ul> <li>legal duties of confidentiality;</li> <li>civil actions for defamation, libel, or slander; or</li> <li>a party's right to establish terms and conditions for the creation of photographs or video of such party's property when those photographs or video are created by an employee or independent contractor of a commercial entity and are solely intended to be used for commercial purposes by that entity.</li> </ul> <p>Such standards also shall not be construed to affect any party's right to remove or refuse to display publicly on an Internet website or webpage owned, operated, or controlled by such party content that: (1) contains the personal information or likeness of another person or is libelous, harassing, abusive, obscene, vulgar, sexually explicit, inappropriate with respect to race, gender, sexuality, ethnicity, or other intrinsic characteristic; (2) is unrelated to the goods or services offered by or available at such party's website; or (3) is clearly false or misleading.</p> <p>A provision shall not be considered void under this bill to the extent that it prohibits disclosure or submission of, or reserves the right of a person or business that hosts online consumer reviews or comments to remove, certain: (1) trade secrets or commercial or financial information; (2) personnel and medical files; (3) law enforcement records; (4) content that is unlawful or that a party has a right to remove or refuse to display; or (5) computer viruses or other potentially damaging computer code, processes, applications, or files.</p> <p>A person is prohibited from offering form contracts containing a provision that is considered void under this bill. </p> <p>Enforcement authority is provided to the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) and states.</p> <p>The FTC must provide businesses with nonbinding best practices for compliance.</p> <p>Nothing in this bill shall be construed to limit, impair, or supersede the Federal Trade Commission Act or any other federal law.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5111v17" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-10-04">
<action-date>2016-09-09</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Consumer Review Fairness Act of 2016</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill makes a provision of a form contract void from the inception if it: (1) prohibits or restricts an individual who is a party to such a contract from engaging in written, oral, or pictorial reviews, or other similar performance assessments or analyses of, including by electronic means, the goods, services, or conduct of a person that is also a party to the contract; (2) imposes penalties or fees against individuals who engage in such communications; or (3) transfers or requires the individual to transfer intellectual property rights in review or feedback content (with the exception of a nonexclusive license to use the content) in any otherwise lawful communications about such person or the goods or services provided by such person. </p> <p>A &quot;form contract&quot; is a contract with standardized terms: (1) used by a person in the course of selling or leasing the person's goods or services, and (2) imposed on an individual without a meaningful opportunity to negotiate the standardized terms. The definition excludes an employer-employee or independent contractor contract.</p> <p>The standards under which provisions of a form contract are considered void under this bill shall not be construed to affect:</p> <ul> <li>legal duties of confidentiality;</li> <li>civil actions for defamation, libel, or slander; or</li> <li>a party's right to establish terms and conditions for the creation of photographs or video of such party's property when those photographs or video are created by an employee or independent contractor of a commercial entity and are solely intended to be used for commercial purposes by that entity.</li> </ul> <p>Such standards also shall not be construed to affect any party's right to remove or refuse to display publicly on an Internet website or webpage owned, operated, or controlled by such party content that: (1) contains the personal information or likeness of another person or is libelous, harassing, abusive, obscene, vulgar, sexually explicit, inappropriate with respect to race, gender, sexuality, ethnicity, or other intrinsic characteristic; (2) is unrelated to the goods or services offered by or available at such party's website; or (3) is clearly false or misleading.</p> <p>A provision shall not be considered void under this bill to the extent that it prohibits disclosure or submission of, or reserves the right of a person or business that hosts online consumer reviews or comments to remove, certain: (1) trade secrets or commercial or financial information; (2) personnel and medical files; (3) law enforcement records; (4) content that is unlawful or that a party has a right to remove or refuse to display; or (5) computer viruses or other potentially damaging computer code, processes, applications, or files.</p> <p>A person is prohibited from offering form contracts containing a provision that is considered void under this bill. </p> <p>Enforcement authority is provided to the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) and states.</p> <p>The FTC must provide businesses with nonbinding best practices for compliance.</p> <p>Nothing in this bill shall be construed to limit, impair, or supersede the Federal Trade Commission Act or any other federal law.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5111v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-06-07">
<action-date>2016-04-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Consumer Review Fairness Act of 2016</b> </p> <p>This bill makes a provision of a form contract void from the inception if it is used in the course of selling or leasing goods or services to: (1) prohibit or restrict an individual who is a party to such a contract from engaging in written, oral, or pictorial reviews, or other similar performance assessments or analyses of, including by electronic means, the goods, services, or conduct of a person that is also a party to the contract; (2) impose penalties or fees against individuals who engage in such communications; or (3) transfer or require the individual to transfer intellectual property rights in review or feedback content (with the exception of a nonexclusive license to use the content) in any otherwise lawful communications about such person or the goods or services provided by such person. </p> <p>The bill does not apply to an employer-employee or independent contractor contract.</p> <p>The standards under which provisions of a form contract are considered void under this bill shall not be construed to affect:</p> <ul> <li>legal duties of confidentiality;</li> <li>civil actions for defamation, libel, or slander; or</li> <li>a party's right to establish terms and conditions for the creation of photographs or video of such party's property when those photographs or video are created by an employee or independent contractor of a commercial entity and are solely intended to be used for commercial purposes by that entity.</li> </ul> <p>Such standards also shall not be construed to affect any party's right to remove or refuse to display on its Internet website content that: (1) contains the personal information or likeness of another person or is libelous, harassing, abusive, obscene, vulgar, sexually explicit, inappropriate with respect to race, gender, sexuality, ethnicity, or other intrinsic characteristic; (2) is unrelated to the goods or services offered by or available at such party's website; or (3) is clearly false or misleading.</p> <p>A provision shall not be considered void under this bill to the extent that it prohibits disclosure or submission of, or reserves the right of a person or business that hosts online consumer reviews or comments to remove, certain: (1) trade secrets or commercial or financial information; (2) personnel and medical files; (3) law enforcement records; (4) content that is unlawful or that a party has a right to remove or refuse to display; or (5) computer viruses or other potentially damaging computer code, processes, applications, or files.</p> <p>A person is prohibited from offering form contracts containing a provision that is considered void under this bill. </p> <p>Enforcement authority is provided to the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) and states. The FTC must provide businesses with nonbinding best practices for compliance. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
