<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1887" measure-id="id114hr1887" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-04-16" update-date="2016-06-03">
<title>To authorize the Comptroller General of the United States to assess a study on the alternatives for the disposition of Plum Island Animal Disease Center, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1887v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-06-03">
<action-date>2016-05-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(Sec. 2) This bill requires the Government Accountability Office (GAO) to assess the Department of Homeland Security's (DHS's) study of the options for the disposition of Plum Island, New York. (In 2005, DHS announced that the operations of the Plum Island Animal Disease Center will move from Plum Island, New York, to a new federal facility in Manhattan, Kansas.) </p> <p>The GAO must determine whether DHS's methodologies adequately support its findings with respect to: </p> <ul> <li>the possible alternative uses for Plum Island, including the transfer to another federal agency, a state or local government, a nonprofit organization, or a combination of the entities for the purpose of education, research, or conservation; </li> <li> the issues and implications of the alternative uses; and </li> <li> the cost for the transition, cleanup, and hazard mitigation by a recipient of the property. </li> </ul> <p>If the DHS methodologies do not adequately support its findings related to an issue, the GAO must report to Congress on the issue.</p> <p>(Sec. 3) The bill suspends until at least 180 days after the GAO submits its reports to Congress the requirement under current law for the General Services Administration to sell the property and assets which support Plum Island operations. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1887v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-08-17">
<action-date>2015-04-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill amends the Consolidated Security, Disaster Assistance, and Continuing Appropriations Act, 2009 and the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2012 to repeal provisions providing for the sale of federal property and assets supporting the Department of Homeland Security's Plum Island Animal Disease Center in New York. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
