<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5871" measure-id="id114hr5871" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-07-14" update-date="2016-08-25">
<title>Spearfish Canyon and Bismarck Lake Land Exchange Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5871v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-08-25">
<action-date>2016-07-14</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Spearfish Canyon and Bismarck Lake Land Exchange Act</b></p> <p>This bill directs the Department of Agriculture (USDA), if South Dakota conveys to it four parcels of specified nonfederal lands, comprising 1,954 acres, to convey to South Dakota in exchange 1,468 acres known as the &quot;Spearfish Canyon Area&quot; and 524 acres known as the &quot;Bismarck Lake Area&quot; in the Black Hills National Forest in South Dakota. </p>  <p>The values of the federal and nonfederal lands to be exchanged shall be equal.</p> <p>USDA shall complete any environmental analyses required under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 regarding the land exchange carried out under this bill. </p> <p>The nonfederal lands acquired by USDA shall be added to and administered as part of the forest.</p> <p>The federal lands acquired by South Dakota shall be managed by it for public recreation uses and the conservation of natural resources. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
