<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1829" measure-id="id114hr1829" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-04-15" update-date="2015-07-08">
<title>DHS Communication Enhancement Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1829v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-07-08">
<action-date>2015-04-15</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>DHS Communication Enhancement Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>Directs the Department of Homeland Security to: (1) assess the ability of each of its components to convey information to, collect information from, and serve individuals with limited English proficiency; and (2) report a plan to improve such ability.</p> <p>Requires such assessment to:</p> <ul> <li>identify the languages spoken fluently and read by individuals with limited English proficiency commonly encountered by personnel of the component, </li> <li>assess the extent to which the public materials of the component are available in such languages, and </li> <li>assess the ability of personnel of the component to communicate with and serve individuals with limited English proficiency. </li></ul> <ul></ul> <ul></ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
