<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4348" measure-id="id114hr4348" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-01-07" update-date="2016-05-02">
<title>DC Personal Protection Reciprocity Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4348v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-05-02">
<action-date>2016-01-07</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>DC Personal Protection Reciprocity Act</b></p> <p>This bill declares that the prohibitions of the District of Columbia Official Code against carrying a pistol within the District either openly or concealed without a license under D.C. law shall not apply to an individual who is:</p> <ul> <li>not prohibited by federal law from possessing, transporting, shipping, or receiving a firearm; </li> <li>carrying a valid license or permit for a concealed firearm issued under the law of a state; and </li> <li>carrying a valid identification document containing the individual's photograph.</li> </ul> <p>The Metropolitan Police Department, upon application by a person with a bona fide residence or place of business within the United States and a license to carry a concealed pistol under the law of any state or local government, shall issue that person a license to carry a concealed pistol within the District for up to two years from its date of issue, regardless of the applicant's reason for applying for the license. </p> <p>The bill repeals the condition on the permission for a non-D.C. resident who lives in a state that does not require a license to carry a concealed pistol to apply to the Metropolitan Police Department for a license to carry one within the District for up to two years. The condition repealed states that the non-resident may apply for a license to carry a concealed weapon only if the non-resident meets the same reasons and requirements a person must meet who has a bona fide residence or place of business in the District.</p> <p>The Metropolitan Police Department shall enter into reciprocity agreements with each other state that requires such an agreement in order to grant recognition to a license to carry a concealed firearm issued by that state. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
