<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="797" measure-id="id114hr797" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-02-05" update-date="2015-04-09">
<title>Disaster Assistance Recoupment Fairness Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr797v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-04-09">
<action-date>2015-02-05</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Disaster Assistance Recoupment Fairness Act of 2015</b></p> <p>Authorizes the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to waive a debt owed to the United States related to federal assistance provided under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to individuals and households in relation to a major disaster declared by the President on or after January 1, 2011, if such assistance was distributed based on an error by FEMA, there was no fault on behalf of the debtor, and the collection of the debt would be against equity and good conscience, unless the debt that involves fraud, the presentation of a false claim, or misrepresentation by the debtor or any party having an interest in the claim.</p> <p>Requires FEMA, in determining whether to waive such a debt, to presume that the debtor should be required to make at least a partial payment if the adjusted gross income of the debtor's household for the last taxable year exceeds $100,000.</p> <p>Directs the Inspector General of the Department of Homeland Security: (1) to report, every six months, on the cost-effectiveness of FEMA's efforts to recoup improper payments of such assistance; (2) to monitor the distribution of such assistance to determine the amount distributed based on a FEMA error; and (3) upon determining that such amount exceeds 4% of the total amount distributed, to notify FEMA and publish the determination in the Federal Register. Cancels FEMA's authority to waive debt with respect to any major disaster declared by the President after the date of such a determination.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
