<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5658" measure-id="id114hr5658" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-07-07" update-date="2016-08-01">
<title>TALENT Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5658v81" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-08-01">
<action-date>2016-07-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p><strong>Tested Ability to Leverage Exceptional National Talent Act of 2016 or the TALENT Act of 2016</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill codifies provisions establishing the Presidential Innovation Fellows Program (originally established pursuant to Executive Order 13704) to encourage successful entrepreneurs, executives, and innovators to join the government and work in close cooperation with government leaders to create meaningful solutions that can help save lives and taxpayer money, fuel job creation, and significantly improve how the government serves the American people.</p> <p>The General Services Administration (GSA) shall continue the program in order to enable exceptional individuals with proven track records to serve time-limited appointments in executive agencies to address some of the nation's most significant challenges and improve existing government efforts that would particularly benefit from expertise using innovative techniques and technology. </p> <p>The program shall be administered by a Director, who shall appoint program fellows and facilitate their placement to participate in projects that have the potential for significant positive effects and that are consistent with the President's goals. </p> <p>The GSA shall continue an advisory board to recommend priorities and standards for fulfilling the program's mission and to assist in identifying potential projects and placements for fellows. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5658v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-07-14">
<action-date>2016-07-07</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Tested Ability to Leverage Exceptional National Talent Act of 2016 or the TALENT Act of 2016</strong></p> <p>This bill codifies provisions establishing the Presidential Innovation Fellows Program (originally established pursuant to Executive Order 13704) to encourage successful entrepreneurs, executives, and innovators to join the government and work in close cooperation with government leaders to create meaningful solutions that can help save lives and taxpayer money, fuel job creation, and significantly improve how the government serves the American people.</p> <p>The General Services Administration (GSA) shall continue the program in order to enable exceptional individuals with proven track records to serve time-limited appointments in executive agencies to address some of the nation's most significant challenges and improve existing government efforts that would particularly benefit from expertise using innovative techniques and technology. </p> <p>The program shall be administered by a Director, who shall appoint program fellows and facilitate their placement to participate in projects that have the potential for significant positive effects and that are consistent with the President's goals. </p> <p>The GSA shall continue an advisory board to recommend priorities and standards for fulfilling the program's mission and to assist in identifying potential projects and placements for fellows. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
