<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="6021" measure-id="id114hr6021" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-09-14" update-date="2016-10-14">
<title>Jobs, On-the-Job `Earn While You Learn' Training, and Apprenticeships for African-American Young Men Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr6021v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-10-14">
<action-date>2016-09-14</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Jobs, On-the-Job "Earn While You Learn" Training, and Apprenticeships for African-American Young Men Act</b></p> <p>This bill requires the Department of Labor to request labor unions, general contractors, and businesses that will rebuild infrastructure, transportation systems, technology and computer networks, and energy distribution systems to actively recruit, hire, and provide on-the-job training to African American men ages 18 to 39 through existing jobs, apprenticeships, and "earn while you learn" programs. Labor must help coordinate such recruitment. </p> <p>The jobs, training, and apprenticeships must be conducted in conjunction with Labor, labor unions and associations involved in infrastructure rebuilding, and the National Joint Apprenticeship and Training Committee.</p> <p>Labor unions, contractors, and businesses involved with such infrastructure or systems must recruit by seeking assistance from the African American community, churches, the National Urban League, the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, 100 Black Men of America, high school and college job placement offices, and media outlets.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
