<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2795" measure-id="id114hr2795" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-06-16" update-date="2016-01-08">
<title>First Responder Identification of Emergency Needs in Disaster Situations</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2795v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-01-08">
<action-date>2015-12-10</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the House on December 7, 2015. The summary of that version is repeated here.)</p> <p><strong>First Responder Identification of Emergency Needs in Disaster Situations or the FRIENDS Act</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill directs the Government Accountability Office (GAO) to submit a report that describes select state and local programs and policies related to the preparedness and protection of first responders, which may include information on:</p> <ul> <li>the degree to which such programs and policies include consideration of the presence of a first responder's family in an area impacted by a terrorist attack,</li> <li>the availability of personal protective equipment for first responders, and </li> <li>the availability of home Medkits for first responders and their families for biological incident response.</li> </ul> <p>The GAO may provide information: (1) in a format that delineates high risk urban areas from rural communities; and (2) on the degree to which the selected state and local programs and policies were developed or are being executed with funding from the Department of Homeland Security (DHS), including grants from the State Homeland Security Grant Program or the Urban Area Security Initiative.</p> <p>DHS shall consider the report's findings and assess its applicability for federal first responders.</p> <ul> <ul> </ul> </ul> <ul> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2795v17" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-01-08">
<action-date>2015-12-07</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>First Responder Identification of Emergency Needs in Disaster Situations or the FRIENDS Act</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill directs the Government Accountability Office (GAO) to submit a report that describes select state and local programs and policies related to the preparedness and protection of first responders, which may include information on:</p> <ul> <li>the degree to which such programs and policies include consideration of the presence of a first responder's family in an area impacted by a terrorist attack,</li> <li>the availability of personal protective equipment for first responders, and </li> <li>the availability of home Medkits for first responders and their families for biological incident response.</li> </ul> <p>The GAO may provide information: (1) in a format that delineates high risk urban areas from rural communities; and (2) on the degree to which the selected state and local programs and policies were developed or are being executed with funding from the Department of Homeland Security (DHS), including grants from the State Homeland Security Grant Program or the Urban Area Security Initiative.</p> <p>DHS shall consider the report's findings and assess its applicability for federal first responders.</p> <ul> <ul> </ul> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2795v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-08-06">
<action-date>2015-06-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>First Responder Identification of Emergency Needs in Disaster Situations or the FRIENDS Act</strong></p> <p>Directs the Department of Homeland Security to submit a report on factors that would result in first responders failing to meet expectations based upon training and planning for terrorist incidents, which: (1) may include information on first responder performance and availability before, during, or after a terrorist threat or event; and (2) shall include first responder input on how the presence of family in the impacted area, the adequacy of personal protective equipment, and training gaps may influence performance and availability.</p> <ul> <ul> </ul> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
