<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2506" measure-id="id114hr2506" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-21" update-date="2015-08-14">
<title>Seniors' Health Care Plan Protection Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2506v18" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-08-14">
<action-date>2015-06-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House amended, Part I</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Seniors' Health Care Plan Protection Act of 2015</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) States the intent of Congress to: (1) continue to study and request input on the effects of socioeconomic status and dual-eligible populations on the Medicare Advantage (MA) STARS rating system before reforming it, and, pending study and input results; (2) delay Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services authority to terminate MA plan contracts solely on the basis of performance under the STARS rating system.</p> <p>Amends part C (Medicare+Choice) of title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to prohibit the Department of Health and Human Services, through the end of plan year 2018, from terminating a contract with respect to the offering of an MA plan by a MA organization solely because the plan has failed to achieve a minimum quality rating under the 5-star rating system.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2506v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-08-14">
<action-date>2015-05-21</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Seniors' Health Care Plan Protection Act of 2015</b></p> <p>States the intent of Congress to: (1) continue to study and request input on the effects of socioeconomic status and dual-eligible populations on the Medicare Advantage (MA) STARS rating system before reforming it, and, pending study and input results, (2) delay Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services authority to terminate MA plan contracts solely on the basis of performance under the STARS rating system.</p> <p>Amends part C (Medicare+Choice) of title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to prohibit the Department of Health and Human Services, through the end of plan year 2018, from terminating a contract with respect to the offering of an MA plan by an MA organization solely because the plan has failed to achieve a minimum quality rating under the 5-star rating system.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
