<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2621" measure-id="id114hr2621" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-06-02" update-date="2015-09-22">
<title>China Human Rights Protection Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2621v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-09-22">
<action-date>2015-06-02</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>China Human Rights Protection Act of 2015</strong></p> <p> Directs the President to impose U.S. entry and property sanctions against a national of China who: </p> <ul> <li>is responsible for gross violations of internationally recognized human rights committed against individuals in China, particularly those who seek to exercise, defend, or promote internationally recognized human rights and freedoms; </li> <li>acted as an agent of or on behalf of a national of China in such activities; or</li> <li> has materially assisted or provided financial, material, or technological support for, or goods or services in support of, such activities.</li> </ul> <p>Authorizes the President, with regard to such sanctions, to: </p> <ul> <li>waive their application, with prior congressional notification, if in U.S. national security interests; and </li> <li>terminate them under specified conditions. </li> </ul> <p>States that sanctions shall not apply if necessary to comply with the Agreement between the United Nations (U.N.) and the United States regarding the U.N. Headquarters, or other applicable international obligations of the United States. </p> <p> Declares that the Secretary of State shall seek to provide for the establishment of, and provide funding for, a nongovernmental China Human Rights Documentation Center to: </p> <ul> <li>compile, publish, and archive evidence of nationals of China who commit gross violations of internationally recognized human rights against individuals in China, and against others seeking to expand freedoms in China; and </li> <li>establish an online and searchable database, in English and in Chinese of evidence of such violations for research and educational purposes.</li> </ul> <p>Directs the President to report to Congress annually regarding each foreign person sanctioned, the type of sanctions imposed, and the reason for their imposition.</p> <p> Directs the Government Accountability Office to assess for Congress: </p> <ul> <li> the process to determine whether a foreign person has engaged in a sanctionable activity, whether sanctions should be imposed, and whether the identity of a sanctioned foreign person should be classified; and </li> <li> implementation of this Act.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
