<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1119" measure-id="id114hr1119" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-02-26" update-date="2015-08-11">
<title>Research and Development Efficiency Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1119v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-08-11">
<action-date>2015-05-19</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Research and Development Efficiency Act</b> </p> <p> Requires the Office of Science and Technology Policy (OSTP) to establish a working group under the authority of the National Science and Technology Council, to include the Office of Management and Budget, to be responsible for reviewing federal regulations affecting research and research universities and making recommendations on how to: (1) harmonize, streamline, and eliminate duplicative federal regulations and reporting requirements; (2) minimize the regulatory burden on U.S. institutions of higher education performing federally funded research while maintaining accountability for federal tax dollars; and (3) identify and update specific regulations to refocus on performance-based goals rather than on process while still meeting the desired outcome. </p> <p>Instructs the working group to take into account input and recommendations from non-federal stakeholders, including researchers, institutions of higher education, industry, and others with a stake in ensuring effectiveness, efficiency, and accountability in the performance of scientific research. </p> <p>Requires OSTP to report to Congress annually on the steps taken to carry out the working group's recommendations. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1119v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-03-20">
<action-date>2015-02-26</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Research and Development Efficiency Act</b></p> <p> Requires the Director of Science and Technology Policy (OSTP) to establish a working group under the authority of the National Science and Technology Council that includes the Office of Management and Budget (OMB). </p> <p>Makes the working group responsible for reviewing federal regulations affecting research and research universities and making recommendations on how to: (1) harmonize, streamline, and eliminate duplicative federal regulations and reporting requirements; and (2) minimize the regulatory burden on U.S. institutions of higher education performing federally funded research while maintaining accountability for federal tax dollars.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
