<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2577" measure-id="id114hr2577" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-27" update-date="2016-10-19">
<title>Military  Construction,  Veterans  Affairs,  and  Related  Agencies  Appropriations  Act,  2017  and  Zika  Response and Preparedness Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2577v48" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-10-19">
<action-date>2016-06-22</action-date>
<action-desc>Conference report filed in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Highlights: </b></p> <p>This bill provides FY2017 appropriations for Military Construction, Veterans Affairs, and Related Agencies and provides FY2016 supplemental appropriations to respond to the Zika virus.</p> <p>The bill includes four divisions: </p> <ul> <li> the Military Construction, Veterans Affairs, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2017; </li> <li> the Zika Response and Preparedness Appropriations Act, 2016; </li> <li> the Zika Vector Control Act; and </li> <li> Rescissions of Funds. </ul> <p><i>Military Construction, Veterans Affairs, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2017 </i></p> <p>This division provides FY2017 appropriations to the Department of Defense (DOD) for military construction, military family housing, the U.S. share of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization Security Investment Program, and base closures and realignments. </p> <p>The division also provides appropriations to the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) for veterans benefit and health care programs, Departmental Administration, and the National Cemetery Administration. </p> <p>Related agencies and programs funded in the division include the U.S. Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims; the Armed Forces Retirement Home; and the Cemeterial Expenses of the Army, including Arlington National Cemetery. </p> <p>The division includes both mandatory and discretionary funding. It increases FY2017 discretionary funding for Military Construction and Veterans Affairs above FY2016 levels, including an increase for the VA and a decrease for Military Construction. </p> <p>The division includes provisions that: </p> <ul> <li>permit the VA to pay for fertility treatments, counseling, and adoption expenses for veterans with certain service-connected disabilities; </li> <li> establish additional procedures and protections for VA whistle-blowers; </li> <li> and prohibit funds from being used for: (1) constructing, renovating, or expanding a facility for the purpose of housing individuals detained at U.S. Naval Station at Guantanamo Bay, Cuba; and (2) closing or transferring the facility. </li> </ul> <p><i>Zika Response and Preparedness Appropriations Act, 2016 </i></p> <p>This division provides FY2016 supplemental appropriations to the Departments of Health and Human Services (HHS) and State to respond to the Zika virus. </p> <p>The division permits the funds to be used for the duration of FY2017, designates the funds as emergency requirements, and sets forth congressional reporting and notification requirements. </p> <p><i>Zika Vector Control Act </i></p> This division waives for 180 days certain permit requirements under the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (commonly known as the Clean Water Act) for pesticides being used to control mosquitos for the prevention and control of the Zika virus. <p><i>Rescissions Of Funds </i></p> <p>This division rescinds specified unobligated balances of funds that were provided for the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act, the Department of Health and Human Services, and the response to the Ebola virus. </p><p><b>Full Summary:</b></p> <p> <b>Military Construction, Veterans Affairs, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2017, and Zika Response and Preparedness Act </b></p> <p>(Sec. 3) Specifies that references to &quot;this Act&quot; included in any division refer only to the provisions of the division unless the bill expressly provides otherwise. </p> <p>(Sec. 4) Specifies that the sums in this bill are appropriated out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated for FY2017. </p> <p>(Sec. 5) Specifies that each amount in this bill designated by Congress as an emergency requirement is contingent on the President also designating all of the emergency amounts and transmitting the designations to Congress. </p> <p> <i>Military Construction, Veterans Affairs, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2017 </i></p> <p>DIVISION A--MILITARY CONSTRUCTION, VETERANS AFFAIRS, AND RELATED AGENCIES APPROPRIATIONS ACT, 2017 </p> <p>TITLE I--DEPARTMENT OF DEFENSE </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Department of Defense (DOD) for Military Construction for: </p> <ul> <li> the Army; </li> <li> the Navy and Marine Corps; </li> <li> the Air Force; </li> <li> Defense-Wide agencies and activities (other than military departments); </li> <li> the Army and Air National Guard; and </li> <li> the Army, Navy, and Air Force Reserves. </li> </ul> <p>Provides appropriations to DOD for the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) Security Investment Program. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to DOD for Construction and Operation and Maintenance of Family Housing for: </p> <ul> <li> the Army, </li> <li> the Navy and Marine Corps, </li> <li> the Air Force, and </li> <li> Defense-Wide agencies and activities (other than military departments). </li> </ul> <p>Provides appropriations for the Department of Defense Family Housing Improvement Fund. </p> <p>Provides appropriations for the Department of Defense Base Closure Account. </p> <p>(Sec. 101) Prohibits funds provided by this title from being used for payments exceeding $25,000 for construction in the United States under a cost-plus-a-fixed-fee contract without DOD approval. Includes an exception for work that is to be performed in Alaska. </p> <p>(Sec. 102) Permits construction funds provided by this title to be used for hiring passenger motor vehicles. </p> <p>(Sec. 103) Permits construction funds provided by this title to be used for advances to the Federal Highway Administration for the construction of access roads DOD has certified as important to national defense. </p> <p>(Sec. 104) Prohibits funds provided by this title from being used to begin construction of new bases in the United States without a specific appropriation. </p> <p>(Sec. 105) Prohibits funds provided by this title from being used to purchase land or land easements in excess of 100% of the value as determined by the Army Corps of Engineers or the Naval Facilities Engineering Command. Includes exceptions for: (1) determinations of value by a federal court, (2) purchases negotiated by the Attorney General or a designee, (3) values less than $25,000, and (4) DOD determinations that the purchase is in the public interest. </p> <p>(Sec. 106) Prohibits funds provided by this title from being used to acquire land, provide for site preparation, or install utilities for family housing, except housing for which appropriations have been provided. </p> <p>(Sec. 107) Prohibits funds provided by this title for minor construction from being used to transfer or relocate any activity from one base or installation to another without notifying Congress in advance. </p> <p>(Sec. 108) Prohibits funds provided by this title from being used to procure steel for construction unless American producers, fabricators, and manufacturers have been allowed to compete for the procurement. </p> <p>(Sec. 109) Prohibits funds provided to DOD for military construction or family housing during the current fiscal year from being used to pay real property taxes in any foreign nation. </p> <p>(Sec. 110) Prohibits funds provided by this title from being used to initiate a new installation overseas without notifying Congress in advance. </p> <p>(Sec. 111) Prohibits funds provided by this title from being used for architect and engineer contracts estimated to exceed $500,000 for projects in Japan, NATO member countries, or countries bordering the Arabian Gulf unless the contracts are awarded to U.S. firms or joint ventures with U.S. firms. </p> <p>(Sec. 112) Prohibits funds provided by this title for military construction in U.S. territories and possessions in the Pacific and on Kwajalein Atoll, or in countries bordering the Arabian Gulf from being used to award a contract over $1 million to a foreign contractor. Includes exceptions. </p> <p>(Sec. 113) Requires DOD to notify Congress in advance of military exercises if construction costs are expected to exceed $100,000. </p> <p>(Sec. 114) Permits funds appropriated to DOD for construction in prior years to be used for construction projects authorized during the current session of Congress. </p> <p>(Sec. 115) Permits expired or lapsed funds to be used to pay for supervision, inspection, overhead, engineering, and design costs for military construction or family housing projects being completed with lapsed or expired funds. </p> <p>(Sec. 116) Permits funds provided for the construction of military projects to be available for five years if: (1) the funds are obligated from funds available for military construction, and (2) do not exceed the amount appropriated or permitted by law. </p> <p>(Sec. 117) Permits the following transfers if Congress is notified and specified conditions are met: </p> <ul> <li> to the Department of Defense Family Housing Improvement Fund from appropriations for construction in Family Housing accounts, and </li> <li>to the Department of Defense Military Unaccompanied Housing Improvement Fund from appropriations for construction of military unaccompanied housing in Military Construction accounts. </li> </ul> <p>(Sec. 118) Permits the transfer of funds from the Department of Defense Base Closure Account to the fund established to pay expenses associated with the Homeowners Assistance Program under the Demonstration Cities and Metropolitan Development Act of 1966. </p> <p>(Sec. 119) Provides that funds for operation and maintenance of family housing in this title shall be the only source of funds for repair and maintenance of all family housing units, including general or flag officer quarters. Sets forth limitations and requirements for expenditures for maintenance and repair of general or flag officer quarters. </p> <p>(Sec. 120) Appropriates funds contained in the Ford Island Improvement Account to remain available until expended or transferred. </p> <p>(Sec. 121) Permits the transfer of unobligated balances of expired military construction and family housing funds into the Foreign Currency Fluctuations--Construction--Defense account. </p> <p>(Sec. 122) Prohibits the Army from using funds provided by this division to relocate a unit that: (1) performs a required testing mission or function not performed by any other unit, and (2) is located at a military installation where the total number of Army civilian employees and contractor personnel exceeds 10% of the regular and reserve Army personnel. Includes an exception if the Army notifies Congress of the relocation's compliance with Army Regulation 5-10 concerning stationing actions. </p> <p>(Sec. 123) Permits funds provided to an account in this title to be transferred among projects and activities within the account subject to specified DOD reprogramming guidelines for military and family housing construction. </p> <p>(Sec. 124) Prohibits DOD military construction funds provided in this title from being used for the planning, design, and construction of projects at Arlington National Cemetery. </p> <p>(Sec. 125) Provides specified additional funds to remain available through FY2021 for unfunded military construction priorities. </p> <p>(Sec. 126) Provides specified additional funds to the Navy and Marine Corps to remain available through FY2021 for unfunded military construction priorities. </p> <p>(Sec. 127) Rescinds specified unobligated balances from Military Construction accounts and the North Atlantic Treaty Organization Security Investment Program. </p> <p>(Sec. 128) Rescinds specified unobligated balances from the fund established by the Demonstration Cities and Metropolitan Development Act of 1966 for expenses associated with the Homeowners Assistance Program. </p> <p>(Sec. 129) Defines &quot;congressional defense committees&quot; to include the House and Senate Armed Services Committees and Appropriations Subcommittees on Military Construction and Veterans Affairs. </p> <p>(Sec. 130) Prohibits funds provided by this division from being used for the closure or realignment of the U.S. Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba. </p> <p>(Sec. 131) Prohibits funds from being used to consolidate or relocate any element of a U.S. Air Force Rapid Engineer Deployable Heavy Operational Repair Squadron Engineer (RED HORSE) squadron outside of the United States until the Air Force: (1) submits to Congress an analysis and comparison of the cost and investment required to consolidate or relocate a RED HORSE squadron outside of the United States versus within the United States, and (2) certifies to Congress that the preferred site yields the greatest savings. </p> <p>TITLE II--DEPARTMENT OF VETERANS AFFAIRS </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Veterans Benefits Administration (VBA) for: </p> <ul> <li> Compensation and Pensions, </li> <li> Readjustment Benefits, </li> <li> Veterans Insurance and Indemnities, </li> <li> the Veterans Housing Benefit Program Fund, </li> <li> the Vocational Rehabilitation Loans Program Account, </li> <li> the Native American Veteran Housing Loan Program Account, and </li> <li> General Operating Expenses. </li> </ul> <p>Provides appropriations to the Veterans Health Administration (VHA) for: </p> <ul> <li> Medical Services, </li> <li> Medical Community Care, </li> <li> Medical Support and Compliance, </li> <li> Medical Facilities, and </li> <li> Medical and Prosthetic Research. </li> </ul> <p>Provides appropriations to the National Cemetery Administration.</p> <p> Provides appropriations to the VA for Departmental Administration, including: </p> <ul> <li>General Administration, </li> <li> the Board of Veterans Appeals, </li> <li> Information Technology Systems, </li> <li> the Office of Inspector General, </li> <li>Construction--Major Projects, </li> <li> Construction--Minor Projects, </li> <li> Grants for Construction of State Extended Care Facilities, and </li> <li> Grants for Construction of Veterans Cemeteries. </li> </ul> <p>Prohibits the expenditure of specified information technology funds for the Veterans Health Information Systems and Technology Architecture (VistA) Evolution Program until the VA submits to Congress reports including specified details regarding the status, costs, and plans for the program. </p> <p>Withholds specified VHA construction funds until the VA: </p> <ul> <li> enters an agreement with a non-VA federal entity to serve as the design and/ or construction agent for any VHA major construction project that exceeds $100 million, and </li> <li>certifies that an agreement is executed to minimize or prevent subsequent major construction project cost overruns. </li> </ul> <p>(Sec. 201) Specifies transfer authorities and requirements for the VBA. </p> <p>(Sec. 202) Specifies transfer authorities and requirements for the VHA. </p> <p>(Sec. 203) Permits appropriations for salaries and expenses to be used for employment of temporary or intermittent experts and consultants, hire of passenger vehicles, lease of a facility or land, and uniforms. </p> <p>(Sec. 204) Prohibits appropriations in this title other than Construction--Major Projects and Construction--Minor Projects from being used for land acquisition or construction of any new hospital or home. </p> <p>(Sec. 205) Requires the VA to be reimbursed for medical services it provides to any person not defined as a beneficiary under specified laws. </p> <p>(Sec. 206) Permits appropriations provided by this title for Compensation and Pensions, Readjustment Benefits, and Veterans Insurance and Indemnities to be used for payment of accrued obligations for the accounts recorded in the last quarter of FY2016. </p> <p>(Sec. 207) Permits appropriations provided by this title to be used to pay specified prior year obligations. Requires obligations from trust fund accounts to be paid only from the Compensation and Pensions account. </p> <p>(Sec. 208) Requires the VA to use surplus earnings from the National Service Life Insurance Fund, the Veterans' Special Life Insurance Fund, and the United States Government Life Insurance Fund to reimburse the General Operating Expenses--Veterans Benefits Administration and Information Technology Systems accounts for the costs to administer the insurance programs during FY2017.</p> <p> (Sec. 209) Permits amounts deducted from enhanced-use lease proceeds for reimbursement of expenses from a prior year to be obligated in the year in which the proceeds are received. </p> <p>(Sec. 210) Permits funds provided by this title for salaries and other administrative expenses to be used to reimburse the Office of Resolution Management and the Office of Employment Discrimination Complaint Adjudication within specified limits. </p> <p>(Sec. 211) Requires the VA to collect third-party reimbursement information prior to providing hospital care, nursing home care, or medical services for a non-service connected disability. Permits the VA to recover reasonable charges for care from anyone who has not provided the required disclosures. </p> <p>(Sec. 212) Permits enhanced-use leasing revenues to be deposited into the Construction--Major Projects and Construction--Minor Projects accounts to be used for construction, alterations, and improvements of VA medical facilities. </p> <p>(Sec. 213) Permits funds provided for Medical Services to be used for: (1) furnishing recreational facilities, supplies, and equipment; and (2) funeral and burial expenses. </p> <p>(Sec. 214) Permits funds deposited in the Medical Care Collections Fund to be transferred to the Medical Services and Medical Community Care accounts and remain available until expended for the purposes of those accounts. </p> <p>(Sec. 215) Permits the VA to enter into agreements with Federally Qualified Health Centers in Alaska and certain Indian tribes and tribal organizations to provide healthcare, including behavioral health and dental care, to veterans in rural Alaska. Defines &quot;rural Alaska&quot; as those lands which are not within the boundaries of the municipality of Anchorage or the Fairbanks North Star Borough. </p> <p>(Sec. 216) Permits funds deposited into the Department of Veterans Affairs Capital Asset Fund to be transferred to the Construction--Major Projects and Construction--Minor Projects accounts to remain available until expended. </p> <p> (Sec. 217) Rescinds specified funds from the Medical Services account to enable the establishment of the Medical Community Care account. </p> <p>(Sec. 218) Requires the VA to report quarterly to Congress on the financial status of the VA. </p> <p>(Sec. 219) Permits specified FY2017 VA funds to be transferred to or from the Information Technology Systems account if approved by Congress. </p> <p>(Sec. 220) Prohibits funds from being used to: (1) convert to contractor performance an activity or function performed by more than 10 federal employees unless the conversion is based on the result of a public-private competition that meets specified criteria, or (2) conduct studies comparing the costs of private and government provision of certain VHA products and services without a specific appropriation for that purpose. </p> <p>(Sec. 221) Permits specified FY2017 VA funds provided for medical accounts, Construction--Minor Projects, and Information Technology Systems to be transferred to the Joint Department of Defense-Department of Veterans Affairs Medical Facility Demonstration Fund and used for the operation of combined federal medical facilities. </p> <p>(Sec. 222) Permits specified FY2018 VA advance funding provided for medical accounts to be transferred to the Joint Department of Defense-Department of Veterans Affairs Medical Facility Demonstration Fund and used for the operation of combined federal medical facilities. </p> <p>(Sec. 223) Permits transfers from the Medical Care Collections Fund to the Joint Department of Defense-Department of Veterans Affairs Medical Facility Demonstration Fund for the operation of combined federal medical facilities. </p> <p>(Sec. 224) Requires specified funds from the Medical Services, Medical Support and Compliance, and Medical Facilities accounts to be transferred to the DOD-VA Health Care Sharing Incentive Fund to remain available until expended. </p> <p>(Sec. 225) Prohibits the VA from using funds to replace the current system that the Veterans Integrated Service Networks use to select and contract for diabetes monitoring supplies and equipment. </p> <p>(Sec. 226) Directs the VA to notify Congress of all bid savings in major construction projects that total at least $5 million or 5% of the programmed amount of the project, whichever is less. </p> <p>(Sec. 227) Prohibits the scope of work for a project included in Construction--Major Projects from being increased above the original budget request without congressional approval. </p> <p>(Sec. 228) Requires the VA to submit to Congress a quarterly report containing performance measures and data from each VBA regional office. </p> <p>(Sec. 229) Limits funds from the Medical Support and Compliance account that may be used for the Veterans Health Information Systems and Technology Architecture (VistA) Evolution and electronic health record interoperability projects. Permits additional funds to be obligated for this purpose if Congress is notified in advance. </p> <p>(Sec. 230) Directs the VA to notify Congress before organizational changes that result in the transfer of 25 or more full-time equivalent staff from one organizational unit to another. </p> <p>(Sec. 231) Requires the VA to report to Congress quarterly regarding any single national outreach and awareness campaign exceeding $2 million. </p> <p>(Sec. 232) Permits the VA to transfer funds to the Medical Services account if the transfer is necessary to address the needs of the VHA, meets specified requirements, and is approved by the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) and Congress. </p> <p>(Sec. 233) Permits FY2017 funds provided for the Board of Veterans Appeals and General Operating Expenses--Veterans Benefits Administration to be transferred between those accounts if Congress approves the transfer. </p> <p>(Sec. 234) Prohibits the VA from reprogramming more than $5 million in funds among major construction projects or programs without congressional approval. </p> <p>(Sec. 235) Rescinds specified unobligated balances from the DOD-VA Health Care Sharing Incentive Fund. </p> <p>(Sec. 236) Rescinds specified unobligated balances from the VA Medical Services, Medical Support and Compliance, and Medical Facilities accounts. </p> <p>(Sec. 237) Rescinds specified unobligated balances of funds provided to the VA. </p> <p>(Sec. 238) Requires the VA to ensure that the toll-free suicide hotline authorized under current law: (1) provides individuals who contact the hotline with immediate assistance from a trained professional, and (2) adheres to all requirements of the American Association of Suicidology. </p> <p>(Sec. 239) Requires the VA to treat a marriage and family therapist as qualified to serve in the VA if the therapist meets specified educational and licensing requirements. </p> <p>(Sec. 240) Prohibits funds from being used to close or diminish services at certain VA medical facilities until the VA submits to Congress a national realignment strategy. </p> <p>(Sec. 241) Prohibits the VA from transferring funds from the Filipino Veterans Equity Compensation Fund to any other VA account. </p> <p>(Sec. 242) Amends the Veterans' Mental Health and Other Care Improvements Act of 2008 to extend through FY2017 the pilot program to provide health care services to veterans in rural areas by contracting with non-VA health care providers </p> <p>(Sec. 243) Eliminates copayments for: (1) opioid antagonists that are provided to a veteran who is at high risk for overdose of a specific medication or substance in order to reverse the effect of an overdose, and (2) education on the use of opioid antagonists to reverse the effects of overdoses of a specific medication or substance. </p> <p>(Sec. 244) Specifies requirements for the Office of Inspector General to provide the VA, Congress, and other entities with access to its reports. </p> <p>(Sec. 245) Provides specified funds from the Medical Services account to carry out and expand to each VA medical center the pilot program for providing child care assistance to veterans receiving health care. </p> <p>(Sec. 246) Requires the VA to disclose to a state controlled substance monitoring program information about a veteran or a dependent that is necessary to prevent misuse and diversion of prescription medicine. </p> <p>(Sec. 247) Establishes additional procedures for filing whistle-blower complaints at the VA and for protecting whistle-blowers from retaliation. </p> <p>Permits VA employees to file complaints with immediate and next-level supervisors, and ultimately with the VA after having properly filed a complaint at each supervisory level. </p> <p>Provides that, if a supervisor makes a positive determination regarding a complaint, the VA must: (1) inform the employee of the ability to volunteer for a transfer, and (2) give preference to the transfer. </p> <p>Requires the central VA whistle-blower office to investigate all complaints, regardless of whether the complaints are made by or against an employee who is not a Senior Executive Service member. </p> <p>Requires the VA to: (1) carry out specified adverse actions against supervisors that retaliate by committing prohibited personnel actions relating to a complaint, and (2) provide employees with annual training regarding whistle-blower complaints. </p> <p>(Sec. 248) Specifies documentation that DOD may accept to verify that a coastwise merchant seaman performed active duty service under honorable conditions. Permits the individuals whose service is recognized as honorable to be: (1) awarded an appropriate medal, ribbon, or other military decoration based on the service; and (2) honored as a veteran with benefits limited to those described in this provision. </p> <p>(Sec. 249) Permits the VA to provide a monthly assistance allowance to certain disabled veterans competing on U.S. Olympic teams. </p> <p>(Sec. 250) Adds coverage under the VA beneficiary travel program for the travel expenses of a veteran with vision impairment, a spinal cord injury or disorder, or double or multiple amputations whose travel is in connection with care provided through a special disabilities rehabilitation program of the VA if the care is provided on an in-patient basis and during a period in which the VA provides the veteran with temporary lodging at a VA facility to make the care more accessible. </p> <p>Requires the VA to report to Congress on beneficiary travel program, including the cost and the number of veterans served by the program. </p> <p>(Sec. 251) Requires the VA to establish a program to conduct inspections of kitchens and food service areas at each VA medical facility. Specifies that: (1) the inspections must occur at least annually, and (2) the program's goal is to ensure that the same standards for kitchens and food service areas at hospitals in the private sector are being met at VA medical facilities. Specifies requirements for an agreement for conducting the inspections, remediation plans, and reports to Congress.</p> <p>(Sec. 252) Requires the VA to establish a program to conduct risk-based inspections for mold and mold issues at each VA medical facility. Specifies requirements for an agreement for conducting the inspections, the frequency of inspections, remediation plans, and reports to Congress.</p> <p> (Sec. 253) Extends a requirement for the VA to report to Congress on its capacity to provide for specialized treatment and rehabilitative needs of disabled veterans. </p> <p>(Sec. 254) Permits the VA to use funds provided by this title to ensure that the ratio of veterans to full-time employment equivalents within any rehabilitation program does not exceed 125 veterans to one full-time employment equivalent. </p> <p>Requires the VA to report to Congress on rehabilitation programs including: (1) an assessment of the veteran-to-staff ratio for each program, and (2) recommendations to reduce the veteran-to-staff ratio for each program. </p> <p>(Sec. 255) Requires departments and agencies funded by this division to provide an Inspector General (IG) funded by this division with timely access to records, documents, or other materials available to the department or agency over which the IG has responsibility. Requires each IG to comply with specified statutory limitations on disclosure of the information provided. </p> <p>(Sec. 256) Prohibits the VA from using funds provided by this title to enter into an agreement related to resolving a dispute or claim with an individual that would restrict the individual from speaking to members of Congress or their staff on any topic not otherwise prohibited from disclosure by federal law or required by Executive Order to be kept secret in the interest of national defense or the conduct of foreign affairs. </p> <p>(Sec. 257) Requires specified funds provided by this division for Medical Services to be used for: (1) adaptive sports programs for disabled veterans and members of the Armed Forces; and (2) payment of a monthly assistance allowance to a disabled veteran invited by the U.S. Olympic Committee to compete for a slot on, or selected for, the Paralympic Team. </p> <p>(Sec. 258) Specifies details that must be included in the budget justification documents submitted for the Construction--Major Projects account. </p> <p>(Sec. 259) Authorizes appropriations for the VA to carry out specified major medical facility projects. </p> <p>(Sec. 260) Permits VA Medical Services funds to be used to provide: (1) fertility counseling and treatment using assisted reproductive technology to a covered veteran or the spouse of a covered veteran, or (2) adoption reimbursement to a covered veteran. Defines a &quot;covered veteran&quot; as a veteran who has a service-connected disability that results in the inability of the veteran to procreate without the use of fertility treatment. </p> <p>TITLE III--RELATED AGENCIES</p> <p> Provides appropriations for related agencies, including: </p> <ul> <li> the American Battle Monuments Commission; </li> <li> the U.S. Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims; </li> <li> Cemeterial Expenses of the Army, including Arlington National Cemetery and Soldiers' and Airmen's Home National Cemetery; and </li> <li> the Armed Forces Retirement Home. </li> </ul> <p>(Sec. 301) Permits funds for Cemeterial Expenses--Army to be provided to Arlington County, Virginia to relocate a federally owned water main at Arlington National Cemetery to make additional land available for ground burials. </p> <p>(Sec. 302) Permits funds from concessions at Army National Military Cemeteries to be used to support activities at the cemeteries. </p> <p>TITLE IV--OVERSEAS CONTINGENCY OPERATIONS </p> <p>Provide appropriations to DOD for Overseas Contingency Operations Military Construction projects for the: </p> <ul> <li> Army, </li> <li> Navy and Marine Corps, </li> <li> Air Force, and </li> <li> Defense-Wide agencies and activities </li> </ul> <p>Designates the amounts provided in this title as for Overseas Contingency Operations/ Global War on Terrorism pursuant to the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985. </p> <p>(Sec. 401) Specifies that funds designated by in this division by the Congress for Overseas Contingency Operations/Global War on Terrorism are only available if the President subsequently designates the amounts and transmits the designations to the Congress. </p> <p>TITLE V--GENERAL PROVISIONS </p> <p>(Sec. 501) Prohibits the obligation of funds in this division beyond the current fiscal year unless expressly permitted in this division. </p> <p>(Sec. 502) Prohibits the use of funds provided by this division for programs, projects, or activities not in compliance with federal laws related to risk assessment, the protection of private property rights, or unfunded mandates. </p> <p>(Sec. 503) Encourages all departments and agencies funded in this division to expand their use of &quot;E-Commerce&quot; technologies and procedures. </p> <p>(Sec. 504) Specifies the congressional committees that are to receive all reports and notifications required by this division. </p> <p>(Sec. 505) Prohibits the transfer of funds to any part of the U.S. government without authority provided by an appropriations law. </p> <p>(Sec. 506) Prohibits funds provided by this division from being used for a project or program named for an individual serving as a Member, Delegate, or Resident Commissioner of the U.S. House of Representatives. </p> <p>(Sec. 507) Requires agencies to post reports submitted to Congress on the public website of the agency. Includes exceptions for national security and confidential or proprietary information. </p> <p>(Sec. 508) Prohibits the use of funds provided by this division for a computer network unless pornography is blocked, with the exception of law enforcement, prosecution, or adjudication activities. </p> <p>(Sec. 509) Prohibits the use of funds provided by this division for first-class travel by an employee of the executive branch. </p> <p>(Sec. 510) Prohibits the use of funds provided by this division for any contract where the contractor has not complied with E-Verify requirements for verification of eligibility for employment. </p> <p>(Sec. 511) Prohibits DOD or the VA from using funds provided by this division to purchase or lease a new vehicle except in accordance with Presidential Memorandum--Federal Fleet Performance, dated May 24, 2011. </p> <p>(Sec. 512) Prohibits the use of funds provided by this division for the renovation, expansion, or construction of any facility in the United States to house any individual detained at the United States Naval Station at Guantanamo Bay, Cuba. Includes an exception for modification to the facility at Guantanamo Bay.</p> <p><i>Zika Response and Preparedness Appropriations Act, 2016 </i></p> <p>DIVISION B--ZIKA RESPONSE AND PREPAREDNESS </p> <p>Provides FY2016 supplemental appropriations to the Department of Health and Human Services, the Department of State, and the United States Agency for International Development (USAID) to prevent, prepare for, and respond to the Zika virus. </p> <p>Designates the funds as an emergency requirement under the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 and permits the funds to remain available through FY2017. (Emergency funds are exempt from discretionary spending limits and other budget enforcement procedures.) </p> <p>TITLE I--DEPARTMENT OF HEALTH AND HUMAN SERVICES </p> <p>Provides FY2016 supplemental appropriations to the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to prevent, prepare for, and respond to the Zika virus, health conditions related to the virus, and other vector-borne diseases, domestically and internationally. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention for CDC-Wide Activities and Program Support. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the National Institutes of Health for the National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Office of the Secretary for the Public Health and Social Services Emergency Fund. </p> <p>(Sec. 101) Permits HHS, the State Department, and the USAID to use funds to appoint candidates for positions to perform critical work relating to the Zika response, without regard to specified requirements regarding hiring preferences if: (1) public notice has been given, and (2) HHS has determined that a public health threat exists. </p> <p>(Sec. 102) Permits funds provided by this title to be transferred between specified HHS accounts if certain requirements are met.</p> <p> (Sec. 103) Requires HHS to submit to Congress a detailed spending plan for funds provided by this title. </p> <p>(Sec. 104) Provides funding to the HHS Office of Inspector General and the Government Accountability Office (GAO) for the oversight of activities funded by this title. </p> <p>TITLE II--DEPARTMENT OF STATE </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the State Department to support response efforts related to the Zika virus, health conditions related to the virus, and other vector-borne diseases.</p> <p>Provides appropriations for the Administration of Foreign Affairs, including: </p> <ul> <li>Diplomatic and Consular Programs, </li> <li> Emergencies in the Diplomatic and Consular Service, and </li> <li> the Repatriation Loans Program Account. </li> </ul> <p>Provides appropriations to the USAID for Operating Expenses. </p> <p>Provides appropriations for Bilateral Economic Assistance for Global Health Programs. </p> <p>(Sec. 201) Permits funds provided by this title to be transferred between specified accounts and sets forth requirements and restrictions for the transfers. </p> <p>(Sec. 202) Prohibits funds provided by this title from being obligated unless the State Department or the USAID notifies Congress 15 days in advance of the obligation. </p> <p>(Sec. 203) Requires the State Department and the USAID to submit to Congress, prior to obligating funds provided by this title, a consolidated report on the anticipated uses of such funds on a country and project basis, including estimated personnel and administrative costs. </p> <p>(Sec. 204) Provides funding to the USAID Office of Inspector General and the GAO for the oversight of activities funded by this title. </p> <p>(Sec. 205) Rescinds specified unobligated balances of funds that were provided to the USAID to prevent, prepare for, and respond to the Ebola virus disease outbreak.</p> <p>TITLE III--GENERAL PROVISIONS--THIS DIVISION </p> <p>(Sec. 301) Provides that, unless otherwise indicated by this division, funds provided by this division are subject to the requirements contained in the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2016. </p> <p>(Sec. 302) Permits fund provided by this division to be used for contracts with individuals for the provision of personal services within the United States and abroad, subject to congressional notification requirements. Prohibits the individuals from being deemed U.S. employees for the purpose of any law administered by the Office of Personnel Management. </p> <p>(Sec. 303) Specifies that any amount provided by this division that is designated as an emergency requirement, subsequently designated by the President, and is transferred pursuant to authorities provided in the division, retains the emergency designation. </p> <p>(Sec. 304) Specifies that this division becomes effective immediately upon enactment of this bill. </p> <p><i>Zika Vector Control Act </i></p> <p>DIVISION C- ZIKA VECTOR CONTROL</p> <p>(Sec. 2) Provides that, for the 180 day period following the date of enactment of this bill, the Environmental Protection Agency or a state may not require a permit under the Clean Water Act for the discharge of certain pesticides from a point source into navigable waters for the prevention or control of the Zika virus. (Point source pollution is waste discharged from a distinct place, such as a pipe, channel, or tunnel.) <p>Applies the waiver of permit requirements to discharges from the application by an entity authorized under state or local law, such as a vector control district, of a pesticide in compliance with all relevant requirements of the Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act to control mosquitos or mosquito larvae for the prevention or control of the Zika virus. <p> DIVISION D--RESCISSIONS OF FUNDS</p> <p>(Sec. 101) Rescinds specified unobligated balances of funds that were provided for: </p> <ul> <li> the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act, </li> <li> the Department of Health and Human Service's Non-Recurring Expenses Fund, and </li> <li> the Economic Support Fund for Ebola response and preparedness. </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2577v40" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-07-06">
<action-date>2016-05-26</action-date>
<action-desc>House agreed to Senate amendment with amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Highlights: </b></p> <p>This bill provides FY2017 appropriations for military construction, the Department of Veterans Affairs, and related agencies. It also provides FY2016 supplemental appropriations to respond to the Zika virus and modifies permit requirements for the discharge of pesticides into navigable waters. </p> <p>The bill includes three divisions: </p> <ul> <li>the Military Construction and Veterans Affairs and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2017; </li> <li>the Zika Response Appropriations Act, 2016; and </li> <li> the Zika Vector Control Act. </li> </ul> <p><i>Military Construction and Veterans Affairs and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2017 </i></p> <p>This division provides FY2017 appropriations to the Department of Defense (DOD) for military construction, military family housing, the U.S. share of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization Security Investment Program, and base closures and realignments. </p> <p>The division also provides appropriations to the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) for veterans benefit and health care programs, Departmental Administration, and the National Cemetery Administration. </p> <p>Related agencies and programs funded in the division include the U.S. Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims; the Armed Forces Retirement Home; and the Cemeterial Expenses of the Army, including Arlington National Cemetery. </p> <p>The division includes Army, Air Force, Navy and Marine Corps, and Defense-Wide military construction funds which are designated as Overseas Contingency Operations (OCO) funds and are not subject to discretionary spending limits. </p> <p>The division includes both mandatory and discretionary funding. It increases discretionary and overall FY2017 Military Construction and Veterans Affairs funding above FY2016 levels. Compared to FY2016 levels, the division increases discretionary funding for the VA and decreases discretionary funding for the DOD Military Construction and Family Housing accounts. </p> <p>The division permits unobligated balances of funds previously provided for the Ebola outbreak to be used to prevent, prepare, and respond to the Zika virus. </p> <p>The division includes provisions that: </p> <ul> <li> prohibit the Administration from renovating, expanding, or constructing facilities in the United States to house individuals held in the detention facility at Guantanamo Bay; </li> <li> restrict the display of Confederate flags in VA cemeteries; </li> <li> permit VA providers to complete forms for a veteran's participation in a state marijuana program, and </li> <li> prohibit the use of funds for a new Base Realignment and Closure (BRAC) round. </li> </ul> <p><i>Zika Response Appropriations Act, 2016</i> </p> <p>This division provides FY2016 supplemental appropriations to the Departments of Health and Human Services (HHS) and State to respond to the Zika virus. The division also rescinds unobligated balances of prior appropriations. </p> <p>The division permits the funds to be used for the duration of FY2016, designates specified funds as emergency requirements, and sets forth congressional reporting and notification requirements. </p> <p><i>The Zika Vector Control Act</i> </p> <p>This division prohibits the Environmental Protection Agency and states from requiring permits for the discharge of certain pesticides from a point source into navigable waters. </p> <p><b>Full Summary:</b></p> <p><i>Military Construction and Veterans Affairs and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2017</i></p> <p>DIVISION A--MILITARY CONSTRUCTION AND VETERANS AFFAIRS AND RELATED AGENCIES</p> <p>TITLE I--DEPARTMENT OF DEFENSE </p> <p>Provides appropriations to DOD for Military Construction for: </p> <ul> <li> the Army; </li> <li>the Navy and Marine Corps; </li> <li> the Air Force; </li> <li> Defense-Wide agencies and activities (other than military departments); </li> <li> the Army and Air National Guard; and </li> <li> the Army, Navy, and Air Force Reserves. </li> </ul> <p>Provides appropriations to DOD for the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) Security Investment Program. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to DOD for Construction and Operation and Maintenance of Family Housing for: </p> <ul> <li> the Army, </li> <li> the Navy and Marine Corps, </li> <li> the Air Force, and </li> <li> Defense-Wide agencies and activities (other than military departments). </li> </ul> <p>Provides appropriations for the Department of Defense Family Housing Improvement Fund. </p> <p>Provides appropriations for the Department of Defense Base Closure Account. </p> <p>(Sec. 101) Prohibits funds provided by this title from being used for payments exceeding $25,000 for construction in the United States under a cost-plus-a-fixed-fee contract without DOD approval. Includes an exception for work that is to be performed in Alaska. </p> <p>(Sec. 102) Permits construction funds provided by this title to be used for hiring passenger motor vehicles. </p> <p>(Sec. 103) Permits construction funds provided by this title to be used for advances to the Federal Highway Administration for the construction of access roads DOD has certified as important to national defense. </p> <p>(Sec. 104) Prohibits funds provided by this title from being used to begin construction of new bases in the United States without a specific appropriation. </p> <p>(Sec. 105) Prohibits funds provided by this title from being used to purchase land or land easements in excess of 100% of the value as determined by the Army Corps of Engineers or the Naval Facilities Engineering Command. Includes exceptions for: (1) determinations of value by a federal court, (2) purchases negotiated by the Attorney General or a designee, (3) values less than $25,000, and (4) DOD determinations that the purchase is in the public interest. </p> <p>(Sec. 106) Prohibits funds provided by this title from being used to acquire land, provide for site preparation, or install utilities for family housing, except housing for which appropriations have been provided. </p> <p>(Sec. 107) Prohibits funds provided this title for minor construction from being used to transfer or relocate any activity from one base or installation to another without notifying Congress in advance. </p> <p>(Sec. 108) Prohibits funds provided by this title from being used to procure steel for construction unless American producers, fabricators, and manufacturers have been allowed to compete for the procurement. </p> <p>(Sec. 109) Prohibits funds provided to DOD for military construction or family housing during the current fiscal year from being used to pay real property taxes in any foreign nation. </p> <p>(Sec. 110) Prohibits funds provided by this title from being used to initiate a new installation overseas without notifying Congress in advance. </p> <p>(Sec. 111) Prohibits funds provided by this title from being used for architect and engineer contracts estimated to exceed $500,000 for projects in Japan, NATO member countries, or countries bordering the Arabian Gulf unless the contracts are awarded to U.S. firms or joint ventures with U.S. firms. </p> <p>(Sec. 112) Prohibits funds provided by this title for military construction in U.S. territories and possessions in the Pacific and on Kwajalein Atoll, or in countries bordering the Arabian Gulf from being used to award a contract over $1 million to a foreign contractor. Includes exceptions. </p> <p>(Sec. 113) Requires DOD to notify Congress in advance of military exercises if construction costs are expected to exceed $100,000. </p> <p>(Sec. 114) Permits funds appropriated to DOD for construction in prior years to be used for construction projects authorized during the current session of Congress. </p> <p>(Sec. 115) Permits expired or lapsed funds to be used to pay for supervision, inspection, overhead, engineering, and design costs for military construction or family housing projects being completed with lapsed or expired funds. </p> <p>(Sec. 116) Permits funds provided for the construction of military projects to be available for five years if: (1) the funds are obligated from funds available for military construction, and (2) do not exceed the amount appropriated or permitted by law. </p> <p>(Sec. 117) Permits the following transfers if Congress is notified and specified conditions are met: </p> <ul> <li> to the Department of Defense Family Housing Improvement Fund from appropriations for construction in Family Housing accounts, and </li> <li> to the Department of Defense Military Unaccompanied Housing Improvement Fund from appropriations for construction of military unaccompanied housing in Military Construction accounts. </li> </ul> <p>(Sec. 118) Permits the transfer of funds from the Department of Defense Base Closure Account to the fund established to pay expenses associated with the Homeowners Assistance Program under the Demonstration Cities and Metropolitan Development Act of 1966. </p> <p>(Sec. 119) Provides that funds for operation and maintenance of family housing in this title shall be the only source of funds for repair and maintenance of all family housing units, including general or flag officer quarters. Sets forth limitations and requirements for expenditures for maintenance and repair of general or flag officer quarters. </p> <p>(Sec. 120) Appropriates funds contained in the Ford Island Improvement Account to remain available until expended or transferred. </p> <p>(Sec. 121) Permits the transfer of unobligated balances of expired military construction and family housing funds into the Foreign Currency Fluctuations--Construction--Defense account. </p> <p>(Sec. 122) Prohibits the Army from using funds provided by this bill to relocate a unit that: (1) performs a required testing mission or function not performed by any other unit, and (2) is located at a military installation where the total number of Army civilian employees and contractor personnel exceeds 10% of the regular and reserve Army personnel. Includes an exception if the Army notifies Congress of the relocation's compliance with Army Regulation 5-10 concerning stationing actions.</p> <p> (Sec. 123) Permits funds provided to an account in this title to be transferred among projects and activities within the account subject to specified DOD reprogramming guidelines for military and family housing construction. </p> <p>(Sec. 124) Prohibits DOD military construction funds provided in this title from being used for the planning, design, and construction of projects at Arlington National Cemetery. </p> <p>(Sec. 125) Rescinds specified unobligated balances from the Military Construction--Army account. </p> <p>(Sec. 126) Rescinds specified unobligated balances from the Military Construction--Navy and Marine Corps account. </p> <p>(Sec. 127) Rescinds specified unobligated balances from the Military Construction--Defense-Wide account. </p> <p>(Sec. 128) Provides specified additional funds to the Army to remain available through FY2021 for unfunded military construction priorities. </p> <p>(Sec. 129) Provides specified additional funds to the Navy and Marine Corps to remain available through FY2021 for unfunded military construction priorities. </p> <p>(Sec. 130) Provides specified additional funds to the Army National Guard to remain available through FY2021 for unfunded military construction priorities. </p> <p>(Sec. 131) Provides specified additional funds to the Army Reserve to remain available through FY2021 for unfunded military construction priorities. </p> <p>(Sec. 132) Provides specified additional funds to the Air Force to remain available through FY2021 for unfunded military construction priorities. </p> <p>(Sec. 133) Rescinds specified unobligated balances from the fund established by the Demonstration Cities and Metropolitan Development Act of 1966 for expenses associated with the Homeowners Assistance Program. </p> <p>(Sec. 134) Defines &quot;congressional defense committees&quot; to include the House and Senate Armed Services Committees and Appropriations Subcommittees on Military Construction and Veterans Affairs. </p> <p>(Sec. 135) Rescinds specified unobligated balances from the NATO Security Investment Program. </p> <p>(Sec. 136) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used for the closure or realignment of the U.S. Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba. </p> <p>TITLE II--DEPARTMENT OF VETERANS AFFAIRS </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Veterans Benefits Administration (VBA) for: </p> <ul> <li> Compensation and Pensions, </li> <li> Readjustment Benefits, </li> <li> Veterans Insurance and Indemnities, </li> <li> the Veterans Housing Benefit Program Fund, </li> <li>the Vocational Rehabilitation Loans Program Account, and </li> <li> the Native American Veteran Housing Loan Program Account. </li> </ul> <p>Provides appropriations to the Veterans Health Administration (VHA) for: </p> <ul> <li>Medical Services, </li> <li> Medical Community Care, </li> <li> Medical Support and Compliance, </li> <li>Medical Facilities, and </li> <li>Medical and Prosthetic Research. </li> </ul> <p>Provides appropriations to the National Cemetery Administration. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the VA for Departmental Administration, including: </p> <ul> <li>General Administration, </li> <li> the Board of Veterans Appeals, </li> <li> General Operating Expenses of the Veterans Benefits Administration, </li> <li> Information Technology Systems, </li> <li> the Office of Inspector General, </li> <li> Construction--Major Projects, </li> <li> Construction--Minor Projects, </li> <li> Grants for Construction of State Extended Care Facilities, and </li> <li> Grants for Construction of Veterans Cemeteries. </li> </ul> <p>Prohibits the expenditure of specified information technology funds for the Veterans Health Information Systems and Technology Architecture (VistA) Evolution Program until the VA: (1) certifies to Congress that it has deployed modernized electronic health record software supporting VA and DOD clinicians no later than December 31, 2016, while ensuring continued support and compatibility with the interoperability platform and full standards-based interoperability; and (2) submits to Congress a report including specified details regarding the status, costs, and plans for the program. </p> <p> Withholds specified VHA construction funds until the VA: </p> <ul> <li> enters an agreement with a non-VA federal entity to serve as the design and/ or construction agent for any VHA major construction project that exceeds $100 million, and </li> <li> certifies that an agreement is executed to minimize or prevent subsequent major construction project cost overruns. </li> </ul> <p>(Sec. 201) Specifies transfer authorities and requirements for the VBA.</p> <p>(Sec. 202) Specifies transfer authorities and requirements for the VHA. </p> <p>(Sec. 203) Permits appropriations for salaries and expenses to be used for employment of temporary or intermittent experts and consultants, hire of passenger vehicles, lease of a facility or land, and uniforms. </p> <p>(Sec. 204) Prohibits appropriations in this title other than Construction--Major Projects and Construction--Minor Projects from being used for land acquisition or construction of any new hospital or home. </p> <p>(Sec. 205) Requires the VA to be reimbursed for medical services it provides to any person not defined as a beneficiary under specified laws. </p> <p>(Sec. 206) Permits appropriations provided by this title for Compensation and Pensions, Readjustment Benefits, and Veterans Insurance and Indemnities to be used for payment of accrued obligations for the accounts recorded in the last quarter of FY2016. </p> <p>(Sec. 207) Permits appropriations provided by this title to be used to pay specified prior year obligations. Requires obligations from trust fund accounts to be paid only from the Compensation and Pensions account. </p> <p>(Sec. 208) Requires the VA to use surplus earnings from the National Service Life Insurance Fund, the Veterans' Special Life Insurance Fund, and the United States Government Life Insurance Fund to reimburse the General Operating Expenses--Veterans Benefits Administration and Information Technology Systems accounts for the costs to administer the insurance programs during FY2017. </p> <p>(Sec. 209) Permits amounts deducted from enhanced-use lease proceeds for reimbursement of expenses from a prior year to be obligated in the year in which the proceeds are received. </p> <p>(Sec. 210) Permits funds provided by this title for salaries and other administrative expenses to be used to reimburse the Office of Resolution Management and the Office of Employment Discrimination Complaint Adjudication within specified limits. </p> <p>(Sec. 211) Requires the VA to collect third-party reimbursement information prior to providing hospital care, nursing home care, or medical services for a non-service connected disability. Permits the VA to recover reasonable charges for care from anyone who has not provided the required disclosures. </p> <p>(Sec. 212) Permits enhanced-use leasing revenues to be deposited into the Construction--Major Projects and Construction--Minor Projects accounts to be used for construction, alterations, and improvements of VA medical facilities. </p> <p>(Sec. 213) Permits funds provided for Medical Services to be used for: (1) furnishing recreational facilities, supplies, and equipment; and (2) funeral and burial expenses. </p> <p>(Sec. 214) Permits funds deposited in the Medical Care Collections Fund to be transferred to the Medical Services and Medical Community Care accounts and remain available until expended for the purposes of those accounts. </p> <p>(Sec. 215) Permits the VA to enter into agreements with certain Indian tribes and tribal organizations in rural Alaska to provide health care to veterans. </p> <p>(Sec. 216) Permits funds deposited into the Department of Veterans Affairs Capital Asset Fund to be transferred to the Construction--Major Projects and Construction--Minor Projects accounts to remain available until expended. </p> <p>(Sec. 217) Permits the Directors of the Veterans Integrated Services Networks to conduct outreach or marketing to enroll new veterans. </p> <p>(Sec. 218) Requires the VA to report quarterly to Congress on the financial status of the VA. </p> <p>(Sec. 219) Permits specified FY2017 VA funds to be transferred to or from the Information Technology Systems account if approved by Congress. </p> <p>(Sec. 220) Permits specified FY2017 VA funds provided for medical accounts, Construction--Minor Projects, and Information Technology Systems to be transferred to the Joint Department of Defense-Department of Veterans Affairs Medical Facility Demonstration Fund and used for the operation of combined federal medical facilities. </p> <p>(Sec. 221) Permits specified FY2018 VA advance funding provided for medical accounts to be transferred to the Joint Department of Defense-Department of Veterans Affairs Medical Facility Demonstration Fund and used for the operation of combined federal medical facilities. </p> <p>(Sec. 222) Permits transfers from the Medical Care Collections Fund to the Joint Department of Defense-Department of Veterans Affairs Medical Facility Demonstration Fund for the operation of combined federal medical facilities. </p> <p>(Sec. 223) Requires specified funds from the Medical Services, Medical Support and Compliance, and Medical Facilities accounts to be transferred to the DOD-VA Health Care Sharing Incentive Fund to remain available until expended. </p> <p>(Sec. 224) Directs the VA to notify Congress of all bid savings in major construction projects that total at least $5 million or 5% of the programmed amount of the project, whichever is less. </p> <p>(Sec. 225) Prohibits the scope of work for a project included in Construction--Major Projects from being increased above the original budget request without congressional approval. </p> <p>(Sec. 226) Limits funds from the Medical Support and Compliance account that may be used for the Veterans Health Information Systems and Technology Architecture (VistA) Evolution and electronic health record interoperability projects. Permits additional funds to be obligated for this purpose if Congress is notified in advance. </p> <p>(Sec. 227) Directs the VA to notify Congress before organizational changes that result in the transfer of 25 or more full-time equivalent staff from one organizational unit to another.</p> <p>(Sec. 228) Requires the VA to report to Congress quarterly regarding any single national outreach and awareness campaign exceeding $2 million. </p> <p>(Sec. 229) Permits the VA to transfer funds to the Medical Services account if the transfer is necessary to address the needs of the VHA, meets specified requirements, and is approved by the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) and Congress. </p> <p>(Sec. 230) Permits FY2017 funds provided for the Board of Veterans Appeals and General Operating Expenses--Veterans Benefits Administration to be transferred between those accounts if Congress approves the transfer. </p> <p>(Sec. 231) Prohibits the VA from reprogramming more than $5 million in funds among major construction projects or programs without congressional approval. </p> <p>(Sec. 232) Rescinds specified unobligated balances from the DOD-VA Health Care Sharing Incentive Fund. </p> <p>(Sec. 233) Rescinds specified unobligated balances from the VA Medical Services, Medical Support and Compliance, and Medical Facilities accounts. </p> <p>(Sec. 234) Rescinds specified unobligated balances of funds provided for the Veterans Health Administration, the National Cemetery Administration, and Departmental Administration. </p> <p>(Sec. 235) Requires the VA to ensure that the toll-free suicide hotline authorized under current law: (1) provides individuals who contact the hotline with immediate assistance from a trained professional, and (2) adheres to all requirements of the American Association of Suicidology. </p> <p>(Sec. 236) Requires the VA to treat a marriage and family therapist as qualified to serve in the VA if the therapist meets specified educational and licensing requirements. </p> <p>(Sec. 237) Prohibits the VA from using funds provided by this bill to pay certain performance awards to career appointees in the Senior Executive Service. </p> <p>(Sec. 238) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to end, suspend, or relocate hospital-based services of a VA healthcare facility that is the subject of an environmental impact statement, designated as a National Historic Landmark by the National Park Service, and located in a highly rural area. </p> <p>TITLE III--RELATED AGENCIES </p> <p>Provides appropriations for related agencies, including: </p> <ul> <li> the American Battle Monuments Commission; </li> <li> the U.S. Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims, </li> <li> Cemeterial Expenses of the Army, including Arlington National Cemetery and Soldiers' and Airmen's Home National Cemetery; and </li> <li> the Armed Forces Retirement Home. </li> </ul> <p>(Sec. 301) Permits funds for Cemeterial Expenses--Army to be provided to Arlington County, Virginia to relocate a federally owned water main at Arlington National Cemetery to make additional land available for ground burials. </p> <p>(Sec. 302) Permits funds from concessions at Army National Military Cemeteries to be used to support activities at the cemeteries. </p> <p>TITLE IV--OVERSEAS CONTINGENCY OPERATIONS </p> <p>Provide appropriations to DOD for Overseas Contingency Operations Military Construction projects for the: </p> <ul> <li> Army, </li> <li>Navy and Marine Corps, </li> <li> Air Force, and </li> <li> Defense-Wide agencies and activities </li> </ul> <p>Designates the amounts provided in this title as for Overseas Contingency Operations/ Global War on Terrorism pursuant to the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985. </p> <p>TITLE V--GENERAL PROVISIONS </p> <p>(Sec. 501) Prohibits the obligation of funds in this bill beyond the current fiscal year unless expressly permitted in this bill. </p> <p>(Sec. 502) Prohibits the use of funds provided by this bill for programs, projects, or activities not in compliance with federal laws related to risk assessment, the protection of private property rights, or unfunded mandates. </p> <p>(Sec. 503) Encourages all departments and agencies funded in this bill to expand their use of &quot;E-Commerce&quot; technologies and procedures. </p> <p>(Sec. 504) Specifies the congressional committees that are to receive all reports and notifications required by this bill. </p> <p>(Sec. 505) Prohibits the transfer of funds to any part of the U.S. government without authority provided by an appropriations law. </p> <p>(Sec. 506) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used for a project or program named for an individual serving as a Member, Delegate, or Resident Commissioner of the U.S. House of Representatives. </p> <p>(Sec. 507) Requires agencies to post reports submitted to Congress on the public web site of the agency. Includes exceptions for national security and confidential or proprietary information. </p> <p>(Sec. 508) Prohibits the use of funds provided by this bill for a computer network unless pornography is blocked, with the exception of law enforcement, prosecution, or adjudication activities. </p> <p>(Sec. 509) Prohibits the use of funds provided by this bill for first-class travel by an employee of the executive branch. </p> <p>(Sec. 510) Prohibits the use of funds provided by this bill for any contract where the contractor has not complied with E-Verify requirements for verification of eligibility for employment. </p> <p>(Sec. 511) Prohibits DOD or the VA from using funds provided by this bill to purchase or lease a new vehicle except in accordance with Presidential Memorandum--Federal Fleet Performance, dated May 24, 2011. </p> <p>(Sec. 512) Prohibits the use of funds provided by this bill for the renovation, expansion, or construction of any facility in the United States to house any individual detained at the United States Naval Station at Guantanamo Bay, Cuba. Includes an exception for modification to the facility at Guantanamo Bay. </p> <p>(Sec. 513) Permits unobligated balances of specified funds provided to the Departments of State and Health and Human Services for Ebola response and preparedness to be used to prevent, prepare, and respond to the Zika virus, domestically and internationally. Designates the funds as an emergency requirement and permits the funds to be available only if the President subsequently designates the amounts and transmits the designation to Congress. </p> <p>(Sec. 514) Establishes a spending reduction account for the amount by which spending proposed in this bill exceeds the subcommittee's allocation under the Congressional Budget Act of 1974. Specifies that the amount is $0. (Under the Rules of the House of Representatives, any savings included in the spending reduction account are not available for further appropriation during consideration of the bill.) </p> <p>(Sec. 515) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used for a new or additional Base Realignment and Closure (BRAC) round. </p> <p>(Sec. 516) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used for a contract with companies convicted, indicted, or charged with certain federal crimes or that have more than $3,000 in delinquent taxes within the three-year period preceding the offer of the contract. </p> <p>(Sec. 517) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used for the Veterans Experience Office. </p> <p>(Sec. 518) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to: (1) enforce the May 20, 2013, Veterans Benefits Administration memorandum known as Fast Letter 13-10 that provided guidance for date of claim issues, or (2) create or maintain any patient record-keeping system other than those currently approved by the VA. </p> <p>(Sec. 519) Provides additional funds to the VHA for grants to states to expand, remodel, or alter existing buildings for furnishing nursing home care to veterans in state homes that are former VA nursing home facilities. Prohibits the funds from being used to implement, administer, or enforce specified prioritization requirements with respect to state applications for funds. Reduces funding provided by this bill for VA Departmental Administration. </p> <p>(Sec. 520) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being using in contravention of regulations for authorizing recruitment and relocation incentives. </p> <p>(Sec. 521) Prohibits the VA from using funds provided by this bill in contravention of provisions of current law that provide training and outreach programs for homeless veterans. </p> <p>(Sec. 522) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to enforce specified provisions of the VA Adjudication Procedure Manual related to Developing Claims Based on Service Aboard Ships Offshore the Republic of Vietnam (RVN). </p> <p>(Sec. 523) Permits VA providers to complete forms seeking recommendations or opinions regarding a veteran's participation in a state marijuana program. </p> <p>(Sec. 524) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to modify a military installation in the United States, including construction or modification of a facility on a military installation, to provide temporary housing for unaccompanied alien children. </p> <p>(Sec. 525) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to permit the flying of the Confederate flag from a flagpole at VA national cemeteries where Confederate veterans are buried in mass graves. </p> <p><i>Zika Response Appropriations Act, 2016 </i></p> <p>DIVISION B--ZIKA RESPONSE APPROPRIATIONS </p> <p>TITLE I--DEPARTMENT OF HEALTH AND HUMAN SERVICES </p> <p>Provides appropriations to HHS for: </p> <ul> <li> the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention to prevent, prepare for, and respond to the Zika virus, domestically and internationally; </li> <li> the National Institutes of Health for the preclinical and clinical development of vaccines for the Zika virus; and </li> <li> the Public Health and Social Services Emergency Fund within the Office of the Secretary to develop necessary countermeasures and vaccines to respond to the Zika virus, domestically and internationally. </li> </ul> <p>(Sec. 101) Requires HHS to notify Congress at least 15 days in advance of obligating the funds provided by this title. Permits a waiver for a substantial risk to human health or welfare. </p> <p>(Sec. 102) Requires HHS to report monthly to Congress on the proposed uses of funds provided by this title. </p> <p>(Sec. 103) Provides funding to the HHS Office of Inspector General and the Government Accountability Office (GAO) for the oversight of activities funded by this title. </p> <p>TITLE II--DEPARTMENT OF STATE </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the State Department for the Administration of Foreign Affairs, the United States Agency for International Development (USAID), and Bilateral Economic Assistance, including funds for: </p> <ul> <li>Diplomatic and Consular Programs for medical evacuations and other response efforts related to the Zika virus and directly associated health conditions; </li> <li> USAID response efforts related to the Zika virus and directly associated health conditions; and </li> <li> Global Health Programs for mosquito control (vector control) efforts to prevent, prepare for, and respond to the Zika virus internationally. </li> </ul> <p>(Sec. 201) Permits specified funds provided by this bill for Diplomatic and Consular Programs to be: (1) used for medical evacuation costs of any U.S. department or agency under Chief of Mission authority, and (2) transferred and merged with funds available for Emergencies in the Diplomatic and Consular Service. </p> <p>(Sec. 202) Requires the State Department or the USAID to notify Congress at least 15 days in advance of obligating the funds provided by this title. Permits a waiver for a substantial risk to human health or welfare. </p> <p>(Sec. 203) Requires the State Department, in consultation with the USAID, to report monthly to Congress on the proposed uses of funds provided by this title. </p> <p>(Sec. 204) Provides funding to the USAID Office of Inspector General and the GAO for the oversight of activities funded by this title. </p> <p>TITLE III--GENERAL PROVISIONS--THIS ACT </p> <p>(Sec. 301) Rescinds specified unobligated balances of funds that were previously provided to HHS and the State Department for the Ebola outbreak and to HHS for the Nonrecurring Expenses Fund. </p> <p>(Sec. 302) Specifies that, unless otherwise indicated in this bill, the funds provided by this bill are subject to the requirements contained in the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2016. </p> <p><i>Zika Vector Control Act </i></p> <p>DIVISION C--ZIKA VECTOR CONTROL </p> <p>(Sec. 2) Amends the Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act (FIFRA) and the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (commonly known as the Clean Water Act) to prohibit the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) or a state from requiring a permit under the Clean Water Act for a discharge from a point source into navigable waters of a pesticide authorized for sale, distribution, or use under FIFRA, or a residue resulting from the application of the pesticide. (Point source pollution is waste discharged from a distinct place, such as a pipe, channel, or tunnel.) </p> <p>(Sec. 3) Sets forth exceptions that permit the EPA or a state to require permits for the following discharges of a pesticide or pesticide residue: </p> <ul> <li> a discharge resulting from the application of a pesticide in violation of FIFRA that is relevant to protecting water quality, if the discharge would not have occurred but for the violation or the amount of pesticide or pesticide residue contained in the discharge is greater than would have occurred without the violation; </li> <li> stormwater discharges regulated under the National Pollutant Discharge Elimination System (NPDES); and </li> <li> discharges regulated under NPDES of manufacturing or industrial effluent or treatment works effluent and discharges incidental to the normal operations of a vessel, including a discharge resulting from ballasting operations or vessel biofouling prevention. </li> </ul> <p>Provides that this division is effective until September 30, 2018. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2577v35" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-09-09">
<action-date>2016-05-19</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed Senate amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Highlights: </b></p> <p>This bill provides FY2017 appropriations for military construction, the Department of Veterans Affairs, the Department of Transportation, the Department of Housing and Urban Development, and several related agencies. </p> <p>The bill also provides FY2016 supplemental appropriations to respond to the Zika virus </p> <p>The bill includes two divisions: </p> <ul> <li> Departments of Transportation, and Housing and Urban Development, and Related Agencies; and </li> <li>Military Construction, the Department of Veterans Affairs, and Related Agencies. </li> </ul> <p><i>Transportation, Housing and Urban Development, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2017 </i></p> <p>This division provides FY2017 appropriations for the Department of Transportation (DOT), the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD), and several related agencies. </p> <p>The division includes both discretionary and mandatory funding. The HUD budget is primarily discretionary spending, and most of the DOT budget is mandatory spending, in the form of contract authority from the Highway Trust Fund. </p> <p>The division decreases net discretionary budget authority for Transportation, Housing and Urban Development, and Related Agencies below FY2016 levels. (When savings due to certain rescissions and receipts are taken into account, the new discretionary budget authority available to agencies funded in the bill is above the FY2016 level.) </p> <p>Compared to FY2016 levels, the division decreases discretionary funding for DOT (including the effects of a rescission of unused contract authority) and increases discretionary funding for HUD. </p> <p>The division also includes a provision that affects DOT regulations regarding commercial truck drivers' rest periods. </p> <p><i>Military Construction, Veterans Affairs, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2017 </i></p> <p>This division provides FY2017 appropriations to the Department of Defense (DOD) for military construction, military family housing, the U.S. share of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization Security Investment Program, and base closures and realignments. </p> <p>The division also provides appropriations to the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) for veterans benefit and health care programs, Departmental Administration, and the National Cemetery Administration. </p> <p>Related agencies and programs funded in the division include the U.S. Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims; the Armed Forces Retirement Home; and the Cemeterial Expenses of the Army, including Arlington National Cemetery. </p> <p>The division includes both mandatory and discretionary funding. It increases FY2017 discretionary funding for Military Construction and Veterans Affairs above FY2016 levels, including an increase for the VA and a decrease for Military Construction. When mandatory funding is included, overall funding in the bill is below FY2016 levels. </p> <p>The division includes provisions that: </p> <ul> <li> permit the VA to pay for fertility treatments and counseling, </li> <li> prohibit the VA from interfering with the ability of veterans to participate in state-approved medical marijuana programs, and </li> <li> establish additional procedures and protections for VA whistle-blowers. </li> </ul> <p>The division also prohibits funds from being used for activities related to the detention facility at the U.S. Naval Station at Guantanamo Bay, Cuba; including: (1) constructing, renovating, or expanding a facility for the purpose of housing individuals detained at Guantanamo; and (2) closing or transferring the facility. </p> <p>This division also provides FY2016 supplemental funding for the Department of Health and Human Services and the Department of State to respond to the Zika virus. </p> <p><b>Full Summary: </b></p> <p><b>Transportation, Housing and Urban Development, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2017 or the Military Construction, Veterans Affairs, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2017 </b></p> <p>DIVISION A-- DEPARTMENTS OF TRANSPORTATION, AND HOUSING AND URBAN DEVELOPMENT, AND RELATED AGENCIES </p> <p><i>Department of Transportation Appropriations Act, 2017 </i></p> <p>TITLE I--DEPARTMENT OF TRANSPORTATION </p> <p>Provides FY2017 appropriations for the Department of Transportation (DOT). </p> <p>Provides appropriations for the Office of the Secretary, including: </p> <ul> <li> Salaries and Expenses; </li> <li>Research and Technology; </li> <li> National Infrastructure Investments (also known as TIGER grants); </li> <li> the National Surface Transportation and Innovative Finance Bureau; </li> <li> Financial Management Capital; </li> <li> Cyber Security Initiatives; </li> <li> the Office of Civil Rights; </li> <li>Transportation Planning, Research, and Development; </li> <li> the Working Capital Fund; </li> <li> the Minority Business Resource Center Program; </li> <li>Small and Disadvantaged Business Utilization and Outreach; and </li> <li> Payments to Air Carriers. </li> </ul> <p>(Sec. 101) Prohibits DOT from approving assessments or reimbursable agreements pertaining to funds appropriated to the modal administrations in this bill except for activities underway on the date of enactment, unless the reprogramming process has been completed. </p> <p>(Sec. 102) Permits DOT to use the Working Capital Fund to provide transit benefits to federal employees. </p> <p>(Sec. 103) Requires DOT to: (1) post on its website the schedule and agenda for all meetings of the Council on Credit and Finance, and (2) require the council to record the decisions and actions of each meeting. </p> <p>(Sec. 104) Reduces the funding provided by this bill for the Salaries and Expenses account of the Office of the Secretary. Increases the funding provided by this bill for Federal Transit Administration Administrative Expenses. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) for: </p> <ul> <li> Operations; </li> <li> Facilities and Equipment; </li> <li> Research, Engineering, and Development; and </li> <li> Grants-In-Aid For Airports. </li> </ul> <p>Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used for: </p> <ul> <li> new applicants for the second career training program, </li> <li> new unauthorized aviation user fees, </li> <li> aeronautical charting and cartography activities through the Working Capital Fund, or </li> <li>eliminating the Contract Weather Observers program at any airport. </li> </ul> <p>Permits funds received from specified public, private, and foreign sources for expenses incurred to be credited to the appropriation. </p> <p>(Sec. 110) Limits technical staff-years under the federally funded research and development center contract between the FAA and the Center for Advanced Aviation Systems Development. </p> <p>(Sec. 111) Prohibits the FAA from requiring airport sponsors to provide the agency without cost building construction, maintenance, utilities and expenses, or space in sponsor-owned buildings for air traffic control, air navigation, or weather reporting, subject to specified exceptions. </p> <p>(Sec. 112) Permits the FAA to reimburse amounts made available from certain fees to carry out the Essential Air Service (EAS) program, which ensures that small communities have a minimum level of air service. </p> <p>(Sec. 113) Permits amounts collected by the FAA for providing technical assistance to foreign aviation authorities to be credited to the Operations account. </p> <p>(Sec. 114) Prohibits the FAA from paying Sunday premium pay except if an individual worked on a Sunday. </p> <p>(Sec. 115) Prohibits the FAA from using funds provided by this bill to purchase a store gift card or gift certificate using a government-issued credit card. </p> <p>(Sec. 116) Allows all airports experiencing the required level of boardings through charter and scheduled air service to be eligible for specified funds. </p> <p>(Sec. 117) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used for retention bonuses for FAA employees without prior approval of the Assistant Secretary for Administration of DOT. </p> <p>(Sec. 118) Requires the FAA, upon the request of an owner or operator, to block the display of the owner's or operator's aircraft registration number in the Aircraft Situational Display to Industry program. </p> <p>(Sec. 119) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to pay the salaries and expenses of more than nine political or presidential FAA appointees. </p> <p>(Sec. 119A) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to increase fees for navigation products until the FAA provides Congress with a justification for all fees for aeronautical navigation products. </p> <p>(Sec. 119B) Requires the FAA to notify Congress prior to closing a regional operations center or reducing the services it provides. </p> <p>(Sec. 119C) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to change weight restrictions or prior permission rules at Teterboro Airport in New Jersey. </p> <p>(Sec. 119D) Prohibits the FAA from withholding consideration and approval of any application for participation in the Contract Tower Program, pending as of January 1, 2016, including applications from Cost-share Program participants, if the tower meets the criteria included in the FAA report entitled &quot;Establishment and Discontinuance Criteria for Airport Traffic Control Towers.&quot; </p> <p>(Sec. 119E) Permits airports that met the 10,000 enplanement qualification for Airport Improvement Program (AIP) funds in calendar year 2012 to continue to receive AIP funds in FY2017. </p> <p>(Sec. 119F) Modifies the federal share of project costs for a primary non-hub airport located in a public lands state within 15 miles from the border of another public lands state to use the greater of the two states' federal shares. </p> <p>(Sec. 119G) Amends the FAA Modernization and Reform Act of 2012 to require the FAA to develop a joint plan with the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA), the Department of Energy, and the Department of Agriculture to carry out the required research program on alternative jet fuel technologies for civil aircraft. </p> <p>(Sec. 119H) Expands the pilot program to integrate unmanned aircraft systems into the national airspace system at test ranges to permit the projects to be carried out at unmanned aircraft system flight test centers. </p> <p>(Sec. 119I) Permits the exchange of passenger facility charges between airports to meet the terms and conditions of a transfer agreement. </p> <p>(Sec. 119J) Requires the Government Accountability Office to submit to Congress a report assessing the importance of collegiate aviation flight training operations and the effect of the operations on the economy and infrastructure of airports in the National Plan of Integrated Airport Systems. </p> <p>Provides funding from the Highway Trust Fund (HTF) to the Federal Highway Administration (FHWA) for Administrative Expenses and Federal-Aid Highways. </p> <p>Rescinds specified balances of unused contract authority from the HTF. </p> <p>(Most of DOT's budget is mandatory budget authority rather than discretionary budget authority. The mandatory budget authority is primarily in the form of contract authority derived from the Highway Trust Fund (HTF). Contract authority is the authority to obligate funds in advance of an appropriation Act. </p> <p>Spending from the HTF is determined both by authorization bills and appropriations bills. Authorization bills provide contract authority for highway programs, and appropriations bills include obligation limitations that determine how much of the contract authority may be used in a given year.) </p> <p>(Sec. 120) Specifies allocations and requirements for distributing obligation authority from the HTF among federal-aid highway programs. </p> <p>(Sec. 121) Credits funds received by the Bureau of Transportation Statistics from the sale of data products to the Federal-Aid Highways account to reimburse the bureau for expenses. </p> <p>(Sec. 122) Requires DOT to transfer specified highway funds from Virginia and the District of Columbia to the National Park Service for projects that: (1) are eligible for the Federal Lands Transportation Program, (2) located on bridges on the National Highway System that are in poor condition and that were originally constructed before 1945, and (3) each have an estimated total project cost of not less than $150 million. Specifies that the federal share of the cost of the projects is 100%. </p> <p>(Sec. 123) Requires DOT to: (1) provide an informal public notice and comment opportunity prior to waiving the Buy America requirement for federal-aid highway projects, and (2) report to Congress annually on waivers. </p> <p>(Sec. 124) Requires DOT to notify Congress prior to providing credit assistance under the Transportation Finance and Innovation Act (TIFIA) program, which provides credit to finance surface transportation projects of national and regional significance. </p> <p>(Sec. 125) Permits states to repurpose certain highway project funding to be used within 50 miles of its original designation. </p> <p>(Sec. 126) Requires DOT to notify Congress 60 days in advance before making grants for nationally significant freight and highway projects. </p> <p>(Sec. 127) Amends the Intermodal Surface Transportation Efficiency Act of 1991 to identify specified routes as high priority corridors on the national highway system and as Interstate routes. </p> <p>Provides funding from the HTF to the Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration (FMCSA) for: (1) Motor Carrier Safety Operations and Programs, and (2) Motor Carrier Safety Grants. </p> <p>(Sec. 130) Directs the FMCSA to require certain Mexican motor carriers to meet specified safety requirements when applying to operate beyond U.S. municipalities and commercial zones on the U.S.-Mexico border. </p> <p>(Sec. 131) Amends the Transportation, Housing and Urban Development, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2016 to make a technical correction to a provision prohibiting enforcement of provisions of the Hours of Service rule regarding the restart of a driver's 60- or 70-hour limit after a 34-hour rest period, unless a study demonstrates that the provisions resulted in statistically significant net safety benefits. </p> <p>Provides that, if the results of the study require the 2013 restart rule to be restored, drivers using the 34-hour restart may not drive after being on duty more than 73 hours in a 7-day period. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration (NHTSA) for Operations and Research.</p> <p> Provides funding from the HTF to NHTSA for Operations and Research and Highway Traffic Safety Grants. </p> <p>(Sec. 140) Provides additional funding to NHTSA for travel and related expenses associated with state management reviews and core competency development training for highway safety staff. </p> <p>(Sec. 141) Exempts from the current fiscal year's obligation limitation any obligation authority that was made available in previous public laws. </p> <p>(Sec. 142) Requires DOT to issue a final rule within six months of enactment of this bill that requires the use of speed limiting devices on trucks with a gross vehicle weight rating in excess of 26,000 pounds. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Federal Railroad Administration (FRA) for: </p> <ul> <li> Safety and Operations, </li> <li>Railroad Research and Development, </li> <li> the Railroad Rehabilitation and Improvement Financing Program, </li> <li> Consolidated Rail Infrastructure And Safety Improvements Grants, </li> <li> Federal-State Partnership for State Of Good Repair Grants, </li> <li>Restoration and Enhancement Grants, </li> <li> Northeast Corridor Grants to the National Railroad Passenger Corporation (Amtrak), and </li> <li> National Network Grants to Amtrak. </li> </ul> <p>(Sec. 150) Limits overtime for Amtrak employees. Permits Amtrak to waive the limit for specific employees due to safety or operational efficiency reasons. Requires Amtrak to report to Congress on waivers granted and overtime payments incurred. </p> <p>(Sec. 151) Modifies the limitations and requirements that apply to FRA Restoration and Enhancement Grants that are provided for operating expenses. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Federal Transit Administration (FTA) for: </p> <ul> <li> Administrative Expenses, </li> <li>Capital Investment Grants, and </li> <li> Grants to the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority. </li> </ul> <p>Provides funding from the HTF to the FTA for Transit Formula Grants. </p> <p>(Sec. 160) Exempts previously made transit obligations from limitations on obligations. </p> <p>(Sec. 161) Permits FTA Fixed Guideway Capital Investment funds for projects specified in this bill or the accompanying report that are not obligated by September 30, 2021, to be used for other projects eligible to use the funds for the same purpose. </p> <p>(Sec. 162) Permits prior appropriations that remain available for expenditure to be transferred to the most recent appropriation heading. </p> <p>(Sec. 163) Makes a technical correction to statutory provisions regarding the treatment of a Bi-State Metropolitan Planning Organization as an urbanized area in California and Nevada. </p> <p>(Sec. 164) Rescinds unobligated balances of funds provided in FY2012 or earlier for the job access and reverse commute program. Provides the funds for grants for new fixed guideway capital projects and core capacity improvement projects that provide both public transportation and intercity passenger rail service. </p> <p>(Sec. 165) Permits small transit operators to use urbanized area formula grants for operating assistance based on locally determined planning processes and requirements, subject to limitations. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Saint Lawrence Seaway Development Corporation for Operations and Maintenance. </p> <p>Provides appropriations for the Maritime Administration (MARAD) for: </p> <ul> <li> the Maritime Security Program, </li> <li> Operations and Training, </li> <li> Assistance to Small Shipyards, </li> <li> Ship Disposal, and </li> <li> The Maritime Guaranteed Loan (Title XI) Program Account. </li> </ul> <p>(Sec. 170) Permits MARAD to furnish utilities and services and make repairs in connection with any lease, contract, or occupancy involving government property under the control of MARAD. Requires rental payments received pursuant to this provision to be credited to the Treasury as miscellaneous receipts. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Pipeline and Hazardous Materials Safety Administration (PHMSA) for: </p> <ul> <li> Operational Expenses, </li> <li>Hazardous Materials Safety, </li> <li> Pipeline Safety, and </li> <li> Emergency Preparedness Grants. </li> </ul> <p>Directs PHMSA to: (1) initiate a rulemaking no later than June 30, 2016, to expand the applicability of comprehensive oil spill response plans, and (2) issue a final rule no later than December 18, 2016. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Office of Inspector General. </p> <p>(Sec. 180) Permits DOT to use funds for maintenance and operation of aircraft, hire of passenger motor vehicles and aircraft, insurance for motor vehicles operating in foreign countries, and uniforms. </p> <p>(Sec. 181) Permits DOT to use funds provided by this bill for the employment of temporary or intermittent experts and consultants if the rates do not exceed the rate for an Executive Level IV. </p> <p>(Sec. 182) Prohibits: (1) funds provided by this bill from being used for more than 110 DOT presidential or political appointees, and (2) any of the appointees from being assigned on temporary detail outside of DOT. </p> <p>(Sec. 183) Prohibits recipients of funds provided by this bill from releasing certain personal information and photographs from a driver's license or motor vehicle record without the consent of the affected individual. Prohibits DOT from withholding funds if a state is not in compliance with this provision. </p> <p>(Sec. 184) Permits funds received by specified DOT agencies from states or other private or public sources for training expenses to be credited to specified agency accounts. </p> <p>(Sec. 185) Prohibits DOT funds provided by this bill from being used for a grant or loan unless DOT notifies Congress at least three full business days before making or announcing the grant or loan. </p> <p>(Sec. 186) Permits funds received by DOT from travel management centers, charge card programs, the subleasing of building space, and miscellaneous sources to be credited to DOT appropriations and allocated to elements of DOT using fair and equitable criteria. </p> <p>(Sec. 187) Requires DOT to use amounts recovered from improper payments to a third party contractor for expenses incurred in the recovery. </p> <p>(Sec. 188) Requires reprogramming action notifications to be transmitted to and approved or denied solely by the House and Senate Committees on Appropriations. </p> <p>(Sec. 189) Permits funds provided by this bill for modal administrations to be obligated to the Office of the Secretary for assessments or reimbursable agreements only if the funds provide a direct benefit to the applicable modal administration. </p> <p>(Sec. 190) Permits DOT to set uniform standards for developing and supporting agency transit passes and transit benefits. </p> <p>(Sec. 191) Prohibits the use of funds for any geographic, economic, or other hiring preference not otherwise authorized by law, unless certain requirements are met related to availability of local labor, displacement of existing employees, and delays in transportation plans. </p> <p><i>Department of Housing and Urban Development Appropriations Act, 2017</i></p> <p> TITLE II--DEPARTMENT OF HOUSING AND URBAN DEVELOPMENT </p> <p>Provides FY2017 appropriations for the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD). </p> <p>Provides appropriations for Management and Administration, including for Executive Offices and Administrative Support Offices. </p> <p>Provides appropriations for Program Office Salaries and Expenses, including: </p> <ul> <li> Public and Indian Housing, </li> <li> Community Planning and Development, </li> <li> Housing, </li> <li> Policy Development and Research, </li> <li> Fair Housing and Equal Opportunity, and </li> <li> the Office of Lead Hazard Control and Healthy Homes. </li> </ul> <p>Permits HUD to transfer specified funds provided by this title for salaries and expenses to the Working Capital Fund to fund centralized activities. </p> <p>Provides appropriations for Public and Indian Housing, including: </p> <ul> <li> Tenant-Based Rental Assistance, </li> <li> the Housing Certificate Fund, </li> <li> the Public Housing Capital Fund, </li> <li> the Public Housing Operating Fund, </li> <li> the Choice Neighborhoods Initiative, </li> <li> the Family Self-Sufficiency Program, </li> <li> Indian Block Grants, </li> <li> the Indian Housing Loan Guarantee Fund Program Account, and </li> <li> the Native Hawaiian Housing Block Grant. </li> </ul> <p>Provides appropriations for Community Planning and Development, including: </p> <ul> <li> Housing Opportunities for Persons with AIDS, </li> <li> the Community Development Fund, </li> <li> the Community Development Loan Guarantees Program Account, </li> <li> the Home Investment Partnerships Program, </li> <li> the Self-Help and Assisted Home Ownership Opportunity Program, and </li> <li> Homeless Assistance Grants. </li> </ul> <p>Provides appropriations for Housing Programs, including: </p> <ul> <li> Rental Assistance Demonstration, </li> <li>Project-Based Rental Assistance, </li> <li> Housing for the Elderly, </li> <li> Housing for Persons with Disabilities, </li> <li> Housing Counseling Assistance, </li> <li> Rental Housing Assistance, and </li> <li> Payment to the Manufactured Housing Fees Trust Fund. </li> </ul> <p>Provides appropriations and establishes limits on loan commitments for the Federal Housing Administration (FHA), which includes: </p> <ul> <li>the Mutual Mortgage Insurance Program Account, and </li> <li> the General and Special Risk Program Account. </li> </ul> <p>Provides appropriation and establishes limits on loan commitments for the Government National Mortgage Association (Ginnie Mae). </p> <p>Provides appropriations to HUD for: </p> <ul> <li>Policy Development and Research, </li> <li>Fair Housing and Equal Opportunity, </li> <li> the Office of Lead Hazard Control and Healthy Homes, </li> <li>the Information Technology Fund, and </li> <li> the Office of Inspector General. </li> </ul> <p>(Sec. 201) Requires 50% of the funds that are recaptured from the refinancing of state projects under the Stewart B. McKinney Homeless Assistance Amendments Act of 1988 to be rescinded or, in the case of cash, remitted to the Treasury. Permits HUD to use up to 15% of the funds that are recaptured and not rescinded or remitted to the Treasury to provide project owners with incentives to refinance projects at lower interest rates. </p> <p>(Sec. 202) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to investigate or prosecute under the Fair Housing Act any lawful activities, including the filing or maintaining of a nonfrivolous legal action to achieve or prevent action by a government entity or a court. </p> <p>(Sec. 203) Requires HUD to make certain adjustments to the formula for distributing Housing Opportunities for Persons With AIDS (HOPWA) funds for certain jurisdictions in New York, New Jersey, Delaware, and North Carolina. </p> <p>(Sec. 204) Requires any grant, cooperative agreement, or other assistance made pursuant to this title to be made on a competitive basis and in accordance with the Department of Housing and Urban Development Reform Act of 1989. </p> <p>(Sec. 205) Permits specified funds to be used, without regard to limitations on administrative expenses, for: (1) legal services; and (2) payment for services and facilities of the Federal National Mortgage Association (Fannie Mae), Ginnie Mae, the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation (Freddie Mac), the Federal Financing Bank, Federal Reserve banks, Federal Home Loan banks, and any bank insured under the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation Act. </p> <p>(Sec. 206) Prohibits HUD appropriations from being used for any program, project, or activity in excess of amounts included in the budget estimates submitted to Congress, unless otherwise provided by this bill or through reprogramming. </p> <p>(Sec. 207) Permits HUD corporations and agencies subject to the Government Corporation Control Act to utilize funds and make contracts and commitments, without regard to fiscal year limitations and subject to specified restrictions, to implement the FY2017 budget. </p> <p>(Sec. 208) Requires HUD to provide quarterly reports to Congress regarding uncommitted, unobligated, recaptured, and excess funds for each program and activity. </p> <p>(Sec. 209) Requires the President's budget request and HUD's congressional budget justifications to use the same account structure included in this bill. </p> <p>(Sec. 210) Provides that a public housing agency (PHA) or other entity that administers federal housing assistance for the Housing Authority of the county of Los Angeles, California; and the states of Alaska, Iowa, and Mississippi is not required to include public housing residents or recipients of section 8 rental assistance (under the United States Housing Act of 1937) on the governing board. </p> <p>Requires each PHA or entity that does not include these individuals on its board to establish an advisory board of at least six residents of public housing or recipients of section 8 assistance to provide advice on issues related to public housing and section 8. </p> <p>(Sec. 211) Exempts Ginnie Mae from certain requirements of the Federal Credit Reform Act of 1990. </p> <p>(Sec. 212) Permits HUD to authorize the transfer of project-based assistance, debt, and use restrictions associated with a multifamily housing project from obsolete or economically nonviable housing to housing that better meets the needs of the assisted tenants, subject to specified requirements. </p> <p>(Sec. 213) Sets forth eligibility requirements for section 8 housing assistance vouchers. </p> <p>(Sec. 214) Requires Indian Block Grant funds to be distributed to the same Native Alaskans that received funds in FY2005. </p> <p>(Sec. 215) Permits HUD to insure home equity conversion mortgages (HECMs or reverse mortgages) for elderly homeowners through FY2017, notwithstanding limitations on insurance authority included in the National Housing Act. </p> <p>(Sec. 216) Sets forth requirements for HUD to maintain section 8 assistance on multifamily housing that is held or owned by HUD. </p> <p>(Sec. 217) Permits Community Development Loan Guarantee funds to be used to guarantee notes or other obligations issued by any state on behalf of its non-entitlement communities. </p> <p>(Sec. 218) Permits certain PHAs that own and operate 400 or fewer public housing units to be exempt from asset management requirements imposed by HUD in connection with the operating fund rule. </p> <p>(Sec. 219) Prohibits HUD from using public housing funds to impose any requirement or guideline relating to asset management that restricts or limits the use of capital funds for central office costs, up to the limits established in the Quality Housing and Work Responsibility Act of 1998. </p> <p>(Sec. 220) Prohibits the designation of a HUD official or employee as an allotment holder unless the Chief Financial Officer has determined that the employee has: (1) implemented an adequate system of funds control, and (2) received training in funds control procedures and directives. </p> <p>(Sec. 221) Requires HUD to publish on the Internet all competitively awarded Notices of Funding Availability for FY2017 and subsequent years. </p> <p>(Sec. 222) Sets forth limitations and reporting requirements for the payment of attorney fees in program-related litigation. </p> <p>(Sec. 223) Sets forth requirements for transferring and reprogramming funds within specified HUD Administrative Support Office and Program Office Salaries and Expenses accounts. </p> <p>(Sec. 224) Permits the Disaster Housing Assistance Programs administered by HUD to be considered HUD programs for the purpose of income verification and matching. </p> <p>(Sec. 225) Requires HUD to take specified actions against owners who are receiving rental subsidies and do not maintain safe properties. </p> <p>(Sec. 226) Limits compensation for PHA officials and employees. </p> <p>(Sec. 227) Amends the United States Housing Act of 1937 to extend the HOPE VI program through FY2017. (The program provides funds to renovate or demolish existing public housing and replace it with mixed-income housing.) </p> <p>(Sec. 228) Requires HUD to notify Congress prior to announcing the recipients of grant awards. </p> <p>(Sec. 229) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to require or enforce the Physical Needs Assessment (PNA). </p> <p>(Sec. 230) Prohibits funds provided by this bill or receipts collected under FHA programs from being used to implement the Homeowners Armed with Knowledge (HAWK) program. </p> <p>(Sec. 231) Prohibits the FHA, Ginnie Mae, or HUD from using funds provided by this bill to finance mortgages for properties that have been subject to eminent domain. </p> <p>(Sec. 232) Prohibits the use of funds made available by this bill to terminate the status of a unit of general local government as a metropolitan city with respect to community development grants under the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974. </p> <p>(Sec. 233) Permits Office of Policy Development and Research funds for research, evaluation, and statistical purposes that are unexpended at the completion of a contract, grant or cooperative agreement to be used for additional research, subject to reprogramming requirements. </p> <p>(Sec. 234) Prohibits funds provided by this title from being used to pay a bonus to an employee who is subject to administrative discipline, including suspension from work. </p> <p>(Sec. 235) Permits HUD to use funds provided for Homeless Assistance Grants to participate in the multiagency Performance Partnerships Pilots program on a limited basis. </p> <p>(Sec. 236) Permits costs paid by the program income of grant recipients to count toward the recipient's matching requirements for 2015, 2016 and 2017 Continuum of Care funds. (The program awards project sponsors or unified funding agencies competitive grants focused on addressing the long-term housing and services needs of homeless individuals and families.) </p> <p>(Sec. 237) Permits HUD to consolidate funds used to manage disaster recovery grants. </p> <p>(Sec. 238) Amends the Lead-Based Paint Poisoning Prevention Act, the Residential Lead-Based Paint Hazard Reduction Act of 1992, and the Toxic Substances Control Act to treat zero-bedroom dwellings in the same manner as other housing units, for the purposes of grants and other provisions of the laws. </p> <p>(Sec. 239) Allows PHAs to establish replacement reserves to address capital needs. </p> <p>(Sec. 240) Amends the United States Housing Act of 1937 to change the requirements for the family unification program. </p> <p>(Sec. 241) Permits HUD to establish a demonstration program to provide incentives to PHAs that reduce energy or water consumption. </p> <p>(Sec. 242) Amends the Department of Housing and Urban Development Appropriations Act, 2008 to repeal the requirement for HUD to report annually to Congress on the number and cost of federally assisted units under lease. </p> <p>(Sec. 243) Permits HUD to provide mobility counseling to housing choice voucher participants to encourage families to move to lower-poverty areas and expand access to opportunity areas. </p> <p>(Sec. 244) Amends the Department of Housing and Urban Development Appropriations Act, 2012 to modify requirements for the Rental Assistance Demonstration program. </p> <p>(Sec. 245) Permits HUD to implement through notice a provision of the Fixing America's Surface Transportation Act regarding the review of tenant incomes. Requires HUD to begin the rulemaking process within six months of issuing the notice. </p> <p>(Sec. 246) Permits HUD to use funds provided for the Continuum of Care (CoC) program to renew a specified grant awarded in the Supplemental Appropriations Act, 2008. Permits the state of Louisiana to continue to permit a program participant to receive or retain tenant-based rental assistance outside the CoC's geographic area without the funding of the assistance being considered the operation of a CoC in more than one geographic area. </p> <p>(Sec. 247) Amends the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act to permit HUD to award one-year transition grants to recipients to transition from one CoC program component to another.</p> <p> (Sec. 248) Permits a jurisdiction to continue to draw from its HOME Investment Trust Fund funds that have otherwise expired or would expire in 2016, 2017, 2018, or 2019 under the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act. </p> <p>(Sec. 249) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to provide housing assistance benefits for an individual who is convicted of: aggravated sexual abuse, murder, or any other federal or state offense involving child pornography or severe forms of trafficking in persons or sex trafficking. </p> <p>(Sec. 250) Requires HUD to prepare and post on its website a report regarding Real Estate Assessment Center inspections of all properties assisted, insured, or both, under a HUD program. </p> <p>(Sec. 251) Prohibits HUD from using funds provided by this bill to direct a grantee to undertake specific changes to existing zoning laws as part of carrying out the final rule entitled &quot;Affirmatively Furthering Fair Housing&quot; or the notice entitled &quot;Affirmatively Furthering Fair Housing Assessment Tool.&quot; </p> <p>TITLE III--RELATED AGENCIES </p> <p>Provides FY2017 appropriations to: </p> <ul> <li> the Access Board,</li> <li> the Federal Maritime Commission, </li> <li> the Amtrak Office of Inspector General, </li> <li> the National Transportation Safety Board, </li> <li> the Neighborhood Reinvestment Corporation, </li> <li> the U.S. Interagency Council on Homelessness, and </li> <li> the Surface Transportation Board. </li> </ul> <p>(Sec. 301) Requires the United States Interagency Council on Homelessness to submit to Congress a report that assesses how federal housing programs and federal health programs could better collaborate to reduce costs and improve health and housing outcomes. </p> <p>TITLE IV--GENERAL PROVISIONS--THIS ACT </p> <p>Sets forth permissible and prohibited uses for funds provided by this and other appropriations Acts.</p> <p>(Sec. 401) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to compensate or pay the expenses of non-federal parties intervening in regulatory or adjudicatory proceedings funded in this bill. </p> <p>(Sec. 402) Prohibits transfers of funds to other appropriations or obligations beyond the current fiscal year, unless expressly permitted in this bill. </p> <p>(Sec. 403) Limits expenditures for consulting services to contracts where the expenditures are a matter of public record and available for public inspection, unless otherwise provided by law. </p> <p>(Sec. 404) Prohibits the use of funds provided by this bill for employee training not specifically related to the performance of official duties. </p> <p>(Sec. 405) Specifies procedures, restrictions, and reporting requirements for the reprogramming of funds provided by this bill. </p> <p>(Sec. 406) Permits up to 50% of unobligated balances remaining at the end of FY2017 from appropriations for salaries and expenses to remain available through FY2018, subject to congressional approval and reprogramming guidelines. </p> <p>(Sec. 407) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used for any project that seeks to use eminent domain unless eminent domain is employed only for a public use. </p> <p>(Sec. 408) Prohibits the transfer of funds provided by this bill to a department, agency, or instrumentality of the U.S. government unless the transfer is pursuant to an appropriations Act. </p> <p>(Sec. 409) Prohibits the use of funds provided by this bill to permanently replace an employee intent on returning to his or her previous occupation after completing military service. </p> <p>(Sec. 410) Requires expenditures of funds provided by this bill to comply with the Buy American Act. </p> <p>(Sec. 411) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being made available to any person or entity that has been convicted of violating the Buy American Act. </p> <p>(Sec. 412) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to purchase first class or premium airline travel in violation of specified federal travel regulations. </p> <p>(Sec. 413) Prohibits the use of funds provided by this bill to approve a new foreign air carrier permit or exemption application if the approval would contravene U.S. law or specified provisions of the U.S.-E.U.-Iceland-Norway Air Transport Agreement. </p> <p>(Sec. 414) Restricts the number of employees that agencies funded in this bill may send to international conferences.</p> <p> (Sec. 415) Limits Surface Transportation Board fees for the filing of rate or practice complaints. </p> <p>(Sec. 416) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to purchase new light-duty vehicles, except in accordance with Presidential Memorandum- Federal Fleet Performance, which establishes requirements for purchasing alternative fueled vehicles. </p> <p>(Sec. 417) Requires departments and agencies funded by this bill to provide an Inspector General (IG) funded by this bill with timely access to records, documents, or other materials available to the department or agency over which the IG has responsibility. Requires each IG to comply with specified statutory limitations on disclosure of the information provided.</p> <p>DIVISION B--MILITARY CONSTRUCTION, THE DEPARTMENT OF VETERANS AFFAIRS, AND RELATED AGENCIES </p> <p>TITLE I--DEPARTMENT OF DEFENSE </p> <p>Provides appropriations to DOD for Military Construction for: </p> <ul> <li> the Army; </li> <li>the Navy and Marine Corps; </li> <li> the Air Force; </li> <li> Defense-Wide agencies and activities (other than military departments); </li> <li> the Army and Air National Guard; and </li> <li> the Army, Navy, and Air Force Reserves. </li> </ul> <p>Provides appropriations to DOD for the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) Security Investment Program. </p> <p>Provides appropriations for the Department of Defense Base Closure Account. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to DOD for Construction and Operation and Maintenance of Family Housing for: </p> <ul> <li> the Army, </li> <li>the Navy and Marine Corps, </li> <li> the Air Force, and </li> <li> Defense-Wide agencies and activities (other than military departments). </li> </ul> <p>Provides appropriations for the Department of Defense Family Housing Improvement Fund. </p> <p>(Sec. 101) Prohibits funds provided by this title from being used for payments exceeding $25,000 for construction in the United States under a cost-plus-a-fixed-fee contract without DOD approval. Includes an exception for work that is to be performed in Alaska. </p> <p>(Sec. 102) Permits construction funds provided by this title to be used for hiring passenger motor vehicles. </p> <p>(Sec. 103) Permits construction funds provided by this title to be used for advances to the Federal Highway Administration for the construction of access roads DOD has certified as important to national defense. </p> <p>(Sec. 104) Prohibits funds provided by this title from being used to begin construction of new bases in the United States without a specific appropriation. </p> <p>(Sec. 105) Prohibits funds provided by this title from being used to purchase land or land easements in excess of 100% of the value as determined by the Army Corps of Engineers or the Naval Facilities Engineering Command. Includes exceptions for: (1) determinations of value by a federal court, (2) purchases negotiated by the Attorney General or a designee, (3) values less than $25,000, and (4) DOD determinations that the purchase is in the public interest. </p> <p>(Sec. 106) Prohibits funds provided by this title from being used to acquire land, provide for site preparation, or install utilities for family housing, except housing for which appropriations have been provided.</p> <p> (Sec. 107) Prohibits funds provided by this title for minor construction from being used to transfer or relocate any activity from one base or installation to another without notifying Congress in advance. </p> <p>(Sec. 108) Prohibits funds provided by this title from being used to procure steel for construction unless American producers, fabricators, and manufacturers have been allowed to compete for the procurement. </p> <p>(Sec. 109) Prohibits funds provided to DOD for military construction or family housing during the current fiscal year from being used to pay real property taxes in any foreign nation. </p> <p>(Sec. 110) Prohibits funds provided by this title from being used to initiate a new installation overseas without notifying Congress in advance. </p> <p>(Sec. 111) Prohibits funds provided by this title from being used for architect and engineer contracts estimated to exceed $500,000 for projects in Japan, NATO member countries, or countries bordering the Arabian Gulf unless the contracts are awarded to U.S. firms or joint ventures with U.S. firms. </p> <p>(Sec. 112) Prohibits funds provided by this title for military construction in U.S. territories and possessions in the Pacific and on Kwajalein Atoll, or in countries bordering the Arabian Gulf from being used to award a contract over $1 million to a foreign contractor. Includes exceptions. </p> <p>(Sec. 113) Requires DOD to notify Congress in advance of military exercises if construction costs are expected to exceed $100,000. </p> <p>(Sec. 114) Permits funds provided to DOD for construction in prior years to be used for construction projects authorized during the current session of Congress.</p> <p> (Sec. 115) Permits expired or lapsed funds to be used to pay for supervision, inspection, overhead, engineering, and design costs for military construction or family housing projects being completed with lapsed or expired funds. </p> <p>(Sec. 116) Permits funds provided for the construction of military projects to be available for five years if: (1) the funds are obligated from funds available for military construction, and (2) do not exceed the amount appropriated or permitted by law. </p> <p>(Sec. 117) Permits the following transfers if Congress is notified and specified conditions are met: </p> <ul> <li> to the Department of Defense Family Housing Improvement Fund from appropriations for construction in Family Housing accounts, and </li> <li> to the Department of Defense Military Unaccompanied Housing Improvement Fund from appropriations for construction of military unaccompanied housing in Military Construction accounts. </li> </ul> <p>(Sec. 118) Permits the transfer of funds from the Department of Defense Base Closure Account to the fund established to pay expenses associated with the Homeowners Assistance Program under the Demonstration Cities and Metropolitan Development Act of 1966.</p> <p> (Sec. 119) Provides that funds for operation and maintenance of family housing in this title shall be the only source of funds for repair and maintenance of all family housing units, including general or flag officer quarters. Sets forth limitations and requirements for expenditures for maintenance and repair of general or flag officer quarters. </p> <p>(Sec. 120) Appropriates funds contained in the Ford Island Improvement Account to remain available until expended or transferred.</p> <p> (Sec. 121) Permits the transfer of unobligated balances of expired military construction and family housing funds into the Foreign Currency Fluctuations--Construction--Defense account. </p> <p>(Sec. 122) Permits funds provided to an account in this title to be transferred among projects and activities within the account subject to specified DOD reprogramming guidelines for military and family housing construction. </p> <p>(Sec. 123) Prohibits DOD military construction funds provided in this title from being used for the planning, design, and construction of projects at Arlington National Cemetery. </p> <p>(Sec. 124) Defines &quot;congressional defense committees&quot; to include the House and Senate Armed Services Committees and Appropriations Subcommittees on Military Construction and Veterans Affairs. </p> <p>(Sec. 125) Provides specified additional funds to remain available through FY2021 for unfunded military construction priorities. </p> <p>(Sec. 126) Rescinds specified unobligated balances from several military construction accounts. </p> <p>(Sec. 127) Prohibits funds from being used to consolidate or relocate any element of a U.S. Air Force Rapid Engineer Deployable Heavy Operational Repair Squadron Engineer (RED HORSE) squadron outside of the United States until the Air Force: (1) submits to Congress an analysis and comparison of the cost and investment required to consolidate or relocate a RED HORSE squadron outside of the United States versus within the United States, and (2) certifies to Congress that the preferred site yields the greatest savings. </p> <p>(Sec. 128) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used for the closure or transfer of the U.S. Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba. </p> <p>(Sec. 129) Requires the Government Accountability Office (GAO) to submit to Congress a report assessing the extent to which DOD has developed a comprehensive force structure plan, including military construction requirements, to meet emerging security threats in Europe. </p> <p>(Sec. 130) Makes a technical correction to a provision of the Military Construction, Veterans Affairs, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2016 which provided FY2016 funding for advances to the Federal Highway Administration for the construction of defense access roads. </p> <p>(Sec. 131) Requires the Army to submit to Congress a report including specified details regarding the aircraft maintenance hangars of the Army's Combat Aviation Brigade. </p> <p>(Sec. 132) Requires DOD to submit to Congress a report on the use of defense access road funding to build alternate routes for military equipment traveling to missile launch facilities, taking into consideration the location of local populations, security risks, safety, and impacts of weather. </p> <p>TITLE II--DEPARTMENT OF VETERANS AFFAIRS </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Veterans Benefits Administration (VBA) for: </p> <ul> <li> Compensation and Pensions, </li> <li> Readjustment Benefits, </li> <li> Veterans Insurance and Indemnities, </li> <li> the Veterans Housing Benefit Program Fund, </li> <li> the Vocational Rehabilitation Loans Program Account, </li> <li> the Native American Veteran Housing Loan Program Account, and </li> <li> General Operating Expenses. </li> </ul> <p>Provides appropriations to the Veterans Health Administration (VHA) for: </p> <ul> <li>Medical Services, </li> <li>Medical Community Care, </li> <li>Medical Support and Compliance, </li> <li> Medical Facilities, and </li> <li> Medical and Prosthetic Research. </li> </ul> <p>Provides appropriations to the National Cemetery Administration. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the VA for Departmental Administration, including: </p> <ul> <li> General Administration, </li> <li> the Board of Veterans Appeals, </li> <li> Information Technology Systems, </li> <li>the Office of Inspector General, </li> <li> Construction--Major Projects, </li> <li> Construction--Minor Projects, </li> <li> Grants for Construction of State Extended Care Facilities, and </li> <li> Grants for Construction of Veterans Cemeteries. </li> </ul> <p>Prohibits the expenditure of specified information technology funds for the Veterans Health Information Systems and Technology Architecture (VistA) Evolution Program until the VA: </p> <ul> <li> certifies to Congress that it has met the requirements for the DOD and VA electronic health record systems to reach interoperability and complied with national standards and architectural requirements identified by the DoD/VA Interagency Program Office; and </li> <li>submits to Congress reports including specified details regarding the status, costs, and plans for the program. </li> </ul> <p>Withholds specified VHA construction funds until the VA: </p> <ul> <li> enters an agreement with a non-VA federal entity to serve as the design and/ or construction agent for any VHA major construction project that exceeds $100 million, and </li> <li>certifies that an agreement is executed to minimize or prevent subsequent major construction project cost overruns. </li> </ul> <p>(Sec. 201) Specifies transfer authorities and requirements for the VBA. </p> <p>(Sec. 202) Specifies transfer authorities and requirements for the VHA. </p> <p>(Sec. 203) Permits appropriations for salaries and expenses to be used for employment of temporary or intermittent experts and consultants, hire of passenger vehicles, lease of a facility or land, and uniforms. </p> <p>(Sec. 204) Prohibits appropriations in this title other than Construction--Major Projects and Construction--Minor Projects from being used for land acquisition or construction of any new hospital or home. </p> <p>(Sec. 205) Requires the VA to be reimbursed for medical services it provides to any person not defined as a beneficiary under specified laws. </p> <p>(Sec. 206) Permits appropriations provided by this title for Compensation and Pensions, Readjustment Benefits, and Veterans Insurance and Indemnities to be used for payment of accrued obligations for the accounts recorded in the last quarter of FY2016. </p> <p>(Sec. 207) Permits appropriations provided by this title to be used to pay specified prior year obligations. Requires obligations from trust fund accounts to be paid only from the Compensation and Pensions account. </p> <p>(Sec. 208) Requires the VA to use surplus earnings from the National Service Life Insurance Fund, the Veterans' Special Life Insurance Fund, and the United States Government Life Insurance Fund to reimburse the General Operating Expenses--Veterans Benefits Administration and Information Technology Systems accounts for the costs to administer the insurance programs during FY2017. </p> <p>(Sec. 209) Permits amounts deducted from enhanced-use lease proceeds for reimbursement of expenses from a prior year to be obligated in the year in which the proceeds are received. </p> <p>(Sec. 210) Permits funds provided by this title for salaries and other administrative expenses to be used to reimburse the Office of Resolution Management and the Office of Employment Discrimination Complaint Adjudication within specified limits. </p> <p>(Sec. 211) Prohibits funds from being used to close or diminish services at certain VA medical facilities until the VA submits to Congress a national realignment strategy. </p> <p>(Sec. 212) Requires the VA to collect third-party reimbursement information prior to providing hospital care, nursing home care, or medical services for a non-service connected disability. Permits the VA to recover reasonable charges for care from anyone who has not provided the required disclosures. </p> <p>(Sec. 213) Permits enhanced-use leasing revenues to be deposited into the Construction--Major Projects and Construction--Minor Projects accounts to be used for construction, alterations, and improvements of VA medical facilities. </p> <p>(Sec. 214) Permits funds provided for Medical Services to be used for: (1) furnishing recreational facilities, supplies, and equipment; and (2) funeral and burial expenses. </p> <p>(Sec. 215) Permits funds deposited in the Medical Care Collections Fund to be transferred to the Medical Services and Medical Community Care accounts and remain available until expended for the purposes of those accounts. </p> <p>(Sec. 216) Permits the VA to enter into agreements with certain Indian tribes and tribal organizations in rural Alaska to provide health care to veterans. </p> <p>(Sec. 217) Permits funds deposited into the Department of Veterans Affairs Capital Asset Fund to be transferred to the Construction--Major Projects and Construction--Minor Projects accounts to remain available until expended. </p> <p>(Sec. 218) Rescinds specified funds from the Medical Services account to enable the establishment of the Medical Community Care account. </p> <p>(Sec. 219) Requires the VA to submit quarterly financial reports to Congress. </p> <p>(Sec. 220) Permits specified FY2017 VA funds to be transferred to or from the Information Technology Systems account if approved by Congress. </p> <p>(Sec. 221) Prohibits funds from being used to: (1) convert to contractor performance an activity or function performed by more than 10 federal employees unless the conversion is based on the result of a public-private competition that meets specified criteria, or (2) conduct studies comparing the costs of private and government provision of certain VHA products and services without a specific appropriation for that purpose.</p> <p> (Sec. 222) Permits specified FY2017 VA funds provided for medical accounts, Construction--Minor Projects, and Information Technology Systems to be transferred to the Joint Department of Defense-Department of Veterans Affairs Medical Facility Demonstration Fund and used for the operation of combined federal medical facilities. </p> <p>(Sec. 223) Permits specified FY2018 VA advance funding provided for medical accounts to be transferred to the Joint Department of Defense-Department of Veterans Affairs Medical Facility Demonstration Fund and used for the operation of combined federal medical facilities. </p> <p>(Sec. 224) Permits transfers from the Medical Care Collections Fund to the Joint Department of Defense-Department of Veterans Affairs Medical Facility Demonstration Fund for the operation of combined federal medical facilities. </p> <p>(Sec. 225) Requires specified funds from the Medical Services, Medical Support and Compliance, and Medical Facilities accounts to be transferred to the DOD-VA Health Care Sharing Incentive Fund to remain available until expended. </p> <p>(Sec. 226) Prohibits the VA from using funds to replace the current system that the Veterans Integrated Service Networks use to select and contract for diabetes monitoring supplies and equipment. </p> <p>(Sec. 227) Directs the VA to notify Congress of all bid savings in major construction projects that total at least $5 million or 5% of the programmed amount of the project, whichever is less. </p> <p>(Sec. 228) Prohibits the scope of work for a project included in Construction--Major Projects from being increased above the original budget request without congressional approval. </p> <p>(Sec. 229) Require the VA to submit to Congress a report including specified details regarding claims processing at VBA regional offices. </p> <p>(Sec. 230) Limits funds from the Medical Support and Compliance account that may be used for the Veterans Health Information Systems and Technology Architecture (VistA) Evolution and electronic health record interoperability projects. Permits additional funds to be obligated for this purpose if Congress is notified in advance. </p> <p>(Sec. 231) Directs the VA to notify Congress before organizational changes that result in the transfer of 25 or more full-time equivalent staff from one organizational unit to another.</p> <p> (Sec. 232) Permits FY2017 funds provided for the Board of Veterans Appeals and General Operating Expenses--Veterans Benefits Administration to be transferred between those accounts if Congress approves the transfer. </p> <p>(Sec. 233) Rescinds specified unobligated balances from the DOD-VA Health Care Sharing Incentive Fund. </p> <p>(Sec. 234) Prohibits the VA from reprogramming more than $5 million in funds among major construction projects or programs without congressional approval. </p> <p>(Sec. 235) Prohibits the VA from transferring funds from the Filipino Veterans Equity Compensation Fund to any other VA account. </p> <p>(Sec. 236) Amends the Veterans' Mental Health and Other Care Improvements Act of 2008 to extend through FY2018 the pilot program to provide health care services to veterans in rural areas by contracting with non-VA health care providers </p> <p>(Sec. 237) Eliminates copayments for: (1) opioid antagonists that are provided to a veteran who is at high risk for overdose of a specific medication or substance in order to reverse the effect of an overdose, and (2) education on the use of opioid antagonists to reverse the effects of overdoses of a specific medication or substance. </p> <p>(Sec. 238) Specifies requirements for the Office of Inspector General to provide the VA, Congress, and other entities with access to its reports. </p> <p>(Sec. 239) Permits the VA to offer grants and enter into cooperative agreements with organizations to train and employ homeless and at-risk veterans in natural resource conservation management. </p> <p>(Sec. 240) Requires the VA to seek to enter an agreement with the National Academy of Medicine for a study of the descendants of veterans with toxic exposure while serving in the Armed Forces. </p> <p>(Sec. 241) Provides specified funds from the Medical Services account to carry out and expand to each VA medical center the pilot program for providing child care assistance to veterans receiving health care. </p> <p>(Sec. 242) Requires the VA to disclose to a state controlled substance monitoring program information about a veteran or a dependent that is necessary to prevent misuse and diversion of prescription medicine. </p> <p>(Sec. 243) Requires the VA to include in its hiring process for medical providers a requirement to obtain from the medical board of each state in which the provider holds or has held a medical license information regarding: </p> <ul> <li> violations of the requirements of the medical license, and </li> <li> settlement agreements entered into for a disciplinary charge relating to the practice of medicine. </li> </ul> <p>(Sec. 244) Requires the VA to provide state medical boards with information regarding VA health care providers that have violated a requirement of their medical licenses. </p> <p>(Sec. 245) Permits the VA to transfer funds from any VA account if the transfer is necessary for providing health care, benefits and other services, subject to specified requirements and limits. </p> <p>(Sec. 246) Establishes additional procedures for filing whistle-blower complaints at the VA and for protecting whistle-blowers from retaliation. </p> <p>Permits VA employees to file complaints with immediate and next-level supervisors, and ultimately with the VA after having properly filed a complaint at each supervisory level. </p> <p>Provides that, if a supervisor makes a positive determination regarding a complaint, the VA must: (1) inform the employee of the ability to volunteer for a transfer, and (2) give preference to the transfer. </p> <p>Requires the central VA whistle-blower office to investigate all complaints, regardless of whether the complaints are made by or against an employee who is not a Senior Executive Service member. </p> <p>Requires the VA to: (1) carry out specified adverse actions against supervisors that retaliate by committing prohibited personnel actions relating to a complaint, and (2) provide employees with annual training regarding whistle-blower complaints. </p> <p>(Sec. 247) Provides specified funds from the Medical Services account for the provision of fertility treatment and counseling, including treatment using assisted reproductive technology, to veterans and their spouses if the veteran has a service-connected condition that results in being unable to procreate without the use of the fertility treatment. </p> <p>(Sec. 248) Prohibits funds provided by title II of this bill from being used to carry out the Home Marketing Incentive Program or the Appraisal Value Offer Program with respect to VA employees in senior executive positions. Permits the VA to waive the prohibition to recruit for a position for which recruitment or retention of qualified personnel is likely to be difficult without the incentives. </p> <p>(Sec. 249) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to: </p> <ul> <li> interfere with the ability of veterans to participate in a state-approved medicinal marijuana program; </li> <li>deny services to veterans participating in a program; or </li> <li> limit or interfere with the ability of a VA health care provider to comply with a program. </li> </ul> <p>(Sec. 250) Specifies documentation that DOD may accept to verify that a coastwise merchant seaman performed active duty service under honorable conditions. Permits the individuals whose service is recognized as honorable to be: (1) awarded an appropriate medal, ribbon, or other military decoration based on the service; and (2) honored as a veteran with benefits limited to those described in this provision. </p> <p>(Sec. 251) Requires the VA Readjustment Counseling Service to coordinate directly with the VA Office of Rural Health on efforts to expand the capacity of Vet Centers in order to ensure that the readjustment and psychological counseling needs of veterans in rural and highly rural communities are met. </p> <p>Requires the VA to report to Congress on the number of Vet Centers operated by the VA and a strategic plan to increase the capacity of the Vet Centers to address unmet readjustment and psychological counseling needs of veterans in rural and highly rural communities. </p> <p>(Sec. 252) Permits the VA to provide a monthly assistance allowance to certain disabled veterans competing on U.S. Olympic teams. </p> <p>(Sec. 253) Adds coverage under the VA beneficiary travel program for the travel expenses of a veteran with vision impairment, a spinal cord injury or disorder, or double or multiple amputations whose travel is in connection with care provided through a special disabilities rehabilitation program of the VA if the care is provided on an in-patient basis and during a period in which the VA provides the veteran with temporary lodging at a VA facility to make the care more accessible. </p> <p>Requires the VA to report to Congress on beneficiary travel program, including the cost and the number of veterans served by the program. </p> <p>(Sec. 254) Requires the VA to provide for annual inspections of kitchens and food service areas at each VA medical facility to ensure that the same standards for kitchens and food service areas at hospitals in the private sector are being met at VA medical facilities. Specifies requirements for an agreement for the inspections, a remediation plan, and reports to Congress. </p> <p>(Sec. 255) Requires the VA to provide for annual inspections of mold issues at VA medical facilities. Specifies requirements for an agreement for the inspections, a remediation plan, and reports to Congress. </p> <p>(Sec. 256) Adds coverage under the VA beneficiary travel program for the travel expenses of a veteran with vision impairment, a spinal cord injury or disorder, or double or multiple amputations whose travel is in connection with care provided through a special disabilities rehabilitation program of the VA if the care is provided on an in-patient basis and during a period in which the VA provides the veteran with temporary lodging at a VA facility to make the care more accessible.</p> <p>Requires the VA to report to Congress on beneficiary travel program, including the cost and the number of veterans served by the program. </p> <p>(Sec. 257) Extends a requirement for the VA to report to Congress on its capacity to provide for specialized treatment and rehabilitative needs of disabled veterans. </p> <p>(Sec. 258) Permits specified Medical Support and Compliance funds to be provided to the Directors of Veterans Integrated Service Networks to contract with non-VA entities to assess, evaluate, and improve the health care delivery by and business operations of medical centers under the jurisdiction of each director. </p> <p>(Sec. 259) Requires the VA to submit to Congress an assessment of whether the hiring of marriage and family therapists trained at Commission on Accreditation for Marriage and Family Therapy Education accredited institutions is adversely impacting the ability of VA to hire marriage and family therapists. </p> <p>(Sec. 260) Requires the VA Office of the Inspector General to conduct an inspection or an audit of the use of specified funds that were awarded in 2013 to renovate a veteran's cemetery in Guam under the Veterans Cemetery Grants Program. Requires the VA to publish the results of the audit or inspection on a publicly available website of the department. </p> <p>(Sec. 261) Permits the VA to use funds provided by this title to ensure that the ratio of veterans to full-time employment equivalents within any rehabilitation program does not exceed 125 veterans to one full-time employment equivalent. </p> <p>Requires the VA to report to Congress on rehabilitation programs including: (1) an assessment of the veteran-to-staff ratio for each program, and (2) recommendations to reduce the veteran-to-staff ratio for each program. </p> <p>(Sec. 262) Requires the VA to submit to Congress a plan to modernize the VHA system for processing claims by non-VA health care providers for reimbursement for health care provided to veterans under the laws administered by VA. </p> <p>(Sec. 263) Authorizes appropriations for the VA to carry out specified major medical facility projects. </p> <p>(Sec. 264) Requires departments and agencies funded by this bill to provide an Inspector General (IG) funded by this bill with timely access to records, documents, or other materials available to the department or agency over which the IG has responsibility. Requires each IG to comply with specified statutory limitations on disclosure of the information provided.</p> <p>(Sec. 265) Requires the VA to submit to Congress an update on the progress in completing the Rural Veterans Burial Initiative and the expected timeline for completion of the initiative. </p> <p>(Sec. 266) Requires the VA to use specified funds provided for Medical Support and Compliance to hire Medical Center Directors and employees for other management and clinical positions that are critical to VA in order to fill vacancies in the positions. </p> <p>(Sec. 267) Prohibits the VA from using funds provided by this title to enter into an agreement related to resolving a dispute or claim with an individual that would restrict the individual from speaking to members of Congress or their staff on any topic not otherwise prohibited from disclosure by federal law. </p> <p>(Sec. 268) Requires the VA to deny or revoke the eligibility of a health care provider to provide non-department health care services to veterans if the VA determines that the provider: </p> <ul> <li> was removed from VA employment due to conduct that violated a policy of the department relating to the delivery of safe and appropriate patient care,</li> <li> violated the requirements of a medical license,</li> <li> had a department credential revoked for grounds that impact the ability to deliver safe and appropriate care, or </li> <li> violated a law for which a term of imprisonment of more than one year may be imposed. </li> </ul> <p>Permits the VA to deny, revoke, or suspend the eligibility of a health care provider to provide non-department health care services if the VA has a reasonable belief that the action is necessary to immediately protect the health, safety, or welfare of veterans and: </p> <ul> <li> the health care provider is under investigation by the medical licensing board of a state in which the provider is licensed or practices,</li> <li> the health care provider has entered into a settlement agreement for a disciplinary charge relating to the practice of medicine, or </li> <li> the VA otherwise determines that the action is appropriate under the circumstances. </li> </ul> <p>Requires the VA to suspend the eligibility of a health care provider to provide non-department health care services to veterans if the health care provider is suspended from serving as a health care provider of the department. </p> <p>TITLE III--RELATED AGENCIES </p> <p>Provides appropriations for related agencies, including: </p> <ul> <li> the American Battle Monuments Commission; </li> <li>the U.S. Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims, </li> <li> Cemeterial Expenses of the Army, including Arlington National Cemetery and Soldiers' and Airmen's Home National Cemetery; and </li> <li> the Armed Forces Retirement Home. </li> </ul> <p>(Sec. 301) Permits funds for Cemeterial Expenses--Army to be provided to Arlington County, Virginia to relocate a federally owned water main at Arlington National Cemetery to make additional land available for ground burials. </p> <p>(Sec. 302) Permits funds from concessions at Army National Military Cemeteries to be used to support activities at the cemeteries. </p> <p>TITLE IV--GENERAL PROVISIONS </p> <p>(Sec. 401) Prohibits the obligation of funds in this bill beyond the current fiscal year unless expressly permitted in this bill. </p> <p>(Sec. 402) Prohibits the use of funds provided by this bill for programs, projects, or activities not in compliance with federal laws related to risk assessment, the protection of private property rights, or unfunded mandates. </p> <p>(Sec. 403) Encourages all departments and agencies funded in this bill to expand their use of &quot;E-Commerce&quot; technologies and procedures. </p> <p>(Sec. 404) Specifies the congressional committees that are to receive all reports and notifications required by this bill. </p> <p>(Sec. 405) Prohibits the transfer of funds to any part of the U.S. government without authority provided by an appropriations law. </p> <p>(Sec. 406) Requires agencies to post reports submitted to Congress on the public web site of the agency, subject to exceptions for national security and confidential or proprietary information. </p> <p>(Sec. 407) Prohibits the use of funds provided by this bill for a computer network unless pornography is blocked, with the exception of law enforcement, prosecution, or adjudication activities. </p> <p>(Sec. 408) Prohibits the use of funds provided by this bill for first-class travel by an employee of the executive branch. </p> <p>(Sec. 409) Prohibits the use of funds provided by this bill for the renovation, expansion, or construction of any facility in the United States to house any individual detained at the United States Naval Station at Guantanamo Bay, Cuba. Includes an exception for modification to the facility at Guantanamo Bay. </p> <p>TITLE V--ZIKA RESPONSE AND PREPAREDNESS </p> <p>Provides FY2016 supplemental appropriations to prevent, prepare for, and respond to the Zika virus. Designates the funds as an emergency requirement under the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985. (Emergency funds are exempt from discretionary spending limits and other budget enforcement procedures.) </p> <p>Chapter 1--Department of Health and Human Services </p> <p>Provides FY2016 supplemental appropriations to the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to prevent, prepare for, and respond to the Zika virus, other vector-borne diseases, and related health outcomes, domestically and internationally. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Health Resources and Services Administration for:</p> <ul> <li> Primary Health Care, </li> <li>the Health Workforce, and </li> <li> Maternal and Child Health. </li> </ul> <p>Provides appropriations to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention for CDC-Wide Activities and Program Support. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the National Institutes for the Health for the National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Office of the Secretary for the Public Health and Social Services Emergency Fund. </p> <p>(Sec. 501) Permit HHS to use funds provided by this chapter to acquire, lease, construct, alter, renovate, equip, furnish, or manage facilities outside of the United States. </p> <p>(Sec. 502) Permits HHS, State, and USAID to use funds to appoint candidates for positions to perform critical work relating to the Zika response, without regard to specified requirements regarding hiring preferences if: (1) public notice has been given; and (2) HHS has determined that a public health threat exists. </p> <p>(Sec. 503) Permits funds provided by this chapter to be transferred between specified HHS accounts if certain requirements are met. </p> <p>(Sec. 504) Requires HHS to submit to Congress a detailed spending plan for funds provided by this chapter. </p> <p>Chapter 2--Department of State </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the State Department to support response efforts related to the Zika virus and related health outcomes, other vector-borne diseases, or other infectious diseases. </p> <p>Provides appropriations for the Administration of Foreign Affairs, including: </p> <ul> <li>Diplomatic and Consular Programs, </li> <li> Emergencies in the Diplomatic and Consular Service, and </li> <li> the Repatriation Loans Program Account. </li> </ul> <p>Provides appropriations to the United States Agency for International Development for Operating Expenses. </p> <p>Provides appropriations for: </p> <ul> <li> Bilateral Economic Assistance for Global Health Programs; </li> <li> International Security Assistance for Nonproliferation, Anti-terrorism, Demining and Related Programs; and </li> <li>Multilateral Assistance for International Organizations and Programs. </li> </ul> <p>(Sec. 505) Permits funds provided by this chapter to be transferred between specified accounts and sets forth requirements and restrictions for the transfers. </p> <p>(Sec. 506) Prohibits funds provided by this chapter to respond to the Zika virus outbreak, other vector-borne diseases, or other infectious diseases from being obligated unless the State Department or USAID notifies Congress 15 days in advance of the obligation. </p> <p>(Sec. 507) Requires the State Department and USAID to submit to Congress a detailed spending plan for funds provided by this chapter. </p> <p>(Sec. 508) Provides appropriations to the GAO for oversight of activities funded by this chapter. </p> <p>(Sec. 509) Rescinds specified unobligated balances that where provided in the Department of State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 2015 to USAID for Operating Expenses to prevent, prepare for, and respond to the Ebola virus disease outbreak. </p> <p>Chapter 3--General Provisions--This Title </p> <p>(Sec. 510) Provides that, unless otherwise indicated by this title, FY2016 funds provided by this title are subject to the requirements contained in the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2016. </p> <p>(Sec. 511) Permits fund provided by this title for response efforts related to the Zika virus and related health outcomes, other vector-borne diseases, or other infectious disease to be used for contracts with individuals for the provision of personal services within the United States and abroad, subject to congressional notification requirements. Prohibit the individuals from being deemed U.S. employees for the purpose of any law administered by the Office of Personnel Management. </p> <p>(Sec. 512) Permits each amount designated as an emergency requirement by this title to be available only if the President subsequently designates all of the amounts and transmits the designations to the Congress. </p> <p>(Sec. 513) Specifies that this title becomes effective immediately upon enactment of this bill. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2577v01" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-10-27">
<action-date>2015-06-25</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to Senate amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Highlights: </b></p> <p>The Transportation, Housing and Urban Development, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2016 provides FY2016 appropriations for the Department of Transportation (DOT), the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD), and several related agencies. </p> <p>The bill includes both discretionary and mandatory funding. The HUD budget is primarily discretionary spending, and most of the DOT budget is mandatory spending, in the form of contract authority from the Highway Trust Fund (HTF). </p> <p>The bill increases overall funding for Transportation, Housing and Urban Development, and Related Agencies above FY2015 levels. Compared to FY2015 levels, the bill decreases funding for DOT and increases funding for HUD. </p> <p>Within the DOT budget, the bill: </p> <ul> <li> increases funding for the Federal Aviation Administration, the Federal Railroad Administration, and the Maritime Administration; </li> <li>decreases funding for the Federal Transit Administration and the Pipeline and Hazardous Materials Safety Administration; and </li> <li>funds the Federal Aid Highway Program and National Infrastructure Investments (Transportation Investment Generating Economic Recovery or TIGER grants) at the FY2015 level. </li> </ul> <p>Within the HUD budget, the bill: </p> <ul> <li>increases funding for the Tenant-Based Rental Assistance and Project-Based Rental Assistance accounts that fund the low-income housing programs under Section 8 of the United States Housing Act of 1937; </li> <li>decreases funding for the Community Development Block Grant (CDBG) formula program and the HOME Investment Partnerships Program. </li> </ul> <p>For Public Housing, the bill increases funding for the Public Housing Operating Fund and decreases funding for both the Public Housing Capital Fund and Choice Neighborhoods compared to FY2015 levels. </p> <p>The bill decreases funding for the Neighborhood Reinvestment Corporation. </p> <p>Also included in the bill are provisions that would: </p> <ul> <li>affect limits on truck size and weight, </li> <li>restrict enforcement of regulations for commercial truck drivers' rest, </li> <li>limit the use of funds to increase minimum insurance requirements for truckers and bus drivers, and</li> <li>prohibit the use of funds for a proposed rule requiring airlines to display ancillary fees in ticket prices. </li> </ul> <p><b>Full Summary: </b></p> <p><b>Transportation, Housing and Urban Development, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2016 </b></p> <p>Provides FY2016 appropriations for the Department of Transportation, the Department of Housing and Urban Development, and several related agencies. </p> <p><i>Department of Transportation Appropriations Act, 2016 </i></p> <p>Provides FY2016 appropriations for the Department of Transportation (DOT). </p> <p>TITLE I--DEPARTMENT OF TRANSPORTATION </p> <p>Provides appropriations for the Office of the Secretary, including: </p> <ul> <li> Salaries and Expenses; </li> <li>Research and Technology; </li> <li>National Infrastructure Investments (also known as TIGER grants); </li> <li>Financial Management Capital; </li> <li>Cyber Security Initiatives; </li> <li>the Office of Civil Rights; </li> <li>Transportation Planning, Research, and Development; </li> <li>an Interagency Infrastructure Permitting Improvement Center;</li> <li>the Working Capital Fund; </li> <li>the Minority Business Resource Center Program; </li> <li>Minority Business Outreach; and </li> <li>Payments to Air Carriers. </li> </ul> <p>(Sec. 101) Prohibits DOT from approving assessments or reimbursable agreements pertaining to funds appropriated to the modal administrations in this bill except for activities underway on the date of enactment, unless the reprogramming process has been completed. </p> <p>(Sec.102) Permits DOT to engage in activities with states and state legislators to consider proposals to reduce motorcycle fatalities.</p> <p>(Sec. 103) Permits DOT to use the Working Capital Fund to provide transit benefits to federal employees. </p> <p>(Sec. 104) Requires DOT to: (1) post on its website the schedule and agenda for all meetings of the Credit Council, and (2) require the Credit Council to record the decisions and actions of each meeting. </p> <p>(Sec. 105) Prohibits DOT from finalizing or implementing specified sections of a proposed rule relating to Transparency of Airline Ancillary Fees and Other Consumer Protection Issues. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) for: Operations; Facilities and Equipment; Research, Engineering, and Development; and Grants-In-Aid For Airports. </p> <p>Prohibits the use of funds provided by this bill for: new applicants for the second career training program, new unauthorized user fees, or aeronautical charting and cartography activities through the Working Capital Fund. </p> <p>Permits funds received from specified public, private, and foreign sources for expenses incurred to be credited to the appropriation. </p> <p>Requires DOT to submit to Congress a five-year capital investment plan for the FAA. </p> <p>Permits funds to be used for installation and commissioning or runway incursion prevention devices and systems. </p> <p>(Sec. 110) Limit technical staff years under the federally funded research and development center contract between the FAA and the Center for Advanced Aviation System Development. </p> <p>(Sec. 111) Prohibits the FAA from requiring airport sponsors to provide the agency without cost building construction, maintenance, utilities and expenses, or space in sponsor-owned buildings for air traffic control, air navigation, or weather reporting, subject to specified exceptions. </p> <p>(Sec. 112) Permits the FAA to reimburse amounts made available from certain fees to carry out the Essential Air Service (EAS) program, which ensures that small communities have a minimum level of air service. </p> <p>(Sec. 113) Permits amounts collected by the FAA for providing technical assistance to foreign aviation authorities to be credited to the Operations account. </p> <p>(Sec. 114) Prohibits the FAA from paying Sunday premium pay except if an individual worked on a Sunday. </p> <p>(Sec. 115) Prohibits the FAA from using funds provided by this bill to purchase a store gift card or gift certificate using a government-issued credit card. </p> <p>(Sec. 116) Allows all airports experiencing the required level of boardings through charter and scheduled air service to be eligible for specified funds. </p> <p>(Sec. 117) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used for retention bonuses for FAA employees without prior approval of the Assistant Secretary for Administration of DOT.</p> <p> (Sec. 118) Requires the FAA to block the display of an owner's or operator's aircraft registration number in the Aircraft Situational Display to Industry data program, upon the request of an owner or operator. </p> <p>(Sec. 119) Prohibits the use of funds provided by this bill to pay the salaries and expenses of more than nine political or presidential FAA appointees. </p> <p>(Sec. 119A) Prohibits the use of funds provided by this bill to increase fees for navigation products until the FAA provides Congress with a justification for all fees for aeronautical navigation products. </p> <p>(Sec. 119B) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to change weight restrictions or prior permission rules at Teterboro Airport in New Jersey. </p> <p>(Sec. 119C) Requires the FAA to notify Congress prior to closing a regional operations center or reducing the services it provides. </p> <p>Provides funding from the Highway Trust Fund (HTF) to the Federal Highway Administration (FHWA) for Administrative Expenses and Federal-Aid Highways. </p> <p>(Most of DOT's budget is mandatory budget authority rather than discretionary budget authority. The mandatory budget authority is primarily in the form of contract authority derived from the Highway Trust Fund (HTF). Contract authority is the authority to obligate funds in advance of an appropriation Act. </p> <p>Spending from the HTF is determined both by authorization bills and appropriations bills. Authorization bills provide contract authority for highway programs, and appropriations bills include obligation limitations that determine how much of the contract authority may be used in a given year.) </p> <p>(Sec. 120) Specifies allocations and requirements for distributing obligation authority from the HTF among federal-aid highway programs. </p> <p>(Sec. 121) Credits funds received by the Bureau of Transportation Statistics from the sale of data products to the Federal-Aid Highways account to reimburse the Bureau for expenses. </p> <p>(Sec. 122) Requires DOT to: (1) provide an informal public notice and comment opportunity prior to waiving the Buy America requirement for federal-aid highway projects, and (2) report to Congress annually on waivers. </p> <p>(Sec. 123) Requires DOT to notify Congress prior to providing credit assistance under the Transportation Finance and Innovation Act (TIFIA) program, which provides credit to finance surface transportation projects of national and regional significance. </p> <p>(Sec. 124) Permits specified contract authority from the HTF to be made available for the FHWA's administrative expenses. </p> <p>(Sec. 125) Allows current truck weight limitations to remain in place on specified highways in Texas and Arkansas. </p> <p>(Sec. 126) Permits states to repurpose certain highway project funding to be used within 50 miles of its original designation. </p> <p>(Sec. 127) Includes Kansas under an agricultural exemption from federal truck trailer length requirements. </p> <p>Provides funding from the HTF to the Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration (FMCSA) for: (1) Motor Carrier Safety Operations and Programs, and (2) Motor Carrier Safety Grants. </p> <p>(Sec. 130) Subjects funds provided by this bill to specified terms and conditions included in prior appropriations Acts regarding Mexico-domiciled motor carriers. Repeals a provision in the Department of Transportation and Related Agencies Appropriation Act, 2002 that established an annual reporting requirement for the Office of Inspector General. </p> <p>(Sec. 131) Requires the FMCSA to provide written notice of violations of certain safety procedures and regulations that could require an expedited safety audit or compliance review or a written response demonstrating corrective action. </p> <p>(Sec. 132) Permits states that issued Commercial License Permits to individuals under age 18 prior to the FMCSA rule establishing a minimum age of 18, to continue to do so. </p> <p>(Sec. 133) Prohibits Motor Carrier Safety Operations and Programs funds from being used to deny an application to renew a hazardous materials safety permit unless a carrier has the opportunity to present its own corrective actions and DOT determines the actions are insufficient. </p> <p>(Sec. 134) Prohibits DOT from using funds to enforce provisions of the Hours of Service rule regarding the restart of a driver's 60- or 70-hour limit unless: (1) the study required by the Consolidated and Further Continuing Appropriations Act, 2015 demonstrates that the restart provisions resulted in statistically significant net safety benefits, and (2) the Inspector General certifies that the final report meets the statutory requirements. </p> <p>(Sec. 135) Prohibits DOT from using funds to increase minimum financial responsibility levels for motor carriers until after reporting to Congress on the impact of raising minimum financial responsibility levels. </p> <p>(Sec. 136) Provides that certain commercial motor carrier transportation regulations do not apply to the transportation of passengers by motor vehicles operated by youth or family camps that provide overnight accommodations and recreational or educational activities at fixed locations. </p> <p>(Sec. 137) Extends the current 28 feet minimum requirement for a semitrailer or trailer operating in a truck tractor semitrailer- trailer combination to 33 feet. </p> <p>Permits a state Department of Transportation, in addition to the existing authority for governors, to request an exemption for any segment of the National Highway Network, if it is not capable of safely accommodating a commercial motor vehicle at the 33-foot configuration. </p> <p>Requires DOT to submit to Congress a study comparing crash data between 28 foot and 33 foot semitrailers or trailers operating in a truck tractor-semitrailer-trailer configuration. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration (NHTSA) for Operations and Research. </p> <p>Provides funding from the HTF to NHTSA for Operations and Research and Highway Traffic Safety Grants. </p> <p>(Sec. 140) Provides additional funding to NHTSA for travel and related expenses associated with state management reviews and core competency development training for highway safety staff. </p> <p>(Sec. 141) Exempts from the current fiscal year's obligation limitation any obligation authority that was made available in previous public laws. </p> <p>(Sec. 142) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used for the National Highway Safety Advisory Committee. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Federal Railroad Administration (FRA) for: </p> <ul> <li> Safety and Operations, </li> <li>Railroad Research and Development, </li> <li>the Railroad Rehabilitation and Improvement Financing Program,</li> <li>Railroad Safety Grants, </li> <li>Operating Grants to the National Railroad Passenger Corporation (Amtrak), and </li> <li>Capital and Debt Service Grants to Amtrak. </li> </ul> <p>(Sec. 150) Permits the FRA to receive and use cash or spare parts to repair or replace damaged automated track inspection cars and equipment. </p> <p>(Sec. 151) Limits overtime for Amtrak employees. Permits Amtrak to waive the limit for specific employees due to safety or operational efficiency reasons. Requires Amtrak to report to Congress on waivers granted and overtime payments incurred. </p> <p>(Sec. 152) Permits specified unobligated funds to be used to assist class II and class III railroads with expenses related to applying for loans and loan guarantees under the Railroad Rehabilitation and Improvement Financing Program. </p> <p>(Sec. 153) Permits specified unobligated balances to be used for capital grants to Amtrak for shared use infrastructure on the Northeast Corridor. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Federal Transit Administration (FTA) for Administrative Expenses, Transit Research, Technical Assistance and Training, Capital Investment Grants, and Grants to the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority. </p> <p>Provides funding from the HTF to the FTA for Transit Formula Grants. </p> <p>(Sec. 160) Exempts previously made transit obligations from limitations on obligations. </p> <p>(Sec. 161) Permits FTA Fixed Guideway Capital Investment funds for projects specified in this bill or the accompanying report that are not obligated by September 30, 2020, to be used for other projects eligible to use the funds for the same purpose. </p> <p>(Sec. 162) Permits the transfer of prior year appropriations from older accounts to be merged into new accounts with similar, current activities. </p> <p>(Sec. 163) Provides an exemption from the charter bus regulations for portions of the state of Washington. </p> <p>(Sec. 164) Provides that conditions imposed on federal public transportation assistance related to property originally built as a prototype having icebreaking capabilities are satisfied by the use of the property for: Arctic research; mapping the Arctic; collecting and analyzing data in the Arctic; supporting Arctic exploration, research, or development; or educational purposes or humanitarian relief efforts. </p> <p>(Sec. 165) Provides that projects eligible for the pilot program for expedited project delivery established by the Moving Ahead for Progress in the 21st Century Act (MAP-21) are exempt from specified requirements that apply to fixed guideway capital investment grants. </p> <p>(Sec. 166) Rescinds specified unobligated balances from funds provided for the bus and bus facilities program. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Saint Lawrence Seaway Development Corporation for Operations and Maintenance. </p> <p>Provides appropriations for the Maritime Administration (MARAD) for the Maritime Security Program, Operations and Training, Assistance to Small Shipyards, Ship Disposal, and The Maritime Guaranteed Loan (Title XI) Program Account. </p> <p>(Sec. 170) Permits MARAD to furnish utilities and services and make repairs in connection with any lease, contract, or occupancy involving government property under the control of MARAD. Permits payments received to be credited to the appropriations account charged with the cost and requires rental payments to be deposited into the Treasury. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Pipeline and Hazardous Materials Safety Administration for Operational Expenses, Hazardous Materials Safety, Pipeline Safety, and Emergency Preparedness Grants. </p> <p>(Sec. 180) Requires DOT to evaluate and report to Congress on an alternative risk-based compliance regime for the siting of small-scale liquefaction facilities that generate and package liquefied natural gas for use as a fuel or delivery to consumers by non-pipeline modes of transportation. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Office of Inspector General and the Surface Transportation Board. </p> <p>(Sec. 190) Permits DOT to use funds for aircraft, motor vehicles, liability insurance, uniforms, or allowances, as authorized by law. </p> <p>(Sec. 191) Permits fund provided by this bill to be used for the employment of temporary or intermittent experts and consultants if the rates do not exceed the rate for an Executive Level IV.</p> <p> (Sec. 192) Prohibits: (1) funds provided by this bill from being used for more than 110 DOT presidential or political appointees, and (2) any of the appointees from being assigned on temporary detail outside of DOT. </p> <p>(Sec. 193) Prohibits recipients of funds provided by this bill from releasing certain personal information and photographs from a driver's license or motor vehicle record without the consent of the affected individual. Prohibits DOT from withholding funds if a state is not in compliance with this provision. </p> <p>(Sec. 194) Permits funds received by specified DOT agencies from states or other private or public sources for training expenses to be credited to specified agency accounts. </p> <p>(Sec. 195) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used for certain loans, loan guarantees, lines of credit, or grants unless DOT notifies Congress prior to announcing competitively selected projects. </p> <p>Requires DOT to provide concurrent notification to Congress regarding any ''quick release'' of funds from the FHWA's Emergency Relief Program. (The program provides funding for the repair or reconstruction of federal-aid highways and roads on federal lands which have suffered serious damage as a result of natural disasters or catastrophic failures from an external cause.) </p> <p>(Sec. 196) Permits rebates, refunds, incentive payments, fees, and other funds received by DOT from travel management centers, charge card programs, the subleasing of building space, and miscellaneous sources to be credited to DOT appropriations and allocated to elements of DOT using fair and equitable criteria. </p> <p>(Sec. 197) Permits DOT to use amounts recovered from improper payments to a third party contractor for expenses incurred in the recovery. </p> <p>(Sec. 198) Requires reprogramming action notifications to be transmitted to and approved or denied solely by the House and Senate Committees on Appropriations. </p> <p>(Sec. 199) Limits Surface Transportation Board fees for the filing of rate or practice complaints. </p> <p>(Sec. 199A) Permits funds provided by this bill for modal administrations to be obligated to the Office of the Secretary for assessments or reimbursable agreements only if the funds provide a direct benefit to the modal administrations. </p> <p>(Sec. 199B) Permits DOT to set uniform standards for transit benefits for agency transit passes and transit benefits. </p> <p>(Sec. 199C) Prohibits the use of funds for any geographic, economic, or other hiring preference pilot program, regulation, or policy unless certain requirements are met related to availability of local labor, displacement of existing employees, and delays in transportation plans.</p> <p><i>Department of Housing and Urban Development Appropriations Act, 2016 </i></p> <p>Provides FY2016 appropriations for the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD). </p> <p>TITLE II--DEPARTMENT OF HOUSING AND URBAN DEVELOPMENT </p> <p>Provides appropriations for Management and Administration, including for Executive Offices and Administrative Support Offices. </p> <p>Provides appropriations for Program Office Salaries and Expenses, including: </p> <ul> <li> Public and Indian Housing, </li> <li>Community Planning and Development, </li> <li>Housing, </li> <li>Policy Development and Research, </li> <li>Fair Housing and Equal Opportunity, and </li> <li>the Office of Lead Hazard Control and Healthy Homes. </li> </ul> <p>Provides appropriations for Public and Indian Housing Programs, including: </p> <ul> <li> Tenant-Based Rental Assistance, </li> <li>the Public Housing Capital Fund, </li> <li>the Public Housing Operating Fund, </li> <li>the Choice Neighborhoods Initiative, </li> <li>the Family Self-Sufficiency program, </li> <li> Indian Block Grants, and </li> <li>the Indian Housing Loan Guarantee Fund Program Account. </li> </ul> <p>Provides appropriations for Community Planning and Development, including: </p> <ul> <li> Housing Opportunities for Persons with AIDS, </li> <li>the Community Development Fund, </li> <li>the Community Development Loan Guarantees Program Account, </li> <li>the Home Investment Partnerships Program, </li> <li>the Self-Help and Assisted Home Ownership Opportunity Program, and </li> <li>Homeless Assistance Grants. </li> </ul> <p>Provides appropriations for Housing Programs, including: </p> <ul> <li> Project-Based Rental Assistance, </li> <li>Housing for the Elderly, </li> <li>Housing for Persons with Disabilities, </li> <li>Housing Counseling Assistance, </li> <li>Rental Housing Assistance, and </li> <li> the Manufactured Housing Standards Program. </li> </ul> <p>Provides appropriations and establishes limits on loan commitments for the Federal Housing Administration (FHA), which includes the Mutual Mortgage Insurance Program Account and the General and Special Risk Program Account. </p> <p>Provides appropriation and establishes limits on loan commitments for the Government National Mortgage Association (Ginnie Mae). </p> <p>Provides appropriations for Policy Development and Research for Research and Technology. </p> <p>Provides appropriations for Fair Housing and Equal Opportunity for Fair Housing Activities. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Office of Lead Hazard Control and Healthy Homes, the Information Technology Fund, and the Office of Inspector General. </p> <p>(Sec. 201) Requires 50% of overpayments due to refinancing of state projects under the Stewart B. McKinney Homeless Assistance Amendments Act of 1988 to be rescinded or, in the case of cash, remitted to the Treasury. Permits HUD to use up to 15% of the overpayments to provide project owners with incentives to refinance projects at lower interest rates. </p> <p>(Sec. 202) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to investigate or prosecute under the Fair Housing Act any lawful activities, including the filing or maintaining of a nonfrivolous legal action to achieve or prevent action by a government entity or a court. </p> <p>(Sec. 203) Requires HUD to make certain adjustments to the formula for distributing Housing Opportunities for Persons With AIDS (HOPWA) funds for certain jurisdictions in New York, New Jersey, Delaware, and North Carolina. </p> <p>(Sec. 204) Requires any grant, cooperative agreement, or other assistance made pursuant to this title to be made on a competitive basis and in accordance with the Department of Housing and Urban Development Reform Act of 1989. </p> <p>(Sec. 205) Permits specified funds to be used, without regard to limitations on administrative expenses, for: (1) legal services; and (2) payment for services and facilities of the Federal National Mortgage Association (Fannie Mae), Ginnie Mae, the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation (Freddie Mac), the Federal Financing Bank, Federal Reserve banks, Federal Home Loan banks, and any bank insured under the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation Act. </p> <p>(Sec. 206) Prohibits HUD appropriations from being used for any program, project, or activity in excess of amounts included in the budget estimates submitted to Congress, unless otherwise provided by this bill or through reprogramming.</p> <p>(Sec. 207) Permits HUD corporations and agencies subject to the Government Corporation Control Act to utilize funds and make contracts and commitments, without regard to fiscal year limitations and subject to specified restrictions, to implement the FY2016 budget. </p> <p>(Sec. 208) Requires HUD to provide quarterly reports to Congress regarding uncommitted, unobligated, recaptured, and excess funds for each program and activity. </p> <p>(Sec. 209) Provides that a public housing agency (PHA) or other entity that administers federal housing assistance for the Housing Authority of the county of Los Angeles, California; or Alaska, Iowa, or Mississippi is not required to include public housing residents or recipients of section 8 rental assistance (under the United States Housing Act of 1937) on the governing board. </p> <p>Requires each PHA or entity that does not include these individuals on its board to establish an advisory board of at least six residents of public housing or recipients of section 8 assistance to provide advice on issues related to public housing and section 8. </p> <p>(Sec. 210) Prohibits funds provided by this title from being use for an audit of Ginnie Mae that applies certain requirements of the Federal Credit Reform Act of 1990. </p> <p>(Sec. 211) Permits HUD to transfer project-based assistance, debt, and use restrictions associated with a multifamily housing project from an obsolete or economically nonviable project to a viable project, subject to specified conditions. </p> <p>(Sec. 212) Prohibits section 8 housing assistance from being provided to any individual who: (1) is a student at an institution of higher education; (2) under 24 years of age; (3) is not a veteran; (4) is unmarried; (5) does not have a dependent child; (6) does not have disabilities and was not receiving assistance as of November 30, 2005; and (7) is not otherwise individually eligible, or has parents who are not eligible, to receive assistance. </p> <p>Provides that, for section 8 rental assistance eligibility purposes, any financial assistance (in excess of amounts received for tuition and fees) received under the Higher Education Act of 1965, from private sources, or an institution of higher education shall be considered income, except for a person over age 23 with dependent children. </p> <p>(Sec. 213) Requires Native American Housing Block Grant funds to be distributed to the same Native Alaskans that received funds in FY2005. </p> <p>(Sec. 214) Permits HUD to insure home equity conversion mortgages (HECMs or reverse mortgages) for elderly homeowners through FY2016, notwithstanding limitations on insurance authority included in the National Housing Act. </p> <p>(Sec. 215) Requires HUD, in managing and disposing of any multifamily property that is owned or held by HUD, and during foreclosure on property with a contract for section 8 rental assistance payments or other federal programs, to maintain rental assistance payments attached to any dwelling units in the property. Permits HUD, if a property is not feasible for continued payments based on specified cost or environmental considerations, to: (1) contract with owners of other existing properties for project-based rental assistance payments, or (2) provide other rental assistance.</p> <p> (Sec. 216) Permits the use of Community Development Loan Guarantee funds to guarantee notes or other obligations issued by any state on behalf of its non-entitlement communities. </p> <p>(Sec. 217) Permits certain public housing agencies that own and operate 400 or fewer public housing units to elect to be exempt from asset management requirements imposed by HUD in connection with the operating fund rule. </p> <p>(Sec. 218) Prohibits HUD from using public housing funds to impose any requirement or guideline relating to asset management that restricts or limits the use of capital funds for central office costs, up to the limits established in the Quality Housing and Work Responsibility Act of 1998. </p> <p>(Sec. 219) Prohibits the designation of a HUD official or employee as an allotment holder unless the Chief Financial Officer has determined that the employee has: (1) implemented an adequate system of funds control, and (2) received training in funds control procedures and directives. </p> <p>(Sec. 220) Requires HUD to publish all Notices of Funding Availability for FY2016 and subsequent years on the Internet. </p> <p>(Sec. 221) Requires HUD to: (1) pay attorney fees in program-related litigation from the individual program office and Office of General Counsel salaries and expenses appropriations, (2) include projected litigation costs for attorney fees as a separate line item in the budget request, and (3) submit a spending plan for review and approval by Congress prior to using any funds provided by this title for attorney fees. </p> <p>(Sec. 222) Sets forth requirements for transferring and reprogramming funds within specified HUD Administrative Support Office and Program Office Salaries and Expenses accounts. </p> <p>(Sec. 223) Provides that the HUD-administered Disaster Housing Assistance Program is a HUD program under the McKinney Act for income verification and matching purposes. </p> <p>(Sec. 224) Requires HUD to take specified actions against owners receiving rental subsidies that do not maintain safe properties based on specified Real Estate Assessment Center (REAC) scores. </p> <p>(Sec. 225) Limits salaries and bonuses for public housing agency officials and employees. </p> <p>(Sec. 226) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used for the HUD doctoral dissertation research grant program. </p> <p>(Sec. 227) Amends the United States Housing Act of 1937 to extend the HOPE VI program through FY2016. (The program provides funds to renovate or demolish existing public housing and replace it with mixed-income housing.)</p> <p>(Sec. 228) Requires HUD to notify Congress prior to announcing the recipients of grant awards. </p> <p>(Sec. 229) Permits HUD to transfer specified funds from salaries and expenses accounts to the Information Technology Fund to support technology improvements. </p> <p>(Sec. 230) Prohibits funds provided by this bill or receipts collected under FHA programs from being used to implement the Homeowners Armed with Knowledge (HAWK) program. </p> <p>(Sec. 231) Prohibits the FHA, Ginnie Mae, or HUD from using funds provided by this bill to finance mortgages for properties that have been subject to eminent domain. </p> <p>(Sec. 232) Prohibits the use of funds made available by this bill to terminate the status of a unit of general local government as a metropolitan city with respect to community development grants under the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974. </p> <p>(Sec. 233) Amends the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act to provide that the waiting period for the termination of tenancy under the HOME Investment Partnerships program is not required if the grounds for the termination or refusal to renew involve a direct threat to the safety of the tenants or employees of the housing, or an imminent and serious threat to the property (and the termination or refusal to renew is in accordance with the requirements of state or local law). </p> <p>(Sec. 234) Prohibits funds provided by this title from being used to pay a bonus to an employee who is subject to administrative discipline, including suspension from work. </p> <p>(Sec. 235) Amends the Consolidated and Further Continuing Appropriations Act, 2012, to modify the requirements for the Rental Assistance Demonstration. </p> <p>(Sec. 236) Allows public housing authorities to establish replacement reserves to address capital needs. </p> <p>(Sec. 237) Increases the flexibility of public housing authorities to transfer funds between their capital and operating funds. </p> <p>(Sec. 238) Amends the National Housing Act to permit HUD to establish exceptions to certain minimum property standards in order to address alternative water systems, including cisterns, which meet requirements of state and local building codes that ensure health and safety standards. </p> <p>(Sec. 239) Expands the number of public housing authorities that may participate in the Moving-to-Work program. (Moving to Work is a demonstration program that provides HUD and local public housing authorities flexibility to test alternative policies for providing housing assistance through the Section 8 Housing Choice Voucher program and the public housing program.) </p> <p>(Sec. 240) Amends the United States Housing Act of 1937 to permit triennial recertification of fixed-income families. </p> <p>(Sec. 241) Extends the period of use of family unification vouchers by youth. </p> <p>(Sec. 242) Requires HUD to establish a demonstration program for the performance-based financing of energy and water conservation improvements in assisted multifamily housing buildings to reduce utility costs. </p> <p>(Sec. 243) Permits HUD to establish a demonstration program to provide incentives to public housing agencies that use capital funds, operating funds, grants, utility rebates, and other resources to reduce energy and/or water consumption. </p> <p>(Sec. 244) Permits HUD to authorize the transfer of existing subsidies and liabilities from obsolete housing for persons with disabilities to housing that complies with specified requirements regarding housing for the disabled. </p> <p>(Sec. 245) Rescinds specified unobligated balances from HUD programs. </p> <p>(Sec. 246) Permits HUD to use funds provided for Homeless Assistance Grants to participate in the Performance Partnerships Pilots program. </p> <p>(Sec. 247) Permits HUD to consolidate funds used to implement disaster recovery grants. </p> <p>(Sec. 248) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to require or enforce the Physical Needs Assessment (PNA). </p> <p>TITLE III--RELATED AGENCIES </p> <p>Provides FY2016 appropriations to: </p> <ul> <li> the Access Board, </li> <li>the Federal Maritime Commission, </li> <li>the Amtrak Office of Inspector General, </li> <li>the National Transportation Safety Board, </li> <li>the Neighborhood Reinvestment Corporation, and </li> <li>the U.S. Interagency Council on Homelessness. </li> </ul> <p>TITLE IV--GENERAL PROVISIONS--THIS ACT </p> <p>Sets forth permissible, restricted, and prohibited used for funds provided by this and other appropriations Acts. </p> <p>(Sec. 401) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to compensate or pay the expenses of non-federal parties intervening in regulatory or adjudicatory proceedings funded in this bill. </p> <p>(Sec. 402) Prohibits transfers of funds to other appropriations or obligations beyond the current fiscal year, unless expressly permitted in this bill. </p> <p>(Sec. 403) Limits expenditures for consulting services to contracts where the expenditures are a matter of public record and available for public inspection, unless otherwise provided by law. </p> <p>(Sec. 404) Prohibits the use of funds provided by this bill for employee training not specifically related to the performance of official duties. </p> <p>(Sec. 405) Specifies procedures, restrictions, and reporting requirements for the reprogramming of funds provided by this bill. </p> <p>(Sec. 406) Permits up to 50% of unobligated balances remaining at the end of FY2016 from appropriations for salaries and expenses to remain available through FY2017, subject to congressional approval and reprogramming guidelines. </p> <p>(Sec. 407) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used for any project that seeks to use eminent domain unless eminent domain is employed only for a public use. </p> <p>(Sec. 408) Requires agencies and departments funded by this bill to provide to Congress specified details regarding all sole-source contracts. </p> <p>(Sec. 409) Prohibits the transfer of funds provided by this bill to a department, agency, or instrumentality of the U.S. government unless the transfer is pursuant to an appropriations Act. </p> <p>(Sec. 410) Prohibits the use of funds provided by this bill to permanently replace an employee intent on returning to his or her previous occupation after completing military service. </p> <p>(Sec. 411) Requires expenditures of funds provided by this bill to comply with the Buy American Act. </p> <p>(Sec. 412) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being made available to any person or entity that has been convicted of violating the Buy American Act. </p> <p>(Sec. 413) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to purchase first class or premium airline travel in violation of specified federal travel regulations. </p> <p>(Sec. 414) Prohibits the use of funds provided by this bill to approve a new foreign air carrier permit or exemption application if the approval would contravene U.S. law or specified provisions of the U.S.-E.U.-Iceland-Norway Air Transport Agreement. </p> <p>(Sec. 415) Prohibits the use of funds provided by this bill for the attendance of more than 50 U.S.-stationed employees at any single conference outside the United States unless Congress is notified in advance that attendance is important to the national interest.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2577v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-10-16">
<action-date>2015-06-09</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Highlights: </b></p> <p>The Transportation, Housing and Urban Development, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2016 provides FY2016 appropriations for the Department of Transportation (DOT), the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD), and several related agencies. </p> <p>The bill includes both discretionary and mandatory funding. The HUD budget is primarily discretionary spending, and most of the DOT budget is mandatory spending, in the form of contract authority from the Highway Trust Fund (HTF). Funding from the HTF is contingent on the enactment of a new authorization bill. </p> <p>The bill increases overall funding for Transportation, Housing and Urban Development, and Related Agencies above FY2015 levels. Compared to FY2015 levels, the bill decreases funding for DOT and increases funding for HUD. </p> <p>Within the DOT budget, the bill: </p> <ul> <li> decreases funding for National Infrastructure Investments (Transportation Investment Generating Economic Recovery or TIGER grants), the National Railroad Passenger Corporation (Amtrak), Capital Investment Grants (New Starts), and the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority; </li> <li>increases funding for the Federal Aviation Administration, the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration, the Maritime Administration, and the Pipeline and Hazardous Materials Safety Administration; and </li> <li>funds the Federal-Aid Highway Program from the HTF at the FY2015 level, contingent on the enactment of a new authorization bill. </li> </ul> <p>Within the HUD budget, the bill: </p> <ul> <li>increases funding for the Tenant-Based Rental Assistance and Project-Based Rental Assistance accounts that fund the low-income housing programs under Section 8 of the United States Housing Act of 1937;</li> <li>decreases funding for Policy Development and Research, the Office of Lead Hazard Control and Healthy Homes, and the Information Technology Fund; and </li> <li>funds the Community Development Block Grant (CDBG) formula program and the HOME Investment Partnerships Program at the FY2015 levels. </li> </ul> <p>For Public Housing, the bill funds the Public Housing Operating Fund at the FY2015 level and decreases funding for the Public Housing Capital Fund and Choice Neighborhoods. </p> <p>The bill decreases funding for the Neighborhood Reinvestment Corporation. </p> <p>Also included in the bill are provisions that would: </p> <ul> <li> restrict flights and cruise ships from traveling to Cuba, </li> <li>prohibit the use of funds for high-speed rail in California, </li> <li>limit the authority of the Surface Transportation Board to approve phases of the California High Speed Rail project, </li> <li>affect limits on truck size and weight, </li> <li>restrict enforcement of regulations for commercial truck drivers' rest, and</li> <li>prohibit funding for a rule modifying requirements and processes HUD program participants use to reduce housing discrimination. </li> </ul> <p><b>Full Summary: </b></p> <p><b>Transportation, Housing and Urban Development, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2016 </b></p> <p>Provides FY2016 appropriations for the Department of Transportation, the Department of Housing and Urban Development, and several related agencies. </p> <p><i>Department of Transportation Appropriations Act, 2016 </i></p> <p>Provides FY2016 appropriations for the Department of Transportation (DOT). </p> <p>TITLE I--DEPARTMENT OF TRANSPORTATION </p> <p>Provides appropriations for the Office of the Secretary, including: </p> <ul> <li> Salaries and Expenses; </li> <li>Research and Technology; </li> <li>National Infrastructure Investments (also known as TIGER grants); </li> <li>Financial Management Capital; </li> <li>Cyber Security Initiatives; </li> <li>the Office of Civil Rights; </li> <li>Transportation Planning, Research, and Development; </li> <li>the Working Capital Fund; </li> <li>the Minority Business Resource Center Program; </li> <li>Small and Disadvantaged Business Utilization and Outreach; and </li> <li>Payments to Air Carriers. </li> </ul> <p>(Sec. 101) Prohibits DOT from approving assessments or reimbursable agreements pertaining to funds appropriated to the modal administrations in this bill except for activities underway on the date of enactment, unless the reprogramming process has been completed. </p> <p>(Sec. 102) Permits DOT to use the Working Capital Fund to provide transit benefits to federal employees. </p> <p>(Sec. 103) Requires DOT to: (1) post on its website the schedule and agenda for all meetings of the Credit Council, and (2) require the Credit Council to record the decisions and actions of each meeting. </p> <p>(Sec. 104) Permits DOT to use the Working Capital Fund to provide payments in advance and accept subsequent reimbursements from federal agencies for distributing transit benefits to federal employees. Requires DOT to maintain a limited operating reserve in the Fund to provide uninterrupted transit benefits. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) for: Operations; Facilities and Equipment; Research, Engineering, and Development; and Grants-In-Aid For Airports. </p> <p>Prohibits the use of funds provided by this bill for: new applicants for the second career training program, new unauthorized user fees, or aeronautical charting and cartography activities through the Working Capital Fund. </p> <p>Permits funds received from specified public, private, and foreign sources for expenses incurred to be credited to the appropriation. </p> <p>Requires DOT to submit to Congress a five-year capital investment plan for the FAA. </p> <p>Permits funds to be used for installation and commissioning or runway incursion prevention devices and systems. </p> <p>(Sec. 110) Limit technical staff years under the federally funded research and development center contract between the FAA and the Center for Advanced Aviation System Development. </p> <p>(Sec. 111) Prohibits the FAA from requiring airport sponsors to provide the agency without cost building construction, maintenance, utilities and expenses, or space in sponsor-owned buildings for air traffic control, air navigation, or weather reporting, except for specified exceptions. </p> <p>(Sec. 112) Permits the FAA to reimburse amounts made available from certain fees to carry out the Essential Air Service (EAS) program, which ensures that small communities have a minimum level of air service. </p> <p>(Sec. 113) Permits amounts collected by the FAA for providing technical assistance to foreign aviation authorities to be credited to the Operations account. </p> <p>(Sec. 114) Prohibits the FAA from paying Sunday premium pay except if an individual worked on a Sunday. </p> <p>(Sec. 115) Prohibits the FAA from using funds provided by this bill to purchase a store gift card or gift certificate using a government-issued credit card. </p> <p>(Sec. 116) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used for retention bonuses for FAA employees without prior approval of the Assistant Secretary for Administration of DOT.</p> <p> (Sec. 117) Requires the FAA to block the display of an owner's or operator's aircraft registration number in the Aircraft Situational Display to Industry data program, upon the request of an owner or operator. </p> <p>(Sec. 118) Prohibits the use of funds provided by this bill to pay the salaries and expenses of more than nine political or presidential FAA appointees. </p> <p>(Sec. 119) Prohibits the use of funds provided by this bill to increase fees for navigation products until the FAA provides Congress with a justification for all fees for aeronautical navigation products. </p> <p>(Sec. 119A) Requires the FAA to notify Congress prior to closing a regional operations center or reducing the services it provides. </p> <p>(Sec. 119B) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to change weight restrictions or prior permission rules at Teterboro Airport in New Jersey. </p> <p>Provides funding from the Highway Trust Fund (HTF) to the Federal Highway Administration (FHWA) for Administrative Expenses and Federal-Aid Highways. </p> <p>(Most of DOT's budget is mandatory budget authority rather than discretionary budget authority. The mandatory budget authority is primarily in the form of contract authority derived from the Highway Trust Fund (HTF). Contract authority is the authority to obligate funds in advance of an appropriation Act. </p> <p>Spending from the HTF is determined both by authorization bills and appropriations bills. Authorization bills provide contract authority for highway programs, and appropriations bills include obligation limitations that determine how much of the contract authority may be used in a given year. </p> <p>Funding included in this bill for the Federal Highway Administration and other programs funded by the HTF is contingent upon the enactment of reauthorization legislation.) </p> <p>(Sec. 120) Specifies allocations and requirements for distributing obligation authority from the HTF among federal-aid highway programs. </p> <p>(Sec. 121) Credits funds received by the Bureau of Transportation Statistics from the sale of data products to the Federal-Aid Highways account to reimburse the Bureau for expenses. </p> <p>(Sec. 122) Requires DOT to: (1) provide an informal public notice and comment opportunity prior to waiving the Buy America requirement for federal-aid highway projects, and (2) report to Congress annually on waivers. </p> <p>(Sec. 123) Requires DOT to notify Congress prior to providing credit assistance under the Transportation Finance and Innovation Act (TIFIA) program, which provides credit to finance surface transportation projects of national and regional significance. </p> <p>(Sec. 124) Amends weight limitations for vehicles using the Interstate System to align federal and state requirements for longer combination vehicles operating in Idaho. </p> <p>(Sec. 125) Modifies length requirements for truck trailers or semitrailers operating on the Interstate System. </p> <p>(Sec. 126) Includes Kansas under an agricultural exemption from federal truck trailer length requirements. </p> <p>(Sec. 127) Increases the amount of highway funding required to be set aside for the elimination of hazards and the installation of protective devices at railroad-highway crossings. </p> <p>Provides funding from the HTF to the Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration (FMCSA) for: (1) Motor Carrier Safety Operations and Programs, and (2) Motor Carrier Safety Grants. </p> <p>(Sec. 130) Subjects funds provided by this bill to specified terms and conditions included in prior appropriations Acts regarding Mexico-domiciled motor carriers. </p> <p>(Sec. 131) Requires the FMCSA to provide written notice of violations of certain safety procedures and regulations that could require an expedited safety audit or compliance review or a written response demonstrating corrective action. </p> <p>(Sec. 132) Prohibits funds from being used to enforce the restart provisions of the hours of service of drivers regulation that went into effect on July 1, 2013, unless the Secretary and the DOT Inspector General determine that a required study has: (1) met statutory requirements, and (2) demonstrated improvement in all outcomes related to safety, operator fatigue, driver health and longevity, and work schedules. </p> <p>(Sec. 133) Prohibits Motor Carrier Safety Operations and Programs funds from being used to deny an application to renew a hazardous materials safety permit unless a carrier has the opportunity to present its own corrective actions and DOT determines the actions are insufficient. </p> <p>(Sec. 134) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used for regulations that increase levels of minimum financial responsibility for transporting passengers or property. </p> <p>(Sec. 135) Prohibits funds for Motor Carrier Safety Operations and Programs from being used for a wireless roadside inspection program until after DOT makes specified certifications to Congress. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration (NHTSA) for Operations and Research. </p> <p>Provides funding from the HTF to NHTSA for Operations and Research and Highway Traffic Safety Grants. </p> <p>(Sec. 140) Provides additional funding to NHTSA for travel and related expenses associated with state management reviews and core competency development training for highway safety staff. </p> <p>(Sec. 141) Exempts from the current fiscal year's obligation limitation any obligation authority that was made available in previous public laws. </p> <p>(Sec. 142) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used for the National Highway Safety Advisory Committee. </p> <p>(Sec. 143) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used for NHTSA's National Roadside Survey. </p> <p>(Sec. 144) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to mandate global positioning system tracking without fully considering privacy concerns. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Federal Railroad Administration (FRA) for: </p> <ul> <li> Safety and Operations, </li> <li>Railroad Research and Development, </li> <li>the Railroad Rehabilitation and Improvement Financing Program,</li> <li>Operating Grants to the National Railroad Passenger Corporation (Amtrak), and </li> <li>Capital and Debt Service Grants to Amtrak. </li> </ul> <p>(Sec. 150) Permits the FRA to receive and use cash or spare parts to repair or replace damaged automated track inspection cars and equipment as a result of third party liability for the damages. </p> <p>(Sec. 151) Limits overtime for Amtrak employees. Permits Amtrak to waive the limit for specific employees due to safety or operational efficiency reasons. Requires Amtrak to report to Congress on waivers granted and overtime payments incurred. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Federal Transit Administration (FTA) for Administrative Expenses, Transit Research, Technical Assistance and Training, Capital Investment Grants, and Grants to the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority. </p> <p>Provides funding from the HTF to the FTA for Transit Formula Grants. </p> <p>(Sec. 160) Exempts previously made transit obligations from limitations on obligations. </p> <p>(Sec. 161) Permits FTA Fixed Guideway Capital Investment funds for projects specified in this bill or the accompanying report that are not obligated by September 30, 2020, to be used for other projects eligible to use the funds for the same purpose. </p> <p>(Sec. 162) Permits the transfer of prior year appropriations from older accounts to be merged into new accounts with similar, current activities. </p> <p>(Sec. 163) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to enter into a full funding grant agreement for a project with a New Starts share greater than 50%. </p> <p>(Sec. 164) Prohibits the use of funds for a new light or heavy rail project for the Metropolitan Transit Authority of Harris County, Texas if the project is constructed at a specified location in Houston, Texas unless the voters approve a ballot proposition specifying the location and the project meets specified criteria. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Saint Lawrence Seaway Development Corporation for Operations and Maintenance. </p> <p>Provides appropriations for the Maritime Administration (MARAD) for the Maritime Security Program, Operations and Training, Ship Disposal, and The Maritime Guaranteed Loan (Title XI) Program Account. </p> <p>(Sec. 170) Permits MARAD to furnish utilities and services and make repairs in connection with any lease, contract, or occupancy involving government property under the control of MARAD. Permits payments received to be credited to the appropriations account charged with the cost and requires rental payments to be deposited into the Treasury. </p> <p>(Sec. 171) Prohibits DOT or MARAD from using funds provided by this bill for fee-for-service contracts for vessel disposal, scrapping, or recycling, unless there is no qualified domestic ship recycler that will pay any sum to purchase and scrap or recycle a vessel owned, operated or managed by MARAD or that is part of the National Defense Reserve Fleet. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Pipeline and Hazardous Materials Safety Administration for Operational Expenses, Hazardous Materials Safety, Pipeline Safety, and Emergency Preparedness Grants. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Office of Inspector General and the Surface Transportation Board. </p> <p>(Sec. 180) Permits DOT to use funds for aircraft, motor vehicles, liability insurance, uniforms, or allowances, as authorized by law. </p> <p>(Sec. 181) Permits fund provided by this bill to be used for the employment of temporary or intermittent experts and consultants if the rates do not exceed the rate for an Executive Level IV.</p> <p> (Sec. 182) Prohibits: (1) funds provided by this bill from being used for more than 110 DOT presidential or political appointees, and (2) any of the appointees from being assigned on temporary detail outside of DOT. </p> <p>(Sec. 183) Prohibits recipients of funds provided by this bill from releasing certain personal information and photographs from a driver's license or motor vehicle record without the consent of the affected individual. Prohibits DOT from withholding funds if a state is not in compliance with this provision. </p> <p>(Sec. 184) Permits funds received by specified DOT agencies from states or other private or public sources for training expenses to be credited to specified agency accounts. </p> <p>(Sec. 185) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used for certain loans, loan guarantees, lines of credit, or grants unless DOT notifies Congress prior to announcing competitively selected projects. </p> <p>Requires DOT to provide concurrent notification to Congress regarding any ''quick release'' of funds from the FHWA's Emergency Relief Program. (The program provides funding for the repair or reconstruction of federal-aid highways and roads on federal lands which have suffered serious damage as a result of natural disasters or catastrophic failures from an external cause.) </p> <p>(Sec. 186) Permits rebates, refunds, incentive payments, fees, and other funds received by DOT from travel management centers, charge card programs, the subleasing of building space, and miscellaneous sources to be credited to DOT appropriations and allocated using fair and equitable criteria. </p> <p>(Sec. 187) Permits DOT to use amounts recovered from improper payments to a third party contractor for expenses incurred in the recovery. </p> <p>(Sec. 188) Requires reprogramming action notifications to be transmitted to and approved or denied solely by the House and Senate Committees on Appropriations. </p> <p>(Sec. 189) Limits Surface Transportation Board fees for the filing of rate or practice complaints. </p> <p>(Sec. 190) Permits funds provided by this bill for modal administrations to be obligated to the Office of the Secretary for assessments or reimbursable agreements only if the funds provide a direct benefit to the modal administrations. </p> <p>(Sec. 191) Permits DOT to set uniform standards for transit benefits for agency transit passes and transit benefits. </p> <p>(Sec. 192) Prohibits the Surface Transportation Board from using funds provided by this bill to take any actions with respect to the construction of a high speed rail project in California unless the permit is issued for the entire project. </p> <p>(Sec. 193) Prohibits finds provided by this bill from being used to facilitate new scheduled air transportation from the United States if the flights would land on or pass through property confiscated by the Cuban government. </p> <p><i>Department of Housing and Urban Development Appropriations Act, 2016 </i></p> <p>Provides FY2016 appropriations for the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD). </p> <p>TITLE II--DEPARTMENT OF HOUSING AND URBAN DEVELOPMENT </p> <p>Provides appropriations for Management and Administration, including for Executive Offices and Administrative Support Offices. </p> <p>Provides appropriations for Program Office Salaries and Expenses, including: </p> <ul> <li> Public and Indian Housing, </li> <li>Community Planning and Development, </li> <li>Housing, </li> <li>Policy Development and Research, </li> <li>Fair Housing and Equal Opportunity, and </li> <li>the Office of Lead Hazard Control and Healthy Homes. </li> </ul> <p>Provides appropriations for Public and Indian Housing Programs, including: </p> <ul> <li> Tenant-Based Rental Assistance, </li> <li>the Public Housing Capital Fund, </li> <li>the Public Housing Operating Fund, </li> <li>the Choice Neighborhoods Initiative, </li> <li>the Family Self-Sufficiency program, </li> <li>Native American Housing Block Grants, and </li> <li>the Indian Housing Loan Guarantee Fund Program Account. </li> </ul> <p>Provides appropriations for Community Planning and Development, including: </p> <ul> <li> Housing Opportunities for Persons with AIDS, </li> <li>the Community Development Fund, </li> <li>the Community Development Loan Guarantees Program Account, </li> <li>the Home Investment Partnerships Program, </li> <li>the Self-Help and Assisted Home Ownership Opportunity Program, and </li> <li>Homeless Assistance Grants. </li> </ul> <p>Provides appropriations for Housing Programs, including Project-Based Rental Assistance, Housing for the Elderly, and Housing for Persons with Disabilities. </p> <p>Provides appropriations for Housing Counseling Assistance, including Rental Housing Assistance and Payment to the Manufactured Housing Fees Trust Fund. </p> <p>Provides appropriations and establishes limits on loan commitments for the Federal Housing Administration (FHA), which includes the Mutual Mortgage Insurance Program Account and the General and Special Risk Program Account. </p> <p>Provides appropriation and establishes limits on loan commitments for the Government National Mortgage Association (Ginnie Mae). </p> <p>Provides appropriations for Policy Development and Research for Research and Technology. </p> <p>Provides appropriations for Fair Housing and Equal Opportunity for Fair Housing Activities. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Office of Lead Hazard Control and Healthy Homes, the Information Technology Fund, and the Office of Inspector General. </p> <p>(Sec. 201) Requires 85% of overpayments due to refinancing of state projects under the Stewart B. McKinney Homeless Assistance Amendments Act of 1988 to be rescinded or, in the case of cash, remitted to the Treasury. Permits HUD to use up to 15% of the overpayments to provide project owners with incentives to refinance projects at lower interest rates. </p> <p>(Sec. 202) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to investigate or prosecute under the Fair Housing Act any lawful activities, including the filing or maintaining of a nonfrivolous legal action to achieve or prevent action by a government entity or a court. </p> <p>(Sec. 203) Extends formula modifications for distributing Housing Opportunities for Persons With Aids (HOPWA) funds for certain jurisdictions in New York, New Jersey, and North Carolina. </p> <p>(Sec. 204) Requires any grant, cooperative agreement, or other assistance made pursuant to this title to be made on a competitive basis and in accordance with the Department of Housing and Urban Development Reform Act of 1989. </p> <p>(Sec. 205) Permits specified funds to be used, without regard to limitations on administrative expenses, for: (1) legal services; and (2) payment for services and facilities of the Federal National Mortgage Association (Fannie Mae), Ginnie Mae, the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation (Freddie Mac), the Federal Financing Bank, Federal Reserve banks, Federal Home Loan banks, and any bank insured under the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation Act. </p> <p>(Sec. 206) Prohibits HUD appropriations from being used for any program, project, or activity in excess of amounts included in the budget estimates submitted to Congress, unless otherwise provided by this bill or through reprogramming.</p> <p>(Sec. 207) Permits HUD corporations and agencies subject to the Government Corporation Control Act to utilize funds and make contracts and commitments, without regard to fiscal year limitations and subject to specified restrictions, to implement the FY2016 budget. </p> <p>(Sec. 208) Requires HUD to provide quarterly reports to Congress regarding uncommitted, unobligated, recaptured, and excess funds for each program and activity. </p> <p>(Sec. 209) Requires the President's budget request and HUD's congressional budget justifications to use the same account structure included in this bill. </p> <p>(Sec. 210) Provides that a public housing agency (PHA) or other entity that administers federal housing assistance for the Housing Authority of the county of Los Angeles, California; or Alaska, Iowa, or Mississippi is not required to include public housing residents or recipients of section 8 rental assistance (under the United States Housing Act of 1937) on the governing board. </p> <p>Requires each PHA or entity that does not include these individuals on its board to establish an advisory board of at least six residents of public housing or recipients of section 8 assistance to provide advice on issues related to public housing and section 8. </p> <p>(Sec. 211) Prohibits funds provided by this title from being use for an audit of Ginnie Mae that applies certain requirements of the Federal Credit Reform Act of 1990. </p> <p>(Sec. 212) Permits HUD to transfer project-based assistance, debt, and use restrictions associated with a multifamily housing project from an obsolete or economically nonviable project to a viable project, subject to specified conditions. </p> <p>(Sec. 213) Prohibits section 8 housing assistance from being provided to any individual who: (1) is a student at an institution of higher education; (2) under 24 years of age; (3) is not a veteran; (4) is unmarried; (5) does not have a dependent child; (6) does not have disabilities and was not receiving assistance as of November 30, 2005; and (7) is not otherwise individually eligible, or has parents who are not eligible, to receive assistance. </p> <p>Provides that, for section 8 rental assistance eligibility purposes, any financial assistance (in excess of amounts received for tuition and fees) received under the Higher Education Act of 1965, from private sources, or an institution of higher education shall be considered income, except for a person over age 23 with dependent children. </p> <p>(Sec. 214) Requires Native American Housing Block Grant funds to be distributed to the same Native Alaskans that received funds in FY2005. </p> <p>(Sec. 215) Permits HUD to insure home equity conversion mortgages (HECMs or reverse mortgages) for elderly homeowners through FY2016, notwithstanding limitations on insurance authority included in the National Housing Act. </p> <p>(Sec. 216) Requires HUD, in managing and disposing of any multifamily property that is owned or held by HUD, and during foreclosure on property with a contract for section 8 rental assistance payments or other federal programs, to maintain rental assistance payments attached to any dwelling units in the property. Permits HUD, if a property is not feasible for continued payments based on specified cost or environmental considerations, to: (1) contract with owners of other existing properties for project-based rental assistance payments, or (2) provide other rental assistance.</p> <p> (Sec. 217) Permits the use of Community Development Loan Guarantee funds to guarantee notes or other obligations issued by any state on behalf of its non-entitlement communities. </p> <p>(Sec. 218) Permits certain public housing agencies that own and operate 400 or fewer public housing units to elect to be exempt from asset management requirements imposed by HUD in connection with the operating fund rule. </p> <p>(Sec. 219) Prohibits HUD from using public housing funds to impose any requirement or guideline relating to asset management that restricts or limits the use of capital funds for central office costs, up to the limits established in the Quality Housing and Work Responsibility Act of 1998. </p> <p>(Sec. 220) Prohibits designation of a HUD official or employee as an allotment holder unless the Chief Financial Officer has determined that the employee has: (1) implemented an adequate system of funds control, and (2) received training in funds control procedures and directives. </p> <p>(Sec. 221) Requires HUD to publish all FY2016 Notices of Funding Availability on the Internet. </p> <p>(Sec. 222) Requires attorney fees for program-related litigation to be paid from the individual program office and Office of General Counsel personnel funding and included as line items in the budget submissions of the offices. </p> <p>(Sec. 223) Provides that the HUD-administered Disaster Housing Assistance Program is a HUD program under the McKinney Act for income verification and matching purposes. </p> <p>(Sec. 224) Requires HUD to take specified actions against owners receiving rental subsidies that do not maintain safe properties based on specified Real Estate Assessment Center (REAC) scores. </p> <p>(Sec. 225) Limits salaries and bonuses for public housing agency officials and employees. </p> <p>(Sec. 226) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used for the HUD doctoral dissertation research grant program. </p> <p>(Sec. 227) Requires HUD to notify Congress prior to announcing the recipients of grant awards. </p> <p>(Sec. 228) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to require or enforce the Physical Needs Assessment (PNA). </p> <p>(Sec. 229) Prohibits the FHA, Ginnie Mae, or HUD from using funds provided by this bill to finance mortgages for properties that have been subject to eminent domain. </p> <p>(Sec. 230) Prohibits the use of funds made available by this bill to terminate the status of a unit of general local government as a metropolitan city with respect to community development grants under the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974. </p> <p>(Sec. 231) Permits Office of Policy Development and Research funds for research, evaluation, and statistical purposes that are unexpended at the completion of a contract, grant or cooperative agreement to be deobligated and reobligated for additional research, subject to reprogramming requirements. </p> <p>(Sec. 232) Prohibits HUD from using funds provided by this bill to require a recipient of funding for land acquisition, affordable housing construction, or affordable housing rehabilitation to meet Energy Star or any other energy efficiency standards that exceed the requirements of applicable state and local building codes. </p> <p>(Sec. 233) Rescinds specified unobligated balances of funds provided by the Dodd- Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act and the Housing and Economic Recovery Act of 2008. </p> <p>(Sec. 234) Rescinds specified unobligated balances from funds appropriated for the Rural Housing and Economic Development, Management and Administration, and Program Office Salaries and Expenses accounts. </p> <p>TITLE III--RELATED AGENCIES </p> <p>Provides FY2016 appropriations to: </p> <ul> <li> the Access Board, </li> <li>the Federal Maritime Commission, </li> <li>the Amtrak Office of Inspector General, </li> <li>the National Transportation Safety Board, </li> <li>the Neighborhood Reinvestment Corporation, and </li> <li>the U.S. Interagency Council on Homelessness. </li> </ul> <p>TITLE IV--GENERAL PROVISIONS--THIS ACT </p> <p>Sets forth permissible, restricted, and prohibited used for funds provided by this and other appropriations Acts. </p> <p>(Sec. 401) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to compensate or pay the expenses of non-federal parties intervening in regulatory or adjudicatory proceedings funded in this bill. </p> <p>(Sec. 402) Prohibits transfers of funds to other appropriations or obligations beyond the current fiscal year, unless expressly permitted in this bill. </p> <p>(Sec. 403) Limits expenditures for consulting services to contracts where the expenditures are a matter of public record and available for public inspection, unless otherwise provided by law. </p> <p>(Sec. 404) Prohibits the use of funds provided by this bill for employee training not specifically related to the performance of official duties. </p> <p>(Sec. 405) Specifies procedures, restrictions, and reporting requirements for the reprogramming of funds provided by this bill. </p> <p>(Sec. 406) Permits up to 50% of unobligated balances remaining at the end of FY2016 from appropriations for salaries and expenses to remain available through FY2017, subject to congressional approval and reprogramming guidelines. </p> <p>(Sec. 407) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used for any project that seeks to use eminent domain unless eminent domain is employed only for a public use. </p> <p>(Sec. 408) Prohibits the transfer of funds provided by this bill to a department, agency, or instrumentality of the U.S. government unless the transfer is pursuant to an appropriations Act. </p> <p>(Sec. 409) Prohibits the use of funds provided by this bill to permanently replace an employee intent on returning to his or her previous occupation after completing military service. </p> <p>(Sec. 410) Requires expenditures of funds provided by this bill to comply with the Buy American Act. </p> <p>(Sec. 411) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being made available to any person or entity that has been convicted of violating the Buy American Act. </p> <p>(Sec. 412) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to purchase first class or premium airline travel in violation of specified federal travel regulations. </p> <p>(Sec. 413) Prohibits the use of funds provided by this bill to approve a new foreign air carrier permit or exemption application if the approval would contravene U.S. law or specified provisions of the U.S.-E.U.-Iceland-Norway Air Transport Agreement. </p> <p>(Sec. 414) Prohibits the Federal Maritime Commission or the Maritime Administration from using funds provided by this bill to issue a license or certificate for a commercial vessel that was docked or anchored within seven miles of a port on property confiscated by the Cuban government. </p> <p>(Sec. 415) Prohibits the FTA from using funds provided by this bill for regulations that prohibit statutorily or administratively imposed state or local geographic preferences in the evaluation of bids or proposals for construction hiring purposes, except where applicable federal statutes expressly mandate or encourage geographic preferences.</p> <p>(Sec. 416) Establishes a spending reduction account for the amount by which spending proposed in this bill exceeds the subcommittee's allocation under the Congressional Budget Act of 1974. Specifies that the amount is $0. (Under the Rules of the House of Representatives, any savings included in the spending reduction account are not available for further appropriation during consideration of the bill.) </p> <p>(Sec. 417) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used for contracts with companies convicted, indicted, or civilly charged with specified federal crimes or that have more than $3,000 in delinquent federal taxes within a three-year period surrounding the contract. </p> <p>(Sec. 418) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used in contravention of FAA safety regulations restricting the opening or unlocking of a flight deck door. </p> <p>(Sec. 419) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to make incentive payments to contractors that are behind schedule or over budget. </p> <p>(Sec. 420) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used in contravention of the Fifth or Fourteenth Amendments of the U.S. Constitution or title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (prohibits discrimination on the basis of race, color, and national origin in programs and activities receiving federal financial assistance). </p> <p>(Sec. 421) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used for the FTA's Rapid Growth Area Transit Program. </p> <p>(Sec. 422) Prohibits the FAA from using funds provided by this bill to redesign the Phoenix, Arizona Metroplex regional airspace. </p> <p>(Sec. 423) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from be used to carry out section 210 of this bill with respect to the Housing Authority of the county of Los Angeles, California. </p> <p>(Sec. 424) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used for the Private Enforcement Initiative under the Fair Housing Initiatives Program. (The Private Enforcement Initiative funds non-profit fair housing organizations to carry out testing and enforcement activities to prevent or eliminate discriminatory housing practices.) </p> <p>(Sec. 425) Prohibits HUD from using funds provided by this bill for the rule entitled &quot;Affirmatively Furthering Fair Housing&quot; or the notice entitled &quot;Affirmatively Furthering Fair Housing Assessment Tool.&quot; (The rule modifies requirements and processes HUD program participants use to reduce housing discrimination.) </p> <p>(Sec. 426) Prohibits funding provided by this bill for FTA--Transit Formula Grants from being used in contravention of statutory provisions governing fixed guideway capital investment grants. </p> <p>(Sec. 427) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to purchase new light-duty vehicles for an executive fleet or an agency's fleet inventory, except in accordance with Presidential Memorandum- Federal Fleet Performance, which establishes requirements for purchasing alternative fueled vehicles. </p> <p>(Sec. 428) Prohibits funds provided by this bill for FAA regulations entitled &quot;Operations and Certification of Small Unmanned Aircraft Systems&quot; in contravention of a regulation requiring consideration of agricultural purposes. </p> <p>(Sec. 429) Prohibits the FAA from using funding provided by this bill to institute certain civil or administration actions against the East Hampton Airport in East Hampton, New York. </p> <p>(Sec. 430) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used for high speed rail in California or for the FRA to administer a grant agreement with the California High Speed Rail Authority that contains a tapered matching requirement. (A tapered match allows a project's federal share to vary from year to year as long as the final contribution of federal funds does not exceed the project's maximum authorized share.) </p> <p>(Sec. 431) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to enforce rules related to roadside signs with respect to signs for service clubs and religious notices. </p> <p>(Sec. 432) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used in contravention of HUD regulations restricting assistance to noncitizens. </p> <p>(Sec. 433) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being use to provide assistance in contravention of provisions of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1980 requiring individuals to provide details regarding citizenship or immigration status to receive financial assistance. </p> <p>(Sec. 434) Prohibits the FAA from using funds provided by this bill for bio-data assessment (a biographical questionnaire) in the hiring of Air Traffic Control Specialists. </p> <p>(Sec. 435) Prohibits HUD from using funds provided by this bill from being used for the final rule entitled &quot;Implementation of the Fair Housing Act's Discriminatory Effects Standard&quot; which establishes a three-part burden-shifting test for determining when a practice with a discriminatory effect violates the Fair Housing Act. </p> <p>(Sec. 436) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used in contravention of Executive Order 11246 (Equal Employment Opportunity). </p> <p>(Sec. 437) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to acquire a camera to collect or store vehicle license plate numbers. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2577v79" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-10-16">
<action-date>2015-05-27</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p><b>Highlights: </b></p> <p>The Transportation, Housing and Urban Development, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2016 provides FY2016 appropriations for the Department of Transportation (DOT), the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD), and several related agencies. </p> <p>The bill includes both discretionary and mandatory funding. The HUD budget is primarily discretionary spending, and most of the DOT budget is mandatory spending, in the form of contract authority from the Highway Trust Fund (HTF). Funding from the HTF is contingent on the enactment of a new authorization bill. </p> <p>The bill increases overall funding for Transportation, Housing and Urban Development, and Related Agencies above FY2015 levels. Compared to FY2015 levels, the bill decreases funding for DOT and increases funding for HUD. </p> <p>Within the DOT budget, the bill: </p> <ul> <li> decreases funding for National Infrastructure Investments (Transportation Investment Generating Economic Recovery or TIGER grants), the National Railroad Passenger Corporation (Amtrak), Capital Investment Grants (New Starts), and the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority; </li> <li>increases funding for the Federal Aviation Administration, the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration, the Maritime Administration, and the Pipeline and Hazardous Materials Safety Administration; and </li> <li>funds the Federal-Aid Highway Program from the HTF at the FY2015 level, contingent on the enactment of a new authorization bill. </li> </ul> <p>Within the HUD budget, the bill: </p> <ul> <li>increases funding for the Tenant-Based Rental Assistance and Project-Based Rental Assistance accounts that fund the low-income housing programs under Section 8 of the United States Housing Act of 1937;</li> <li>decreases funding for Policy Development and Research, the Office of Lead Hazard Control and Healthy Homes, and the Information Technology Fund; and </li> <li>funds the Community Development Block Grant (CDBG) formula program and the HOME Investment Partnerships Program at the FY2015 levels. </li> </ul> <p>For Public Housing, the bill funds the Public Housing Operating Fund at the FY2015 level and decreases funding for the Public Housing Capital Fund and Choice Neighborhoods. </p> <p>The bill decreases funding for the Neighborhood Reinvestment Corporation and funds the other related agencies included in the bill at the FY2015 levels. </p> <p>Also included in the bill are provisions that would: </p> <ul> <li> restrict flights and cruise ships from traveling to Cuba, </li> <li>limit the authority of the Surface Transportation Board to approve phases of the California High Speed Rail project, </li> <li>affect limits on truck size and weight, and </li> <li>restrict enforcement of regulations for commercial truck drivers' rest. </li> </ul> <p><b>Full Summary: </b></p> <p><b>Transportation, Housing and Urban Development, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2016 </b></p> <p>Provides FY2016 appropriations for the Department of Transportation, the Department of Housing and Urban Development, and several related agencies. </p> <p><i>Department of Transportation Appropriations Act, 2016 </i></p> <p>Provides FY2016 appropriations for the Department of Transportation (DOT). </p> <p>TITLE I--DEPARTMENT OF TRANSPORTATION </p> <p>Provides appropriations for the Office of the Secretary, including: </p> <ul> <li> Salaries and Expenses; </li> <li>Research and Technology; </li> <li>National Infrastructure Investments (also known as TIGER grants); </li> <li>Financial Management Capital; </li> <li>Cyber Security Initiatives; </li> <li>the Office of Civil Rights; </li> <li>Transportation Planning, Research, and Development; </li> <li>the Working Capital Fund; </li> <li>the Minority Business Resource Center Program; </li> <li>Small and Disadvantaged Business Utilization and Outreach; and </li> <li>Payments to Air Carriers. </li> </ul> <p>(Sec. 101) Prohibits DOT from approving assessments or reimbursable agreements pertaining to funds appropriated to the modal administrations in this bill except for activities underway on the date of enactment, unless the reprogramming process has been completed. </p> <p>(Sec. 102) Permits DOT to engage in activities with states and state legislators to consider proposals to reduce motorcycle fatalities. </p> <p>(Sec. 103) Permits DOT to use the Working Capital Fund to provide transit benefits to federal employees. </p> <p>(Sec. 104) Requires DOT to: (1) post on its website the schedule and agenda for all meetings of the Credit Council, and (2) require the Credit Council to record the decisions and actions of each meeting. </p> <p>(Sec. 105) Permits DOT to use the Working Capital Fund to provide payments in advance and accept subsequent reimbursements from federal agencies for distributing transit benefits to federal employees. Requires DOT to maintain a limited operating reserve in the Fund to provide uninterrupted transit benefits. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) for: Operations; Facilities and Equipment; Research, Engineering, and Development; and Grants-In-Aid For Airports. </p> <p>Prohibits the use of funds provided by this bill for: new applicants for the second career training program, new unauthorized user fees, or aeronautical charting and cartography activities through the Working Capital Fund. </p> <p>Permits funds received from specified public, private, and foreign sources for expenses incurred to be credited to the appropriation. </p> <p>Requires DOT to submit to Congress a five-year capital investment plan for the FAA. </p> <p>Permits funds to be used for installation and commissioning or runway incursion prevention devices and systems. </p> <p>(Sec. 110) Limit technical staff years under the federally funded research and development center contract between the FAA and the Center for Advanced Aviation System Development. </p> <p>(Sec. 111) Prohibits the FAA from requiring airport sponsors to provide the agency without cost building construction, maintenance, utilities and expenses, or space in sponsor-owned buildings for air traffic control, air navigation, or weather reporting, except for specified exceptions. </p> <p>(Sec. 112) Permits the FAA to reimburse amounts made available from certain fees to carry out the Essential Air Service (EAS) program, which ensures that small communities have a minimum level of air service. </p> <p>(Sec. 113) Permits amounts collected by the FAA for providing technical assistance to foreign aviation authorities to be credited to the Operations account. </p> <p>(Sec. 114) Prohibits the FAA from paying Sunday premium pay except if an individual worked on a Sunday. </p> <p>(Sec. 115) Prohibits the FAA from using funds provided by this bill to purchase a store gift card or gift certificate using a government-issued credit card. </p> <p>(Sec. 116) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used for retention bonuses for FAA employees without prior approval of the Assistant Secretary for Administration of DOT.</p> <p> (Sec. 117) Requires the FAA to block the display of an owner's or operator's aircraft registration number in the Aircraft Situational Display to Industry data program, upon the request of an owner or operator. </p> <p>(Sec. 118) Prohibits the use of funds provided by this bill to pay the salaries and expenses of more than nine political or presidential FAA appointees. </p> <p>(Sec. 119) Prohibits the use of funds provided by this bill to increase fees for navigation products until the FAA provides Congress with a justification for all fees for aeronautical navigation products. </p> <p>(Sec. 119A) Requires the FAA to notify Congress prior to closing a regional operations center or reducing the services it provides. </p> <p>(Sec. 119B) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to change weight restrictions or prior permission rules at Teterboro Airport in New Jersey. </p> <p>Provides funding from the Highway Trust Fund (HTF) to the Federal Highway Administration (FHWA) for Administrative Expenses and Federal-Aid Highways. </p> <p>(Most of DOT's budget is mandatory budget authority rather than discretionary budget authority. The mandatory budget authority is primarily in the form of contract authority derived from the Highway Trust Fund (HTF). Contract authority is the authority to obligate funds in advance of an appropriation Act. </p> <p>Spending from the HTF is determined both by authorization bills and appropriations bills. Authorization bills provide contract authority for highway programs, and appropriations bills include obligation limitations that determine how much of the contract authority may be used in a given year. </p> <p>Funding included in this bill for the Federal Highway Administration and other programs funded by the HTF is contingent upon the enactment of reauthorization legislation.) </p> <p>(Sec. 120) Specifies allocations and requirements for distributing obligation authority from the HTF among federal-aid highway programs. </p> <p>(Sec. 121) Credits funds received by the Bureau of Transportation Statistics from the sale of data products to the Federal-Aid Highways account to reimburse the Bureau for expenses. </p> <p>(Sec. 122) Requires DOT to: (1) provide an informal public notice and comment opportunity prior to waiving the Buy America requirement for federal-aid highway projects, and (2) report to Congress annually on waivers. </p> <p>(Sec. 123) Requires DOT to notify Congress prior to providing credit assistance under the Transportation Finance and Innovation Act (TIFIA) program, which provides credit to finance surface transportation projects of national and regional significance. </p> <p>(Sec. 124) Amends weight limitations for vehicles using the Interstate System to align federal and state requirements for longer combination vehicles operating in Idaho. </p> <p>(Sec. 125) Modifies length requirements for truck trailers or semitrailers operating on the Interstate System. </p> <p>(Sec. 126) Includes Kansas under an agricultural exemption from federal truck trailer length requirements. </p> <p>(Sec. 127) Increases the amount of highway funding required to be set aside for the elimination of hazards and the installation of protective devices at railroad-highway crossings. </p> <p>Provides funding from the HTF to the Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration (FMCSA) for: (1) Motor Carrier Safety Operations and Programs, and (2) Motor Carrier Safety Grants. </p> <p>(Sec. 130) Subjects funds provided by this bill to specified terms and conditions included in prior appropriations Acts regarding Mexico-domiciled motor carriers. </p> <p>(Sec. 131) Requires the FMCSA to provide written notice of violations of certain safety procedures and regulations that could require an expedited safety audit or compliance review or a written response demonstrating corrective action. </p> <p>(Sec. 132) Prohibits funds from being used to enforce the restart provisions of the hours of service of drivers regulation that went into effect on July 1, 2013, unless the Secretary and the DOT Inspector General determine that a required study has: (1) met statutory requirements, and (2) demonstrated improvement in all outcomes related to safety, operator fatigue, driver health and longevity, and work schedules. </p> <p>(Sec. 133) Prohibits Motor Carrier Safety Operations and Programs funds from being used to deny an application to renew a hazardous materials safety permit unless a carrier has the opportunity to present its own corrective actions and DOT determines the actions are insufficient. </p> <p>(Sec. 134) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used for regulations that increase levels of minimum financial responsibility for transporting passengers or property. </p> <p>(Sec. 135) Prohibits funds for Motor Carrier Safety Operations and Programs from being used for a wireless roadside inspection program until after DOT makes specified certifications to Congress. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration (NHTSA) for Operations and Research. </p> <p>Provides funding from the HTF to NHTSA for Operations and Research and Highway Traffic Safety Grants. </p> <p>(Sec. 140) Provides additional funding to NHTSA for travel and related expenses associated with state management reviews and core competency development training for highway safety staff. </p> <p>(Sec. 141) Exempts from the current fiscal year's obligation limitation any obligation authority that was made available in previous public laws. </p> <p>(Sec. 142) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used for the National Highway Safety Advisory Committee. </p> <p>(Sec. 143) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used for NHTSA's National Roadside Survey. </p> <p>(Sec. 144) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to mandate global positioning system tracking without fully considering privacy concerns. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Federal Railroad Administration (FRA) for: </p> <ul> <li> Safety and Operations, </li> <li>Railroad Research and Development, </li> <li>the Railroad Rehabilitation and Improvement Financing Program,</li> <li>Operating Grants to the National Railroad Passenger Corporation (Amtrak), and </li> <li>Capital and Debt Service Grants to Amtrak. </li> </ul> <p>(Sec. 150) Permits the FRA to receive and use cash or spare parts to repair or replace damaged automated track inspection cars and equipment as a result of third party liability for the damages. </p> <p>(Sec. 151) Limits overtime for Amtrak employees. Permits Amtrak to waive the limit for specific employees due to safety or operational efficiency reasons. Requires Amtrak to report to Congress on waivers granted and overtime payments incurred. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Federal Transit Administration (FTA) for Administrative Expenses, Transit Research, Technical Assistance and Training, Capital Investment Grants, and Grants to the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority. </p> <p>Provides funding from the HTF to the FTA for Transit Formula Grants. </p> <p>(Sec. 160) Exempts previously made transit obligations from limitations on obligations. </p> <p>(Sec. 161) Permits FTA Fixed Guideway Capital Investment funds for projects specified in this bill or the accompanying report that are not obligated by September 30, 2020, to be used for other projects eligible to use the funds for the same purpose. </p> <p>(Sec. 162) Permits the transfer of prior year appropriations from older accounts to be merged into new accounts with similar, current activities. </p> <p>(Sec. 163) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to enter into a full funding grant agreement for a project with a New Starts share greater than 50%. </p> <p>(Sec. 164) Prohibits the use of funds for a new light or heavy rail project for the Metropolitan Transit Authority of Harris County, Texas if the project is constructed at a specified location in Houston, Texas unless the voters approve a ballot proposition specifying the location and the project meets specified criteria. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Saint Lawrence Seaway Development Corporation for Operations and Maintenance. </p> <p>Provides appropriations for the Maritime Administration (MARAD) for the Maritime Security Program, Operations and Training, Ship Disposal, and The Maritime Guaranteed Loan (Title XI) Program Account. </p> <p>(Sec. 170) Permits MARAD to furnish utilities and services and make repairs in connection with any lease, contract, or occupancy involving government property under the control of MARAD. Permits payments received to be credited to the appropriations account charged with the cost and requires rental payments to be deposited into the Treasury. </p> <p>(Sec. 171) Prohibits DOT or MARAD from using funds provided by this bill for fee-for-service contracts for vessel disposal, scrapping, or recycling, unless there is no qualified domestic ship recycler that will pay any sum to purchase and scrap or recycle a vessel owned, operated or managed by MARAD or that is part of the National Defense Reserve Fleet. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Pipeline and Hazardous Materials Safety Administration for Operational Expenses, Hazardous Materials Safety, Pipeline Safety, and Emergency Preparedness Grants. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Office of Inspector General and the Surface Transportation Board. </p> <p>(Sec. 180) Permits DOT to use funds for aircraft, motor vehicles, liability insurance, uniforms, or allowances, as authorized by law. </p> <p>(Sec. 181) Permits fund provided by this bill to be used for the employment of temporary or intermittent experts and consultants if the rates do not exceed the rate for an Executive Level IV.</p> <p> (Sec. 182) Prohibits: (1) funds provided by this bill from being used for more than 110 DOT presidential or political appointees, and (2) any of the appointees from being assigned on temporary detail outside of DOT. </p> <p>(Sec. 183) Prohibits recipients of funds provided by this bill from releasing certain personal information and photographs from a driver's license or motor vehicle record without the consent of the affected individual. Prohibits DOT from withholding funds if a state is not in compliance with this provision. </p> <p>(Sec. 184) Permits funds received by specified DOT agencies from states or other private or public sources for training expenses to be credited to specified agency accounts. </p> <p>(Sec. 185) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used for certain loans, loan guarantees, lines of credit, or grants unless DOT notifies Congress prior to announcing competitively selected projects. </p> <p>Requires DOT to provide concurrent notification to Congress regarding any ''quick release'' of funds from the FHWA's Emergency Relief Program. (The program provides funding for the repair or reconstruction of federal-aid highways and roads on federal lands which have suffered serious damage as a result of natural disasters or catastrophic failures from an external cause.) </p> <p>(Sec. 186) Permits rebates, refunds, incentive payments, fees, and other funds received by DOT from travel management centers, charge card programs, the subleasing of building space, and miscellaneous sources to be credited to DOT appropriations and allocated using fair and equitable criteria. </p> <p>(Sec. 187) Permits DOT to use amounts recovered from improper payments to a third party contractor for expenses incurred in the recovery. </p> <p>(Sec. 188) Requires reprogramming action notifications to be transmitted to and approved or denied solely by the House and Senate Committees on Appropriations. </p> <p>(Sec. 189) Limits Surface Transportation Board fees for the filing of rate or practice complaints. </p> <p>(Sec. 190) Permits funds provided by this bill for modal administrations to be obligated to the Office of the Secretary for assessments or reimbursable agreements only if the funds provide a direct benefit to the modal administrations. </p> <p>(Sec. 191) Permits DOT to set uniform standards for transit benefits for agency transit passes and transit benefits. </p> <p>(Sec. 192) Prohibits the Surface Transportation Board from using funds provided by this bill to take any actions with respect to the construction of a high speed rail project in California unless the permit is issued for the entire project. </p> <p>(Sec. 193) Prohibits finds provided by this bill from being used to facilitate new scheduled air transportation from the United States if the flights would land on or pass through property confiscated by the Cuban government. </p> <p><i>Department of Housing and Urban Development Appropriations Act, 2016 </i></p> <p>Provides FY2016 appropriations for the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD). </p> <p>TITLE II--DEPARTMENT OF HOUSING AND URBAN DEVELOPMENT </p> <p>Provides appropriations for Management and Administration, including for Executive Offices and Administrative Support Offices. </p> <p>Provides appropriations for Program Office Salaries and Expenses, including: </p> <ul> <li> Public and Indian Housing, </li> <li>Community Planning and Development, </li> <li>Housing, </li> <li>Policy Development and Research, </li> <li>Fair Housing and Equal Opportunity, and </li> <li>the Office of Lead Hazard Control and Healthy Homes. </li> </ul> <p>Provides appropriations for Public and Indian Housing Programs, including: </p> <ul> <li> Tenant-Based Rental Assistance, </li> <li>the Public Housing Capital Fund, </li> <li>the Public Housing Operating Fund, </li> <li>the Choice Neighborhoods Initiative, </li> <li>the Family Self-Sufficiency program, </li> <li>Native American Housing Block Grants, and </li> <li>the Indian Housing Loan Guarantee Fund Program Account. </li> </ul> <p>Provides appropriations for Community Planning and Development, including: </p> <ul> <li> Housing Opportunities for Persons with AIDS, </li> <li>the Community Development Fund, </li> <li>the Community Development Loan Guarantees Program Account, </li> <li>the Home Investment Partnerships Program, </li> <li>the Self-Help and Assisted Home Ownership Opportunity Program, and </li> <li>Homeless Assistance Grants. </li> </ul> <p>Provides appropriations for Housing Programs, including Project-Based Rental Assistance, Housing for the Elderly, and Housing for Persons with Disabilities. </p> <p>Provides appropriations for Housing Counseling Assistance, including Rental Housing Assistance and Payment to the Manufactured Housing Fees Trust Fund. </p> <p>Provides appropriations and establishes limits on loan commitments for the Federal Housing Administration (FHA), which includes the Mutual Mortgage Insurance Program Account and the General and Special Risk Program Account. </p> <p>Provides appropriation and establishes limits on loan commitments for the Government National Mortgage Association (Ginnie Mae). </p> <p>Provides appropriations for Policy Development and Research for Research and Technology. </p> <p>Provides appropriations for Fair Housing and Equal Opportunity for Fair Housing Activities. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Office of Lead Hazard Control and Healthy Homes, the Information Technology Fund, and the Office of Inspector General. </p> <p>(Sec. 201) Requires 85% of overpayments due to refinancing of state projects under the Stewart B. McKinney Homeless Assistance Amendments Act of 1988 to be rescinded or, in the case of cash, remitted to the Treasury. Permits HUD to use up to 15% of the overpayments to provide project owners with incentives to refinance projects at lower interest rates. </p> <p>(Sec. 202) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to investigate or prosecute under the Fair Housing Act any lawful activities, including the filing or maintaining of a nonfrivolous legal action to achieve or prevent action by a government entity or a court. </p> <p>(Sec. 203) Extends formula modifications for distributing Housing Opportunities for Persons With Aids (HOPWA) funds for certain jurisdictions in New York, New Jersey, and North Carolina. </p> <p>(Sec. 204) Requires any grant, cooperative agreement, or other assistance made pursuant to this title to be made on a competitive basis and in accordance with the Department of Housing and Urban Development Reform Act of 1989. </p> <p>(Sec. 205) Permits specified funds to be used, without regard to limitations on administrative expenses, for: (1) legal services; and (2) payment for services and facilities of the Federal National Mortgage Association (Fannie Mae), Ginnie Mae, the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation (Freddie Mac), the Federal Financing Bank, Federal Reserve banks, Federal Home Loan banks, and any bank insured under the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation Act. </p> <p>(Sec. 206) Prohibits HUD appropriations from being used for any program, project, or activity in excess of amounts included in the budget estimates submitted to Congress, unless otherwise provided by this bill or through reprogramming.</p> <p>(Sec. 207) Permits HUD corporations and agencies subject to the Government Corporation Control Act to utilize funds and make contracts and commitments, without regard to fiscal year limitations and subject to specified restrictions, to implement the FY2016 budget. </p> <p>(Sec. 208) Requires HUD to provide quarterly reports to Congress regarding uncommitted, unobligated, recaptured, and excess funds for each program and activity. </p> <p>(Sec. 209) Requires the President's budget request and HUD's congressional budget justifications to use the same account structure included in this bill. </p> <p>(Sec. 210) Provides that a public housing agency (PHA) or other entity that administers federal housing assistance for the Housing Authority of the county of Los Angeles, California; or Alaska, Iowa, or Mississippi is not required to include public housing residents or recipients of section 8 rental assistance (under the United States Housing Act of 1937) on the governing board. </p> <p>Requires each PHA or entity that does not include these individuals on its board to establish an advisory board of at least six residents of public housing or recipients of section 8 assistance to provide advice on issues related to public housing and section 8. </p> <p>(Sec. 211) Prohibits funds provided by this title from being use for an audit of Ginnie Mae that applies certain requirements of the Federal Credit Reform Act of 1990. </p> <p>(Sec. 212) Permits HUD to transfer project-based assistance, debt, and use restrictions associated with a multifamily housing project from an obsolete or economically nonviable project to a viable project, subject to specified conditions. </p> <p>(Sec. 213) Prohibits section 8 housing assistance from being provided to any individual who: (1) is a student at an institution of higher education; (2) under 24 years of age; (3) is not a veteran; (4) is unmarried; (5) does not have a dependent child; (6) does not have disabilities and was not receiving assistance as of November 30, 2005; and (7) is not otherwise individually eligible, or has parents who are not eligible, to receive assistance. </p> <p>Provides that, for section 8 rental assistance eligibility purposes, any financial assistance (in excess of amounts received for tuition and fees) received under the Higher Education Act of 1965, from private sources, or an institution of higher education shall be considered income, except for a person over age 23 with dependent children. </p> <p>(Sec. 214) Requires Native American Housing Block Grant funds to be distributed to the same Native Alaskans that received funds in FY2005. </p> <p>(Sec. 215) Permits HUD to insure home equity conversion mortgages (HECMs or reverse mortgages) for elderly homeowners through FY2016, notwithstanding limitations on insurance authority included in the National Housing Act. </p> <p>(Sec. 216) Requires HUD, in managing and disposing of any multifamily property that is owned or held by HUD, and during foreclosure on property with a contract for section 8 rental assistance payments or other federal programs, to maintain rental assistance payments attached to any dwelling units in the property. Permits HUD, if a property is not feasible for continued payments based on specified cost or environmental considerations, to: (1) contract with owners of other existing properties for project-based rental assistance payments, or (2) provide other rental assistance.</p> <p> (Sec. 217) Permits the use of Community Development Loan Guarantee funds to guarantee notes or other obligations issued by any state on behalf of its non-entitlement communities. </p> <p>(Sec. 218) Permits certain public housing agencies that own and operate 400 or fewer public housing units to elect to be exempt from asset management requirements imposed by HUD in connection with the operating fund rule. </p> <p>(Sec. 219) Prohibits HUD from using public housing funds to impose any requirement or guideline relating to asset management that restricts or limits the use of capital funds for central office costs, up to the limits established in the Quality Housing and Work Responsibility Act of 1998. </p> <p>(Sec. 220) Prohibits designation of a HUD official or employee as an allotment holder unless the Chief Financial Officer has determined that the employee has: (1) implemented an adequate system of funds control, and (2) received training in funds control procedures and directives. </p> <p>(Sec. 221) Requires HUD to publish all FY2016 Notices of Funding Availability on the Internet. </p> <p>(Sec. 222) Requires attorney fees for program-related litigation to be paid from the individual program office and Office of General Counsel personnel funding and included as line items in the budget submissions of the offices. </p> <p>(Sec. 223) Provides that the HUD-administered Disaster Housing Assistance Program is a HUD program under the McKinney Act for income verification and matching purposes. </p> <p>(Sec. 224) Requires HUD to take specified actions against owners receiving rental subsidies that do not maintain safe properties based on specified Real Estate Assessment Center (REAC) scores. </p> <p>(Sec. 225) Limits salaries and bonuses for public housing agency officials and employees. </p> <p>(Sec. 226) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used for the HUD doctoral dissertation research grant program. </p> <p>(Sec. 227) Requires HUD to notify Congress prior to announcing the recipients of grant awards. </p> <p>(Sec. 228) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to require or enforce the Physical Needs Assessment (PNA). </p> <p>(Sec. 229) Prohibits the FHA, Ginnie Mae, or HUD from using funds provided by this bill to finance mortgages for properties that have been subject to eminent domain. </p> <p>(Sec. 230) Prohibits the use of funds made available by this bill to terminate the status of a unit of general local government as a metropolitan city with respect to community development grants under the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974. </p> <p>(Sec. 231) Permits Office of Policy Development and Research funds for research, evaluation, and statistical purposes that are unexpended at the completion of a contract, grant or cooperative agreement to be deobligated and reobligated for additional research, subject to reprogramming requirements. </p> <p>(Sec. 232) Prohibits HUD from using funds provided by this bill to require a recipient of funding for land acquisition, affordable housing construction, or affordable housing rehabilitation to meet Energy Star or any other energy efficiency standards that exceed the requirements of applicable state and local building codes. </p> <p>(Sec. 233) Rescinds specified unobligated balances of funds provided by the Dodd- Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act and the Housing and Economic Recovery Act of 2008. </p> <p>(Sec. 234) Rescinds specified unobligated balances from funds appropriated for the Rural Housing and Economic Development, Management and Administration, and Program Office Salaries and Expenses accounts. </p> <p>TITLE III--RELATED AGENCIES </p> <p>Provides FY2016 appropriations to: </p> <ul> <li> the Access Board, </li> <li>the Federal Maritime Commission, </li> <li>the Amtrak Office of Inspector General, </li> <li>the National Transportation Safety Board, </li> <li>the Neighborhood Reinvestment Corporation, and </li> <li>the U.S. Interagency Council on Homelessness. </li> </ul> <p>TITLE IV--GENERAL PROVISIONS--THIS ACT </p> <p>Sets forth permissible, restricted, and prohibited used for funds provided by this and other appropriations Acts. </p> <p>(Sec. 401) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to compensate or pay the expenses of non-federal parties intervening in regulatory or adjudicatory proceedings funded in this bill. </p> <p>(Sec. 402) Prohibits transfers of funds to other appropriations or obligations beyond the current fiscal year, unless expressly permitted in this bill. </p> <p>(Sec. 403) Limits expenditures for consulting services to contracts where the expenditures are a matter of public record and available for public inspection, unless otherwise provided by law. </p> <p>(Sec. 404) Prohibits the use of funds provided by this bill for employee training not specifically related to the performance of official duties. </p> <p>(Sec. 405) Specifies procedures, restrictions, and reporting requirements for the reprogramming of funds provided by this bill. </p> <p>(Sec. 406) Permits up to 50% of unobligated balances remaining at the end of FY2016 from appropriations for salaries and expenses to remain available through FY2017, subject to congressional approval and reprogramming guidelines. </p> <p>(Sec. 407) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used for any project that seeks to use eminent domain unless eminent domain is employed only for a public use. </p> <p>(Sec. 408) Prohibits the transfer of funds provided by this bill to a department, agency, or instrumentality of the U.S. government unless the transfer is pursuant to an appropriations Act. </p> <p>(Sec. 409) Prohibits the use of funds provided by this bill to permanently replace an employee intent on returning to his or her previous occupation after completing military service. </p> <p>(Sec. 410) Requires expenditures of funds provided by this bill to comply with the Buy American Act. </p> <p>(Sec. 411) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being made available to any person or entity that has been convicted of violating the Buy American Act. </p> <p>(Sec. 412) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to purchase first class or premium airline travel in violation of specified federal travel regulations. </p> <p>(Sec. 413) Prohibits the use of funds provided by this bill to approve a new foreign air carrier permit or exemption application if the approval would contravene U.S. law or specified provisions of the U.S.-E.U.-Iceland-Norway Air Transport Agreement. </p> <p>(Sec. 414) Prohibits the Federal Maritime Commission or the Maritime Administration from using funds provided by this bill to issue a license or certificate for a commercial vessel that was docked or anchored within seven miles of a port on property confiscated by the Cuban government. </p> <p>(Sec. 415) Establishes a spending reduction account for the amount by which spending proposed in this bill exceeds the subcommittee's allocation under the Congressional Budget Act of 1974. Specifies that the amount is $0. (Under the Rules of the House of Representatives, any savings included in the spending reduction account are not available for further appropriation during consideration of the bill.) </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2577v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-05-29">
<action-date>2015-05-27</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Transportation, Housing and Urban Development, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2016 </b></p> <p>Provides FY2016 appropriations to the Department of Transportation (DOT), the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD), and several related agencies. </p> <p><i>Department of Transportation Appropriations Act, 2016 </i></p> <p>Provides appropriations to DOT for the Office of the Secretary, the Federal Aviation Administration, the Federal Highway Administration, the Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration, the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration, the Federal Railroad Administration, the Federal Transit Administration, the Saint Lawrence Seaway Development Corporation, the Maritime Administration, the Pipeline and Hazardous Materials Safety Administration, the Office of Inspector General, and the Surface Transportation Board.</p> <p> <i>Department of Housing and Urban Development Appropriations Act, 2016 </i></p> <p>Provides appropriations to HUD for Management and Administration, Program Office Salaries and Expenses, Public and Indian Housing Programs, Community Planning and Development, Housing Programs, Housing Counseling Assistance, the Federal Housing Administration, the Government National Mortgage Association (Ginnie Mae), Policy Development and Research, Fair Housing and Equal Opportunity, the Office of Lead Hazard Control and Healthy Homes, and the Office of Inspector General. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to related agencies, including the Access Board, the Federal Maritime Commission, the National Railroad Passenger Corporation (Amtrak) Office of Inspector General, the National Transportation Safety Board, the Neighborhood Reinvestment Corporation, and the U.S. Interagency Council on Homelessness. </p> <p>Rescinds specified unobligated balances from prior appropriations. Sets forth permissible, restricted, and prohibited uses for funds provided by this and other appropriations Acts. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
