<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3741" measure-id="id114hr3741" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-10-09" update-date="2015-10-21">
<title>Commission to Verify Iranian Nuclear Compliance Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3741v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-10-21">
<action-date>2015-10-09</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Commission to Verify Iranian Nuclear Compliance Act</strong></p> <p>This bill establishes in the legislative branch the Commission to Verify Iranian Nuclear Compliance, which shall continually: </p> <ul> <li> verify the Islamic Republic of Iran's compliance with its obligations under the agreement, </li> <li>assess the adequacy of the safeguards and other control mechanisms contained in the agreement with respect to Iran's nuclear program, and </li> <li>assess the capacity of the International Atomic Energy Agency to implement the verification regime required by or related to the agreement. </li> </ul> <p>&quot;Agreement&quot; means an agreement related to Iran's nuclear program that includes the United States, commits the United States to take action, or pursuant to which the United States commits or otherwise agrees to take action, whether a political commitment or otherwise, and regardless of whether it is legally binding or not.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
