<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4961" measure-id="id114hr4961" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-04-15" update-date="2016-06-15">
<title>Federal Disaster Notification and Payment Protection Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4961v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-06-15">
<action-date>2016-04-15</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Federal Disaster Notification and Payment Protection Act of 2016</strong></p> <p>This bill prohibits the use of federal funds to recoup a debt owed to the United States related to assistance provided to an individual or household under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act with respect to a major disaster declared by the President on or after January 1, 2011, if:</p> <ul> <li>the assistance was distributed based on an error by the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA),</li> <li>the collection of the debt would be against equity and good conscience, and </li> <li>the debt is not the result of fraud or other fault of the debtor or any party having an interest in the assistance distributed. </li></ul> <p>The Stafford Act is amended to require the President to establish a process to ensure that each individual and business that applies for a category of federal disaster assistance is provided written notice that describes:</p> <ul> <li>the various categories of federal disaster assistance that may be available, </li> <li>the impact that receiving or declining such assistance will have on eligibility for other categories of assistance, and </li> <li>repayment requirements or penalties that may apply if multiple categories of assistance are accepted. </li></ul> <p>An individual or business that is not provided such notice may not be held responsible for any repayment requirement or penalty that would otherwise result from the receipt of such assistance.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
