<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3106" measure-id="id114hr3106" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-07-16" update-date="2016-02-10">
<title>Construction Reform Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3106v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-02-10">
<action-date>2016-02-09</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Construction Reform Act of 2016</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill requires the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to use industry standards, standard designs, and best practices in carrying out medical facility construction.</p> <p>A super construction project is one for the construction, alteration, or acquisition of a medical facility involving a total expenditure of more than $100 million (but does not include an acquisition by exchange).</p> <p> The VA shall provide, on a non-reimbursable basis, a non-VA federal entity with: (1) design, planning, and construction assistance; (2) project documents; and (3) other assistance upon request. </p> <p>With respect to a proposed change to a contract entered into by a non-VA federal entity with which the VA has entered into an agreement that is estimated at a value of less than $250,000, the entity shall issue a final decision regarding such change within 30 days. </p> <p> With respect to a proposed contract change estimated at a value of $250,000 or more: </p> <ul> <li> the VA may make recommendations to the entity; </li> <li> the VA may issue the final decision regarding the change within 30 days after the entity proposes it; and </li> <li> if the VA does not issue a final decision within 60 days after the entity proposes the contract change, the entity shall issue a final decision regarding the change no later than 90 days after it proposes the change. </li> </ul> <p> The VA shall ensure that each VA employee with responsibilities relating to the construction or alteration of medical facilities undergoes ongoing professional training and development. </p> <p> The VA is prohibited from: </p> <ul> <li> obligating or expending funds for advance planning or design for any super construction project until 60 days after congressional notification,</li> <li> obligating funds for a major medical facility project or a super construction project by more than 10% of the amount approved by law unless certain congressional committees approve the obligation, or</li> <li> using bid savings amounts or funds for other than their original purpose before 30 days after notifying those committees unless each committee approves the obligation.</li> </ul> <p> The VA shall enter into a contract with an appropriate non-department federal entity to conduct an external forensic audit of: (1) the medical center construction project in Aurora, Colorado; and (2) the expenditures relating to any major medical facility or super construction project when such expenditures exceed the amount approved by law by more than 25%. </p> <p>The VA must complete a 10-year master plan for: (1) each existing VA medical facility by December 31, 2016, and (2) each new VA medical facility by not later than the earlier of the date on which activation is completed or the date of the facility's formal dedication. </p> <p>(Sec. 3) There is established in the Office of Inspector General an Assistant Inspector General for Construction who shall be responsible for conducting, supervising, and coordinating audits, evaluations, and investigations of the planning, design, contracting, and construction of VA facilities and infrastructure, including major and minor construction projects and leases.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3106v17" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-01-27">
<action-date>2015-12-03</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Construction Reform Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill requires the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to: (1) enter into an agreement with an appropriate non-VA entity to provide full project management services for a super construction project; and (2) use industry standards, standard designs, and best practices in carrying out medical facility construction.</p> <p>A super construction project is one for the construction, alteration, or acquisition of a medical facility involving a total expenditure of more than $100 million (but does not include an acquisition by exchange).</p> <p> The VA shall provide, on a non-reimbursable basis, a non-VA federal entity with: (1) design, planning, and construction assistance; (2) project documents; and (3) other assistance upon request. </p> <p>With respect to a proposed change to a contract entered into by a non-VA federal entity with which the VA has entered into an agreement that is estimated at a value of less than $250,000, the entity shall issue a final decision regarding such change within 30 days. </p> <p> With respect to a proposed contract change estimated at a value of $250,000 or more: </p> <ul> <li> the VA may make recommendations to the entity; </li> <li> the VA may issue the final decision regarding the change within 30 days after the entity proposes it; and </li> <li> if the VA does not issue a final decision within 60 days after the entity proposes the contract change, the entity shall issue a final decision regarding the change no later than 90 days after it proposes the change. </li> </ul> <p> The VA shall ensure that each VA employee with responsibilities relating to the construction or alteration of medical facilities undergoes ongoing professional training and development. </p> <p> The VA is prohibited from: </p> <ul> <li> obligating or expending funds for advance planning or design for any super construction project until 60 days after congressional notification,</li> <li> obligating funds for a major medical facility project or a super construction project by more than 10% of the amount approved by law unless certain congressional committees approve the obligation, or</li> <li> using bid savings amounts or funds for other than their original purpose before 30 days after notifying those committees unless each committee approves the obligation.</li> </ul> <p> The VA must complete a 10-year master plan for: (1) each existing VA medical facility by December 31, 2016, and (2) each new VA medical facility by not later than the earlier of the date on which activation is completed or the date of the facility's formal dedication. </p> <p>(Sec. 3) Funding authority is modified to provide for constructing a new bed tower at the VA medical center in Tampa, Florida, in lieu of providing bed tower upgrades at such medical center. </p> <p>(Sec. 4) The VA may carry out the following major medical facility projects in FY2015 (with each project not to exceed specified amounts): </p> <ul> <li>construction of a community living center, outpatient clinic, renovated domiciliary, and renovation of existing buildings in Canandaigua, New York; </li> <li>seismic corrections to the mental health and community living center in Long Beach, California; </li> <li>seismic correction of 12 buildings in West Los Angeles, California; and </li> <li>construction of a spinal cord injury building and seismic corrections in San Diego, California.</li> </ul> <p> The bill authorizes FY2015 appropriations for such projects.</p> <p> These projects may only be carried out using: </p> <ul> <li> funds appropriated for FY2015 pursuant to such authorization;</li> <li> funds available for Construction, Major Projects, for a fiscal year before, or a fiscal year after, FY2015 that remain available for obligation; </li> <li> funds appropriated for Construction, Major Projects, for FY 2015 for a category of activity not specific to a project; and </li> <li> funds appropriated for Construction, Major Projects, for a fiscal year before, or a fiscal year after, FY2015 for a category of activity not specific to a project.</li> </ul> <p>(Sec. 5) There is established in the Office of Inspector General an Assistant Inspector General for Construction who shall be responsible for conducting, supervising, and coordinating audits, evaluations, and investigations of the planning, design, contracting, and construction of VA facilities and infrastructure, including major and minor construction projects and leases.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3106v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-09-03">
<action-date>2015-07-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Construction Reform Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>This bill requires the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to: (1) enter into an agreement with an appropriate non-VA entity to provide full project management services for a super construction project; and (2) use industry standards, standard designs, and best practices in carrying out medical facility construction.</p> <p>A super construction project is one for the construction, alteration, or acquisition of a medical facility involving a total expenditure of more than $100 million (but does not include an acquisition by exchange).</p> <p>The VA is prohibited from: </p> <ul> <li>obligating or expending funds for advance planning or design for any super construction project until 60 days after congressional notification,</li> <li> obligating funds for a major medical facility project or a super construction project by more than 10% of the amount approved by law unless certain congressional committees each approve the obligation, and </li> <li> using bid savings amounts or funds for other than their original purpose before 30 days after notifying such committees unless each committee approves the obligation.</li> </ul> <p>The VA must complete a master plan for each VA medical facility meeting specified requirements to inform investment decisions and funding requests over a 10-year period for construction projects at the facility. </p> <p>The VA may carry out the following major medical facility projects in FY2015 (with each project not to exceed specified amounts): </p> <ul> <li>construction of a community living center, outpatient clinic, renovated domiciliary, and renovation of existing buildings in Canandaigua, New York; </li> <li>seismic corrections to the mental health and community living center in Long Beach, California; </li> <li>seismic correction of 12 buildings in West Los Angeles, California; and </li> <li>construction of a spinal cord injury building and seismic corrections in San Diego, California.</li> </ul> <p> Funding authority is modified to provide for constructing a new bed tower at the VA medical center in Tampa, Florida, in lieu of providing bed tower upgrades at such medical center. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
