<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1927" measure-id="id114hr1927" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-04-22" update-date="2016-02-10">
<title>Fairness in Class Action Litigation and Furthering Asbestos Claim Transparency Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1927v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-02-10">
<action-date>2016-01-08</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Fairness in Class Action Litigation and Furthering Asbestos Claim Transparency Act of 2016</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends the federal judicial code to prohibit federal courts from certifying any proposed class seeking monetary relief for personal injury or economic loss unless the party seeking to maintain such a class action affirmatively demonstrates that each proposed class member suffered an injury of the same type and scope as the injury of the named class representatives. </p> <p>A court's certification of such a class must include a determination, based on a rigorous analysis of the evidence presented, that the requirements of this Act have been satisfied.</p> <p>(Sec. 3) The bill also amends federal bankruptcy law concerning a trust formed under a reorganization plan following the discharge in bankruptcy of a debtor corporation in order to assume the debtor's liability with respect to claims seeking recovery for personal injury, wrongful death, or property damage allegedly caused by the presence of, or exposure to, asbestos or asbestos-containing products. Such a trust shall file with the bankruptcy court quarterly reports, available on the public docket, which describe each demand the trust has received from a claimant and the basis for any payment made to that claimant (excluding any confidential medical record or the claimant's full Social Security number). Upon written request, and subject to payment (demanded at the option of the trust) for any reasonable cost incurred by the trust to comply with such request, such a trust shall provide any information related to payment from, and demands for payment from, the trust to any party to any action in law or equity concerning liability for asbestos exposure. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1927v17" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-12-10">
<action-date>2015-11-05</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Fairness in Class Action Litigation Act of 2015</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends the federal judicial code to prohibit federal courts from certifying any proposed class seeking monetary relief for personal injury or economic loss unless the party seeking to maintain such a class action affirmatively demonstrates that each proposed class member suffered an injury of the same type and scope as the injury of the named class representatives. </p> <p>A court's certification of such a class must include a determination, based on a rigorous analysis of the evidence presented, that the requirements of this Act have been satisfied.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1927v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-05-04">
<action-date>2015-04-22</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Fairness in Class Action Litigation Act of 2015</b></p> <p>Amends the federal judicial code to prohibit federal courts from certifying any proposed class unless the party seeking to maintain a class action affirmatively demonstrates through admissible evidentiary proof that each proposed class member suffered an injury of the same type and extent as the injury of the named class representatives. </p> <p>Defines &quot;injury&quot; as the alleged impact of the defendant's actions on the plaintiff's body or property.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
