<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5200" measure-id="id114hr5200" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-05-11" update-date="2016-09-09">
<title>Iran-Russia Cooperation Reporting Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5200v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-09-09">
<action-date>2016-05-11</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Iran-Russia Cooperation Reporting Act</strong></p> <p>This bill directs the Department of Defense to report to Congress annually (as long as the Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action [JCPA] is in effect) on cooperation between Iran and Russia and how and to what extent such cooperation affects U.S. national security and strategic interests. (The JCPA is the agreement reached by China, France, Germany, Russia, the United Kingdom, the United States, the European Union, and Iran to ensure that Iran's nuclear program will be exclusively peaceful).</p> <p>The report shall include matters relating to: </p> <ul> <li> Iran's space and ballistic missile programs; </li> <li>overlapping Russia-Iran interests in Latin America; </li> <li>the intelligence-sharing center established by Iran, Russia, and Syria in Baghdad, Iraq; </li> <li> naval cooperation between Iran and Russia and the long-term consequences of Russia's naval presence in the Eastern Mediterranean and Iran's naval presence in the Persian Gulf; </li> <li> how cooperation between Iran and Russian has increased with respect to the JCPA; </li> <li>the likelihood of Iran adopting the Russian model of hybrid warfare against potential targets such as the Gulf Cooperation Council states; </li> <li>Russian cooperation with Hezbollah in Syria, Lebanon, and Iraq; and </li> <li>a list of weapons the sale of which by Russia to Iran would violate United Nations Security Council resolutions imposing an arms embargo on Iran.</li></ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
