<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="328" measure-id="id114hr328" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-01-13" update-date="2015-05-22">
<title>American Indian Empowerment Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr328v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-05-22">
<action-date>2015-01-13</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>American Indian Empowerment Act of 2015</b></p> <p> Requires the Secretary of the Interior to transfer land the federal government holds in trust for a federally recognized Indian tribe to such tribe as restricted fee tribal land, subject to a restriction against alienation and taxation, after receiving the Indian tribe's request for such transfer. (Restricted fee tribal land is land to which a tribe holds legal title, but which carries legal restrictions against alienation or encumbrance.)</p> <p>Allows Indian tribes to lease, or grant an easement or right-of-way on, restricted fee tribal land for any period of time without the Secretary's review and approval.</p> <p>Gives the laws of a federally recognized Indian tribe that establish a system of land tenure governing the use of the land the tribe holds precedence over any federal law or regulation governing the use of such land, excepting a federal restriction against its alienation and taxation.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
