<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5243" measure-id="id114hr5243" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-05-16" update-date="2016-07-06">
<title>Zika Response Appropriations Act, 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5243v81" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-07-06">
<action-date>2016-05-18</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p><b>Highlights:</b></p> <p>This bill provides FY2016 supplemental appropriations to the Departments of Health and Human Services (HHS) and State to respond to the Zika virus. The bill also rescinds unobligated balances of prior appropriations. </p> <p>The bill permits the funds to be used for the duration of FY2016, designates specified funds as emergency requirements, and sets forth congressional reporting and notification requirements. </p> <p><b>Full Summary: </b></p> <p><b>Zika Response Appropriations Act, 2016 </b></p> <p>TITLE I--DEPARTMENT OF HEALTH AND HUMAN SERVICES </p> <p>Provides appropriations to HHS for: </p> <ul> <li> the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention to prevent, prepare for, and respond to the Zika virus, domestically and internationally; </li> <li> the National Institutes of Health for the preclinical and clinical development of vaccines for the Zika virus; and </li> <li> the Public Health and Social Services Emergency Fund within the Office of the Secretary to develop necessary countermeasures and vaccines to respond to the Zika virus, domestically and internationally.</li> </ul> <p>(Sec. 101) Requires HHS to notify Congress at least 15 days in advance of obligating the funds provided by this title. Permits a waiver for a substantial risk to human health or welfare. </p> <p>(Sec. 102) Requires HHS to report monthly to Congress on the proposed uses of funds provided by this title. </p> <p>(Sec. 103) Provides funding to the HHS Office of Inspector General and the Government Accountability Office (GAO) for the oversight of activities funded by this title. </p> <p>TITLE II--DEPARTMENT OF STATE </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the State Department for the Administration of Foreign Affairs, the United States Agency for International Development (USAID), and Bilateral Economic Assistance, including funds for: </p> <ul> <li> Diplomatic and Consular Programs for medical evacuations and other response efforts related to the Zika virus and directly associated health conditions;</li> <li> USAID response efforts related to the Zika virus and directly associated health conditions; and </li> <li> Global Health Programs for mosquito control (vector control) efforts to prevent, prepare for, and respond to the Zika virus internationally.</li> </ul> <p>(Sec. 201) Permits specified funds provided by this bill for Diplomatic and Consular Programs to be: (1) used for medical evacuation costs of any U.S. department or agency under Chief of Mission authority, and (2) transferred and merged with funds available for Emergencies in the Diplomatic and Consular Service. </p> <p>(Sec. 202) Requires the State Department or the USAID to notify Congress at least 15 days in advance of obligating the funds provided by this title. Permits a waiver for a substantial risk to human health or welfare. </p> <p>(Sec. 203) Requires the State Department, in consultation with the USAID, to report monthly to Congress on the proposed uses of funds provided by this title. </p> <p>(Sec. 204) Provides funding to the USAID Office of Inspector General and the GAO for the oversight of activities funded by this title. </p> <p>TITLE III--GENERAL PROVISIONS--THIS ACT </p> <p>(Sec. 301) Rescinds specified unobligated balances of funds that were previously provided to HHS and the State Department for the Ebola outbreak and to HHS for the Nonrecurring Expenses Fund. </p> <p>(Sec. 302) Specifies that, unless otherwise indicated in this bill, the funds provided by this bill are subject to the requirements contained in the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2016. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5243v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-05-18">
<action-date>2016-05-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Zika Response Appropriations Act, 2016 </b></p> <p>This bill provides FY2016 supplemental appropriations to the Departments of Health and Human Services (HHS) and State to respond to the Zika virus. </p> <p> The bill provides appropriations to HHS for: </p> <ul> <li> the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, </li> <li> the National Institutes of Health, and </li> <li> the Public Health and Social Services Emergency Fund within the Office of the Secretary. </li> </ul> <p>For the State Department, the bill provides funding for: </p> <ul> <li>the Administration of Foreign Affairs, </li> <li> the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID), and </li> <li> Bilateral Economic Assistance. </li> </ul> <p>The bill sets forth congressional notification and reporting requirements that apply to the funds. It also provides funds to the Government Accountability Office and the USAID and HHS Inspectors General for the oversight of activities funded by this bill. </p> <p>The bill also rescinds unobligated balances of funds that were previously provided to HHS and the State Department for the Ebola outbreak and to HHS for the Nonrecurring Expenses Fund. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
