<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2225" measure-id="id114hr2225" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-01" update-date="2015-06-30">
<title>PRIMED Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2225v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-06-30">
<action-date>2015-05-01</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Prioritizing Reinvestment in Infrastructure and Military while Eliminating Debt Act of 2015 or the PRIMED Act</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow corporate taxpayers to elect a tax deduction for cash dividends received from a controlled foreign corporation during the period beginning after the bill's enactment date and ending on December 31, 2016. The dividends received are subject to an effective tax rate of 5.25% when repatriated in the United States. </p> <p>The bill divides tax revenues attributable to such repatriated earnings equally for: (1) federal debt reduction, (2) transfers to the Highway Trust Fund, and (3) adjustments to limitations on defense discretionary spending. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
