<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5296" measure-id="id114hr5296" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-05-19" update-date="2016-05-25">
<title>CI Realignment Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5296v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-05-25">
<action-date>2016-05-19</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>CI Realignment Act </b></p> <p>This bill establishes a Bureau of Criminal Investigation within the Department of the Treasury and transfers the functions, personnel, assets, and obligations of the Internal Revenue Service's (IRS's) Criminal Investigation Division to the new bureau. </p> <p>Treasury must provide a semi-annual report to Congress on: (1) the cases the IRS referred to the bureau, and (2) the cases the bureau referred to the Department of Justice. </p> <p>The bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to permit the disclosure of returns and return information to employees and officers of the bureau for tax administration purposes. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
