<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2664" measure-id="id114hr2664" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-06-04" update-date="2015-07-10">
<title>Structured Settlement Claimants Rights Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2664v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-07-10">
<action-date>2015-06-04</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Structured Settlement Claimants Rights Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>Amends the federal judicial code to declare that a claimant in any civil action before a federal court shall have the right to retain a structured settlement broker to act on behalf of that claimant for purposes of negotiating a schedule of payments or other terms of payment previously agreed to be paid by or on behalf of the defendant in satisfaction of a judgment against that defendant or in accordance with the terms of a settlement.</p> <p>Requires that a party to an administrative proceeding have the same right to retain such a structured settlement broker for negotiations with other parties. </p>Directs: (1) the court or the agency in an administrative proceeding to inform the claimant of this right at the appropriate time, and (2) the defendant to provide timely notice of any current or previous professional relationship between the defendant and the broker.]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
