<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1236" measure-id="id114hr1236" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-03-04" update-date="2015-03-13">
<title>Fiscal Sanity Act for the National Debt</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1236v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-03-13">
<action-date>2015-03-04</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Fiscal Sanity Act for the National Debt</b></p> <p>This bill suspends the public debt limit for the period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act and ending 60 days later. The debt limit, often referred to as the debt ceiling, is the maximum amount of debt that the Department of the Treasury can issue to the public and to other federal agencies. Under current law, the debt limit is suspended through March 15, 2015. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
