<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1640" measure-id="id114hr1640" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-03-25" update-date="2015-06-29">
<title>Department of Homeland Security Headquarters Consolidation Accountability Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1640v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-06-29">
<action-date>2015-06-23</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the House on June 17, 2015. The summary of that version is repeated here.)</p> <p><strong>Department of Homeland Security Headquarters Consolidation Accountability Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) Directs the Department of Homeland Security (DHS), in coordination with the General Services Administration (GSA), to submit a report on the DHS headquarters consolidation project within the National Capital Region, including:</p> <ul> <li>a proposed occupancy plan that includes specific information about which DHS-wide operations, component operations, and support offices will be located at the site, the aggregate number of full time equivalent employees projected to occupy the site, and schedule estimates for migrating operations to the site;</li> <li>a comprehensive assessment of the real property needed by DHS in the Region to carry out its mission to secure the homeland and defend against terrorism;</li> <li>an analysis of the difference between the current and needed capital assets and facilities of DHS;</li> <li>a current plan for construction of the headquarters consolidation at the St. Elizabeth's campus that includes the estimated costs and schedule for the current plan and any estimated costs savings associated with reducing the scope of the project and increasing the use of existing capacity developed under the project;</li> <li>a current plan for the leased portfolio of DHS in the Region that includes the total rentable square feet, number of personnel, and proposed utilization rates, the replacement and consolidation plan, including an end-state vision that identifies which DHS-wide operations, component operations, and support offices do not migrate to the St. Elizabeths campus and continue to operate at a property in the leased portfolio, the number of full time equivalent employees who are expected to operate at each property, component, or office, and timing and anticipated leased terms for leased space, and the costs and benefits of leasing and construction alternatives; and</li> <li>a detailed list of alternatives considered by DHS during the plan's development, including their costs and benefits. </li> </ul> <p>Directs DHS, in coordination with GSA, to complete the update of the cost and schedule estimates for the portions of the project that are not yet complete based on the information contained in the report. Directs the Comptroller General to review the update, evaluate the quality and reliability of such estimates, and report on the results.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1640v17" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-06-29">
<action-date>2015-06-17</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Department of Homeland Security Headquarters Consolidation Accountability Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) Directs the Department of Homeland Security (DHS), in coordination with the General Services Administration (GSA), to submit a report on the DHS headquarters consolidation project within the National Capital Region, including:</p> <ul> <li>a proposed occupancy plan that includes specific information about which DHS-wide operations, component operations, and support offices will be located at the site, the aggregate number of full time equivalent employees projected to occupy the site, and schedule estimates for migrating operations to the site; </li> <li>a comprehensive assessment of the real property needed by DHS in the Region to carry out its mission to secure the homeland and defend against terrorism; </li> <li>an analysis of the difference between the current and needed capital assets and facilities of DHS; </li> <li>a current plan for construction of the headquarters consolidation at the St. Elizabeth's campus that includes the estimated costs and schedule for the current plan and any estimated costs savings associated with reducing the scope of the project and increasing the use of existing capacity developed under the project; </li> <li>a current plan for the leased portfolio of DHS in the Region that includes the total rentable square feet, number of personnel, and proposed utilization rates, the replacement and consolidation plan, including an end-state vision that identifies which DHS-wide operations, component operations, and support offices do not migrate to the St. Elizabeths campus and continue to operate at a property in the leased portfolio, the number of full time equivalent employees who are expected to operate at each property, component, or office, and timing and anticipated leased terms for leased space, and the costs and benefits of leasing and construction alternatives; and </li> <li>a detailed list of alternatives considered by DHS during the plan's development, including their costs and benefits. </li></ul> <p>Directs DHS, in coordination with GSA, to complete the update of the cost and schedule estimates for the portions of the project that are not yet complete based on the information contained in the report. Directs the Comptroller General to review the update, evaluate the quality and reliability of such estimates, and report on the results.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1640v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-06-23">
<action-date>2015-03-25</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Department of Homeland Security Headquarters Consolidation Accountability Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>Directs the Department of Homeland Security (DHS), in coordination with the General Services Administration (GSA), to submit a report on the DHS headquarters consolidation project within the National Capital Region, including:</p> <ul> <li>a current list of the components and offices proposed to be included;</li> <li>a comprehensive assessment of the real property needed by DHS in the Region to carry out its mission to secure the homeland and defend against terrorism;</li> <li>an analysis of the difference between the current and needed capital assets and facilities of DHS;</li> <li>a current plan for construction of the headquarters consolidation at the St. Elizabeth's campus that includes the estimated costs and schedule for the current plan and the estimated costs savings of reducing the scope of the project and increasing the use of existing capacity developed under the project;</li> <li>a current plan for the leased portfolio of DHS in the Region that includes the total rentable square feet, number of personnel, and proposed utilization rates, the replacement and consolidation plan for leased space, and the costs and benefits of leasing and construction alternatives; and</li> <li>a detailed list of alternatives considered by DHS during the plan's development, including their costs and benefits.</li> </ul> <p>Directs DHS, in coordination with GSA, to complete the update of the cost and schedule estimates for the portions of the project that are not yet complete based on the information contained in the report. Directs the Comptroller General to review the update, evaluate the quality and reliability of such estimates, and report on the results.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
