<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4789" measure-id="id114hr4789" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-03-17" update-date="2016-09-09">
<title>To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to establish a structure for visitor services on the Arlington Ridge tract, in the area of the U.S. Marine Corps War Memorial, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4789v81" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-09-09">
<action-date>2016-09-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The expanded summary of the House reported version is repeated here.)</p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill authorizes the Department of the Interior to construct on the Arlington Ridge tract in the area of the U.S. Marine Corps War Memorial in Arlington County, Virginia, a structure for visitor services, including a public restroom facility. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4789v79" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-07-21">
<action-date>2016-07-14</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill authorizes the Department of the Interior to construct on the Arlington Ridge tract in the area of the U.S. Marine Corps War Memorial in Arlington County, Virginia, a structure for visitor services, including a public restroom facility. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4789v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-03-30">
<action-date>2016-03-17</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill authorizes the Department of the Interior to construct on the Arlington Ridge tract in the area of the U.S. Marine Corps War Memorial in Arlington County, Virginia, a structure for visitor services, including a public restroom facility. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
