<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="613" measure-id="id114hr613" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-01-28" update-date="2015-02-19">
<title>To amend the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to authorize veterans' treatment courts and encourage services for veterans.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr613v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-02-19">
<action-date>2015-01-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Servicemember Assistance for Lawful Understanding, Treatment, and Education Act or the SALUTE Act</strong></p> <p>Amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to authorize the Attorney General to award grants for developing, implementing, or enhancing veterans' treatment courts or expanding operational mental health or drug courts to serve veterans to ensure that such courts effectively integrate substance abuse treatment, mental health treatment, sanctions and incentives, and transitional services, in a judicially supervised court setting with jurisdiction over offenders who are veterans. </p> <p>Authorizes the Attorney General to award such grants to states, state courts, local courts, local governments, and Indian tribal governments for court programs that involve</p> <ul> <li>continuing judicial supervision over offenders who are veterans with substance abuse or mental health problems;</li> <li>coordination with appropriate federal, state, or local prosecutors;</li> <li>coordination with the Veterans Health Administration; and</li> <li>the integrated administration of other sanctions and services, including substance abuse and mental health treatment, supervised release involving the possibility of prosecution, confinement, or incarceration based on non-compliance with program requirements or failure to show satisfactory progress, and offender management.</li> </ul> <p>Prohibits the use of grant funds to provide judicial supervision over, treatment of, or other services to violent offenders.</p> <p>Directs the Comptroller General to conduct a study to assess the effectiveness and impact of such grant program.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
