<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="914" measure-id="id114hr914" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-02-12" update-date="2015-06-09">
<title>To direct the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to jointly operate the Federal Recovery Coordination Program, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr914v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-06-09">
<action-date>2015-02-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Requires the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to provide collaborative recovery coordinator training at a qualified nursing or medical school selected by the VA, to lead the systematic evidence review of care coordination and a consensus conference to build the model on evidence-based guidelines. Designates such school to lead: (1) the literature review and development of evidence-based guidelines for recovery coordination, training modules for care coordination, and software that is compatible with VA systems for recovery coordination; and (2) a consensus conference on evidence-based care coordination.</p> <p>Directs the VA to: (1) subcontract with an appropriate entity for the development of care coordination software, (2) carry out a conference for recovery coordinator tool validation, and (3) carry out a software pilot program.</p> <p>Authorizes the qualified nursing or medical school to train 45 recovery coordinators.</p> <p>Directs the VA and the Department of Defense (DOD), in carrying out the Federal Recovery Coordination Program, to jointly develop, and enter a memorandum to carry out, a plan to ensure that:</p> <ul> <li>the Program is operated jointly by the Secretaries; </li> <li>the administration of the Program is not delegated to an individual outside the respective office of each Secretary; </li> <li>the Program assists members of the Armed Forces with severe or catastrophic injuries or illnesses who are unlikely to return to active duty and who will most likely be medically separated and members and veterans whose individual circumstances (including illness, injury, mental health, family situation, and unique benefit needs) cause difficulties in transitioning to civilian life; </li> <li>the VA Secretary and the Secretaries of the military departments refer members and veterans to the Program at the earliest possible time; and </li> <li>each federal agency provides a Federal Recovery Coordinator of the Program with the information, coordination, and cooperation necessary for the Coordinator to assist participating members and veterans. </li></ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
