<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4362" measure-id="id114hr4362" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-01-11" update-date="2016-07-11">
<title>State Health Flexibility Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4362v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-07-11">
<action-date>2016-01-11</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>State Health Flexibility Act of 2016</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Social Security Act (SSAct) to replace federal requirements for Medicaid and the Children's Health Insurance Program (CHIP) with health care block grants to states. A state may use block grant funds to: (1) provide health care services&nbsp;to indigent individuals; (2) fund risk adjustment mechanisms for the purpose of subsidizing the cost of private health insurance for the high-risk population; and (3)&nbsp;support other welfare-related programs, as specified by the bill.</p> <p>In addition to repealing titles XIX (Medicaid) and XXI (CHIP) of the SSAct, the bill repeals: (1)&nbsp;the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act, and (2) the Health Care and Educational Reconciliation Act of 2010.</p> <p>With respect to an alien not lawfully admitted for permanent residence in the United States,&nbsp;a state may use grant funds to provide only emergency health care services, as specified by the bill.</p> <p>A state shall contract with an approved auditing entity for annual audits of its grant fund expenditures.</p> <p>The bill limits the authority of any federal agency to supervise a state's use of funds received under the block grant program.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
