<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1575" measure-id="id114hr1575" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-03-24" update-date="2015-11-04">
<title>To amend title 38, United States Code, to make permanent the pilot program on counseling in retreat settings for women veterans newly separated from service in the Armed Forces.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1575v79" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-11-04">
<action-date>2015-11-02</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p>(Sec. 1) This bill makes permanent the requirement for the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to carry out, through the Readjustment Counseling Service of the Veterans Health Administration, a program to provide reintegration and readjustment services in group retreat settings to women veterans who are recently separated from service after a prolonged deployment. (Currently, such program is required as a pilot program under the Caregivers and Veterans Omnibus Health Services Act of 2010.)</p> <p> Such services shall include: </p> <ul> <li>information on family, employment, and community reintegration; </li> <li>financial and occupational counseling; and </li> <li>information and counseling on stress reduction and conflict resolution. </li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1575v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-06-19">
<action-date>2015-03-24</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Makes permanent the requirement for the Department of Veterans Affairs to carry out, through the Readjustment Counseling Service of the Veterans Health Administration, a program to provide reintegration and readjustment services in group retreat settings to women veterans who are recently separated from service after a prolonged deployment. (Currently, such program is required as a pilot program under the Caregivers and Veterans Omnibus Health Services Act of 2010.)</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
