<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2503" measure-id="id114hr2503" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-21" update-date="2015-06-18">
<title>Permanently Ending Receipt by Prisoners Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2503v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-06-18">
<action-date>2015-05-21</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Permanently Ending Receipt by Prisoners Act</b></p> <p> Amends title III (Grants to States for Unemployment Compensation Administration) of the Social Security Act to require the state agency charged with administering a state's unemployment compensation law to seek from the Commissioner of Social Security, and through additional appropriate means, information necessary to carry out any provision of that law which renders ineligible for regular compensation, because he or she is unable to satisfy work requirements, any individual confined in a jail, prison, or other penal institution or correctional facility for conviction of a criminal offense.</p> Directs the Department of Labor to notify any state whose unemployment compensation agency fails to comply substantially with such requirements that further payments (for unemployment benefits) will not be made to the state until there is no longer any such failure.]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
