<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2638" measure-id="id114hr2638" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-06-03" update-date="2015-07-10">
<title>Broadband Adoption Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2638v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-07-10">
<action-date>2015-06-03</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Broadband Adoption Act of 2015</b></p> <p>Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to direct the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to adopt a final rule establishing support under the Universal Service Fund Lifeline Assistance Program for qualifying low-income consumers in urban and rural areas to purchase broadband Internet access service at reduced charges by reimbursing participating providers for each such consumer served.</p> <p>Requires the program to allow qualifying consumers to elect to apply support from the Lifeline program to basic telephone service, voice telephony service, or broadband Internet access service, regardless of whether the service is purchased as a stand-alone service or in a bundle.</p> <p>Directs the FCC to consult with the federal-state joint board on universal service regarding ways to encourage states to develop programs in conjunction with the Lifeline program.</p> <p>Requires the program to be technology neutral to promote competition from service providers.</p> <p>Requires participating broadband Internet access service providers to obtain FCC authorization to participate in the Lifeline program, but a provider is not required to be an eligible telecommunications carrier to receive support under the program.</p> <p>Directs the FCC to: (1) adopt regulations to prevent receipt of duplicative support under the Lifeline program, and (2) establish a national database to determine consumer eligibility. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
