<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="295" measure-id="id114hr295" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-01-13" update-date="2016-10-27">
<title>To reauthorize the Historically Black Colleges and Universities Historic Preservation program.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr295v17" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-10-27">
<action-date>2016-05-10</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(Sec. 1) This bill amends the Omnibus Parks and Public Lands Management Act of 1996 to reauthorize for FY2017-FY2023 the Historically Black Colleges and Universities Historic Preservation Fund Grant Program.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr295v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-01-29">
<action-date>2015-01-13</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Amends the Omnibus Parks and Public Lands Management Act of 1996 to reauthorize, for FY2016-FY2025, Historic Preservation Fund activities related to the preservation and restoration of historic buildings and structures on the campuses of historically black colleges and universities.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
