<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2453" measure-id="id114hr2453" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-19" update-date="2015-07-07">
<title>National Mall Revitalization and Designation Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2453v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-07-07">
<action-date>2015-05-19</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>National Mall Revitalization and Designation Act</b></p> <p> Authorizes the National Capital Planning Commission (the Commission) to modify the boundaries of Areas I and II of the National Mall in the District of Columbia reserved for the location of commemorative works of preeminent historical and lasting significance to the United States. Prohibits any review of such a decision. Requires the Commission to notify the Secretary of the Interior and the Administrator of General Services (GSA), the National Capital Memorial Advisory Commission, and certain congressional committees of any boundary modification made under such authority. </p> <p>Allows the Secretary or the Administrator to submit a recommendation to Congress that the legislative authority for a commemorative work be terminated before its expiration date, if the person authorized to establish the work does not possess the capacity or resources to complete successfully the project for the establishment of the work before that expiration date. </p> <p>Directs: (1) the Commission to prepare recommendations for improving upon the process required for the selection, design, and subject matter of commemorative works in the District of Columbia and its environs; and (2) the Secretary to submit a plan to enhance cultural experiences in, and visitor enjoyment, amenities, and the vitality of, the National Mall. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
