<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5508" measure-id="id114hr5508" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-06-16" update-date="2016-09-30">
<title>JOBS Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5508v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-09-30">
<action-date>2016-06-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Job Opportunity and Business Services Act or the JOBS Act</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act to require the reports to the Department of Labor each state, local board, and any other recipient of funds under the Act is required to make to include information regarding programs and activities carried out under the Act pertaining to the advertising budget, and a description of the advertising, for which the funds received were used.</p> <p>The bill also exempts from the prohibition against using funds received under the Act for lobbying purposes, and from specified other restrictions, the use of such funds for public relations and advertising costs for program outreach or activities otherwise related to carrying out the Act's purposes.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
