<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4297" measure-id="id114hr4297" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-12-18" update-date="2016-04-22">
<title>To impose certain requirements on the Secretary of the Treasury relating to transmittals of country-by-country reports for purposes of the Base Erosion and Profit Shifting Action Plan.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4297v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-04-22">
<action-date>2015-12-18</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill expressly prohibits the Department of the Treasury from collecting from a U.S. person or transmitting to any foreign jurisdiction any country-by-country report (CbCR) information of any U.S. person for taxable years beginning before January 1, 2017. CbCR information is used by the Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development to develop its Base Erosion and Profit Shifting (BEPS) Action Plan to increase the transparency of transfer pricing practices and other tax transactions of multinational business enterprises. </p> <p>Treasury must: (1) suspend the transmittal of CbCR information of any U.S. person to a foreign jurisdiction if it determines that such jurisdiction is abusing BEPS master file documentation requirements or failing to safeguard the confidentiality of information required in the master file, and (2) report to the congressional tax committees on allegations or reports received concerning the abuse of master file documentation requirements and any actions taken with respect to such allegations.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
