<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4287" measure-id="id114hr4287" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-12-17" update-date="2016-02-17">
<title>Wireless Tax Fairness Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4287v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-02-17">
<action-date>2015-12-17</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Wireless Tax Fairness Act of 2015</strong></p> <p> This bill prohibits states or local governments from imposing any new discriminatory tax on or with respect to mobile services, mobile service providers, or mobile service property for five years after the enactment of this Act. A &quot;new discriminatory tax&quot; is a tax imposed on mobile services, providers, or property that is not generally imposed on other types of services or property, or that is generally imposed at a lower rate, unless such tax was imposed and actually enforced prior to the enactment date of this Act.</p> <p>The bill grants jurisdiction to federal district courts to provide injunctive and other appropriate relief to prevent, restrain, or terminate any acts in violation of this Act. </p> <p>The bill requires the Government Accountability Office to study and report on the impact of: (1) state and local taxes on mobile services, providers, or property on the costs consumers pay for mobile services; and (2) the prohibition in this Act against discriminatory mobile services taxes on such costs.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
