<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="974" measure-id="id114hr974" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-02-13" update-date="2015-12-14">
<title>Yellowstone and Grand Teton Paddling Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr974v17" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-12-14">
<action-date>2015-12-08</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Yellowstone and Grand Teton Paddling Act</b></p> <p>(Sec. 3) This bill directs the Department of the Interior to promulgate regulations to allow the use of hand-propelled vessels on certain rivers and streams within: (1) the Yellowstone National Park in Idaho, Montana, and Wyoming; and (2) the Grand Teton National Park and the John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Memorial Parkway in Wyoming. </p>   <p>The regulations issued under this Act shall not consider any expansion of commercial use of hand-propelled vessels in the Parks. </p> <p>When promulgating such regulations, the Department of the Interior shall consult with the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service and the National Park Service to help ensure that the regulations make recreational use of hand-propelled vessels on the Gros Ventre River within the National Elk Refuge in Wyoming adjacent to Grand Teton National Park consistent with the requirements of the National Refuge System Administration Act of 1966. </p> <p>Upon the issuance of final regulations, existing regulations prohibiting hand-propelled vessels on streams and rivers in Yellowstone National Park and Grand Teton National Park shall no longer have any force or effect.</p> <p>Interior is authorized to recover all costs associated with monitoring the use of hand-propelled vessels, including the cost of inspecting and decontaminating vessels to prevent the introduction or spread of invasive or injurious species in such National Parks and the Memorial Parkway. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr974v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-09-08">
<action-date>2015-02-13</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Yellowstone and Grand Teton Paddling Act</b></p> <p>Directs the Department of the Interior to promulgate regulations to allow the use of hand-propelled vessels on certain rivers and streams within: (1) the Yellowstone National Park in Idaho, Montana, and Wyoming; and (2) the Grand Teton National Park and the John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Memorial Parkway in Wyoming. </p> <p>Makes the regulations promulgated under this Act inapplicable to waters that are: (1) open to use by hand-propelled vessels on the day before enactment of this Act; and (2) within the Teton Range in Grand Teton National Park as specified. </p> <p>States that the regulations issued under this Act shall not consider any expansion of commercial use of hand-propelled vessels in the Parks. </p> <p>Preempts existing regulations governing vessels in Yellowstone National Park and in Grand Teton National Park. </p> <p>Authorizes Interior to recover all costs associated with monitoring the use of hand-propelled vessels, including the cost of inspecting and decontaminating vessels to prevent the introduction or spread of invasive or injurious species in such National Parks and the Memorial Parkway. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
