<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2960" measure-id="id114hr2960" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-07-07" update-date="2016-01-13">
<title>TALENT Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2960v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-01-13">
<action-date>2015-07-07</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>To Aid Gifted and High-Ability Learners by Empowering the Nation's Teachers Act or the TALENT Act</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to require state assessments of student proficiency to measure individual academic achievement, including above grade level achievement.</p> <p>States must: (1) assist their local educational agencies (LEAs) and schools in providing additional educational assistance to advanced, gifted, and talented students; and (2) report annually a comparison of the performance of students between different LEAs at each level of achievement, disaggregated by specified student subgroups.</p> <p>LEAs must identify gifted and talented students and support their learning needs and train educators to implement instructional practices that support their education. </p> <p>The Institute of Education Sciences must: (1) continue research and development activities regarding the education of gifted and talented students; (2) support a National Research and Dissemination Center on the Gifted and Talented; (3) administer demonstration grants that enhance the ability of educators to support gifted and talented students; and (4) ensure that statistical data regarding the education of gifted and talented children is collected, reported, analyzed, and disseminated.</p>    <p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
