<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3327" measure-id="id114hr3327" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-07-29" update-date="2016-03-24">
<title>Kids Before Cons Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3327v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-03-24">
<action-date>2015-07-29</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Kids Before Cons Act</strong></p> <p>This bill amends title IV (Student Assistance) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to limit waiver authority of the Department of Education (ED) under the Experimental Sites Initiative.</p> <p>Specifically, it prohibits ED from waiving statutory provisions that ban Pell Grant eligibility and federal financial aid for incarcerated students (e.g., as part of an experimental initiative to allow incarcerated students to receive Pell Grants for postsecondary education opportunities). The legislation also prohibits ED from awarding funds to an institution of higher education for providing such postsecondary education to incarcerated individuals. </p> <p>ED must conduct and make publicly available a study that compares incarceration rates of: (1) private or charter school students who receive vouchers, and (2) traditional public school students. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
