<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4488" measure-id="id114hr4488" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-02-08" update-date="2016-03-22">
<title>Rights for Transportation Security Officers Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4488v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-03-22">
<action-date>2016-02-08</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Rights for Transportation Security Officers Act of 2016</strong></p> <p>This bill repeals: (1) provisions authorizing the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to establish a human resources management system for some or all of its organizational units, and (2) the authority granted to the Transportation Security Administration (TSA) to establish or modify a personnel management system for TSA employees engaged in airport security screening. </p> <p>Within 60 days after the enactment date of this bill: (1) any such human resources management system and all TSA personnel management policies, directives, letters, and guidelines shall cease to be effective, and (2) all TSA positions and DHS positions that provide transportation security in furtherance of the purposes of the Aviation and Transportation Security Act shall become subject to general civil service provisions. </p> <p>This bill sets forth transition rules that protect the pay rates and other rights of such employees. DHS shall consult with the labor organization certified by the Federal Labor Relations Authority to carry out the conversion of such positions. </p> <p>The provisions of this bill do not affect the prohibitions against disloyalty and asserting the right to strike against the federal government. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
