<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4334" measure-id="id114hr4334" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-01-06" update-date="2016-01-08">
<title>Fiscal Year 2016 Department of Veterans Affairs Seismic Safety and Construction Authorization Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4334v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-01-08">
<action-date>2016-01-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Fiscal Year 2016 Department of Veterans Affairs Seismic Safety and Construction Authorization Act</strong></p> <p>This bill authorizes the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to carry out the following major medical facility projects (each with specified maximum authorized funds): </p> <ul> <li>seismic corrections to buildings, including retrofitting and replacement of high-risk buildings, in San Francisco, California; </li> <li>seismic corrections to facilities, including facilities to support homeless veterans, at the medical center in West Los Angeles, California;</li> <li>seismic corrections to the mental health and community living center in Long Beach, California; </li> <li>construction of an outpatient clinic, administrative space, cemetery, and columbarium in Alameda, California; </li> <li>realignment of medical facilities in Livermore, California; </li> <li>construction of a medical center in Louisville, Kentucky; </li> <li>construction of a replacement community living center in Perry Point, Maryland; and </li> <li>seismic corrections and other renovations to several buildings and construction of a specialty care building in American Lake, Washington.</li> </ul> <p>A specified amount is authorized to be appropriated to the VA for such projects for FY2016 or the year in which funds are appropriated for the Construction, Major Projects, account.</p> <p>Such projects may only be carried out using specified funds.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
