<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1668" measure-id="id114hr1668" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-03-26" update-date="2016-04-26">
<title>Save Our Water Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1668v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-04-26">
<action-date>2015-03-26</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Save Our Water Act</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (ESA) to suspend during droughts the application of the ESA to water releases from water storage facilities by federal and state agencies in a navigable river basin.</p>  <p>The bill prohibits a state from enforcing ESA requirements in an area of the state in which a suspension applies, but does not affect the authority of a state to carry out and enforce its own laws.</p> <p>The bill does not prohibit any release of water from a water storage facility under the ESA if a relevant authority certifies that such release will not cause harm to the economy and no water conservation measures will be required to be taken by any water users as a result of such release.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
