<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2542" measure-id="id114hr2542" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-21" update-date="2015-08-31">
<title>Bereaved Borrowers' Bill of Rights Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2542v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-08-31">
<action-date>2015-05-21</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Bereaved Borrowers' Bill of Rights Act of 2015 </b></p> <p>Amends the Truth in Lending Act to require a private educational lender to include in a private education loan for which the cosigner is jointly liable a process for releasing the cosigner from obligations on the loan.</p> <p> Requires a lender who receives notification of the death or bankruptcy of a cosigner who is jointly liable for the loan to notify the borrower about the borrower's rights under the loan agreement regarding: (1) release of the cosigner, and (2) identification of a new cosigner or refinancing of the loan. </p> <p> Amends the Fair Credit Reporting Act to prohibit: (1) consumer reporting agencies from containing in any consumer report default on a private education loan that results from accelerated repayment terms of the loan after the death or bankruptcy of a jointly liable cosigner, and (2) the lender or servicer of a private educational loan from furnishing loan information to a consumer reporting agency if the consumer defaulted on the loan due to accelerated repayment terms after the death or bankruptcy of such a cosigner.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
