<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2800" measure-id="id114hr2800" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-06-17" update-date="2015-07-24">
<title>Pregnancy Discrimination Amendment Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2800v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-07-24">
<action-date>2015-06-17</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Pregnancy Discrimination Amendment Act </b></p> <p style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt" class="MsoNormal">Amends provisions of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 that protect against pregnancy discrimination in the workplace to provide for women affected by pregnancy, childbirth, or related medical conditions to be treated the same for all employment-related purposes as any other persons who are applicants for employment with, or employees of, the same employer in work that is performed under similar working conditions and who are not so affected but are similar in their temporary ability or inability to work. </p> <p style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt" class="MsoNormal">Makes such treatment applicable to existing prohibited categories of employment discrimination on the basis of sex or because of sex. </p> <p>Prohibits this treatment from permitting a labor organization to cause an employer to commit an unlawful employment practice against an employee in violation of such provisions.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
