<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1972" measure-id="id114hr1972" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-04-22" update-date="2015-05-07">
<title>Nuclear Power Licensing Reform Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1972v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-05-07">
<action-date>2015-04-22</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Nuclear Power Licensing Reform Act of 2015</b></p> <p> Amends the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 to require, for a commercial license for an atomic power production or utilization facility, that: (1) the facility does not pose an unreasonable threat to persons or the environment because of safety or security vulnerabilities (including vulnerability to terrorist attacks), and (2) there exist adequate evacuation plans for emergency events which have been approved by the relevant federal agencies and states within 50 miles of the facility.</p> <p>Conditions renewal of any such license on the same criteria and requirements applicable to an original application for initial construction.</p> <p>Directs the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC) to ensure that any changes in the size or distribution of the surrounding population, or seismic or other scientific data not available at the time of original licensing, have not resulted in the facility's being located at a site at which a new facility would not be allowed to be built.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
