<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1850" measure-id="id114hr1850" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-04-16" update-date="2015-05-21">
<title>FPS Improvement Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1850v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-05-21">
<action-date>2015-04-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>FPS Improvement Act of 2015</strong></p> <p> Assigns responsibility to the Federal Protective Service (FPS) for the protection of federal buildings, grounds, and property and persons on the property. Authorizes FPS to: (1) designate Department of Homeland Security employees with enhanced law enforcement powers for duty in connection with the protection of federal property and persons on the property, (2) authorize protective service officers for the protection of federal buildings and grounds, and (3) assess security charges to owners or tenants of a federal facility protected by FPS that is not in compliance with federal security standards. Requires tenants at federal facilities to maintain a Facility Security Committee.</p> <p>Establishes the Interagency Security Committee to develop safety and security standards and best practices to mitigate the effects of natural and manmade hazards in federal facilities. </p> <p>Requires reports on: (1) FPS personnel needs, (2) the feasibility of federalizing the protective service officer workforce, (3) a method for funding FPS, and (4) methods to detect or prevent explosives from entering federal facilities.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
