<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5861" measure-id="id114hr5861" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-07-14" update-date="2016-08-25">
<title>To establish terms and conditions under which the Secretary of the Interior shall convey, for fair market value, certain properties in the Lake Roosevelt National Recreation Area in the State of Washington to the permittees of those properties, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5861v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-08-25">
<action-date>2016-07-14</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill requires the Department of the Interior to give permittees of specified federal land (including improvements) located along Sherman Creek and Rickey Point in Lake Roosevelt National Recreation Area in the state of Washington the first option to purchase such property for fair market value. </p> <p>Interior shall offer to sell for fair market value: </p> <ul> <li>all interest of the United States in and to each property; and </li> <li>easements for vehicular access to it, access to and use of one dock for it, and access to and use of all boathouses, ramps, retaining walls, and other improvements for which access is provided in the permit. </li> </ul> <p>Interior shall also: </p> <ul> <li>solicit sealed bids for each property, and </li> <li>sell each property to the bidder who submits the highest bid at or above its fair market value.</li> </ul>  <p>The cost of a conveyance of a property, including the costs of required appraisals, shall be paid by:</p> <ul> <li>Interior, for a sale to a permittee, from revenues of that sale; and </li> <li> the purchaser, for a sale to any person other than the permittee.</li> </ul> <p>Revenues from sales of federal lands under this bill shall be made available, without further appropriation, for conveyance costs and for deferred maintenance activities in the recreation area. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
