<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2675" measure-id="id114hr2675" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-06-04" update-date="2016-03-23">
<title>Low Volume Motor Vehicle Manufacturers Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2675v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-03-23">
<action-date>2015-06-04</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Low Volume Motor Vehicle Manufacturers Act of 2015</b></p> <p> This bill directs the Department of Transportation (DOT) to exempt from certain federal motor vehicle safety and labeling standards up to 500 replica motor vehicles per year manufactured or imported by a low volume manufacturer. </p> <p>The term &quot;low volume manufacturer&quot; means a motor vehicle manufacturer (other than a person registered as an importer meeting certain requirements) that annually produces no more than 5,000 motor vehicles worldwide.</p> <p>Manufacturers shall register with DOT to qualify for an exemption.</p> <p>DOT shall require a manufacturer to affix a permanent label to an exempt replica motor vehicle that identifies the motor vehicle safety and labeling standards from which that vehicle is exempt and the model year the vehicle replicates.</p> <p>The Clean Air Act is amended to allow a low volume motor vehicle manufacturer to install in an exempted specifically produced replica motor vehicle a motor vehicle engine (including engine emission controls) from a motor vehicle granted a certificate of conformity with Environmental Protection Agency emission control standards, or another kind of engine granted an executive order for the model year in which the motor vehicle is assembled, if certain requirements are met.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
