<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5727" measure-id="id114hr5727" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-07-12" update-date="2016-09-22">
<title>Preventing Iranian Destabilization of Iraq Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5727v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-09-22">
<action-date>2016-07-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Preventing Iranian Destabilization of Iraq Act of 2016</strong></p> <p>This bill declares it shall be the policy of the United States to impose sanctions with respect to terrorist organizations and foreign countries, including the government of Iran, that threaten the peace or stability of Iraq.</p> <p>The bill directs the President to impose sanctions to block transactions in property and interests in property in the United States of, and the Department of State or the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to deny admissions into the United States or revoke the visa of, any foreign person that State or DHS determines: </p> <ul> <li>has knowingly committed, or poses a significant risk of committing, violence that threatens the peace or stability of Iraq or that undermines economic reconstruction, political reform, or humanitarian efforts in Iraq;</li> <li>has knowingly materially assisted, sponsored, or provided financial, material, or technological support for, or goods or services in support of, any such act; or</li> <li>is owned or controlled by, or has acted on behalf of, a foreign person that has carried out any such act or activity. </li> </ul> <p> Such admissions-related sanctions shall not apply if a person's admission is necessary to permit the United States to comply with the Agreement regarding the Headquarters of the United Nations or other applicable international obligations.</p> <p>The President may waive the application of sanctions under this bill for up to 90 days if the President provides prior certification that the waiver is vital to U.S. national security interests. </p> <p>The sanction provisions of this bill shall cease to be effective on January 1, 2022.</p> <p>It is the sense of Congress that the government of Iran has committed acts of violence, and poses a significant risk of committing further acts of violence, that threaten the peace or stability of Iraq. </p> <p>The bill directs the President to determine whether specified Iranian officials are responsible for engaging in acts or activities described in this bill and, if so, to impose admissions-related sanctions on such officials.</p> <p>The President must report, every 180 days for 5 years, on Iranian activities in Iraq, including Iran's support for Iraqi militias or political parties.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
