<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1782" measure-id="id114hr1782" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-04-14" update-date="2015-04-20">
<title>Cuba Human Rights Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr1782v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-04-20">
<action-date>2015-04-14</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p> <strong>Cuba Human Rights Act of 2015</strong> </p> <p>This bill expresses the sense of Congress that: </p> <ul> <li>the United States-Cuba relationship should not be changed, nor should any federal law or regulation be amended, until the government of Cuba ceases violating the human rights of the people of Cuba; </li> <li>the United States should overcome the jamming of radio and television signals of the Radio y Television Marti by the government of Cuba, and that the Broadcasting Board of Governors should not cut staffing, funding, or broadcast hours for Radio y Television Marti;</li> <li>if certain human rights conditions are not met the U.S. Permanent Representative to the United Nations (U.N.) should oppose and encourage other U.N. members to oppose Cuba's continued membership on the United Nations Human Rights Council; and </li> <li>the annual trafficking victims report to Congress should include an in-depth analysis of the facilitation of or involvement in severe forms of human trafficking by any official of the government of Cuba or of companies wholly or partially owned by the government of Cuba. </li> </ul> <p>Nothing in this Act may be construed as: </p> <ul> <li>prohibiting the donation of food to nongovernmental organizations or individuals in Cuba; </li> <li>restricting the export of medicine or medical supplies to Cuba, or abrogating any requirement that such exports be verified in conformity with the Cuban Democracy Act of 1992 or any other applicable federal law; or </li> <li>prohibiting or restricting any other form of assistance specified in the Cuban Democracy Act of 1992, including telecommunications, mail, and support for democracy.</li></ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
