<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2415" measure-id="id114hr2415" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-19" update-date="2015-11-09">
<title>To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to provide for establishment of a streamlined data review program.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2415v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-11-09">
<action-date>2015-05-19</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to require the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) to establish a streamlined data review program under which the holder of an approved application for a drug or biological product may submit a summary of clinical data to support approval of the drug for the treatment of cancer or another indication subject to the program.</p> <p>For a drug to be eligible for the streamlined data review program there must be a database regarding the safety of the drug and the full data sets used to develop the data summaries must be submitted, unless the FDA determines that the full data sets are not required.</p> The FDA must annually publish: (1) the number of applications reviewed under the streamlined data review program, (2) the average time for completion of review under the streamlined data review program compared to review of other applications for new indications, and (3) the number of applications reviewed under the streamlined data review program for which the FDA made use of full data sets.]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
