<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3589" measure-id="id114hr3589" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-09-22" update-date="2015-10-13">
<title>Midshipmen Education Certainty Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3589v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-10-13">
<action-date>2015-09-22</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Midshipmen Education Certainty Act </b></p> <p> Makes appropriations available each fiscal year for operations of the U.S. Merchant Marine Academy for any period during which interim or full-year appropriations for the Academy are not in effect.</p> <p>Requires funds made available for a fiscal year under this Act to remain available until the enactment of: (1) an appropriation for such fiscal year (including a continuing appropriation) for such operations; or (2) an applicable regular appropriation for the Maritime Administration for such fiscal year, or continuing appropriations resolution for such fiscal year, without any appropriation for such operations.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
