<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5511" measure-id="id114hr5511" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-06-16" update-date="2016-09-28">
<title>Equal Access to Banking Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5511v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-09-28">
<action-date>2016-06-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Equal Access to Banking Act</strong></p> <p>This bill requires the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC) to issue regulations: (1) easing the restrictive impact of regulations issued pursuant to the Federal Deposit Insurance Act relating to the factors to be considered for deposit insurance on non-profit community development financial institution banks, and (2) easing restrictions on the operation of such banks insured by the FDIC.</p>  <p> The FDIC shall ensure that such regulations issued under this bill: (1) will not provide an opportunity for individuals or for-profit financial institutions to avoid taxation or other requirements related to deposit insurance, and (2) allow charitable contributions and grants to such banks.</p> <p>The FDIC shall terminate the deposit insurance of such a bank if the bank loses its certification as a community development financial institution.</p> <p>The bill defines a &quot;non-profit community development financial institution bank&quot; as a non-profit depository institution that: (1) is certified as a community development financial institution by the Community Development Financial Institutions Fund, and (2) serves low-income and moderate-income customers.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
