<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4074" measure-id="id114hr4074" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-11-18" update-date="2016-01-20">
<title>To require the Secretary of Homeland Security to collect data regarding foreign travel, or repatriation, to the country of nationality or last habitual residence by an alien admitted to the United States as a refugee, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4074v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-01-20">
<action-date>2015-11-18</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill directs the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to collect data, and report annually to Congress, regarding instances in which an alien admitted to the United States as a refugee returns temporarily or permanently: (1) to the country of the alien's nationality at the time of such admission; or (2) in the case of an alien having no nationality at the time of such admission, to the country in which the alien last habitually resided prior to such admission.</p> <p>The bill prohibits DHS from admitting aliens into the United States as refugees until Congress passes a joint resolution giving DHS authority to resume admitting such aliens.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
