<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="81" measure-id="id114hr81" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-01-06" update-date="2015-01-14">
<title>FAMS Augmentation Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr81v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-01-14">
<action-date>2015-01-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>FAMS Augmentation Act of 2015</b></p> <p> Directs the Assistant Secretary of Homeland Security for the Transportation Security Administration to increase the number of federal air marshals by at least an additional 1,750 above the number of such marshals as of January 31, 2011, to ensure increased transportation security for inbound international flights.</p> <p>Declares the goal of this Act is to increase the number of inbound flights with federal marshals onboard while maintaining federal marshal presence on domestic point-to-point flights at or above December 25, 2009, levels.</p><p>Directs the Federal Air Marshal Service (FAMS) to establish a policy requiring newly hired federal air marshals to complete as part of their basic training the criminal investigative training program at the Federal Law Enforcement Training Center. Requires federal air marshals hired before enactment of this Act who have not completed such program to attend an alternative training program.</p><p>Directs the Assistant Secretary to establish in FAMS an Office of the Ombudsman.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
