<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4733" measure-id="id114hr4733" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-03-14" update-date="2016-07-07">
<title>To permit the United States Capitol Police to accept certain property from other Federal agencies and to dispose of certain property in its possession.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4733v79" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-07-07">
<action-date>2016-07-05</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p>(Sec. 1) This bill amends the Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 2003 to authorize the U.S. Capitol Police, by interagency transfer, donation, sale, trade-in, or other appropriate method, to dispose of any property in their possession because it has been disposed of, forfeited, voluntarily abandoned, or unclaimed. (Currently the U.S. Capitol Police are authorized to use these methods to dispose of only their own surplus or obsolete property.)</p> <p>Upon notifying specified congressional committees, the U.S. Capitol Police may accept surplus or obsolete property offered by another federal department, agency, or office.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4733v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-04-11">
<action-date>2016-03-14</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill amends the Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 2003 to authorize the U.S. Capitol Police, by interagency transfer, donation, sale, trade-in, or other appropriate method, to dispose of any property in their possession because it has been disposed of, forfeited, voluntarily abandoned, or unclaimed. (Currently the U.S. Capitol Police are authorized to use these methods to dispose of only their own surplus or obsolete property.)</p> <p>Upon notifying specified congressional committees, the U.S. Capitol Police may accept surplus or obsolete property offered by another federal department, agency, or office.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
