<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2280" measure-id="id114hr2280" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-12" update-date="2015-07-22">
<title>Federal Bird-Safe Buildings Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2280v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-07-22">
<action-date>2015-05-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Federal Bird-Safe Buildings Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>Requires each public building constructed, substantially altered, or acquired by the General Services Administration (GSA) to meet the following standards:</p> <ul> <li>at least 90% of the exposed facade material from ground level to 40 feet shall not be composed of glass or shall be composed of glass employing elements that preclude bird collisions without completely obscuring vision, ultraviolet (UV) patterned glass that contains UV-reflective or contrasting patterns that are visible to birds, patterns on glass designed in accordance with a rule that restricts horizontal spaces to less than 2 inches high and vertical spaces to less than 4 inches wide, opaque, etched, stained, frosted, or translucent glass, orany combination of these methods (modified glass);</li> <li>at least 60% of the exposed facade material above 40 feet shall meet such glass standard;</li> <li>there shall not be any transparent passageways or corners;</li> <li>all glass adjacent to atria or courtyards containing water features, plants, and other materials attractive to birds shall meet the modified glass standard; and</li> <li>outside lighting shall be appropriately shielded and minimized.</li> </ul> <p>Directs GSA to: (1) ensure that actual bird mortality is monitored at each public building; and (2) reduce exterior building and site lighting for each public building, where practicable.</p> <p>Exempts historic buildings of national significance, the White House and its grounds, the Supreme Court building and its grounds, or the U.S. Capitol and its related buildings and grounds.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
