<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5332" measure-id="id114hr5332" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-05-25" update-date="2016-08-12">
<title>Women, Peace, and Security Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5332v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-08-12">
<action-date>2016-05-25</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Women, Peace, and Security Act of 2016</strong></p> <p>This bill expresses the sense of Congress that the United States should be a global leader in promoting the meaningful participation of women in conflict prevention, management, and resolution and post-conflict relief and recovery efforts. </p> <p>The President, not later than October 1 of 2017, 2022, and 2027, shall submit to Congress and make public a Women, Peace, and Security Strategy, which shall: </p> <ul> <li> be aligned with other nations' plans to improve the participation of women in peace and security processes, conflict prevention, peace building, and decision-making institutions in conflict-affected environments; and </li> <li>include goals and evaluation plans to ensure strategy effectiveness. </li> </ul> <p>The Foreign Service Act of 1980 is amended to direct the Department of State to ensure that personnel responsible for, or deploying to, countries or regions considered to be at risk of undergoing, or emerging from, violent conflict obtain training in the following areas, each of which shall include a focus on ensuring participation by women: </p> <ul> <li>conflict prevention, mitigation, and resolution; </li> <li>protecting civilians from violence, exploitation, and trafficking in persons; and </li> <li>international human rights law.</li> </ul> <p>The Department of Defense shall ensure that personnel responsible for, or deploying to, countries or regions considered to be at risk of undergoing, or emerging from, violent conflict obtain training in: </p> <ul> <li>conflict prevention, peace processes, mitigation, resolution, and security initiatives that addresses the importance of participation by women; and </li> <li>gender considerations and meaningful participation by women, including training regarding international human rights law and protecting civilians from violence, exploitation, and trafficking in persons. </li> </ul> <p>The State Department and the U.S. Agency for International Development shall establish guidelines for overseas U.S. personnel to consult with stakeholders regarding U.S. efforts to: </p> <ul> <li>prevent, mitigate, or resolve violent conflict; and </li> <li>enhance the success of mediation and negotiation processes by ensuring the meaningful participation of women. </li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
