<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3577" measure-id="id114hr3577" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-09-18" update-date="2015-11-09">
<title>Unnecessary Government Printing Reform Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3577v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-11-09">
<action-date>2015-09-18</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Unnecessary Government Printing Reform Act of 2015</b></p> <p>This bill requires the Government Publishing Office (GPO) to make any document of the House of Representatives or Senate available only in an electronic format accessible through the Internet, and prohibits printing or distribution of a printed copy.</p> <p> Upon the request of any person to whom GPO would have been required to provide a printed copy before this requirement, GPO may print and distribute it for the person's use, except that:</p> <ul> <li>the number of printed copies may not exceed the number GPO would have provided had this requirement not been in effect; and</li> <li>GPO may print and distribute copies to the person only upon payment of printing and distributing costs.</li> </ul> <p>Any Member of Congress office shall be exempt from these requirements.</p> <p>Members and committees providing documents in electronic format are deemed to have met requirements of House and Senate rules and regulations with respect to distribution of printed copies of any document (including bills or resolutions).</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
