<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4649" measure-id="id114hr4649" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-02-29" update-date="2016-06-13">
<title>Decade for the People of African Descent Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4649v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-06-13">
<action-date>2016-02-29</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Decade for the People of African Descent Act</strong></p> <p>This bill establishes within the Department of State an Office on the International Decade for People of African Descent which shall be headed by an Ambassador-at-Large for the International Decade for People of African Descent.</p> <p> The State Department, with the assistance of the Ambassador-at-Large, shall establish an Internet site containing major international documents relating to the International Decade for People of African Descent. </p> <p>It is the sense of Congress that: </p> <ul> <li>U.S. diplomatic missions in countries may promote the International Decade for People of African Descent; and </li> <li>in allocating or recommending the allocation of funds or the recommendation of candidates for programs and grants, U.S. diplomatic missions should give consideration to those programs, initiatives, and candidates deemed to assist in the promotion of the International Decade for People of African Descent.</li> </ul> <p>The bill also establishes the U.S. Commission on the International Decade for People of African Descent, which shall: (1) promote the International Decade for People of African Descent; and (2) make policy recommendations to the President, the State Department, and Congress regarding matters involving the International Decade for People of African Descent.</p>  <p>It is the sense of Congress that there should be within the Executive Office of the President a Special Adviser to the President on the International Decade for People of African Descent, to serve as liaison with the Ambassador-at-Large for the International Decade, the commission, Congress, and nongovernmental organizations.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
