<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3506" measure-id="id114hr3506" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-09-15" update-date="2015-09-21">
<title>State and Local Fleet Efficiency Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3506v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-09-21">
<action-date>2015-09-15</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>State and Local Fleet Efficiency Act</b></p> <p> Recognizes state or local government authority to require fleet owners or operators to acquire only new fleet vehicles that: </p> <ul> <li> utilize natural gas as a fuel; </li> <li> are flexible fuel vehicles that operate on gasoline, E85, and M85; or </li> <li> meet a technology or performance-based characteristic that is commercially available. </li> </ul> <p>Provides that nothing in this Act or any other provision of law shall limit the purchase requirement authority of a state or local government applicable to fleets operating primarily within the jurisdiction if the requirements further any policy regarding climate change, the control of air pollution, energy independence, or local economic benefits.</p> <p>Defines &quot;fleet&quot; as a group of 20 or more light-duty motor vehicles, medium-duty motor vehicles, or heavy-duty motor vehicles carrying 14 or more passengers operating primarily in a metropolitan area with a population of more than 250,000 that are: </p> <ul> <li> centrally dispatched; or </li> <li> centrally fueled, or capable of being centrally fueled, and owned, operated, leased, or otherwise controlled by a governmental entity or other person meeting specified criteria.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
