<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4977" measure-id="id114hr4977" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-04-18" update-date="2016-06-14">
<title>VA Scheduling Accountability Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4977v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-06-14">
<action-date>2016-04-18</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>VA Scheduling Accountability Act</strong></p> <p>This bill directs the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to ensure that the director of each VA medical facility annually certifies to the VA that the facility is in full compliance with all provisions of law and regulations relating to scheduling appointments for veterans hospital care and medical services, including pursuant to Veterans Health Administration Directive 2010-027 (regarding scheduling of outpatient clinic appointments and ensuring staff competency). The VA may not waive any applicable provision of such laws or regulations.</p> <p>If unable to make such certification, a director shall provide the VA with an explanation of noncompliance and a description of compliance actions being taken. </p> <p>The VA shall ensure that its directives and policies apply uniformly to each VA office or facility.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
