<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2053" measure-id="id114hr2053" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-04-28" update-date="2015-06-02">
<title>Military Reserve Survivor Benefit Equity Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2053v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-06-02">
<action-date>2015-04-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Military Reserve Survivor Benefit Equity Act</strong></p> <p>Makes the Survivor Benefit Plan (SBP) annuity for survivors of members of the reserves who die from an injury or illness incurred or aggravated in the line of duty during inactive-duty training the same as the annuity for survivors of members of the regular Armed Forces who die in the line of duty while on active duty. </p> <p>Prescribes the same increase with respect to the payment of an SBP annuity to a dependent child or children when there is no eligible surviving spouse. </p> <p> Declares that, for any death that occurred before the date of enactment of this Act for which an annuity is being paid (or could be paid) to a surviving spouse, the Secretary concerned may, within six months of that date and in consultation with the surviving spouse, provide an annuity for the dependent children of the decedent instead of an annuity for the surviving spouse.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
