<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2250" measure-id="id114hr2250" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-12" update-date="2016-01-04">
<title>Further Continuing Appropriations Act, 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2250v49" currentChamber="BOTH" update-date="2016-01-04">
<action-date>2015-12-11</action-date>
<action-desc>Public Law</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was passed by the Senate on December 10, 2015. The summary of that version is repeated here.)</p> <p><b>Further Continuing Appropriations Act, 2016 </b></p> <p>This bill amends the Continuing Appropriations Act, 2016 to extend the continuing FY2016 appropriations for federal agencies at the current annual rate until the earlier of midnight on December 16, 2015, or enactment of FY2016 appropriations legislation. The bill prevents a government shutdown when funding under current law expires on December 11, 2015. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2250v35" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-12-11">
<action-date>2015-12-10</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed Senate amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Further Continuing Appropriations Act, 2016 </b></p> <p>This bill amends the Continuing Appropriations Act, 2016 to extend the continuing FY2016 appropriations for federal agencies at the current annual rate until the earlier of midnight on December 16, 2015, or enactment of FY2016 appropriations legislation. The bill prevents a government shutdown when funding under current law expires on December 11, 2015. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2250v01" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-08-17">
<action-date>2015-06-11</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to Senate amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Highlights: </b></p> <p>The Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 2016 provides FY2016 appropriations for Congress and the agencies that serve Congress.</p> <p>It includes funding for the House of Representatives, the Senate, and Joint Items such as the Joint Economic Committee, the Joint Congressional Committee on Inaugural Ceremonies of 2017, the Joint Committee on Taxation, and the Office of the Attending Physician. </p> <p>It also provides appropriations for the Capitol Police, the Office of Compliance, the Congressional Budget Office, the Architect of the Capitol, the Library of Congress, the Government Publishing Office, and the Government Accountability Office.</p> <p>Pursuant to a longstanding practice under which each chamber of Congress determines its own requirements, funds for the House are included in this bill at the level approved by the House in H.R. 2250.</p> <p>The bill increases overall legislative branch funding above the FY2015 level and also increases funding for the Senate, the Capitol Police, the Government Accountability Office, and the Library of Congress.</p> <p>The bill decreases funding below FY2015 levels for the Architect of the Capitol and the Government Publishing Office. </p> <p>The bill also prohibits a cost of living adjustment for Members of Congress, provides a payment to the widow of the late Representative Alan Nunnelee, permits the installation of battery charging stations in Library of Congress parking areas, and prohibits or restricts the delivery to House offices of printed copies of legislation and materials such as the Congressional Record and the U.S. Code. </p> <p><b>Full Summary: </b></p> <p><b>Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 2016</b></p> <p>Provides FY2016 appropriations for the legislative branch. </p> <p>TITLE I--LEGISLATIVE BRANCH </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Senate for: (1) Expense Allowances; (2) Representational Allowances for the Majority and Minority Leaders; (3) Salaries, Officers, and Employees; (4) the Office of the Legislative Counsel of the Senate; (5) the Office of the Senate Legal Counsel; (6) Expense Allowances of the Secretary of the Senate, Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate, and Secretaries for the Majority and Minority of the Senate; (7) and Contingent Expenses of the Senate. </p> <p>(Sec. 1) Requires that amounts remaining in the Senators' Official Personnel and Office Expense Account be used for deficit reduction or to reduce the federal debt </p> <p>(Sec. 2) Amends the Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 1991 to permit the Chaplain of the Senate to transfer funds between specified accounts. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the House of Representatives for: (1) Salaries and Expenses; (2) Payment to the Widows and Heirs of Deceased Members of Congress; (3) House Leadership Offices; (4) Members' Representational Allowances, including Members' Clerk Hire, Official Expenses of Members, and Official Mail; (5) Committee Employees; (6) Salaries, Officers, and Employees; and (7) Allowances and Expenses. </p> <p>(In this bill, the term &quot;Member of the House of Representatives&quot; also includes a Delegate or Resident Commissioner to the Congress.) </p> <p>(Sec. 101) Requires amounts remaining in Member's Representational Allowances after all payments are made for FY2016 to be used for deficit or debt reduction. </p> <p>(Sec. 102) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to deliver a printed copy of a bill, joint resolution, or resolution to the office of a Member of the House of Representatives unless the Member requests a copy. </p> <p>(Sec. 103) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to deliver a printed copy of the Congressional Record to the office of a Member of the House of Representatives. </p> <p>(Sec. 104) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to make payments from any Members' Representational Allowance to lease a vehicle, excluding mobile district offices, at a rate that exceeds $1,000 for the vehicle in any month. </p> <p>(Sec. 105) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to provide an aggregate number of more than 50 printed copies of the United States Code to all offices of the House of Representatives. </p> <p>(Sec. 106) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to deliver a printed copy of the report of disbursements for the operations of the House of Representatives to the office of a Member of the House of Representatives. </p> <p>(Sec. 107) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to deliver to the office of a Member of the House Representatives a printed copy of the Daily Calendar of the House of Representatives prepared by the Clerk of the House of Representatives. </p> <p>Provides appropriations for Joint Items, including the Joint Economic Committee, the Joint Congressional Committee on Inaugural Ceremonies of 2017, the Joint Committee on Taxation, the Office of the Attending Physician, and the Office of Congressional Accessibility Services.</p> <p>Provides appropriations for the Capitol Police, the Office of Compliance, and the Congressional Budget Office. </p> <p>(Sec. 1001) Amends the Supplemental Appropriations Act, 2001 to permit the Capitol Police to deposit and use reimbursements for law enforcement assistance in connection with an activity that was not sponsored by Congress. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Architect of the Capitol (AOC) for Capitol Construction and Operations; the Capitol Building; Capitol Grounds; Senate Office Buildings; House Office Buildings; Capitol Power Plant; Library Buildings and Grounds; Capitol Police Buildings, Grounds and Security; the Botanic Garden; and the Capitol Visitor Center. </p> <p>(Sec. 1101) Prohibits funds provided by this bill for the AOC from being used to make incentive or award payments to contractors for work that is behind schedule or over budget, unless the deviations are due to unforeseeable events, government-driven scope changes, or are insignificant within the overall scope of the project or program. </p> <p>(Sec. 1102) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used for scrims (coverings for buildings that are being renovated) containing photographs of building facades during restoration or construction projects performed by the AOC. </p> <p>(Sec. 1103) Authorizes the AOC to acquire from the Maryland State Highway Administration, at no cost to the United States, land that is located within the portion of Fort George Meade that the Army transferred to the AOC for long-term storage and service needs of the Library of Congress and other legislative branch agencies. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Library of Congress for Salaries and Expenses, the Copyright Office, the Congressional Research Service, and Books for the Blind and Physically Handicapped. </p> <p>(Sec. 1201) Limits the FY2016 obligational authority of the Library of Congress to $186.015 million for reimbursable and revolving fund activities funded from sources other than appropriations. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Government Publishing Office for Congressional Publishing, Public Information Programs of the Superintendent of Documents, and the Government Publishing Office Business Operations Revolving Fund. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Government Accountability Office, the Open World Leadership Center Trust Fund, and the John C. Stennis Center for Public Service Training and Development. </p> <p>(Sec. 1301) Permits employees from federal agencies to be detailed to the Government Accountability Office. </p> <p>TITLE II--GENERAL PROVISIONS </p> <p>(Sec. 201) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used for the maintenance or care of private vehicles, except for emergency assistance and cleaning. </p> <p>(Sec. 202) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from remaining available for obligation beyond FY2016 unless expressly provided in this bill. </p> <p>(Sec. 203) Provides that: (1) rates of compensation or designations of offices or positions included in this bill that are either not established by the Legislative Pay Act of 1929 or are contrary to that Act are considered permanent law; and (2) provisions in this bill for official congressional expenses and clerk hire for Senators and Members of the House of Representatives are permanent law. </p> <p>(Sec. 204) Limits contracts for certain consulting services to those where expenditures are a matter of public record and available for public inspection. </p> <p>(Sec. 205) Permits legislative branch entities participating in the Legislative Branch Financial Managers Council to use funds provided for administrative expenses to pay a share of the cost of the Council if the total cost shared among all participating entities does not exceed $2000. </p> <p>(Sec. 206) Permits the AOC to maintain and improve landscape features in a specified area in the District of Columbia. </p> <p>(Sec. 207) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being transferred to any department, agency, or instrumentality of the U.S. government unless the transfer is pursuant to authority provided by this bill or any other appropriations Act. </p> <p>(Sec. 208) Prohibits the AOC from using funds provided by this bill to eliminate or restrict guided Capitol tours led by congressional employees and interns. Permits the tours to be temporarily suspended for security or related reasons at the direction of the Capitol Police Board or at the direction of the AOC with the approval of the Capitol Police Board. </p> <p>(Sec. 209) Permits the AOC to use funds provided for the Capitol Power Plant for the construction, operation, and maintenance of battery recharging stations in Library of Congress parking areas. Requires the AOC to charge fees to recover the costs and permits the fees to be available for obligation without further appropriation during the fiscal year in which the fee is collected. </p> <p>(Sec. 210) Prohibits a cost of living adjustment for Members of Congress during FY2016. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2250v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-08-17">
<action-date>2015-05-19</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Highlights: </b></p> <p>The Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 2016 provides FY2016 appropriations for the House of Representatives and Joint Items such as the Joint Economic Committee, the Joint Committee on Taxation, and the Office of the Attending Physician. </p> <p>It also provides appropriations for the Capitol Police, the Office of Compliance, the Congressional Budget Office, the Architect of the Capitol, the Library of Congress, the Government Publishing Office, and the Government Accountability Office.</p> <p>Pursuant to a longstanding practice under which each chamber of Congress determines its own requirements, the House bill does not include funds for the Senate. </p> <p>Overall legislative branch funding in the bill is the same as the FY2015 level, and the House of Representatives is also funded at the FY2015 level. </p> <p>The bill increases funding above FY2015 levels for the Capitol Police, the Congressional Budget Office, the Library of Congress, and the Office of the Attending Physician. It decreases funding below FY2015 levels for the Architect of the Capitol and the Government Publishing Office. </p> <p>The bill also prohibits a cost of living adjustment for Members of Congress, provides a payment to the widow of the late Representative Alan Nunnelee, permits the installation of battery charging stations in Library of Congress parking areas, and prohibits or restricts the delivery to congressional offices of printed copies of legislation and materials such as the Congressional Record and the U.S. Code. </p> <p><b>Full Summary: </b></p> <p><b>Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 2016</b></p> <p>Provides FY2016 appropriations for the legislative branch. </p> <p>TITLE I--LEGISLATIVE BRANCH </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the House of Representatives for: (1) Payments to Widows and Heirs of Deceased Members of Congress; (2) Salaries and Expenses; (3) House Leadership Offices; (4) Members' Representational Allowances, including Members' Clerk Hire, Official Expenses of Members, and Official Mail; (5) Committee Employees; (6) Salaries, Officers, and Employees; and (7) Allowances and Expenses. </p> <p>(In this bill, the term &quot;Member of the House of Representatives&quot; also includes a Delegate or Resident Commissioner to the Congress.) </p> <p>(Sec. 101) Requires amounts remaining in Member's Representational Allowances after all payments are made for FY2016 to be used for deficit or debt reduction. </p> <p>(Sec. 102) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to deliver a printed copy of a bill, joint resolution, or resolution to the office of a Member of the House of Representatives unless the Member requests a copy. </p> <p>(Sec. 103) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to deliver a printed copy of the Congressional Record to the office of a Member of the House of Representatives. </p> <p>(Sec. 104) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to make payments from any Members' Representational Allowance to lease a vehicle, excluding mobile district offices, at a rate that exceeds $1,000 for the vehicle in any month. </p> <p>(Sec. 105) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to provide an aggregate number of more than 50 printed copies of the United States Code to all offices of the House of Representatives. </p> <p>(Sec. 106) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to deliver a printed copy of the report of disbursements for the operations of the House of Representatives to the office of a Member of the House of Representatives. </p> <p>(Sec. 107) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to deliver to the office of a Member of the House Representatives a printed copy of the Daily Calendar of the House of Representatives prepared by the Clerk of the House of Representatives. </p> <p>Provides appropriations for Joint Items, including the Joint Economic Committee, the Joint Committee on Taxation, and the Office of the Attending Physician. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Office of Congressional Accessibility Services, Capitol Police, the Office of Compliance, and the Congressional Budget Office. </p> <p>(Sec. 1001) Amends the Supplemental Appropriations Act, 2001 to permit the Capitol Police to deposit and use reimbursements for law enforcement assistance in connection with an activity that was not sponsored by Congress. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Architect of the Capitol (AOC) for Capitol Construction and Operations; the Capitol Building; Capitol Grounds; House Office Buildings; Capitol Power Plant; Library Buildings and Grounds; Capitol Police Buildings, Grounds and Security; the Botanic Garden; and the Capitol Visitors Center. </p> <p>(Sec. 1101) Prohibits funds provided by this bill for the AOC from being used to make incentive or award payments to contractors for work that is behind schedule or over budget, unless the deviations are due to unforeseeable events, government-driven scope changes, or are insignificant within the overall scope of the project or program. </p> <p>(Sec. 1102) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used for scrims (coverings for buildings that are being renovated) containing photographs of building facades during restoration or construction projects performed by the AOC. </p> <p>(Sec. 1103) Authorizes the AOC to acquire from the Maryland State Highway Administration, at no cost to the United States, land that is located within the portion of Fort George Meade that the Army transferred to the AOC for long-term storage and service needs of the Library of Congress and other legislative branch agencies. </p> <p>(Sec. 1104) Prohibits the AOC from obligating more than 25% of the funds made available by this bill for projects for which $5 million or more is appropriated until a plan for using the funds is approved by the Government Accountability Office and the House Appropriations Committee.</p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Library of Congress for Salaries and Expenses, the Copyright Office, the Congressional Research Service, and Books for the Blind and Physically Handicapped. </p> <p>(Sec. 1201) Limits the FY2016 obligational authority of the Library of Congress to $186.015 million for reimbursable and revolving fund activities funded from sources other than appropriations. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Government Publishing Office for Congressional Publishing, Public Information Programs of the Superintendent of Documents, and the Government Publishing Office Business Operations Revolving Fund. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Government Accountability Office and the John C. Stennis Center for Public Service Training and Development. </p> <p>(Sec. 1301) Permits employees from federal agencies to be detailed to the Government Accountability Office. </p> <p>TITLE II--GENERAL PROVISIONS </p> <p>(Sec. 201) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used for the maintenance or care of private vehicles, except for emergency assistance and cleaning. </p> <p>(Sec. 202) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from remaining available for obligation beyond FY2016 unless expressly provided in this bill. </p> <p>(Sec. 203) Provides that: (1) rates of compensation or designations of offices or positions included in this bill that are either not established by the Legislative Pay Act of 1929 or are contrary to that Act are considered permanent law; and (2) provisions in this bill for official congressional expenses and clerk hire for Senators and Members of the House of Representatives are permanent law. </p> <p>(Sec. 204) Limits contracts for certain consulting services to those where expenditures are a matter of public record and available for public inspection. </p> <p>(Sec. 205) Permits legislative branch entities participating in the Legislative Branch Financial Managers Council to use funds provided for administrative expenses to pay a share of the cost of the Council if the total cost shared among all participating entities does not exceed $2000. </p> <p>(Sec. 206) Permits the AOC to maintain and improve landscape features in a specified area in the District of Columbia. </p> <p>(Sec. 207) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being transferred to any department, agency, or instrumentality of the U.S. government unless the transfer is pursuant to authority provided by this bill or any other appropriations Act. </p> <p>(Sec. 208) Prohibits the AOC from using funds provided by this bill to eliminate or restrict guided Capitol tours led by congressional employees and interns. Permits the tours to be temporarily suspended for security or related reasons at the direction of the Capitol Police Board or at the direction of the AOC with the approval of the Capitol Police Board. </p> <p>(Sec. 209) Permits the AOC to use funds provided for the Capitol Power Plant for the construction, operation, and maintenance of battery recharging stations in Library of Congress parking areas. Requires the AOC to charge fees to recover the costs and permits the fees to be available for obligation without further appropriation during the fiscal year in which the fee is collected. </p> <p>(Sec. 210) Prohibits a cost of living adjustment for Members of Congress during FY2016. </p> <p>(Sec. 211) Establishes a spending reduction account for the amount by which the subcommittee's allocation under Section 302(b) of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 exceeds the amount of new budget authority proposed in the bill. Specifies that the amount is $5.7 million. (Under the Rules of the House of Representatives, any savings included in the spending reduction account are not available for further appropriation during consideration of the bill.) </p> <p>(Sec. 212) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to deliver a printed copy of the Congressional Pictorial Directory to the office of a Member of the House of Representatives.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2250v79" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-08-17">
<action-date>2015-05-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p><b>Highlights: </b></p> <p>The Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 2016 provides FY2016 appropriations for the House of Representatives and Joint Items such as the Joint Economic Committee, the Joint Committee on Taxation, and the Office of the Attending Physician. </p> <p>It also provides appropriations for the Capitol Police, the Office of Compliance, the Congressional Budget Office, the Architect of the Capitol, the Library of Congress, the Government Publishing Office, the Government Accountability Office, and the Open World Leadership Center. </p> <p>Pursuant to a longstanding practice under which each chamber of Congress determines its own requirements, the House bill does not include funds for the Senate. </p> <p>Overall legislative branch funding in the bill is the same as the FY2015 level, and the House of Representatives is also funded at the FY2015 level. </p> <p>The bill increases funding above FY2015 levels for the Capitol Police, the Congressional Budget Office, the Library of Congress, and the Office of the Attending Physician. It decreases funding below FY2015 levels for the Architect of the Capitol and the Government Publishing Office. </p> <p>The bill also prohibits a cost of living adjustment for Members of Congress, provides a payment to the widow of the late Representative Alan Nunnelee, permits the installation of battery charging stations in Library of Congress parking areas, and prohibits or restricts the delivery to congressional offices of printed copies of legislation and materials such as the Congressional Record and the U.S. Code. </p> <p><b>Full Summary: </b></p> <p><b>Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 2016</b></p> <p>Provides FY2016 appropriations for the legislative branch. </p> <p>TITLE I--LEGISLATIVE BRANCH </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the House of Representatives for: (1) Payments to Widows and Heirs of Deceased Members of Congress; (2) Salaries and Expenses; (3) House Leadership Offices; (4) Members' Representational Allowances, including Members' Clerk Hire, Official Expenses of Members, and Official Mail; (5) Committee Employees; (6) Salaries, Officers, and Employees; and (7) Allowances and Expenses. </p> <p>(In Sections 101-107, the term &quot;Member of the House of Representatives&quot; also includes a Delegate or Resident Commissioner to the Congress.) </p> <p>(Sec. 101) Requires amounts remaining in Member's Representational Allowances after all payments are made for FY2016 to be used for deficit or debt reduction. </p> <p>(Sec. 102) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to deliver a printed copy of a bill, joint resolution, or resolution to the office of a Member of the House of Representatives unless the Member requests a copy. </p> <p>(Sec. 103) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to deliver a printed copy of the Congressional Record to the office of a Member of the House of Representatives. </p> <p>(Sec. 104) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to make payments from any Members' Representational Allowance to lease a vehicle, excluding mobile district offices, at a rate that exceeds $1,000 for the vehicle in any month. </p> <p>(Sec. 105) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to provide an aggregate number of more than 50 printed copies of the United States Code to all offices of the House of Representatives. </p> <p>(Sec. 106) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to deliver a printed copy of the report of disbursements for the operations of the House of Representatives to the office of a Member of the House of Representatives. </p> <p>(Sec. 107) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used to deliver to the office of a Member of the House Representatives a printed copy of the Daily Calendar of the House of Representatives prepared by the Clerk of the House of Representatives. </p> <p>Provides appropriations for Joint Items, including the Joint Economic Committee, the Joint Committee on Taxation, and the Office of the Attending Physician. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Office of Congressional Accessibility Services, Capitol Police, the Office of Compliance, and the Congressional Budget Office. </p> <p>(Sec. 1001) Amends the Supplemental Appropriations Act, 2001 to permit the Capitol Police to deposit and use reimbursements for law enforcement assistance in connection with an activity that was not sponsored by Congress. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Architect of the Capitol (AOC) for Capitol Construction and Operations; the Capitol Building; Capitol Grounds; House Office Buildings; Capitol Power Plant; Library Buildings and Grounds; Capitol Police Buildings, Grounds and Security; the Botanic Garden; and the Capitol Visitors Center. </p> <p>(Sec. 1101) Prohibits funds provided by this bill for the AOC from being used to make incentive or award payments to contractors for work that is behind schedule or over budget, unless the deviations are due to unforeseeable events, government-driven scope changes, or are insignificant within the overall scope of the project or program. </p> <p>(Sec. 1102) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used for scrims (coverings for buildings that are being renovated) containing photographs of building facades during restoration or construction projects performed by the AOC. </p> <p>(Sec. 1103) Authorizes the AOC to acquire from the Maryland State Highway Administration, at no cost to the United States, land that is located within the portion of Fort George Meade that the Army transferred to the AOC for long-term storage and service needs of the Library of Congress and other legislative branch agencies. </p> <p>(Sec. 1104) Prohibits the AOC from obligating more than 25% of the funds made available by this bill for projects for which $5 million or more is appropriated until a plan for using the funds is approved by the Government Accountability Office and the House Appropriations Committee.</p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Library of Congress for Salaries and Expenses, the Copyright Office, the Congressional Research Service, and Books for the Blind and Physically Handicapped. </p> <p>(Sec. 1201) Limits the FY2016 obligational authority of the Library of Congress to $186.015 million for reimbursable and revolving fund activities funded from sources other than appropriations. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Government Publishing Office for Congressional Publishing, Public Information Programs of the Superintendent of Documents, and the Government Publishing Office Business Operations Revolving Fund. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Government Accountability Office, the Open World Leadership Center Trust Fund, and the John C. Stennis Center for Public Service Training and Development. </p> <p>(Sec. 1301) Permits employees from federal agencies to be detailed to the Government Accountability Office. </p> <p>TITLE II--GENERAL PROVISIONS </p> <p>(Sec. 201) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being used for the maintenance or care of private vehicles, except for emergency assistance and cleaning. </p> <p>(Sec. 202) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from remaining available for obligation beyond FY2016 unless expressly provided in this bill. </p> <p>(Sec. 203) Provides that: (1) rates of compensation or designations of offices or positions included in this bill that are either not established by the Legislative Pay Act of 1929 or are contrary to that Act are considered permanent law; and (2) provisions in this bill for official congressional expenses and clerk hire for Senators and Members of the House of Representatives are permanent law. </p> <p>(Sec. 204) Limits contracts for certain consulting services to those where expenditures are a matter of public record and available for public inspection. </p> <p>(Sec. 205) Permits legislative branch entities participating in the Legislative Branch Financial Managers Council to use funds provided for administrative expenses to pay a share of the cost of the Council if the total cost shared among all participating entities does not exceed $2000. </p> <p>(Sec. 206) Permits the AOC to maintain and improve landscape features in a specified area in the District of Columbia. </p> <p>(Sec. 207) Prohibits funds provided by this bill from being transferred to any department, agency, or instrumentality of the U.S. government unless the transfer is pursuant to authority provided by this bill or any other appropriations Act. </p> <p>(Sec. 208) Prohibits the AOC from using funds provided by this bill to eliminate or restrict guided Capitol tours led by congressional employees and interns. Permits the tours to be temporarily suspended for security or related reasons at the direction of the Capitol Police Board or at the direction of the AOC with the approval of the Capitol Police Board. </p> <p>(Sec. 209) Permits the AOC to use funds provided for the Capitol Power Plant for the construction, operation, and maintenance of battery recharging stations in Library of Congress parking areas. Requires the AOC to charge fees to recover the costs and permits the fees to be available for obligation without further appropriation during the fiscal year in which the fee is collected. </p> <p>(Sec. 210) Prohibits a cost of living adjustment for Members of Congress during FY2016. </p> <p>(Sec. 211) Establishes a spending reduction account for the amount by which the subcommittee's allocation under Section 302(b) of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 exceeds the amount of new budget authority proposed in the bill. Specifies that the amount is $0. (Under the Rules of the House of Representatives, any savings included in the spending reduction account are not available for further appropriation during consideration of the bill.) </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2250v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-05-19">
<action-date>2015-05-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 2016 </b></p> <p>Provides FY2016 appropriations for the legislative branch, including the House of Representatives and Joint Items such as the Joint Economic Committee, the Joint Committee on Taxation, the Office of the Attending Physician, and the Office of Congressional Accessibility Services. </p> <p>Provides appropriations for the Capitol Police; the Office of Compliance; the Congressional Budget Office; the Architect of the Capitol (except Senate Office Buildings); the Library of Congress, including the Congressional Research Service; the Government Publishing Office; the Government Accountability Office; the Open World Leadership Center Trust Fund; and the John C. Stennis Center for Public Service Training and Development. </p> <p>(Pursuant to the longstanding practice of each chamber of Congress determining its own requirements, funds for the Senate are not included in the House bill.)</p> <p>Sets forth permissible, restricted, and prohibited uses for funds provided by this bill. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
