<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5442" measure-id="id114hr5442" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-06-09" update-date="2016-08-02">
<title>STURDY Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5442v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-08-02">
<action-date>2016-06-09</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Stop Tip-overs of Unstable, Risky Dressers on Youth Act or the STURDY Act</b></p> <p> This bill requires the Consumer Product Safety Commission (CPSC) to promulgate a final consumer product safety standard for free-standing clothing storage units (furniture items referred to as, or that may contain, a chest, door chest, chest of drawers, dresser, or bureau) to protect children from tip-over-related death or injury, unless the CPSC determines that a voluntary ASTM (American Society for Testing and Materials) International standard adequately protects children and is likely to be complied with by furniture manufacturers.</p> <p>If an ASTM standard meets the CPSC's requirements, the standard shall be treated as a consumer product safety rule.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
