<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5485" measure-id="id114hr5485" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-06-15" update-date="2016-06-21">
<title>Financial Services and General Government Appropriations Act, 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5485v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-06-21">
<action-date>2016-06-15</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Financial Services and General Government Appropriations Act, 2017 </b></p> <p>Provides FY2017 appropriations to the Department of the Treasury, the Executive Office of the President, the judiciary, the District of Columbia, and several independent agencies. </p> <p><i>Department of the Treasury Appropriations Act, 2017 </i></p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Department of the Treasury, including the Internal Revenue Service. </p> <p><i>Executive Office of the President Appropriations Act, 2017 </i></p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Executive Office of the President and Funds Appropriated to the President. </p> <p><i>Judiciary Appropriations Act, 2017 </i></p> <p>Provides appropriations to the judiciary, including the U.S. Supreme Court, other federal courts, administrative offices, and the U.S. Sentencing Commission. </p> <p><i>District of Columbia Appropriations Act, 2017 </i></p> <p>Provides appropriations to the District of Columbia, including Federal Funds and District of Columbia Funds. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to independent agencies, including: </p> <ul> <li> the Administrative Conference of the United States, </li> <li>the Consumer Product Safety Commission, </li> <li> the Election Assistance Commission, </li> <li>the Federal Communications Commission, </li> <li>the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, </li> <li> the Federal Election Commission, </li> <li> the Federal Labor Relations Authority, </li> <li> the Federal Trade Commission, </li> <li> the General Services Administration, </li> <li> the Merit Systems Protection Board, </li> <li> the National Archives and Records Administration, </li> <li> the National Credit Union Administration, </li> <li> the Office of Government Ethics, </li> <li> the Office Personnel Management, </li> <li> the Office of Special Counsel, </li> <li> the Postal Regulatory Commission, </li> <li> the Privacy and Civil Liberties Oversight Board, </li> <li> the Securities and Exchange Commission, </li> <li> the Selective Service System, </li> <li> the Small Business Administration, </li> <li> the U.S. Postal Service, and </li> <li> the U.S. Tax Court. </li> </ul> <p>Sets forth permissible and prohibited uses for funds provided by this and other appropriations Acts. </p> <p><i>Scholarships for Opportunity and Results Reauthorization Act or the SOAR Reauthorization Act </i></p> <p>Reauthorizes and amends the Scholarships for Opportunity and Results Act, which authorizes education funding for the District of Columbia, including the Opportunity Scholarship Program, public schools, and public charter schools. </p> <p><i>SEC Small Business Advocate Act of 2016 </i></p> <p>Establishes the Office of the Advocate for Small Business Capital Formation and the Small Business Capital Formation Advisory Committee within the Securities and Exchange Commission. </p> <p><i>Financial Institution Bankruptcy Act of 2016 </i></p> <p>Amends the Bankruptcy Code to establish a new bankruptcy process for certain financial institutions. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
