<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4431" measure-id="id114hr4431" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-02-02" update-date="2016-03-22">
<title>To direct the Attorney General to reimburse State and local law enforcement agencies for costs incurred in carrying out law enforcement activities associated with the armed occupation of the Malheur National Wildlife Refuge, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4431v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-03-22">
<action-date>2016-02-02</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill directs the Department of Justice (DOJ) to reimburse state and local law enforcement agencies for costs associated with the armed occupation of the Malheur National Wildlife Refuge in Harney County, Oregon.</p> <p>DOJ may file a civil action against an armed occupation participant to recover reimbursement costs. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
