<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2461" measure-id="id114hr2461" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-20" update-date="2015-08-10">
<title>To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to improve access to, and utilization of, bone mass measurement benefits under part B of the Medicare program by establishing a minimum payment amount under such part for bone mass measurement.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2461v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-08-10">
<action-date>2015-05-20</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act, with respect to the establishment of physicians' fee schedules, to extend for 2016 and each subsequent year the classification of dual-energy x-ray absorptiometry services as imaging services used in bone mass scans.</p> <p>The Department of Health and Human Services shall establish national minimum payment amounts for such services as identified by specified Healthcare Common Procedure Coding System codes and adjusted by the pertinent geographical adjustment factors.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
