<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5570" measure-id="id114hr5570" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-06-22" update-date="2016-06-29">
<title>Western Colorado Wilderness Study Area Release Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5570v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-06-29">
<action-date>2016-06-22</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Western Colorado Wilderness Study Area Release Act</b></p> <p>This bill releases the following areas in Colorado from further review for designation as wilderness: (1) any public lands in the North Sand Hills Instant Study Area, (2) any portions of the Dominguez Canyon Wilderness Study Area within the Dominguez-Escalante National Conservation Area not designated as wilderness, and (3) any portions of the Black Ridge Canyons Wilderness Study Area within the McInnis Canyons National Conservation Area not designated as wilderness.</p> <p>The bill states that in areas in which the Colorado River is used as a reference for defining the boundary of McInnis Canyons National Conservation Area, the boundary shall: (1) be located at the edge of the river, and (2) change according to the river's level. </p> <p>The bill prohibits the inclusion of any portion of the Colorado River, regardless of its level, within the conservation area. </p> <p>The Omnibus Public Land Management Act of 2009 is amended to authorize the Department of the Interior to enter into land exchanges within the conservation area which would enhance the values for which it was established.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
