<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4472" measure-id="id114hr4472" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-02-04" update-date="2016-05-31">
<title>Modernizing the Interstate Placement of Children in Foster Care Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4472v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-05-31">
<action-date>2016-03-22</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Modernizing the Interstate Placement of Children in Foster Care Act</b></p> <p>(Sec. 3) This bill amends part E (Foster Care and Adoption Assistance) of title IV of the Social Security Act to require the procedures a state must have in effect for the orderly and timely interstate placement of children to include the use of an electronic interstate case-processing system.</p> <p>(Sec. 4) The bill also authorizes grants for development of an electronic interstate case-processing system to expedite the interstate placement of children in foster care, guardianship, or adoptive homes.</p> <p>(Sec. 5) Discretionary funding shall continue through FY2017 to promote safe and stable families.</p> <p>(Sec. 6) The Department of Health and Human Services shall reserve $5 million of the amount made available for such grants for FY2017, which reserved amount shall remain available through FY2021.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4472v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-03-14">
<action-date>2016-02-04</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Modernizing the Interstate Placement of Children in Foster Care Act</b></p> <p>This bill amends part E (Foster Care and Adoption Assistance) of title IV of the Social Security Act to require the procedures a state must have in effect for the orderly and timely interstate placement of children to include a centralized electronic case processing system.</p> <p>Grants are authorized for development of a centralized electronic system to expedite the interstate placement of children in foster care, guardianship, or adoptive homes.</p> <p>Discretionary funding shall be continued through FY2017 to promote safe and stable families.</p> <p>The Department of Health and Human Services shall reserve $5 million of the amount made available for such grants for FY2017, which reserved amount shall remain available through FY2021.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
