<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4593" measure-id="id114hr4593" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-02-23" update-date="2016-03-24">
<title>Reducing Long-Term Unemployment Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4593v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-03-24">
<action-date>2016-02-23</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Reducing Long-Term Unemployment Act </strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to extend until December 31, 2017, the suspension of employment and railroad retirement taxes for employers who hire unemployed individuals.&nbsp; The aggregate reduction in taxes from such suspension is limited to $5,000 per employee. </p> <p>The bill modifies the unemployment requirement to require a signed affidavit from the unemployed individual that, during the entire 27-week period ending on the hiring date, such individual: (1) was receiving federal or state unemployment compensation, or (2) was unemployed and would have received unemployment compensation except for having exhausted the right to receive such compensation during such period. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
