<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2587" measure-id="id114hr2587" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-06-01" update-date="2015-06-04">
<title>To further enhance the promotion of exports of United States goods and services, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2587v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-06-04">
<action-date>2015-06-01</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>State Trade Coordination Act</b></p> <p> Amends the Export Enhancement Act of 1988 to revise membership of the Trade Promotion Coordinating Committee (TPCC) to include one or more presidential appointees representing state trade promotion agencies.</p> <p>Directs the Secretary of Commerce, acting through the TPCC and in coordination with representatives of state trade promotion agencies, to develop a plan to integrate resources and strategies of state trade promotion agencies into the overall federal trade promotion program.</p> <p>Directs the Secretary, acting through the head of the U.S. Commercial Service, to develop an annual federal-state export strategy for goods and services for each state that submits to the Secretary its export strategy for the upcoming year.</p> <p>Directs the Secretary, in coordination with representatives of state trade promotion agencies, to develop a framework to share export success information, and develop a coordinated set of reporting metrics.</p> <p>Revises the strategic plan for federal trade promotion efforts to include an annual survey and analysis of the overall effectiveness of federal-state coordination and export promotion goals, as well as best practices, recommendations to better assist small businesses, and other relevant matters.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
