<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3193" measure-id="id114hr3193" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-07-23" update-date="2016-06-27">
<title>Animal Emergency Planning Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr3193v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-06-27">
<action-date>2015-07-23</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Animal Emergency Planning Act of 2015</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Animal Welfare Act to require research facilities, dealers, exhibitors, intermediate handlers, and carriers (covered persons) to develop, document, and follow a contingency plan to provide for the humane handling, treatment, transportation, housing, and care of their animals in the event of an emergency or disaster.</p> <p>The plan must:</p> <ul> <li>identify situations that the covered person might experience that would trigger the need to implement the measures identified in the plan; </li> <li> outline tasks to be carried out in response to emergencies or disasters; </li> <li> establish a chain of command and identify the individuals responsible for fulfilling the tasks; and </li> <li> address how response and recovery will be handled in terms of materials, resources, and training needed.</li> </ul> <p>Covered persons must review their plan at least annually, train personnel in their roles and responsibilities as outlined in the plan, and provide training when the plan changes.</p> <p>The bill does not preempt state law that provides equal or greater protection for animals.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
