<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4837" measure-id="id114hr4837" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-03-22" update-date="2016-03-31">
<title>S.O.S. Veterans Caregivers Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4837v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-03-31">
<action-date>2016-03-22</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Support our Services to Veterans Caregivers Act or the S.O.S. Veterans Caregivers Act</strong></p> <p> This bill includes a veteran who has a serious illness or injury (currently, a serious injury) incurred or aggravated in the line of active duty on or after September 11, 2001, as an &quot;eligible veteran&quot; for purposes of the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) program of comprehensive assistance for family caregivers of eligible veterans. </p> <p>As part of such program, the VA shall give each caregiver designated as the primary provider of personal care services for an eligible veteran, not less than annually, a multidimensional assessment to measure the burden and strain the caregiver has felt. </p> <p>The VA's annual report on such program shall include a description of the satisfaction experienced by caregivers and veterans with such program.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
