<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4267" measure-id="id114hr4267" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-12-16" update-date="2016-01-04">
<title>Resettlement REFORM (Re-Evaluation of Financing Our Refugee Mission) Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4267v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-01-04">
<action-date>2015-12-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Resettlement REFORM (Re-Evaluation of Financing Our Refugee Mission) Act</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to authorize a state to refuse without penalty to expend refugee resettlement assistance with respect to an alien who: </p> <ul> <li>is a national of a country that is a state sponsor of terrorism or a terrorist sanctuary, or </li> <li>has no nationality and the country in which the alien last habitually resided is a state sponsor of terrorism or a terrorist sanctuary.</li> </ul> <p>A state may not refuse to expend such funds with respect to an alien who is an Iraqi national (or spouse or children of one) who was employed by, or worked for the U.S. government in Iraq and has or is experiencing an ongoing serious threat because of such employment.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
