<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5358" measure-id="id114hr5358" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-05-26" update-date="2016-09-08">
<title>Penn School - Reconstruction Era National Monument Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr5358v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-09-08">
<action-date>2016-05-26</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Penn School - Reconstruction Era National Monument Act</b></p> <p>This bill establishes the Penn School - Reconstruction Era National Monument in South Carolina, which shall become a unit of the National Park System (NPS) when the Department of the Interior has: </p> <ul> <li>acquired sufficient land or an interest in land within the monument's boundary to constitute a manageable unit, and </li> <li>entered into a written agreement with Penn Community Services, Inc. (known as Penn Center) pursuant to this bill. </li> </ul> <p>The bill declares that the monument's boundaries shall be the same as those of the Penn Center National Historic Landmark District.</p> <p>Interior may enter into an agreement with Penn Center:</p> <ul> <li>regarding the transfer of land or interests in land; and </li> <li>delineating the respective roles and responsibilities of the National Park Service and Penn Center in the operation, maintenance, and interpretation of the monument. </li> </ul> <p>Interior may acquire by donation, purchase from a willing seller, or exchange lands or interests in land within the monument's boundary and within its vicinity. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
