<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2764" measure-id="id114hr2764" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-06-12" update-date="2015-06-22">
<title>CARE Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2764v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-06-22">
<action-date>2015-06-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Children's Act for Responsible Employment of 2015 or the CARE Act of 2015</b></p> <p> Amends the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to define &quot;oppressive child labor,&quot; for purposes of the Act's child labor prohibitions, as the employment of any employee who is: </p> <ul> <li> 16 or 17 in any occupation found by the Department of Labor to be particularly hazardous for their employment or detrimental to their health or well-being; </li> <li> 14 or 15, unless the employment is confined to periods which do not interfere with the employee's schooling, health, or well-being; or </li> <li> under 14.</li> </ul> <p>Revises the Act's exemptions to make the restrictions on oppressive child labor inapplicable to the following:</p> <ul> <li> employment in agriculture of an employee under age 18 by his or her parent, or by a person standing in the place of the parent, on a farm owned by the parent or person (current law uses an age- and consent-based scheme); and </li> <li> employment of an employee under age 16 by a parent, or a person standing in place of a parent, other than in agriculture, manufacturing, mining, or any other employment the Department finds to be particularly hazardous for the employment of children age 16 or 17 or detrimental to their health or well-being. (Current law applies the child labor restrictions to particularly hazardous agricultural employment, except where the child is employed by a parent or a person standing in place of the parent on a farm owned or operated by such person). </li> </ul> <p>Eliminates any waiver of such prohibitions for hand-harvesting of certain crops.</p> <p>Increases civil and establishes criminal penalties for child labor violations.</p> <p>Directs the Department to revise federal child labor regulations to prohibit the employment of children under age 18 in duties involving the handling of pesticides.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
