<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4213" measure-id="id114hr4213" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-12-10" update-date="2016-02-10">
<title>Tax Equity and Prosperity for Puerto Rican Families Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr4213v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-02-10">
<action-date>2015-12-10</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Tax Equity and Prosperity for Puerto Rican Families Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to make citizens of Puerto Rico eligible for the federal earned income tax credit and allow them to claim the refundable portion of the child tax credit on the same basis as U.S. taxpayers. In making the earned income tax credit applicable to Puerto Rican citizens, the bill modifies credit requirements to allow taxpayers in Puerto Rico to claim the credit at age 21 (rather than age 25) and to allow a credit percentage of 40, without regard to the number of qualifying children claimed by the taxpayer. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
