<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2167" measure-id="id114hr2167" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-04-30" update-date="2015-07-20">
<title>Public Lands Service Corps Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hr2167v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-07-20">
<action-date>2015-04-30</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Public Lands Service Corps Act of 2015</b></p> <p> Amends the Public Lands Corps Act of 1993 to rename: (1) the Public Lands Corps Act of 1993 as the Public Lands Service Corps Act of 1993, and (2) the Public Lands Corps as the Public Lands Service Corps (the Corps). </p> <p> Establishes the Corps in the Department of Commerce (as well as in the Department of Agriculture and the Department of the Interior, as under current law).</p> <p>Requires: (1) establishment of a department-level office within the Department of the Interior, Forest Service, and the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration for the coordination of Corps activities; and (2) designation of a Corps coordinator for each agency within the Departments of the Interior, of Agriculture, and of Commerce that administers such activities. Establishes an Indian Youth Service Corps liaison. </p> <p>Permits the enrollment of resource assistants and consulting interns. Sets a maximum enrollment term of two years.</p> <p>Requires a recruitment program for the Corps. </p> <p>Instructs the Department concerned, for purposes of training, to take into account training already received by Corps participants enrolled from qualified youth or conservation corps. </p> <p>Describes the types of natural and cultural resources conservation projects that may be carried out by the Corps. </p> <p>Authorizes the Corps to provide certain visitor and interpretation services.</p> <p>Authorizes each Department to make: (1) arrangements for temporary housing for Corps participants in conservation centers, and (2) individual placements of consulting interns to perform management analysis activities for agencies under the Department's jurisdiction carrying out appropriate natural and cultural resources conservation projects. </p> <p>Authorizes cooperative agreements and competitive grants for Indian tribes and qualified youth or conservation corps to establish Indian Youth Service Corps programs. </p> <p>Requires the Secretary to issue management guidelines for programs of the Corps.</p> <p>Revises requirements for: (1) participant living allowances to include certain travel costs; (2) noncompetitive hiring status to cover Indian Youth Service Corps particpants, resource assistants, and consulting interns.</p> <p>Removes resource assistants from eligibility for national service educational awards.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
