<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="sjres" measure-number="30" measure-id="id114sjres30" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-02-24" update-date="2016-03-01">
<title>A joint resolution relating to the disapproval of the proposed foreign military sale to the Government of Pakistan of F-16 Block 52 aircraft.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114sjres30v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-03-01">
<action-date>2016-02-24</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This joint resolution prohibits the issuance of a letter of offer with respect to any of the following proposed sales to Pakistan in Transmittals Numbered 15-80 and 16-80, including related defense articles and defense services: </p> <ul> <li>8 F-16 Block 52 aircraft with the Fl00-PW-229 increased performance engine,</li> <li> 2 F-16 Block 52 C models with the Fl00-PW-229 increased performance engine,</li> <li>6 F-16 Block 52 D models with the Fl00-PW-229 increased performance engine,</li> <li>14 Joint Helmet Mounted Cueing Systems,</li> <li>8 AN/APG-68(V)9 radars, and</li> <li>8 ALQ-211(V)9 Advanced Integrated Defensive Electronic Warfare Suites.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
