<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="sconres" measure-number="42" measure-id="id114sconres42" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-07-06" update-date="2016-08-30">
<title>A concurrent resolution to express the sense of Congress regarding the safe and expeditious resettlement to Albania of all residents of Camp Liberty.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114sconres42v80" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-08-30">
<action-date>2016-07-14</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to Senate without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.)</p> <p>Expresses the sense of Congress that the United States should: </p> <ul> <li>work with Iraq and the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR) to ensure that all residents of Camp Liberty (located in Iraq) are safely and expeditiously resettled in Albania; </li> <li>work with Iraq, Albania, and the UNHCR to prevent Iran from intervening in the resettlement process; </li> <li>urge Iraq to protect residents during the resettlement process, including by ensuring that security personnel are vetted to determine that they are not affiliated with the Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps' Qods Force; </li> <li>urge Iraq to ensure access to food, clean water, medical assistance, and energy needs; </li> <li>work with Iraq to facilitate the sale of residents' property and assets;</li> <li> work with Iraq and the UNHCR to ensure that residents may exercise full control of all personal assets; and </li> <li>urge Albania and the UNHCR to ensure the continued recognition of the resettled residents as &quot;persons of concern&quot; entitled to international protections.</li></ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114sconres42v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-08-30">
<action-date>2016-07-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Expresses the sense of Congress that the United States should: </p> <ul> <li>work with Iraq and the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR) to ensure that all residents of Camp Liberty (located in Iraq) are safely and expeditiously resettled in Albania; </li> <li>work with Iraq, Albania, and the UNHCR to prevent Iran from intervening in the resettlement process; </li> <li>urge Iraq to protect residents during the resettlement process, including by ensuring that security personnel are vetted to determine that they are not affiliated with the Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps' Qods Force; </li> <li>urge Iraq to ensure access to food, clean water, medical assistance, and energy needs; </li> <li>work with Iraq to facilitate the sale of residents' property and assets;</li> <li> work with Iraq and the UNHCR to ensure that residents may exercise full control of all personal assets; and </li> <li>urge Albania and the UNHCR to ensure the continued recognition of the resettled residents as &quot;persons of concern&quot; entitled to international protections.</li></ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
