<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="sconres" measure-number="32" measure-id="id114sconres32" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-02-25" update-date="2016-02-29">
<title>A concurrent resolution recognizing the soldiers of the 14th Quartermaster Detachment of the United States Army Reserve, who were killed or wounded in their barracks by an Iraqi SCUD missile attack in Dhahran, Saudi Arabia, during Operation Desert Shield and Operation Desert Storm, on the occasion of the 25th anniversary of the attack.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114sconres32v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-02-29">
<action-date>2016-02-25</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Recognizes the sacrifice and dedicated service of Pennsylvanians during Operation Desert Shield and Operation Desert Storm.</p> <p> Honors: (1) the 13 soldiers of the 14th Quartermaster Detachment of the United States Army Reserve who were killed in action on February 25, 1991, in the attack on Dhahran, Saudi Arabia; and (2) the 43 soldiers of the 14th Quartermaster Detachment of the United States Army Reserve who were wounded during the attack. </p> <p>Pledges the support of the House of Representatives to the families of these soldiers.</p> <p> Encourages the people of the United States to commemorate the role and contribution of Pennsylvanians and Pennsylvania-based units of the Army National Guard, the Army Reserve, the Marine Corps Reserve, the Navy Reserve, the Air National Guard, and the Air Force Reserve who supported Operation Desert Shield and Operation Desert Storm.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
