<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="sconres" measure-number="48" measure-id="id114sconres48" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-07-14" update-date="2016-10-31">
<title>A concurrent resolution expressing the sense of Congress that the Italian Supreme Court of Cassation should domesticate and recognize judgments issued by United States courts on behalf of United States victims of terrorism, and that the Italian Ministry of Foreign Affairs should cease its political interference with Italy's independent judiciary, which it carries out in the interests of state sponsors of terrorism such as the Islamic Republic of Iran.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114sconres48v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-10-31">
<action-date>2016-07-14</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Expresses the sense of Congress that:</p> <ul> <li> Italy has violated the principle of reciprocity governing the mutual recognition of domestic court awards between Italy and the United States; </li> <li> the intervention by the Italian Ministry of Foreign Affairs on behalf of Iran against victims of Iranian terrorism was initiated to the detriment of both United States and European Union terrorism victims; and </li> <li> the European Court of Human Rights should overturn the Italian Supreme Court of Cassation's erroneous rulings in <em>Flatow v. Islamic Republic of Iran</em> and <em>Eisenfeld v. Islamic Republic of Iran</em> and order such court to recognize the U.S. judgments held by the Flatow, Duker, and Eisenfeld families against Iran. </li> </ul> <ul> <ul> </ul> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
