<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="sconres" measure-number="12" measure-id="id114sconres12" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-04-16" update-date="2015-04-22">
<title>A concurrent resolution recognizing the need to improve physical access to many federally funded facilities for all people of the United States, particularly people with disabilities.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114sconres12v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-04-22">
<action-date>2015-04-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Recognizes the hardships that people with disabilities must overcome every day. </p> <p>Reaffirms support of the Architectural Barriers Act of 1968 and the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990.</p> <p>Recommends that the United States Postal Service and federal agencies install power-assisted doors at post offices and other federally funded facilities to ensure equal access for all people.</p> <p> Pledges to continue to identify and remove the barriers that prevent equal access to federal government services.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
