<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="standard" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HRES 279 IH: Urging respect for freedom of expression and human rights in Turkey.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 279</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20150520">May 20, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000556">Mr. Grayson</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="I000057">Mr. Israel</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000515">Mr. Rush</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000563">Mr. Lipinski</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Urging respect for freedom of expression and human rights in Turkey.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
 <whereas><text>Whereas Turkey is a constitutional, secular state with an ethnically, religiously, and culturally diverse population;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Turkey has long been a modern democracy, an Organization for Security and Co-operation in Europe (OSCE) participating State, and a major North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) ally to the United States;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas respect for universal human rights, especially freedom of expression, is essential to maintain a democratic, open society;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas prominent human rights monitors, including the U.S. Department of State, Bureau of Democracy, Human Rights and Labor, the OSCE Representative on Freedom of the Media, Freedom House, and Human Rights Watch, have expressed concern about the erosion of freedom of expression under President Recep Tayyip Erdogan and the Justice and Development Party (AKP);</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Government of Turkey has increasingly conducted widespread intimidation and manipulation of media, private companies, and other civil society actors through a number of means, including active interference in their operations and regulatory action to compel government-friendly outcomes;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in recent years, criminal prosecution or intimidation based on overly broad terrorism laws and other measures taken by authorities in Turkey have been widely criticized as ideologically driven and unusually severe;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas several members of independent media groups in Turkey have been arrested on questionable charges;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas following protests in late 2013 and early 2014, authorities in Turkey banned Twitter and YouTube for two weeks until the Constitutional Court of Turkey overturned the ban; and</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on April 6, 2015, Turkey again blocked access to Twitter and YouTube for several hours and threatened to ban Google: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body id="H047A5F10247D4A09A6A4D89E2F15616D" style="traditional">
 <section id="id67473255B80D45C9B189C0295D208D1A" section-type="resolved"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="H382A91D67FD3454EBB55287B8123F33A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>calls on the Government of Turkey to immediately lift restrictions on freedom of expression, including expression online or in social media;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD565FA58D88444DF9D53E5F914EF76D0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>urges the Government of Turkey to fully respect universal human rights consistent with its OSCE commitments; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8BEF8440E70E401CBE9EBCAF8ED1DBB5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>reaffirms the United States long-standing partnership and friendship with the people of Turkey.</text> </paragraph></section></resolution-body> </resolution> 

