<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="HC07DD7AB29BD4177AE7BF47CBF70E28A" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HRES 443 IH: Commending the Departments of Defense and Veterans Affairs for their joint campaign to raise awareness during September, Suicide Prevention Month, to reduce suicide among members of the United States Armed Forces and veterans.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-09-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 443</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20150925">September 25, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000293">Ms. Esty</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="G000564">Mr. Gibson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000179">Mrs. Napolitano</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000820">Mrs. Mimi Walters of California</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Veterans’ Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Commending the Departments of Defense and Veterans Affairs for their joint campaign to raise
			 awareness during September, Suicide Prevention Month, to reduce suicide
			 among members of the United States Armed Forces and veterans.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
 <whereas><text>Whereas suicide is a leading noncombat cause of death among members of the United States Armed Forces;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to the Department of Veterans Affairs 2012 Suicide Data Report, as many as 22 veterans are lost to suicide in the United States each day;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas more than 38,000 people in the United States take their lives each year, 20 percent of whom are veterans;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Joshua Omvig Suicide Prevention Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/110">Public Law 110–110</external-xref>; 121 Stat. 1031) was enacted in 2007 to establish a comprehensive program for suicide prevention among veterans;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Veterans Crisis Line, which was established under the Joshua Omvig Suicide Prevention Act, has received more than 890,000 telephone calls and facilitated more than 30,000 life-saving rescues;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas many suicides are preventable, and 90 percent of individuals who die by suicide have a diagnosable psychiatric disorder at the time of death;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Clay Hunt Suicide Prevention for American Veterans Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/2">Public Law 114–2</external-xref>; 129 Stat. 30) was enacted in 2015 to provide veterans increased access to mental health care and resources;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas September is National Suicide Prevention Awareness Month; and</text> </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas in September 2014, the Department of Defense and the Department of Veterans Affairs launched the joint public awareness campaign <quote>The Power of 1</quote> to draw attention to the mental health services and suicide prevention programs available to members of the United States Armed Forces and veterans, focusing on everyday actions that can save lives: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body id="HA2A11B52D59D483488C4336E743ECD4D" style="traditional">
 <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H07FE9337B970418A9DBE98D48D764549" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="H327E47B0D1074F13A2ADFEE3DB831360"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">commends the Department of Defense and the Department of Veterans Affairs for raising awareness during Suicide Prevention Month of the life-saving resources available to those who have served, or are currently serving, in uniform; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2739E26424C348509BCAA579E7260A4A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>supports the goals and ideals of National Suicide Prevention Awareness Month, <quote>The Power of 1</quote> campaign, and efforts to improve outreach to individuals at risk for suicide, especially those addressed to veterans and members of the United States Armed Forces.</text>
			</paragraph></section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


