<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="HA3414306A8F84608A03E09F3435C6DD0" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HRES 360 IH: Recognizing the 50th anniversary of the National Collegiate Honors Council.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 360</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20150710">July 10, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000604">Mr. Russell</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001271">Mr. Benishek</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001250">Mr. Bishop of Utah</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001255">Mr. Boustany</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001053">Mr. Cole</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Recognizing the 50th anniversary of the National Collegiate Honors Council.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
 <whereas><text>Whereas the National Collegiate Honors Council supports honors education at more than 800 member colleges and universities, challenging over 325,000 high-achieving students from six regions in the United States and internationally;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the National Collegiate Honors Council, with 50 years of tradition in providing networking and support for professional honors staff, continues to define and hold true to the guiding principles of honors education;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the National Collegiate Honors Council provides opportunities for Honors Directors and other professional staff to share best practices in honors education;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the National Collegiate Honors Council supports Honors Directors through numerous continuing education tracks, including specific options for beginning in honors, developing in honors, and best honors administrative practices;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the National Collegiate Honors Council’s member organizations contribute to a collection of honors education best practices and provide consultation and publications for others researching honors education pedagogy; and</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the National Collegiate Honors Council, in support of its members, influences and provides unique and collaborative learning experiences in all academic disciplines: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body id="H5212DD4121764C73B639BCD2BBD5D4BE" style="traditional">
 <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H4F0DF5C53512406DBA0FDAE78A7F4E31" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="H3397AD0CE5D84D5C9DA07FD9D2E2E0D0"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">commends the National Collegiate Honors Council, its officers, staff, members, institutions, and students on the 50th anniversary of the Council;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H323B94E89BB842C09A85189DF9FF42C3"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognizes the members of the National Collegiate Honors Council for their continued hard work and devotion to educational excellence in higher education; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF28DD22F2A714BC2BDF99363AD8EFF9D"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">congratulates the National Collegiate Honors Council for its distinguished history and long record of achievements.</text>
			</paragraph></section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


