<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="H37F6BE12B2044C36B5DA4D46E0E9BEEE" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HRES 54 IH: Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the United States Postal Service should take all appropriate measures to restore service standards in effect as of July 1, 2012.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 54</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20150127">January 27, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001180">Mr. McKinley</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000033">Mr. Young of Alaska</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000578">Mr. LaMalfa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000127">Mr. Nolan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000295">Mr. Joyce</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001156">Ms. Linda T. Sánchez of California</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the United States Postal Service should
			 take all appropriate measures to restore service standards in effect as of
			 July 1, 2012.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
 <whereas><text>Whereas on January 5, 2015, the United States Postal Service has implemented lower <quote>service standards</quote> to virtually eliminate overnight delivery of first class mail and periodicals, and further delay most other mail;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas delayed mail negatively impacts businesses, hurts residents, rural communities and the economy, and drives customers away, resulting in lower revenue and worsens the Postal Service’s financial situation; and</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas robust service standards implemented by the United States Postal Service are essential to providing prompt and timely delivery of all mail: online purchases, local newspapers, newsletters, bill payments, letters, invitations, packages, and medicines: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body id="H46F1D5DF312B44FBB70A9BA72AFCA8D5" style="traditional">
 <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H26C32561DCFC4E8CB4542F481CAF2446" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That it is the sense of the House of Representatives that the United States Postal Service should take all appropriate measures to restore service standards in effect as of July 1, 2012.</text>
		</section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


