<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="H9901D359A81A435585B5ABC1D4F0B5E2" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HRES 226 IH: Calling on the President to work toward equitable, constructive, stable, and durable Armenian-Turkish relations for the next 100 years based upon the two countries’ common interests and the United States’ significant security interests in the region.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 226</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20150428">April 28, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000250">Mr. Sessions</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Calling on the President to work toward equitable, constructive, stable, and durable
			 Armenian-Turkish relations for the next 100 years based upon the two
			 countries’ common interests and the United States’ significant security
			 interests in the region.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
 <whereas><text>Whereas the Obama Administration has, since early 2009, sought to improve Armenian-Turkish relations; and</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas at the start of this process, President Barack Obama had, on April 6, 2009, voiced the United States Government's expectation that the Armenia-Turkey dialogue would <quote>bear fruit very quickly</quote>, but recent attempts to reestablish diplomatic relations have been unsuccessful: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body id="HBE5F8CC600F24BDEA6A3F324B4CA8D60" style="traditional">
 <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H7349D3A938CA4F4F89A24E07F41CD883" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives calls on the President to work toward equitable, constructive, stable, and durable Armenian-Turkish relations for the next 100 years, based upon the two countries’ common interests and the United States’ significant security interests in the region.</text>
		</section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


