<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="H467D2324AF05475AA212F2E6955AC206" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HRES 498 IH: Expressing support for designation of October 2015 as “National Breast Cancer Awareness Month”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-10-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 498</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20151027">October 27, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001151">Mr. Murphy of Pennsylvania</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Expressing support for designation of October 2015 as <quote>National Breast Cancer Awareness Month</quote>.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
 <whereas><text>Whereas breast cancer is the most common cancer among women worldwide;</text> </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 1 in 8 women in the United States will be diagnosed with breast cancer in her lifetime;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas breast cancer is the second leading cause of cancer death among women in the United States;</text> </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas each year it is estimated that over 230,000 women in the United States will be diagnosed with breast cancer and more than 40,000 will die;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas an estimated 2,300 men will be diagnosed with breast cancer in the United States and more than 400 will die each year;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas in recent years, there has been a gradual reduction in female breast cancer incidence rates among women aged 50 and older;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas death rates from breast cancer have been declining since about 1990, due in part to better screening and early detection, increased awareness, and continually improving treatment options; and</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas October 2015 would be an appropriate month to designate as <quote>National Breast Cancer Awareness Month</quote>: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble> <resolution-body id="H58E31A05430D47AE8BF95A7BAC0D1633" style="traditional"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HD4C65BA681D649FE80C08FD4E5315DA6" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That the House of Representatives—</text>
 <paragraph id="H428C7DA5B48D4C28907ECD2EC1145248"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supports the designation of <quote>National Breast Cancer Awareness Month</quote> and the goals and ideals of that month; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HBF720D45B2494E15BEA1E6243E9925E4"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">encourages the people of the United States to observe the month with appropriate awareness and educational activities, and take steps to reduce their risk of breast cancer, including maintaining a healthy weight, exercising, limiting alcohol intake and menopausal hormones, and breastfeeding, if they can.</text>
			</paragraph></section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


