<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="H0490ea4a-5e0e-4b36-8fe6-e9487dbcfbd8" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Reported-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HRES 212 RH: Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 1560) to improve cybersecurity in the United States through enhanced sharing of information about cybersecurity threats, and for other purposes, and providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 1731) to amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to enhance multi-directional sharing of information related to cybersecurity risks and strengthen privacy and civil liberties protections, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<calendar display="yes">House Calendar No. 24</calendar>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 212</legis-num>
		<associated-doc display="yes" role="report">[Report No. 114–88]</associated-doc>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20150421">April 21, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><cosponsor name-id="">Mr. Collins of Georgia</cosponsor>, from the <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Committee on Rules</committee-name>, reported the following resolution; which was referred to the House Calendar and ordered to be
			 printed</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 1560) to improve cybersecurity in the United States
			 through enhanced sharing of information about cybersecurity threats, and
			 for other purposes, and providing for consideration of the bill (H.R.
			 1731) to amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to enhance
			 multi-directional sharing of information related to cybersecurity risks
			 and strengthen privacy and civil liberties protections, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<resolution-body id="Hdfbfefcd-513e-4d64-99d4-9e9381998192" style="traditional">
 <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="Hf5d1b46f-949a-4836-94fd-577d21a9f829" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That at any time after adoption of this resolution the Speaker may, pursuant to clause 2(b) of rule XVIII, declare the House resolved into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for consideration of the bill (H.R. 1560) to improve cybersecurity in the United States through enhanced sharing of information about cybersecurity threats, and for other purposes. The first reading of the bill shall be dispensed with. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived. General debate shall be confined to the bill and shall not exceed one hour equally divided and controlled by the chair and ranking minority member of the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence. After general debate the bill shall be considered for amendment under the five-minute rule. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence now printed in the bill. The committee amendment in the nature of a substitute shall be considered as read. All points of order against the committee amendment in the nature of a substitute are waived. No amendment to the committee amendment in the nature of a substitute shall be in order except those printed in part A of the report of the Committee on Rules accompanying this resolution. Each such amendment may be offered only in the order printed in the report, may be offered only by a Member designated in the report, shall be considered as read, shall be debatable for the time specified in the report equally divided and controlled by the proponent and an opponent, shall not be subject to amendment, and shall not be subject to a demand for division of the question in the House or in the Committee of the Whole. All points of order against such amendments are waived. At the conclusion of consideration of the bill for amendment the Committee shall rise and report the bill to the House with such amendments as may have been adopted. Any Member may demand a separate vote in the House on any amendment adopted in the Committee of the Whole to the bill or to the committee amendment in the nature of a substitute. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the bill and amendments thereto to final passage without intervening motion except one motion to recommit with or without instructions.</text>
 </section><section id="HF1F205ED386F4A2EB8896A2E9C748E84"><enum>2.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At any time after adoption of this resolution the Speaker may, pursuant to clause 2(b) of rule XVIII, declare the House resolved into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for consideration of the bill (H.R. 1731) to amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to enhance multi-directional sharing of information related to cybersecurity risks and strengthen privacy and civil liberties protections, and for other purposes. The first reading of the bill shall be dispensed with. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived. General debate shall be confined to the bill and amendments specified in this section and shall not exceed one hour equally divided and controlled by the chair and ranking minority member of the Committee on Homeland Security. After general debate the bill shall be considered for amendment under the five-minute rule. In lieu of the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Homeland Security now printed in the bill, it shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule an amendment in the nature of a substitute consisting of the text of Rules Committee Print 114-12. That amendment in the nature of a substitute shall be considered as read. All points of order against that amendment in the nature of a substitute are waived. No amendment to that amendment in the nature of a substitute shall be in order except those printed in part B of the report of the Committee on Rules accompanying this resolution. Each such amendment may be offered only in the order printed in the report, may be offered only by a Member designated in the report, shall be considered as read, shall be debatable for the time specified in the report equally divided and controlled by the proponent and an opponent, shall not be subject to amendment, and shall not be subject to a demand for division of the question in the House or in the Committee of the Whole. All points of order against such amendments are waived. At the conclusion of consideration of the bill for amendment the Committee shall rise and report the bill to the House with such amendments as may have been adopted. Any Member may demand a separate vote in the House on any amendment adopted in the Committee of the Whole to the bill or to the amendment in the nature of a substitute made in order as original text. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the bill and amendments thereto to final passage without intervening motion except one motion to recommit with or without instructions.</text>
		</section><section id="H1B3A75497E9041E5B43E37E726EF5789"><enum>3.</enum>
 <subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H0E7028B7CB724149AB7CC308040D5958"><enum>(a)</enum><text>In the engrossment of H.R. 1560 the Clerk shall—</text> <paragraph id="H6803AE5AE1504C13A1842778E6FC6755"><enum>(1)</enum><text>add the text of H.R. 1731, as passed by the House, as new matter at the end of H.R. 1560;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3BC01C104D8E4DF9B3D56428E251A681"><enum>(2)</enum><text>conform the title of H.R. 1560 to reflect the addition of H.R. 1731, as passed by the House, to the engrossment;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD9558B39C6494ACAAE3D2A0D7DB88EB5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>assign appropriate designations to provisions within the engrossment; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6DEBB59E91624F5096AFC572EDE29D21"><enum>(4)</enum><text>conform cross-references and provisions for short titles within the engrossment.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9AEA31B7238344CC822AD67FBCBBCEBC"><enum>(b)</enum><text>Upon the addition of the text of H.R. 1731, as passed by the House, to the engrossment of H.R. 1560, H.R. 1731 shall be laid on the table.</text>
			</subsection></section></resolution-body>
	<endorsement><action-date>April 21, 2015</action-date><action-desc>Referred to the House Calendar and ordered to be
			 printed</action-desc></endorsement></resolution>


