<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="H5F0E705308A64D2E9BEF92A9BF8D8F1B" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HRES 170 IH: Recognizing the National Association of Letter Carriers’ One Day Food Drive.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. RES. 170</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action display="yes"> 
<action-date date="20150324">March 24, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000462">Mr. Tiberi</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000266">Mr. Chabot</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000295">Mr. Joyce</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000577">Mr. Ryan of Ohio</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">Recognizing the National Association of Letter Carriers’ One Day Food Drive.</official-title> 
</form> 
<preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the National Association of Letter Carriers (NALC) began their One Day Food Drive in 1992;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas for many years prior to 1992, a number of NALC branches collected food for the needy in the communities they served;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas in 1992, 10 cities were selected to explore a coordinated effort, and a pilot food drive was held in Columbus, Ohio, by Branch 78 of the NALC;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the pilot food drive was so successful that the food drive was then expanded nationwide;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas a nationwide One Day Food Drive was organized for May 15, 1993, with the goal of having at least one NALC Branch participate in each of the 50 States;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas more than 220 NALC branches participated in the first national One Day Food Drive and set a one-day record for food collection in the United States by collecting more than 11 million pounds of food;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas in 2014, the NALC collected nearly 73 million pounds of food to help restock food banks, pantries, and shelters throughout the United States;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas 2014 marked the 11th consecutive year that the One Day Food Drive collected more than 70 million pounds of food;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the NALC One Day Food Drive has collected more than 1.3 billion pounds of food since it began in 1992; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the NALC One Day Food Drive occurs on the second Saturday in May each year: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble> 
<resolution-body style="traditional" id="H3F95B21A2C8D495CB0665717CC563E68"> 
<section id="H96A809354A5E43D1B1ABFB2A3DDF3895" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="H966A9B121C4E48F8B1CB101AF34DD715"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes the National Association of Letter Carriers’ One Day Food Drive; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEBB1A513CD2847EEB5513B6650EA7758"><enum>(2)</enum><text>honors the National Association of Letter Carriers for their distinguished community service and philanthropic efforts.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body> </resolution> 

