<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="HC193D5D8D7034B38A042232DF00E6E4F" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HRES 205 IH: Congratulating the administration, staff, students, and alumni of Roosevelt University on the occasion of the University’s 70th anniversary.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 205</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20150415">April 15, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="R000515">Mr. Rush</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Danny K. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000535">Mr. Gutiérrez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000622">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000454">Mr. Foster</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000563">Mr. Lipinski</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000378">Mr. Kinzinger of Illinois</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Congratulating the administration, staff, students, and alumni of Roosevelt University on the
			 occasion of the University’s 70th anniversary.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
 <whereas><text>Whereas, on April 17, 2015, Roosevelt University, located in Chicago, Illinois, will celebrate the 70th anniversary of the founding of the University on April 17, 1945;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Roosevelt University has graduated more than 95,000 students who have become leaders in their professions and careers, including Chicago’s first African-American mayor, Harold Washington;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Roosevelt University was founded at a time when most American universities and colleges did not enroll large numbers of minority or immigrant students;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Roosevelt University became one of the Nation’s first colleges to admit all qualified students, regardless of race, religion, or national origin;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas throughout its history, Roosevelt University has always remained true to the values of inclusiveness, opportunity, and social justice; and</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas today, Roosevelt remains one of the most diverse universities in the Midwest: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body id="HA81193032C8B483D8F4377378B43BC06" style="traditional">
 <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H5994EDC470B24AABA827D941038374E8" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="HB6072C6436EB428BBDAFF995586373C5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">congratulates the administration, staff, students, and alumni of Roosevelt University on the occasion of the University’s 70th anniversary; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0B4B44C018FB44E490F65F721D6B1518"><enum>(2)</enum><text>wishes the entire Roosevelt community many years of continued success in the future.</text> </paragraph></section></resolution-body> </resolution> 

