<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="H9E3C3913EB8E4870BD17EA8D689FCDAD" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HRES 246 IH: Honoring the vital role of small business and the passion of entrepreneurs in the United States during “National Small Business Week”, beginning on May 4, through May 8, 2015.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 246</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20150501">May 1, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001097">Mr. Cárdenas</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000565">Mr. Gosar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000515">Mr. Rush</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001245">Ms. Bordallo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000911">Ms. Brown of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001286">Mrs. Bustos</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson of Indiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000215">Ms. Eshoo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000293">Ms. Esty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000636">Mr. Hinojosa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001191">Ms. Sinema</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000560">Mr. Larsen of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000376">Mr. Kelly of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000578">Mr. LaMalfa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000470">Mr. Tipton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000474">Mrs. Torres</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000454">Mr. Foster</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000018">Mr. Salmon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001148">Mr. Simpson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001191">Mr. Murphy of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001084">Mr. Cicilline</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Al Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001294">Mr. Blum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000599">Mr. Ruiz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000580">Ms. Michelle Lujan Grisham of New Mexico</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Judy Chu of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001101">Ms. Clark of Massachusetts</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSM00">Committee on Small Business</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Honoring the vital role of small business and the passion of entrepreneurs in the United States
			 during <quote>National Small Business Week</quote>, beginning on May 4, through May 8, 2015.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
 <whereas><text>Whereas this year marks the 52nd anniversary of <quote>National Small Business Week</quote> and has been endorsed by every President since 1963;</text> </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas approximately 28,000,000 small businesses in the United States, comprising the leading force behind the United States economy, create nearly 7 out of every 10 new jobs and generate close to 50 percent of the Nation’s nonfarm gross domestic product;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas small firms account for 63 percent of the net new jobs created between 1993 and mid-2013, and 60 percent of the net new jobs created since the end of the recession;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 22,000,000 small businesses are nonemployer sole proprietorship firms;</text> </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 2,450,000 veterans are small business owners and account for 9.1 percent of all United States businesses;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the share of total businesses owned by women continues to increase, currently including over 7,800,000 small businesses;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas small businesses employ 48.5 percent of the country’s private sector workforce;</text> </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas small businesses represent 37 percent of high-tech employment;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas small businesses produce 16 times more patents per employee than large patenting firms;</text> </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas small businesses represent 98 percent of all exporters and produce 33 percent of exported goods;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on July 30, 1953, Congress created the Small Business Administration to aid, counsel, assist, and protect the interests of small businesses by working to preserve free and competitive enterprise, to ensure that a fair proportion of the total sales of government property are made to small businesses, and to maintain and strengthen the overall economy of the United States;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, for more than 50 years, the Small Business Administration has helped over 10,000,000 entrepreneurs reach the American dream of creating and maintaining a small business, and has played a key role in fostering local and national economic growth; and</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the President has designated the week beginning on May 4, 2015, as <quote>National Small Business Week</quote>: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble> <resolution-body id="H6199D1791D45447EAAAFE75366C77D0F" style="traditional"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H2AAD6E16BBED44F1B0DC482DE81864FF" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That the House of Representatives—</text>
 <paragraph id="H3DB4255C7AED4077B17743F9649E7FD8"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">honors the vital role of small business and entrepreneurs in the United States during <quote>National Small Business Week</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H26812D13C6B941D582657ABA36202D4F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>supports the designation of <quote>National Small Business Week</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H58A05EEA56A046448E42576AAA7228FB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recognizes the important role of the Small Business Administration as a valuable resource for the United States entrepreneur;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5E776A8082A1432EB0C1479E09F400F4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>supports and encourages young entrepreneurs to pursue their passions and create more start-up businesses;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HABD2F9221F65461F8989ABD3F43B67C9"><enum>(5)</enum><text>recognizes the importance of creating policies that promote a business friendly environment for small business owners free of unnecessary and burdensome regulations and red tape;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H000556AC7BF44C3EB3B02CC4468D4F89"><enum>(6)</enum><text>recognizes the National Small Business Person of the Year and the National Lender of the Year; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8A473D2DACF346F797738A63A69ED0B9"><enum>(7)</enum><text>supports efforts to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H6B57565952484A169BDA5356CA6640B4"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">encourage consumers to shop locally; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H97B8837AA1B64D9F9C0E5A87541D2B82"><enum>(B)</enum><text>increase awareness of the value of locally owned small businesses and the impact of locally owned small business on the economy of the United States.</text>
				</subparagraph></paragraph></section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


