<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="HE30EF7E6120D446C91B06AAE6D16CB6C" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HRES 215 IH: Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that any comprehensive plan to reform our national energy policy must promote the sustainable use of renewable and alternative energy sources; increase our domestic refining capacity; promote conservation and increased energy efficiency; expand research and development, including domestic onshore and offshore exploration; and enhance consumer education.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 215</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20150421">April 21, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000566">Mr. Latta</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that any comprehensive plan to reform our
			 national energy policy must promote the sustainable use of renewable and
			 alternative energy sources; increase our domestic refining capacity;
			 promote conservation and increased energy efficiency; expand research and
			 development, including domestic onshore and offshore exploration; and
			 enhance consumer education.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
 <whereas><text>Whereas the United States consumes roughly an average of 19,050,000 barrels of oil per day;</text> </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the global average of daily oil consumption stands at 92,000,000 barrels of oil per day;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States total annual energy consumption is approximately 97.5 quadrillion BTU, with the global total annual energy consumption at 520 quadrillion BTU;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States has greatly increased domestic oil production over the last decade leading to net imports of petroleum decreasing to 27 percent, the lowest number since 1985;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States has seen natural gas reserves and production exceed all estimates and due to this is expected to be a net exporter of natural gas by 2016;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States has abundant coal reserves, including a demonstrated reserve base estimated to contain 480 billion short tons, and processes such as gasification and liquefaction offer cleaner alternatives for utilizing this resource;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas renewable sources of energy account for 9.3 quadrillion BTU per year in the United States; and</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas such sources such as biomass, geothermal, hydropower, nuclear, solar, and wind need and deserve our attention and the necessary resources to encourage their commercial viability: Now, therefore, be it</text>
		</whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body id="H013C82A20B2345F285672F2ECA587D64" style="traditional">
 <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H1EE107DE909348BF93414E901DDF900C" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That it is the sense of the House of Representatives that in order to meet our Nation’s growing long-term energy demands and maintain our economic viability in the world marketplace, the following must be addressed in any comprehensive and economically viable energy bill considered by the 114th Congress:</text>
 <paragraph id="HBC9147487DF447D8A973C7892D44E16C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Taking advantage of our abundant domestic coal supply.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H1CDEAF8238E4424AA0AD9BF88F4C9078"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Using recent technological innovations to exploit our vast supply of natural gas.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H929C88DF15204B4297026A72CCBABA2C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Increasing our domestic oil production, infrastructure, and refining capacity.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H9213DF1565F547BBADDFDC59E9C9F14C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Expanding use of renewable and alternative energy sources.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB4D6E349D99C4FC4816E470582613D38"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Exploring and investing in advanced nuclear reactor technologies.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H1AAFFE225D7146F18E377A1DCA2522B6"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Reflecting the discoveries of light sweet crude in the United States, which has exceeded what was predicted even 5 years ago, and evaluating the capacity and market for extracting and refining this natural resource.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H21D9A2B4A98A4F4EA966C2EA20ED1677"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Promoting and providing incentives for an increase in conservation and energy efficiency.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H81EFBA1AFFA0453798F72C1D078FB792"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Expanding and promoting additional research and development through new and innovative methods such as public-private partnerships.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFC4F826AFFA04066BEC40BC04F8DEC1D"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Enhancing consumer awareness and education regarding methods to increase energy efficiency and available alternative fuel sources to reduce our dependence on Middle Eastern oil and provide American energy security.</text>
			</paragraph></section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


