<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="H95B2F15E0C024B379CA180B210517E8A" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HRES 228 IH: Expressing support for the designation of May 7, 2015, as a “National Day of Reason” and recognizing the importance of reason in the betterment of humanity.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 228</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20150429">April 29, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001034">Mr. Honda</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of May 7, 2015, as a <quote>National Day of Reason</quote> and recognizing the importance of reason in the betterment of humanity.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
 <whereas><text>Whereas the application of reason has proven to offer hope for human survival upon Earth, improving conditions within the universe, and cultivating intelligent, moral, and ethical interactions among people and their environments;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas those who wrote the Constitution of the United States, the basic document for governing the affairs of humankind within the United States, based it upon principles delineated within the philosophies distinguishing the historical Age of Reason;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas most citizens of the United States purport to value reason and its application;</text> </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas it is the duty and responsibility of every citizen to promote the development and application of reason; and</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas May 7, 2015, would be an appropriate date to designate as a <quote>National Day of Reason</quote>: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body id="HD9AA2F0F4EDA425F94927280D6122EDF" style="traditional">
 <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HFBB20C1AD5204470AB0A91828F889C75" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="H3043CD8C0DD149AD9CA0684FFB84C5C5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supports the designation of <quote>National Day of Reason</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H61C0F9C688594C77BA8CA00844CD6A11"><enum>(2)</enum><text>encourages all citizens, residents, and visitors to join in observing this day and focusing upon the employment of reason, critical thought, the scientific method, and free inquiry to the resolution of human problems and for the welfare of human kind.</text>
			</paragraph></section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


