<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="HAC463BE06C7D4E19A484215FC9106F33" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HRES 485 IH: Expressing solidarity with the people of Israel in the wake of recent terrorist attacks and condemning the Palestinian Authority for inciting an atmosphere of violence.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-10-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 485</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20151021">October 21, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001197">Ms. McSally</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="B001293">Mr. Bishop of Michigan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000615">Mr. Duncan of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001094">Mr. Cook</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001106">Mr. Costello of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000174">Mr. Sam Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000290">Ms. Jenkins of Kansas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000605">Mr. Perry</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000564">Mr. Lamborn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001289">Mr. Byrne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000591">Mr. Tom Price of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000377">Ms. Granger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000018">Mr. Salmon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000813">Mrs. Walorski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000621">Mr. DeSantis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Z000018">Mr. Zinke</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001105">Mrs. Comstock</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000291">Mrs. Ellmers of North Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000613">Mr. Dold</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001183">Mr. Schweikert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001269">Mr. Barletta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000448">Mr. Franks of Arizona</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000578">Mr. LaMalfa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001107">Mr. Curbelo of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000603">Mr. Rouzer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001243">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001255">Mr. Boustany</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000564">Mr. Gibson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000611">Mr. Poliquin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001190">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000604">Mr. Dent</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001196">Ms. Stefanik</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000601">Mr. Ratcliffe</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000129">Mr. Valadao</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000604">Mr. Russell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000625">Mr. Donovan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000565">Mr. Gosar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000820">Mrs. Mimi Walters of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000584">Mrs. Love</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000386">Mr. Katko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001045">Mr. Crenshaw</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001193">Mr. MacArthur</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Expressing solidarity with the people of Israel in the wake of recent terrorist attacks and
			 condemning the Palestinian Authority for inciting an atmosphere of
			 violence.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
 <whereas><text>Whereas the United States is the single largest donor to the Palestinians, having committed over $5,000,000,000 in bilateral assistance with the aims of preventing terrorism against Israel from Hamas and other military organizations; fostering stability, prosperity, and self-governance in the West Bank; and meeting humanitarian needs;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Palestinian Authority makes payments to terrorists who are in Israeli jails;</text> </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Oslo II Agreement specifically details that Israel and the Palestinian Authority shall <quote>abstain from incitement, including hostile propaganda, against each other and, without derogating from the principle of freedom of expression, shall take legal measures to prevent such incitement by any organizations, groups or individuals within their jurisdiction</quote>;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas no aid is permitted for a power-sharing Palestinian Authority government that includes Hamas as a member, or that results from an agreement with Hamas and over which Hamas exercises <quote>undue influence</quote> unless the President certifies that the Palestinian Authority government, including all ministers, has <quote>publicly accepted and is complying with</quote> conditions that they recognize the Jewish state of Israel’s right to exist and accept previous Israeli-Palestinian agreements;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Fatah and Hamas agreed to the June 2014 formation of a consensus Palestinian Authority government;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Hamas retains de facto control over the Gaza Strip;</text> </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Palestinian Authority President Mahmoud Abbas said in September 2015 that <quote>Each drop of blood that was spilled in Jerusalem is pure blood as long as it’s for the sake of Allah. Every shahid (martyr) will be in heaven and every wounded person will be rewarded, by Allah’s will.</quote>;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on October 14, 2015, President Mahmoud Abbas falsely accused the Government of Israel of executing a Palestinian boy, who is alive and recovering in an Israeli hospital after he stabbed an innocent Israeli citizen and was hit by an automobile, thus continuing to incite violence against innocent Israelis; and</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas seven people have been killed and dozens have been wounded in several terrorist attacks against Israelis committed by Palestinians from September 13, 2015, through October 14, 2015, including—</text>
 <paragraph id="H7216082677244619A0EB248E79AE874F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a September 13th attack on a personal vehicle in Jerusalem which resulted in the driver’s death;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC1FE3DEB742F4B17A6941858C29FD09F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an October 1st attack in Samaria where a rabbi and his wife were murdered in front of their four children;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1D577CFF905247389D9EBE95EAEF9547"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an October 3rd attack in Jerusalem where a young man was stabbed to death in front of his wife and child, who also suffered wounds;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEF19CE93EF904D60A3D0F38E25FB750C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>an October 4th attack in Jerusalem where a teenager was stabbed;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6B9F2B70BA5246169F12399688B0AE8D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>a series of attacks on October 7th involving a knife attack at a shopping mall, an attack on a woman driving her car in Tekoa, a stabbing in the Old City of Jerusalem, and an attack on an Israeli Defense Forces (IDF) soldier near Tel Aviv;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H247BB90B7603470289ED2834AC634302"><enum>(6)</enum><text>a series of attacks on October 8th involving a stabbing of a female IDF soldier and three others in Tel Aviv, a stabbing in Jerusalem, a stabbing near Hebron, and a stabbing of an IDF soldier near Galilee;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1A06E93F7018495C8D8700E6CD8E3AFD"><enum>(7)</enum><text>a series of attacks on October 9th involving 5 children wounded by rocks, a boy beaten and stabbed in Jerusalem, a police officer who was stabbed near Hebron, and a woman whose car was attacked near Jerusalem;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H004313663CEC48618476A1F331F0834C"><enum>(8)</enum><text>a series of attacks on October 10th involving 2 elderly men who were stabbed in Jerusalem, 2 police officers who were stabbed in Jerusalem, a bus driver who was injured in Jerusalem, and a woman who was injured while driving south of Jerusalem;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6AAFBAD711504F19A5AB8715E50F124D"><enum>(9)</enum><text>a series of attacks on October 11th involving a police officer who was injured when an explosive device was detonated during a traffic stop, and four people, including a girl celebrating her 15th birthday, who were injured when a terrorist rammed his car into the victims and proceeded to stab them;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H25DCBBF855A14A369F5ADF49BDDC1E95"><enum>(10)</enum><text>a series of attacks on October 12th involving a stabbing in Jerusalem, a border policeman who was stabbed in Jerusalem, a man and a 13-year-old boy who were stabbed in Jerusalem, and a soldier who was stabbed on a bus in Jerusalem;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4C3BFBABF3B8461C8AE35A1BEF8A7F99"><enum>(11)</enum><text>a series of attacks on October 13th involving the stabbing of five people north of Tel Aviv, a shooting and stabbing on a bus in Jerusalem, and the stabbing and shooting of 5 people, including a rabbi, in Jerusalem; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF89C2577897E41E19DE496D6C8C2F387"><enum>(12)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a series of attacks in Jerusalem on October 14th involving a woman who was stabbed at a bus station and a terrorist who attacked armed guards: Now, therefore, be it</text></paragraph></whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body id="H5DE77DB7A4E2406DB17D2A56132146D1" style="traditional">
 <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H63AEBF9CE9C94C0EB57FC6810443967F" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="H8D42EBD73F2C425AA42B4DAB6443111D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>expresses support for the recent terrorism victims and their families in Israel, the people of Israel, and the Government of Israel;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9E8E61DE94854ED9BD8237B1A409F7C2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>condemns terrorism committed under the auspices of the Palestinian Authority;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H824B9320D5DB47009054AA388F95635B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>calls on Palestinian leaders to cease supporting, justifying, inciting, or allowing terrorist activities in Israel;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE685291BAE8948469E29A86F5CDC76AA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>urges the President of the United States to emphatically condemn the attacks carried out against innocent Israelis and freeze all United States funding to the Palestinian Authority until their leaders openly increase efforts to end their incitement of violence;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2A8D02164CBD485B9E4A25C4F7828D86"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is concerned about the use of national security waivers to continue supplying aid to the Palestinian Authority; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H940EEEAEA46149EEAD88C8AFC4F5FC10"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">demands, as a condition of continued United States aid consistent with section 620K of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2378b">22 U.S.C. 2378b</external-xref>), as added by the Palestinian Anti-Terrorism Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/109/449">Public Law 109–449</external-xref>; 120 Stat. 3318), that the President re-certify that the Palestinian Authority government, including all ministers, has publicly accepted and is complying with the principles of such section 620K, which demand the recognition of Israel’s right to exist and the acceptance of previous Israeli-Palestinian agreements.</text>
			</paragraph></section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


