<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="H8F097507C4DA44459E81D8C9E6CACF05" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HRES 541 IH: Expressing support for designation of June 2016 as “National Gun Violence Awareness Month”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-11-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 541</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20151130">November 30, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000053">Mr. Rangel</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="J000294">Mr. Jeffries</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Expressing support for designation of June 2016 as <quote>National Gun Violence Awareness Month</quote>.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
 <whereas><text>Whereas annually on average 32,514 people die from gun violence;</text> </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas annually on average over 108,000 people including 17,000 children in the United States are shot in murders, assaults, suicides and suicide attempts, unintentional shootings, or by police intervention;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas annually on average 2,677 children die from gun violence;</text> </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas on average 31 people in the United States are murdered with guns every day and 151 are treated for a gun assault in an emergency room;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 1 in 3 people in the United States know someone who has been shot;</text> </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas every day on average 55 people kill themselves with a firearm, and 46 people are shot or killed in an accident with a gun;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States firearm homicide rate is 20 times higher than the combined rates of 22 countries that are our peers in wealth and population;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas a gun in the home is 22 times more likely to be used to kill or injure in a domestic homicide, suicide, or unintentional shooting than to be used in self-defense; and</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas June 2016 would be an appropriate month to designate as <quote>National Gun Violence Awareness Month</quote>: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble> <resolution-body id="H3F68D8CEE27A45E2991C27928594854B" style="traditional"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HC24FE9D9BAA24AC6BCC05A1D94AC8A10" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That the House of Representatives—</text>
 <paragraph id="H3957D5E6D3A740B8B67D9E926B7E0AFE"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supports the designation of <quote>National Gun Violence Awareness Month</quote> and the goals and ideals of that month; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HAB528FDC474243EB80F36507EC1C3467"><enum>(2)</enum><text>calls on the people of the United States to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H23A9A1AC5D9E4D0EA015096BFDB6AD6F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>promote greater awareness about gun violence and gun safety;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE3B966C66C244D83A2C10E2C6594AC86"><enum>(B)</enum><text>concentrate annual heightened attention to gun violence during the summer months, when gun violence typically increases; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA641326E465B4E78B99E020A119CE0E8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>bring citizens and community leaders together to discuss ways to make the communities safer.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></section></resolution-body> </resolution> 

