<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="H3A44191F093B444D97AE18A0A6640BBF" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HRES 476 IH: Supporting the establishment of a national Children’s Bill of Rights.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-10-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 476</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20151009">October 9, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000535">Mr. Gutiérrez</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001270">Ms. Bass</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Judy Chu of California</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Supporting the establishment of a national Children’s Bill of Rights.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
 <whereas><text>Whereas all children and youth have the inalienable right to live in a just, safe, and supportive society; and</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas this right belongs to all children, regardless of gender, class, race, ethnicity, national origin, culture, religion, immigration status, sexual orientation, or ability: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body id="H395DBCC66EB94647924DF7B2B44965EB" style="traditional">
 <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H8FCA521B50A44694B0C5C36744B7C439" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">it is the sense of the House of Representatives that every child is entitled to—</text> <paragraph id="H2E71505CB6D5430E9056023602E728B6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>physical well-being, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H797BF00946F94AD4ACD9EC4F535B4979"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the right to be free from all forms of physical, psychological, or sexual abuse, neglect, and exploitation;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6499016AC87248E195491D14DE491089"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the right to have the child’s essential needs met, including nutritious food, safe and accessible shelter, clothing, health care, and accessible transportation;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAE62402EDBA44B97AE827D540F294723"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the right to a safe and healthy environment, including homes, schools, neighborhoods, and communities;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6AA027995E0B408C931380DC4E27E2A7"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the right to the care and protection of the State in which the child resides if there is no parent, legal guardian, or other caregiver willing and able to assume responsibility for the care and well-being of the child; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA4183D17D81E4666BA8B360C589FC512"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the right to receive appropriate medical treatment, and the right to access affordable health insurance coverage, including effective therapeutic interventions for behavioral health;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6425F925C57C460993A56FF3FE3FFDD0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>social and emotional well-being, including—</text> <subparagraph id="H2E9BB975FF25403C90D603C9B6BE7733"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the right to develop a healthy attachment to a parent, legal guardian, or caregiver, and the right to an ongoing relationship with a caring and supportive adult;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA8715B10A4F54C549146C47AC0B7DFBE"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the right to remain with a parent, legal guardian, or caregiver, except when authorities determine separation is in the best interest of the child;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEDEBC9B26D3D4A95B33AA9D1F813BAC1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the right to be reunited with a parent, legal guardian, or caregiver should separation occur, with priority given to keeping children with their family or with kin in a home setting, whenever it remains in the child’s best interest to do so;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFF95D6E5A1D44C4FBE79A68981635C2E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the right to maintain direct contact with parents on a regular basis when a child is separated from a parent, including cases in which a parent is incarcerated or detained, whenever it remains in the child’s best interest to do so;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDF49133AD1FA4A39B181C9FFBB6C5862"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the right to access sports and other extracurricular activities that support the child’s healthy social, emotional, and physical development;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAC3E1AE185D748A0AB4DBAC76CFB4893"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the right to a voice in matters that affect the child, and the right to participation in age-appropriate forums, including representation on youth councils and other decisionmaking bodies;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB7C29637DC414A338D405F40CA3A5B18"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the right to have the child’s best interest taken into consideration with regards to decisions that affect the child;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H687426187D3548059AA62091A828557D"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the right to have appropriate legal representation and a child advocate in legal proceedings to represent the interest of the child;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE167E35C3BA8456D9E0FB8AB8C76262B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the right to rehabilitative services and periodic review if detained or incarcerated as a juvenile; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4E5334E1FE45418D8164E3CB2F5A3026"><enum>(J)</enum><text>the right to have parents, elected officials, and other adults consider the effect that their decisions will have on a child’s care and community; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H01EF5DA6A0F74CBF92158F0FBBB9E885"><enum>(3)</enum><text>educational and life skills, including—</text> <subparagraph id="H27D2214F69934A0DB251EBCBA5851FFC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the right to a well-rounded, high-quality, and culturally competent education that promotes success in life and in future careers;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H17207B85EE914279A774014ED0E2C05B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the right to access educational services and supports necessary to accommodate the child’s needs;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H310E39EF9738418F9664BE57379A9049"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the right to a safe learning environment, and the right to be free from bullying;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEF1D7C61FD264C16BF1E2BCEEA5C508C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the right to an education that is sufficiently funded to provide the child with the tools and technology necessary for a successful learning experience;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA1796250DEC142B38511B609A592002A"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the right to be heard in age-appropriate ways on issues regarding the education of the child and to be represented on school boards and other decisionmaking bodies;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8F34944B84BF4196ACB4D061460DFCF2"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the right of access to training in life skills that will prepare the child to live independently and contribute to the child’s community; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF97D801715D644D4A20CA4ED6649A615"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the right to protections from unfair and unsafe labor practices in the workforce.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></section></resolution-body> </resolution> 

