<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="H00ED9A4C9FAE42FFA6AA354AC96F53B6" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HRES 44 IH: Amending the Rules of the House of Representatives to permit Delegates and the Resident Commissioner to the Congress to cast votes in the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 44</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20150122">January 22, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="H000874">Mr. Hoyer</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Committee on Rules</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Amending the Rules of the House of Representatives to permit Delegates and the Resident
			 Commissioner to the Congress to cast votes in the Committee of the Whole
			 House on the state of the Union.</official-title>
	</form>
	<resolution-body id="H1841AAF960A54196A99A4349780E6E7F" style="OLC">
		<section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H26E308A8E54E4701867FAD49D81AD4CB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Voting by Delegates and Resident Commissioner in Committee of the Whole</header>
 <subsection id="H4F487484E74140A196B50EFE29F8B5B3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Permitting Votes To be Cast</header><text>Clause 3(a) of rule III of the Rules of the House of Representatives is amended by inserting before the first sentence the following: <quote>In a Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union, each Delegate and the Resident Commissioner shall possess the same powers and privileges as Members of the House.</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1458C32F1FEE4CFEB6127A03F27C50D3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Appointment of Chair</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The first sentence of clause 1 of rule XVIII of the Rules of the House of Representatives is amended by striking <quote>Member</quote> and inserting <quote>Member, Delegate, or the Resident Commissioner</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7B4D30B6F7E44B6587DF95C9F249DEFA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Repeating of Certain Votes</header><text>Clause 6 of rule XVIII of the Rules of the House of Representatives is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEDBC5971F7C547148D501A841747856E" style="traditional">
 <subsection id="H5C43544175114E4AADBB5051E1701F92"><enum>(h)</enum><text>Whenever a recorded vote on any question has been decided by a margin within which the votes cast by the Delegates and the Resident Commissioner have been decisive, the Committee of the Whole shall rise and the Speaker shall put such question de novo without intervening motion. Upon the announcement of the vote on that question, the Committee of the Whole shall resume its sitting without intervening motion.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


