<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="HB1BADD4D7BAE43A698C3E43438F233EE" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HRES 415 IH: Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that regular order should be restored in the House and Senate.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-09-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 415</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20150910">September 10, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000127">Mr. Nolan</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Committee on Rules</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that regular order should be restored in the
			 House and Senate.</official-title>
	</form>
	<resolution-body id="H8E00E33F87A0411E9BDA05B1DB941099" style="OLC">
 <section id="H25C307C1CE2B45CC8497AFA5E973583F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Requiring regular order in the House and Senate</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of the House of Representatives that—</text> <paragraph id="H6A58082E2F9C45C6AC5855A042E3FFAB"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">it should not be in order to consider a bill or resolution in the House unless each committee to which the bill or resolution is referred—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H57E930E4EE0243EEA3FF59D5C6F2FF72"><enum>(A)</enum><text>had a hearing on the bill or resolution at which amendments were permitted to be offered and debated and a vote was taken on each amendment offered and on final passage, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF9532B795E244AFA9165FC9DB064CDB3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>filed a report with respect to the bill or resolution;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD30080386D8F4823BB6737BBA3E9E204"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a conference report should not be filed in the House unless—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H0958D772111F436E8C0F16FD16F21E87"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the conference committee held at least 3 meetings in which all members of the conference committee were allowed to be present,</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1CDF33C75E4B4D35B9FF4B975B6FE375"><enum>(B)</enum><text>all items of difference between the House and Senate were addressed, voted on, and resolved by the full conference committee membership, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7610BC765B0A43D3B95D9F0A65B05097"><enum>(C)</enum><text>printed or electronic copies of the conference report and the accompanying joint explanatory statement were available to Members and Delegates for at least 48 hours prior to filing;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA7F78A4A38FB4616B140DCC8CCC2B2C7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the House and Senate should schedule simultaneous 5-day work weeks in Washington and district work periods; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD8F8505E729948B4B8D19CACE514CB26"><enum>(4)</enum><text>every bill brought to committee should be open to amendment and every bill brought to the floor of the House for a vote should be considered under an open rule.</text>
			</paragraph></section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


