<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="H61FA726F668C4DC6828D466BDFA2C804" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HRES 467 IH: Establishing the Select Committee on Gun Violence Prevention.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-10-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 467</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20151008">October 8, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="E000293">Ms. Esty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000043">Mr. Fattah</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000179">Mrs. Napolitano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000127">Mr. Nolan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000593">Mr. Perlmutter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000523">Mr. Price of North Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000602">Miss Rice of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000185">Mr. Scott of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001175">Ms. Speier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000197">Ms. Pelosi</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Committee on Rules</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Establishing the Select Committee on Gun Violence Prevention.</official-title>
	</form>
	<resolution-body id="HF9E5B3451E4E403280040458624485F7" style="OLC">
 <section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H621B946658DD44A9BCF3CE25A3CC46D3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is hereby established the Select Committee on Gun Violence Prevention (hereafter referred to as the <quote>Select Committee</quote>).</text>
		</section><section id="H63870B07E3FB4B98A299297B0AAF232D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Composition</header>
 <subsection id="H350F8029D5524158A59764490A7677D6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Composition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Select Committee shall be composed of 12 Members appointed by the Speaker, of whom 6 shall be appointed after consultation with the Minority Leader.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H38F839FF06E5489FBDF47A0A292680D9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Chair and Ranking Minority Member</header><text>The Speaker shall designate one Member to serve as chair of the Select Committee, and the Minority Leader shall designate one Member to serve as ranking minority member of the Select Committee.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H11B4D7CABD8A4198BA35625C928F77BE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Vacancies</header><text>Any vacancy in the Select Committee shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment.</text> </subsection></section><section id="HC4FFC49E9FAA418CA89C1286DE5B7E1D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Duties</header> <subsection id="H2C1C811D08AA49D8ABE19E17724FBEFA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Investigation and Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Select Committee is authorized and directed to conduct a full and complete investigation and study, and to issue a report of its findings to the House, regarding each of the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H8C76F131473C44D5B2BB7CC8FE8CE221"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The causes of mass shootings.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2C322D1358664A2B82652D7BDA071367"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Methods to improve the Federal firearms purchaser background check system.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAB59DF199CDB4A33A6D6B371980EBE7B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Connections between access to firearms and dangerously mentally ill individuals.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H9B1FCA3E989A48CA9D797E7630013258"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Strengthening Federal penalties for trafficking and straw purchasing of firearms.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEE9360777DD848C59C84C9735FE21219"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Closing loopholes that allow some domestic abusers continued access to firearms.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H396D662EDCA1465FAED0D3EAB5282E89"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Linkages between firearms and suicide.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H846B8E38052A4431B1664544824F08BF"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Gun violence’s effect on public health.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD020BF0827F64CEABB8D1EEAED130BDC"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The correlation between State gun violence prevention laws and the incidence of gun violence.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4F12E2A8E95B4F2DAF26446065D7149C"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The importance of having reliable and accurate information on gun violence and its toll on our Nation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5A2281D9F76046638B7F3D8DD720E564"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The implementation of effective gun violence prevention laws in accordance with the Second Amendment to the Constitution.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H05FCE9DE288046B5816E438DBFA2A1CA"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Rates of gun violence in large metropolitan areas.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H01DBFADDB15441678454DB75A669B3C5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Hearings</header><text>In carrying out its duties under subsection (a), the Select Committee shall hold at least one public hearing in the District of Columbia and at least two public hearings in locations outside of the District of Columbia.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H0F768ECFC0CC4B3CBC28C3F76B336349"><enum>4.</enum><header>Rules and procedures</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Rule XI of the Rules of the House of Representatives shall apply to the Select Committee in the same manner as such rule applies to a standing committee of the House, except to the extent inconsistent with this resolution.</text>
		</section><section id="HA16222D400094D059CC49973270F8D22"><enum>5.</enum><header>Staff; funding</header>
 <subsection id="HF4B0D62347134B6AAFD8A87ED6C3DA50"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Staff</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The chair of the Select Committee, upon consultation with the ranking minority member of the Select Committee, may employ and fix the compensation of such staff as the chair considers necessary to carry out this resolution.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H518AA62200AB4F3AAE5087B919249BC3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There shall be paid out of the applicable accounts of the House of Representatives such sums as may be necessary for the expenses of the Select Committee. Such payments shall be made on vouchers signed by the chair of the Select Committee and approved in the manner directed by the Committee on House Administration. Amounts made available under this subsection shall be expended in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Committee on House Administration.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HA745F7B71F774E5E934D830A4BBEEEC1"><enum>6.</enum><header>Recommendations</header>
 <subsection id="H5160712CA25646D0A4657291DAB3F420"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Final Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Select Committee shall issue a final report and recommendations, including legislative proposals, not later than 60 days after the date of the adoption of this resolution.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC3BBDAC5E03841FBA7ACBED0C72AEDF6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Interim Findings and Reports</header><text>In addition to the final report and recommendations required under subsection (a), the Select Committee may issue such interim findings and reports as it deems necessary.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H1215F25016A94713A4F75D0D02ED9980" indent="down1"><enum>7.</enum><header>Termination</header>
 <subsection id="HA47DB5FC72FE409F95A61A02966A61E9" indent="up1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Select Committee and all authority granted in this resolution shall expire upon the issuance by the Select Committee of the final report and recommendations under section 6(a).</text>
 </subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDDBE79BD14CF446EA94A2F8F62133B8B" indent="up1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Records</header><text>Upon the dissolution of the Select Committee, the records, files, and materials of the Select Committee shall be transferred to the Clerk of the House.</text>
			</subsection></section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


