<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="HAA9FA620647D47588F38A4FBDAD36949" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HRES 225 IH: Recognizing the 40th anniversary of the Fall of Saigon on April 30, 1975.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 225</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20150428">April 28, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000579">Mr. Lowenthal</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001097">Mr. Cárdenas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Judy Chu of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000598">Mrs. Davis of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000404">Mr. McDermott</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000030">Ms. Loretta Sanchez of California</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Recognizing the 40th anniversary of the Fall of Saigon on April 30, 1975.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
 <whereas><text>Whereas since 1975, hundreds of thousands of Vietnamese have resettled in the United States and built vibrant communities across the United States which contribute to the rich diversity of the Nation;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on April 30, 1975, the Republic of Vietnam was overthrown by communist forces in an event known as “Black April” or the “Fall of Saigon”, which is observed in Vietnamese American communities across the United States each year;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas members of the South Vietnamese military fought side-by-side with the United States Armed Forces in defense of the ideals of democracy and freedom;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Vietnamese Americans have continuously advocated for freedom and democracy in Vietnam, and spoken out against human rights abuses by the Vietnamese Government; and</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Vietnam continues to hold one of the worst records on human rights in the region, violating religious freedom, obstructing press freedom, restricting its own citizens’ freedom of speech and assembly, and detaining prisoners of conscience: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body id="H157DF75AC7074703985DF17126098674" style="traditional">
 <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HC2D7FF73D59642A8A99A6EDA9311B325" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="HE3E0E80551BA4381B2ED891720F18789"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognizes the significance of the 40th anniversary of the Fall of Saigon on April 30, 1975;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD78F03CD394C46CCAF67E359023EF8C7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>honors the contributions of Vietnamese Americans to the United States over the last 40 years and their tireless commitment to upholding freedom, human rights, and democracy in Vietnam;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3BE7D0EDA3614349802706139F36BD92"><enum>(3)</enum><text>honors the service of members of the United States Armed Forces and of the South Vietnamese forces who fought in Vietnam, including those who gave their lives;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4BC5D1E566184F5B81CB931A4656C496"><enum>(4)</enum><text>honors the memory of the Vietnamese who lost their lives while attempting to flee Vietnam; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HED0015B75C6640CBB5A01575DB1DFC95"><enum>(5)</enum><text>encourages all citizens of the United States to join in remembering the Fall of Saigon, honoring the contributions of the Vietnamese American community, and calling for freedom, human rights, and democracy in Vietnam.</text>
			</paragraph></section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


