<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="HAD8DF3DBF8F64864ADB09D9B2FC5677F" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HRES 515 IH: Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives regarding the importance of civic education and civic involvement programs in the elementary and secondary schools of the United States.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-11-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 515</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20151104">November 4, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000593">Mr. Ross</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="G000575">Ms. Graham</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives regarding the importance of civic education
			 and civic involvement programs in the elementary and secondary schools of
			 the United States.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
 <whereas><text>Whereas civic education, democratic engagement, governmental and constitutional knowledge, and social service in the United States are on the decline;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas in past decades, civic education was a prominent component of the curriculum in our Nation’s schools; and</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the advancement of civic education, democratic engagement, governmental and constitutional knowledge, and social service are essential for the future health and welfare of the United States: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body id="H8A131792E7014FDDB6D395BD1EE05C9E" style="traditional">
 <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H98B4B53E34B24C26B97E63F5DA040191" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That it is the sense of the House of Representatives that—</text> <paragraph id="HD6E382DAF4044544BA14D2D5A3DE9BE8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>civic education, democratic engagement, governmental and constitutional knowledge, and social service are necessary to motivate and inspire future leaders of the United States;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE72FB4D2E13D4A1E85FD1B56313F70A0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>elementary and secondary schools in the United States are encouraged to offer courses promoting civic education, democratic engagement, governmental and constitutional knowledge, and social service such as civics, government, economics, geography, history, and American history;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H657EC7FE7CA6446DA49EBB23EE35CEC8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>elementary and secondary schools in the United States are encouraged to integrate civic education, democratic engagement, governmental and constitutional knowledge, and social service in electives such as art, English language arts, music, mathematics, and science;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7DEA097E206749BA9BF65A1A7975413F"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in order to measure students’ basic civic knowledge, secondary schools in the United States are encouraged to administer a test to seniors based on the official list of 100 civics questions and answers published and used by the Secretary of Homeland Security for purposes of administering the civics test component of naturalization examinations; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H590EFB0BDD5245B39843A927A0F2E9C4"><enum>(5)</enum><text>elementary and secondary schools in the United States are encouraged to promote civic participation and social service, at Federal, State, and local levels, and encourage such participation from students and families.</text>
			</paragraph></section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


