<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="HF3FF84A4ADC34993B2BB8ED43AC8A6E1" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HRES 300 IH: On the passing of Joseph Robinette Biden, III.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-06-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 300</legis-num>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20150604">June 4, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001083">Mr. Carney</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">On the passing of Joseph Robinette Biden, III.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
 <whereas><text>Whereas Joseph Robinette <quote>Beau</quote> Biden, III, born in Wilmington, Delaware and a graduate of the University of Pennsylvania and Syracuse University law school, served our country as an attorney in the Department of Justice for seven years, including assisting the nation of Kosovo in rebuilding their criminal justice system;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Beau Biden served his beloved State of Delaware for eight years as Attorney General;</text> </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Beau Biden joined the Army in 2003 at the age of 34, rose to the rank of major in the Delaware Army National Guard’s Judge Advocate General Corps, deployed to Iraq in 2008 and received the Bronze Star for his service;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Beau Biden leaves behind a beloved wife, Hallie, and two children, Natalie and Hunter; and</text> </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Beau Biden was the eldest son of the former Senator from Delaware and current Vice President of the United States and President of the United States Senate, Joseph Robinette Biden, Jr.: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body id="H5910F702FE0647429C26C08FCB3920DA" style="multiple-resolved-clause">
 <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HAE3ADC4191A2449589C0E02045FCCFC5" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives has heard with profound sorrow and deep regret the announcement of the untimely death of Joseph Robinette Biden, III.</text>
 </section><section id="H42FF41BCF5A24CE89DD769FB2F035FC7" section-type="resolved"><text>That the Clerk of the House of Representatives communicate this resolution to the Senate and transmit a copy thereof to the family of the Vice President of the United States.</text>
		</section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


