<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="H8065496CD30D47B1AAE35A91D1A4AB1F" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HRES 164 IH: Recognizing Dr. Elmira Mangum as the first female president of Florida Agricultural &amp; Mechanical University.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 164</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20150323">March 23, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="H000324">Mr. Hastings</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B000911">Ms. Brown of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001066">Ms. Castor of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000610">Mr. Deutch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000435">Ms. Ros-Lehtinen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000689">Mr. Mica</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000185">Mr. Nugent</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Recognizing Dr. Elmira Mangum as the first female president of Florida Agricultural &amp; Mechanical University.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
 <whereas><text>Whereas Florida Agricultural &amp; Mechanical University (FAMU) was founded on October 3, 1887, as the State Normal College for Colored Students at Tallahassee with 15 students and 2 instructors;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas FAMU was established as an 1890 land-grant institution dedicated to the advancement of knowledge, resolution of complex issues, and the empowerment of citizens and communities;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the institution has gone by 3 other names prior to becoming Florida Agricultural &amp; Mechanical University (FAMU) in 1953, and remains the only historically black university in the 12-member State University System of Florida;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas FAMU students have a legacy of social involvement, including the boycott of Tallahassee buses that successfully integrated the city’s public transportation system;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas FAMU now boasts approximately 11,000 students and 700 faculty members, and has had 10 men serve as presidents during the institution’s 127-year history;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Dr. Elmira Mangum has a 28-year history as a higher education administrator, ranging from the University of Wisconsin-Madison and the University of Buffalo to the University of North Carolina-Chapel Hill and Cornell University;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Dr. Mangum holds a Master’s in Public Policy and Public Administration, a Master’s in Urban and Regional Planning, and a Ph.D. in Educational Leadership and Policy;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Dr. Mangum has taught higher education administration, leadership theory and practice, and financial management;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Dr. Mangum was in the inaugural class of the Millennium Leadership Institute, attended the Harvard Graduate School of Education Management Development Program, and Cornell’s Administrative Management Institute;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Dr. Mangum is a life member of the National Council of Negro Women and Zeta Phi Beta Sorority, Inc., a historically black Greek-lettered organization that promotes scholarship, sisterly love, service, and finer womanhood;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Dr. Mangum was selected as the first permanent female president in the 127-year history of FAMU;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Dr. Mangum has made tremendous strides to advance the legacy of FAMU with forward thinking plans, such as her Sustainability Initiative, which will provide research-based solutions to the world’s socio-economic and environmental problems, and strengthening FAMU’s STEM programs, which are the hallmark of academia;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Dr. Mangum has consistently articulated resourceful, innovative ideas for Black college survival; and</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas our Nation must remain committed to celebrating the accomplishments and advancements of women: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body id="H0DD80FE186E549B6BE2FFB98A01C4F12" style="traditional">
 <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H363785FD6ED649E88040035CE0F5B9C7" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="H870FDC7A6A2D4772BAA77B46F3020ABD"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognizes Dr. Elmira Mangum for being selected as the first female permanent president of Florida Agricultural &amp; Mechanical University;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H508710FC51B54C9AAD88020EF8E4EE86"><enum>(2)</enum><text>acknowledges the significance of Florida Agricultural &amp; Mechanical University in the history of Historically Black Colleges and Universities and the civil rights movement; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8A953FD4C65E45F5AE1E28AE3431EBC9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>emphasizes the importance of celebrating the accomplishments of trailblazers across the country, such as Dr. Elmira Mangum.</text>
			</paragraph></section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


