<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="HC72257C20E1946BDAE5B35048D1CF6E7" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HRES 123 IH: Expressing support for designation of August 6 as National Voting Rights Day.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 123</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20150224">February 24, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="H000324">Mr. Hastings</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="T000473">Mr. Takai</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000381">Mr. Kilmer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000053">Mr. Rangel</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000800">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000610">Mr. Deutch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001227">Mr. Brady of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000490">Mr. Bishop of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001191">Mr. Murphy of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000187">Ms. Maxine Waters of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001286">Mrs. Bustos</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson of Indiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001034">Mr. Honda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000480">Ms. Slaughter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000263">Mr. Levin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000510">Mr. Smith of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Al Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000185">Mr. Scott of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000911">Ms. Brown of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000984">Mr. Cummings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000455">Ms. Fudge</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000062">Mr. Yarmuth</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001066">Ms. Castor of Florida</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Expressing support for designation of August 6 as National Voting Rights Day.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
 <whereas><text>Whereas the landmark Voting Rights Act was signed into law by President Lyndon B. Johnson on August 6, 1965;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Voting Rights Act is arguably the Nation’s most important law for removing race-based restrictions on voting and has stood as an essential safeguard against racial discrimination in our political system since its inception;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas prior to its passage, African-Americans were often systematically prevented from voting by tactics such as literacy tests, poll taxes, the grandfather clause, and intimidation and violence;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas in response a violent backlash sparked by efforts to register Black voters in the Deep South in the 1960s, the Johnson Administration proposed the enactment of a voting rights law which provided for direct Federal intervention to uphold the guarantees of the fifteenth amendment;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Voting Rights Act was enacted in 1965 to rectify years of disenfranchisement of African-American voters by prohibiting States from imposing qualifications or practices to deny access to the ballot on account of race, permitted direct Federal intervention in the electoral process in certain places based on a specific formula, and required preclearance of new laws in covered States to ensure that they did not have the purpose or effect of limiting the ability to vote on account of race;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas following enactment of this critically important legislation, Black voter registration and participation increased dramatically;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Voting Rights Act has had a significant impact on electoral dynamics by vastly expanding the number of African-American, Hispanic, and women elected officials on both a local and national level;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the recent Supreme Court decision in Shelby County v. Holder and State laws that place restrictions on voters have dealt a heavy blow to voter protections nationwide;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas although progress has undoubtedly been made in the 49 years since the Voting Rights Act was passed, sadly, discrimination continues to exist; and</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Nation must remain committed to the fight to create an open and transparent electoral process for all United States citizens: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body id="HDF3B459AEC614EC6953B4C21536788A0" style="traditional">
 <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H07CEFFCD60E44D4FAC8C6DA5A45E7E62" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="HCD3A054E3EA9407FB4B61A6A1F37B7CF"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supports the designation of <quote>National Voting Rights Day</quote> in commemoration of the upcoming 50th anniversary of the enactment of the Voting Rights Act of 1965;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H513BEA71693645A38C6B5BCB3DD10EF8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>acknowledges the significance of the Voting Rights Act with regard to enforcing the civil rights of all United States citizens; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB4923863EE794626A52590DD869F4A2F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>emphasizes the importance of ensuring the ability of all United States citizens to fully participate in the electoral process.</text>
			</paragraph></section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


