<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="HDD12FFCBBAB34DEF915935FE650E3608" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HRES 384 IH: Calling for a formal end of the Korean War.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 384</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20150727">July 27, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000053">Mr. Rangel</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="J000174">Mr. Sam Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Veterans’ Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Calling for a formal end of the Korean War.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
 <whereas><text>Whereas the Korean War broke out on June 25, 1950, and active combat ceased with the Armistice Agreement signed on July 27, 1953;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Armistice Agreement did not formally end the war, so the Korean War remains one of the world’s longest ongoing armed conflicts;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Korean War was a global conflict that involved not only South Korea and North Korea, but also the United States along with more than 20 other nations, which altogether suffered hundreds of thousands casualties and losses, including millions of civilians killed and wounded;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 2015 marks the 70th anniversary of Korea’s independence after Imperial Japan surrendered to the United States during World War II on August 15, 1945; and</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas peaceful unification of Korea is desired by all Korean people: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble> <resolution-body id="H5675386CBED24B809254B0F5280523FE" style="traditional"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H307F6BED99E24F349D64682CC5F6B3A3" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That the House of Representatives—</text>
 <paragraph id="H931E13650DDB410E87D1051F754682E5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">pays tribute to the sacrifices of the Veterans of the Korean War, its victims and divided families; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC6E1D6D44AB74ADD869414D07552A9A3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>calls upon the international community to support the vision of a unified Korea and assist efforts to promote international peace and security, denuclearization, economic prosperity, human rights, and the rule of law both on the Korean Peninsula and elsewhere.</text>
			</paragraph></section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


