<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="H4D588C80CE9348CE9E53F59D207590F9" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HRES 222 IH: Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that any resolution to the Israeli-Palestinian conflict should come from direct bilateral negotiations without preconditions and without interference from the United Nations.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 222</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20150428">April 28, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001180">Mr. McKinley</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000564">Mr. Lamborn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="J000292">Mr. Johnson of Ohio</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that any resolution to the Israeli-Palestinian
			 conflict should come from direct bilateral negotiations without
			 preconditions and without interference from the United Nations.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
 <whereas><text>Whereas it has been longstanding policy of the United States under both Democratic and Republican Administrations and Congresses that a durable resolution to the Israeli-Palestinian conflict can be achieved only through direct negotiations between two parties without preconditions;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas it has been longstanding policy of the United States under both Democratic and Republican Administrations and Congresses to promote a resolution to the Israeli-Palestinian conflict through direct negotiations between the two parties;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas both Democratic and Republican-led Congresses have long appropriated funds to promote a resolution to the Israeli-Palestinian conflict through direct negotiations between the two parties;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas it has been the longstanding policy of the United States under both Democratic and Republican Administrations and Congresses that a United Nations mandate to force a final status agreement to the Israeli-Palestinian peace process is harmful and not appropriate; and</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas this Congress would view any support by the United States Government for a United Nations effort to dictate conditions, details, or timelines for negotiations and a resolution between Israel and the Palestinian Authority as a violation of long-standing and sound United States policy: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body id="HD531885ECDA54C50987E12EBAF37450B" style="traditional">
 <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HDC6B6BCB56704EB6BF2E0C9A010341AF" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That it is the sense of the United States House of Representatives that a resolution to the Israeli-Palestinian conflict should come from direct bilateral negotiations without preconditions and without interference from the United Nations.</text>
		</section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


