<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="HF71E945FD2FE414788D145AE7C8B32FE" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HRES 364 IH: Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the Fédération Internationale de Football Association should immediately eliminate gender pay inequity and treat all athletes with the same respect and dignity.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 364</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20150715">July 15, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001156">Ms. Linda T. Sánchez of California</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S001175">Ms. Speier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000290">Ms. Edwards</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001036">Mrs. Capps</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000216">Ms. DeLauro</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001066">Ms. Castor of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001101">Ms. Clark of Massachusetts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000480">Ms. Slaughter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000610">Mr. Deutch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001286">Mrs. Bustos</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson of Indiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000622">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000288">Mr. Ellison</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Judy Chu of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000062">Mr. Yarmuth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001034">Mr. Honda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000580">Ms. Michelle Lujan Grisham of New Mexico</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000287">Mr. Lewis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000096">Mr. Pascrell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000030">Mr. Farr</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000128">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Ted Lieu of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000380">Mr. Kildee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000911">Ms. Brown of Florida</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="I000057">Mr. Israel</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the Fédération Internationale de Football
			 Association should immediately eliminate gender pay inequity and treat all
			 athletes with the same respect and dignity.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
 <whereas><text>Whereas the Fédération Internationale de Football Association (referred to in this preamble as <quote>FIFA</quote>) awarded $576,000,000 to the 32 teams that competed in the 2014 Men's World Cup, but only awarded $15,000,000 to the 24 teams that competed in the 2015 Women's World Cup;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas FIFA awarded $35,000,000 to the team that won the 2014 Men's World Cup, but only awarded $2,000,000 to the team that won the 2015 Women’s World Cup;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas FIFA awarded $6,000,000 more in prizes to each team that lost in the first round of the 2014 Men's World Cup than to the team that won the 2015 Women's World Cup;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas FIFA awarded $420,000,000 to the 32 teams that competed in the 2010 Men’s World Cup, but only awarded $10,000,000 to the 24 teams that competed in the 2011 Women’s World Cup;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas FIFA awarded $31,000,000 to the team that won the 2010 Men's World Cup, but only awarded $1,000,000 to the team that won the 2011 Women's World Cup;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the 2015 Women’s World Cup Final had more than 25,000,000 viewers in the United States, making it more widely viewed than the Major League Baseball World Series or the National Basketball Association Finals;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the 2015 Women’s World Cup highlighted the need to eliminate the existing gender pay disparity in prize award structure in athletic competitions that has persisted for decades;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the unfair and unjust prize award allocation system used by FIFA sends a terrible message to women and girls around the world about the value of their contribution to sports;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2007, Wimbledon finally implemented an equal prize payment structure for all athletes, regardless of gender; and</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas gender should not determine the amount of a prize award that a person or team receives in an athletic competition: Now, therefore, be it</text>
		</whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body id="HEB27861DAC2A4B01AFFA7A1BE403BEB2" style="traditional">
 <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HEFF0A49884E947F081127ABD5D9DE840" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="H62CA094D4CCC4AEE8B4B7580301BEAA2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>urges the Fédération Internationale de Football Association to immediately eliminate gender pay inequity and to treat all athletes with the respect and dignity those athletes deserve;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC74A815A2C6846A78F21433FD932522F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>supports an end to the unfair and unjust practice of gender pay inequity in the workplace, including athletic competitions and related prize awards;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H780051CCD866485296A53E483C398D41"><enum>(3)</enum><text>urges all other local, State, Federal, and international organizations to eliminate gender pay inequity; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5C225B2745734587B1FC5A31B3CC1C29"><enum>(4)</enum><text>instructs the Secretary of the House of Representatives to submit a copy of this resolution to the President of the Fédération Internationale de Football Association.</text>
			</paragraph></section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


