<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="H3474D8B051EB4B7B89DF905A384D10C7" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HRES 214 IH: Supporting efforts to ensure that students have access to debt-free higher education.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 214</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20150421">April 21, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="E000288">Mr. Ellison</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001101">Ms. Clark of Massachusetts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="I000057">Mr. Israel</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000574">Mr. Gallego</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001034">Mr. Honda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000556">Mr. Grayson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Judy Chu of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000128">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000290">Ms. Edwards</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000984">Mr. Cummings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Ted Lieu of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000535">Mr. Gutiérrez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000191">Mr. DeFazio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000404">Mr. McDermott</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000053">Mr. Rangel</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001063">Ms. Hahn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000187">Ms. Maxine Waters of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000598">Mr. Polis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000370">Ms. Adams</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000800">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001049">Mr. Clay</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell of California</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Supporting efforts to ensure that students have access to debt-free higher education.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
 <whereas><text>Whereas the economic competitiveness of the United States in the global economy requires a well-educated workforce;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas current and future young people in the United States should have the same opportunity offered to those who went to college in previous generations, including the ability to attend State colleges and universities without taking on burdensome debt;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2015, higher education is more important than ever because it is an essential step to entering and remaining in the middle class;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, because of the importance of higher education, the United States should expand the opportunity to pursue and attain higher education to more people than had that opportunity in the past;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas public investment in higher education pays off, as evidenced by the fact that workers with college degrees earn more money, pay more taxes, and rely less on government services; and</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas student loan debt saddles the very students who most depend on a college degree to level the economic playing field with a burden that—</text>
 <paragraph id="id1A1837BF18D54B108F9B2EB3BDB21061"><enum>(1)</enum><text>constrains the career choices and hurts the credit rating of the students;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idC927ACCC461243CABC09D52E23DFD86A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>prevents people from fully participating in the economy by purchasing goods and services; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id3A19CA4C766142C48E59D9852BDF31D0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>threatens essential milestones of the American dream, including the purchase of a home or car, starting a family, and saving for retirement: Now, therefore, be it</text>
			</paragraph></whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body id="H00A3E5A5EEA6447F81BC167039C88FD3" style="traditional">
 <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H29CE7F8EAC504F089B275CE8E7714186" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That the House of Representatives supports efforts—</text> <paragraph id="HBB7D3E1F3183446CA337621BA7BAE03A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to ensure that through a combination of efforts all students have access to debt-free higher education, defined to mean having no debt upon graduation from all public institutions of higher education;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEE9DF159EE5D43FD8DD1F9A5E526672C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to provide support to States so States can make increased investments in higher education that will result in lower tuition and costs for students;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDA6417CB05A1440991D6C2E4E75F2DD7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to increase financial aid to students to help them afford the total cost of college attendance without taking on debt;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF3989A338EB14CAB83395F6BFDC81461"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to encourage innovation by States and institutions of higher education to cut costs for students and make college more affordable by increasing efficiency and enabling speedy and less-costly degree completion; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1C6D8A36CFBF4D38852020020132F39D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to reduce the burden of existing student loan debt.</text> </paragraph></section></resolution-body> </resolution> 

