<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="H42354B91164F45888FBF6EAB99746F34" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HRES 224 IH: Expressing support for designation of April 2015 as “National Congenital Diaphragmatic Hernia Awareness Month”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 224</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20150428">April 28, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001065">Mr. Holding</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Expressing support for designation of April 2015 as <quote>National Congenital Diaphragmatic Hernia Awareness Month</quote>.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
 <whereas><text>Whereas congenital diaphragmatic hernia (referred to in this preamble as <quote>CDH</quote>) occurs when the diaphragm fails to fully form, allowing abdominal organs to migrate into the chest cavity and preventing lung growth;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention recognizes CDH as a birth defect;</text> </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the majority of CDH patients suffer from underdeveloped lungs or poor pulmonary function;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas babies born with CDH endure extended hospital stays in intensive care with multiple surgeries;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas CDH patients often endure long-term complications, such as pulmonary hypertension, pulmonary hypoplasia, asthma, gastrointestinal reflex, feeding disorders, and developmental delays;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas CDH survivors sometimes endure long-term mechanical ventilation dependency, skeletal malformations, supplemental oxygen dependency, enteral and parenteral nutrition, and hypoxic brain injury;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas CDH is treated through mechanical ventilation, a heart and lung bypass (commonly known as <quote>extracorporeal membrane oxygenation</quote>), machines, and surgical repair;</text> </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas surgical repair is often not a permanent solution for CDH and can lead to reherniation and require additional surgery;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas CDH is diagnosed in utero in less than 50 percent of cases;</text> </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas infants born with CDH have a high mortality rate, ranging from 20 to 60 percent, depending on the severity of the defect and interventions available at delivery;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas CDH has a rate of occurrence of 1 in every 3,800 live births worldwide;</text> </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas CDH affects approximately 1,088 babies each year in the United States;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas CDH has affected more than 700,000 babies worldwide since 2000;</text> </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas CDH does not discriminate based on race, gender, or socioeconomic status;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the cause of CDH is unknown;</text> </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the average CDH survivor will face postnatal care of at least $100,000;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Federal support for CDH research at the National Institutes of Health for 2014 is estimated to be not more than $2,500,000; and</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas April 2015 would be an appropriate month to designate as <quote>National Congenital Diaphragmatic Hernia Awareness Month</quote>: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble> <resolution-body id="HA3638E6F300744458ABFAE5370DE3986" style="traditional"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HF5FF8D0F070F4AA69FC5B38F0DA1B06C" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That the House of Representatives—</text>
 <paragraph id="H06259FA36E494918B3B8F4274936CB40"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the designation of <quote>National Congenital Diaphragmatic Hernia Awareness Month</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4BA81F46B9ED4CF98351650199D68DCA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>encourages that steps should be taken to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H5BBE180EE8844F949953FD55340FD1ED"><enum>(A)</enum><text>raise awareness of and increase public knowledge about congenital diaphragmatic hernia (referred to in this resolution as <quote>CDH</quote>);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC6D267FF13024B7794FDBD8A10B52566"><enum>(B)</enum><text>inform all Americans about the dangers of CDH, especially those groups that may be disproportionately affected by CDH or have lower survival rates;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6DE5897F362E47E4A7F394DA33B5B09D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>disseminate information on the importance of quality neonatal care of CDH patients;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8CD7F6BDB26D4B4A8A06ADFBA0C7EBB9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>promote quality prenatal care and ultrasounds to detect CDH in utero; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF74F9952DD724EB4921545EE56E720D2"><enum>(E)</enum><text>support research funding of CDH to—</text> <clause id="H7830CF0AF97949C8B687972E2A947DBD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>improve screening and treatment for CDH;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HADF11BEA8D04483D9ECBF1D21F0711DD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>discover the causes of CDH; and</text> </clause><clause id="HBBAC103043BF4542AA4828B3DA628B1F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>develop a cure for CDH; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3F46A0ACF1934855BEF7146F2012E59E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>calls on the people of the United States, interest groups, and affected persons to—</text> <subparagraph id="HCF1D2A069D7740B2831457064AC112E2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>promote awareness of CDH;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB092A17B1FB34AF084D24E634CFD0E2A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>take an active role in the fight against this devastating birth defect; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD094A3D66A804E318051FF1EEEEB8AA1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>observe National Congenital Diaphragmatic Hernia Awareness Month with appropriate ceremonies and activities.</text>
				</subparagraph></paragraph></section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


