<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="HB9B381C1F7944536B68AD7EF9BA9C681" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HRES 376 IH: To refer H.R. 3133, a bill making congressional reference to the United States Court of Federal Claims pursuant to sections 1492 and 2509 of title 28, United States Code, of certain Indian land-related takings claims of the Grand Traverse Band of Ottawa and Chippewa Indians of Michigan and its individual members.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 376</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20150723">July 23, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001271">Mr. Benishek</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To refer H.R. 3133, a bill making congressional reference to the United States Court of Federal
			 Claims pursuant to sections 1492 and 2509 of title 28, United States Code,
			 of certain Indian land-related takings claims of the Grand Traverse Band
			 of Ottawa and Chippewa Indians of Michigan and its individual members.</official-title>
	</form>
	<resolution-body id="HA6B093A70179464FAABB26CBCEFE1B4B" style="traditional">
 <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H7FF2ECF83FB847AFAE4D00672A9760AA" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That pursuant to section 1492 of title 28, United States Code, the bill (H.R. 3133), entitled <quote>A Bill relating to certain Indian land-related takings claims of the Grand Traverse Band of Ottawa and Chippewa Indians of Michigan and its individual members,</quote> now pending in the House of Representatives, is referred to the chief judge of the United States Court of Federal Claims for a determination as to whether the Band, on behalf of itself and of its individual members, has legal or equitable claims for just compensation against the United States for land-related takings occurring during the period between 1855 and 1900 within the areas reserved for the Band and its members by Article 1 of the July 31, 1855, Treaty with the Ottawa and Chippewa, 11 Stat. 621.</text>
		</section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


