<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="HA0D7CFEA155C41E98C0FF7361C388E22" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HRES 64 IH: Recognizing January 2015 as “National Mentoring Month”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 64</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20150128">January 28, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="B001270">Ms. Bass</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000911">Ms. Brown of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001097">Mr. Cárdenas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson of Indiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001066">Ms. Castor of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000598">Mrs. Davis of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Danny K. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000043">Mr. Fattah</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000455">Ms. Fudge</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Al Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000559">Mr. Langevin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000565">Mr. Loebsack</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000593">Mr. Perlmutter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001150">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000467">Mr. Thompson of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000465">Ms. Tsongas</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Recognizing January 2015 as <quote>National Mentoring Month</quote>.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
 <whereas><text>Whereas in 2002, the Harvard School of Public Health and MENTOR: the National Mentoring Partnership created National Mentoring Month;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the goals of National Mentoring Month are to raise awareness of mentoring, recruit individuals to mentor, and encourage organizations to engage and integrate quality in mentoring into their efforts;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas a mentor is a caring, consistent presence who devotes time to a young person to help that young person discover personal strength and achieve their potential through a structured and trusting relationship;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas quality mentoring encourages positive choices, promotes self-esteem, supports academic achievement and introduces young people to new ideas;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas mentoring programs have shown to be effective in combating school violence and discipline problems, substance abuse, incarceration and truancy;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas research shows that young people who were at risk for not completing high school but who had a mentor were 55 percent more likely to be enrolled in college, 81 percent more likely to report participating regularly in sports or extracurricular activities, more than twice as likely to say they held a leadership position in a club or sports team, and 78 percent more likely to volunteer regularly in their communities;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas youth development experts agree that mentoring is critical to the social, emotional, and cognitive development of youth, helping them navigate the path to adulthood more successfully;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas mentors help young people set career goals and use their personal contacts to help young people meet industry professionals and find jobs;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas mentoring is a proven cost-effective investment: for every $1 invested in mentoring, there is a $3 return to society;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas all of the above listed benefits serve to link youth to economic opportunity while also strengthening the fiber of our communities; and</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas despite these benefits, 1 in 3 youth will reach age 19 without a mentor, constituting a <quote>mentoring gap</quote> that demonstrates a need for collaboration and resources: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble> <resolution-body id="HDABC0AB6532F4C0BBBC7A97984883E6E" style="traditional"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HD825DDC44148454A868C9FF0DAB37CCB" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That the House of Representatives—</text>
 <paragraph id="H222D7050A7294137BF9C692915D0ACB1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognizes <quote>National Mentoring Month</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE604AC66C580449088B70BEABEAF46FC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the men and women who serve as staff and volunteers at quality mentoring programs and help our young people find inner strength and reach their full potential;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC755E870941440FBBFDA7D2CA139C701"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">acknowledges that mentoring is beneficial because it encourages educational achievement, reduces juvenile delinquency, improves life outcomes, and strengthens communities;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H258C6A73E6234D61815655AC5AAFB2AB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>promotes the creation and expansion of quality mentoring programs across the United States to equip young people with the tools needed to lead healthy and productive lives; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H64DC1829D051463A8AA84B3539CCD776"><enum>(5)</enum><text>supports initiatives to close the <quote>mentoring gap</quote>.</text> </paragraph></section></resolution-body> </resolution> 

