<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="H2D02A4EAE28D4D56A950FF85704B800D" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HRES 573 IH: Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the President has failed to adequately develop and execute a strategy capable of defeating the Islamic State of Iraq and Syria and a significant course correction is necessary at this time to ensure the protection of the people of the United States and United States allies.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-12-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 573</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20151218">December 18, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000601">Mr. Ratcliffe</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the President has failed to adequately
			 develop and execute a strategy capable of defeating the Islamic State of
			 Iraq and Syria and a significant course correction is necessary at this
			 time to ensure the protection of the people of the United States and
			 United States allies.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
 <whereas><text>Whereas the Islamic State of Iraq and Syria (ISIS) continues to plan and promote attacks against the United States homeland;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas approximately 30,000 people from more than 100 countries have traveled to Syria and Iraq in order to join ISIS and other groups;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas roughly 4,500 individuals from Western countries and more than 250 Americans have traveled or attempted to travel to Syria and Iraq;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas there have been more than twice as many ISIS-inspired terror plots against the West in 2015 than in 2014;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States faces the threat of United States citizens being radicalized abroad and returning to the United States to carry out a terrorist attack;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas ISIS has launched waves of attacks throughout the Middle East, North Africa, and South Asia;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas ISIS has further expanded its ability to inspire and direct terrorist attacks against targets in North America, Europe, and the Asia-Pacific region;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas an ISIS-inspired terrorist stabbed two counterterrorism officers near Melbourne, Australia, on September 23, 2014;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas a Canadian citizen inspired by ISIS rammed a car into two soldiers near Montreal, Canada, on October 20, 2014;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas ISIS took responsibility for inspiring a United States citizen to attempt to attack four police officers with a hatchet in New York City on October 23, 2014;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas an Australian citizen, claiming to be acting on behalf of ISIS, took 17 hostages in Sydney, Australia, on December 15, 2014;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the three assailants in the attack on the Charlie Hebdo newspaper and Hypercacher Jewish Market in Paris, France, on January 7 to 9, 2015, declared allegiance to ISIS and Al-Qaeda in the Arabian Peninsula;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas a Danish citizen, allegedly inspired by ISIS, killed two civilians and injured five police officers on February 15, 2015;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas radicalized individuals inspired by ISIS attempted to attack a Prophet Muhammad cartoon contest in Garland, Texas, on May 3, 2015;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas ISIS-inspired assailants killed more than 130 people and wounded 369 more in Paris, France, on November 14 and 15, 2015; and</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States and its allies will continue to be threatened by terrorist attacks until ISIS and its affiliates are completely destroyed: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body id="HEFB3440AB7F548D288EDF39A7F6B938A" style="traditional">
 <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H72A7FE0B5D094944858A4EAA5A69C5B3" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives collectively believes the President has failed to adequately develop and execute a strategy capable of defeating the Islamic State of Iraq and Syria and a significant course correction is necessary at this time to ensure the protection of the people of the United States and United States allies.</text>
		</section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


