<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="HB9B381C1F7944536B68AD7EF9BA9C681" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HRES 381 IH: To refer H.R. 3133, a bill making congressional reference to the United States Court of Federal Claims pursuant to sections 1492 and 2509 of title 28, United States Code, of certain Indian land-related takings claims of the Grand Traverse Band of Ottawa and Chippewa Indians of Michigan and its individual members.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 381</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20150727">July 27, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001271">Mr. Benishek</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To refer H.R. 3133, a bill making congressional reference to the United States Court of Federal
			 Claims pursuant to sections 1492 and 2509 of title 28, United States Code,
			 of certain Indian land-related takings claims of the Grand Traverse Band
			 of Ottawa and Chippewa Indians of Michigan and its individual members.</official-title>
	</form>
	<resolution-body id="HA6B093A70179464FAABB26CBCEFE1B4B" style="traditional">
 <section id="H177C98A8B9724008BABDC0CE9AD5B898" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Referral</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Pursuant to section 1492 of title 28, United States Code, the bill (H.R. 3133) entitled <quote>A Bill relating to certain Indian land-related takings claims of the Grand Traverse Band of Ottawa and Chippewa Indians of Michigan and its individual members,</quote> now pending in the House of Representatives, is referred to the chief judge of the United States Court of Federal Claims for a determination as to whether the Band, on behalf of itself and of its individual members, has legal or equitable claims for just compensation against the United States for land-related takings occurring during the period between 1855 and 1900 within the areas reserved for the Band and its members by Article 1 of the July 31, 1855, Treaty with the Ottawa and Chippewa, 11 Stat. 621.</text>
 </section><section id="HFF4969DF52C143C5BB18C928075EFF24"><enum>2.</enum><header>Proceeding and report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon receipt of the bill, the chief judge shall, notwithstanding the bar of any statute of limitations—</text>
 <paragraph id="H59B96419F404472DA32003B2003011AD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>proceed according to the provisions of sections 1492 and 2509 of title 28, United States Code; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC8B49A35409B416EBFF9D1C3A54EE3C6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>report back to the House of Representatives, at the earliest practicable date, providing findings of fact and conclusions of law that are sufficient to inform the Congress of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8C23BECFEC95437083026F4CC1585E33"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the nature, extent, and character of the legal or equitable claims of the Grand Traverse Band of Ottawa and Chippewa Indians of Michigan, on behalf of itself and of its individual members, for just compensation against the United States for land-related takings within the areas reserved for the Band and its members by Article 1 of the July 31, 1855, Treaty with the Ottawa and Chippewa, 11 Stat. 621;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB487872D63774656B119BFC7AE4968FD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>whether the Band has good cause for not having filed said claims with the Indian Claims Commission within the August 13, 1946, to August 13, 1951, limitations period established by the Indian Claims Commission Act of 1946, and accordingly has good cause to be excused from that limitations period;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8EF0E212DACA490587603C8859A75225"><enum>(C)</enum><text>whether any other statute of limitations bar is applicable to the Band’s claims; and if so, whether the Band has good cause to be excused from the operation of any such bar;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2D406A8DA9024770ACDCB360EEC81F6E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>whether the doctrine of laches is applicable to the Band’s claims; and if so, whether the Band has good cause to be excused from the operation of that doctrine; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9D7C491EBE0E470FBBA42BC59BA103D9"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amount of just compensation, if any, legally or equitably due from the United States to the Band, on behalf of itself and of its individual members.</text>
				</subparagraph></paragraph></section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


