<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="HC315C80C0AE44718B07F39EBF63C497F" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HRES 18 IH: Expressing support for designation of January 7, 2015, as “National Be Active at Work Day”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 18</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20150107">January 7, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000580">Ms. Michelle Lujan Grisham of New Mexico</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Expressing support for designation of January 7, 2015, as <quote>National Be Active at Work Day</quote>.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas><text>Whereas physical inactivity is a major contributor to the development of obesity, cardiovascular
			 disease, diabetes, and other chronic diseases;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas sitting for long periods of time at work is a risk factor for obesity, cardiovascular
			 disease, metabolic diseases, and other chronic conditions;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas less than 25 percent of jobs require physical activity and jobs that require primarily
			 sedentary work have become increasingly common;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas exercise performed outside of work does not fully counteract the negative impacts of
			 sitting all day;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas stair climbing burns calories at a high rate, enhances cardiovascular fitness, and promotes
			 healthy lungs;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas walking throughout the day improves cardiovascular health, lowers the risk of obesity, and
			 related diseases;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas stretching improves circulation, increases range of motion, and alleviates stress;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas individuals with physical disabilities can often participate in physical activity
			 throughout the work day with minor modifications;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas all of these activities generally require no special equipment and can be performed by most
			 people regardless of their fitness level;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas many people start the new year with resolutions to improve their health;</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas there is a growing effort to encourage people to make small changes in their lives to
			 improve their health; and</text>
		</whereas><whereas><text>Whereas January 7, 2015, would be an appropriate date to designate as <quote>National Be Active at Work Day</quote>: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body id="H11B1544FBCEA468AB525A5F40E536A73" style="traditional">
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HBA6C040F8CD14DD8BD374BF1949658B7" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That the House of Representatives—</text>
			<paragraph id="HC30AC429B8004E75A4DA8A5B5B01D2F2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supports the designation of <quote>National Be Active at Work Day</quote>; and</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H156705D231EF420E918F54AA360447BD"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">encourages the people of the United States to observe the day with the appropriate activities.</text>
			</paragraph></section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


