<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="H41DAA62E77AD4C25B3FCDB2E9855D6DE" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HRES 565 IH: Supporting the peace process in Colombia.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-12-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 565</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20151215">December 15, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000574">Mr. Gallego</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001289">Mr. Byrne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000287">Mr. Lewis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000030">Mr. Farr</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Supporting the peace process in Colombia.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
 <whereas><text>Whereas the Republic of Colombia is one of the United States strongest allies in the Western Hemisphere;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the peoples of the United States and Colombia share a history of friendship and a common commitment to peace and democratic values;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas peace negotiations between the Colombian Government and the Revolutionary Armed Forces of Colombia (FARC) are advancing, affording an opportunity to end the most enduring conflict in our hemisphere;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas according to Colombia’s National Center of Historical Memory, over 6,000,000 people have been internally displaced and more than 220,000 killed over the course of the conflict, 80 percent of them civilians;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Colombians of all walks of life have suffered as a result of the violence, which has included massacres, kidnappings, assassinations, sexual violence, extrajudicial executions, use of landmines, recruitment of child soldiers, forced disappearances, and forced displacement;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas minority groups, including the Afro-Colombian, indigenous and rural communities, as well as women, have been disproportionately harmed by the conflict; and</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas successfully negotiating an end to the Colombian conflict will positively contribute to regional stability and promote United States policy goals in the Western Hemisphere by strengthening the rule of law, democracy, and human rights in Colombia: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body id="H988759DBFFD7494D95C2C4458BC1CA5A" style="traditional">
 <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H059318B18822474292C9511466AE7FF6" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="HCA6FEB37F1E7454CA0F536473649BD16"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognizes the importance of the ongoing negotiations between the Colombian government and the FARC;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9519CCF0964A4A89A6E72CBEDC35F1E6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>commends Colombian President Juan Manuel Santos, who has demonstrated vision and leadership in effectively seeking a negotiated settlement to end the conflict and lay the foundations for a sustainable peace;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB1D1280439844B7780A1FF70C326AC47"><enum>(3)</enum><text>calls on the negotiating parties to fully address the just demands of victims of violence for truth, justice, meaningful reparations and guarantees that the violence of the past will not be repeated; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4D11387AD91F468C9CDAE99058E73860"><enum>(4)</enum><text>urges President Barack Obama and his Administration to continue to vigorously support these negotiations and to develop plans to support the Colombian people in building a just and lasting peace.</text>
			</paragraph></section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


