<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="H2AC330DA96BB4AE0AC9BE670C83ADEAC" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HRES 453 IH: Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the United States Government should provide additional relief and assistance to the island of Dominica.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-09-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 453</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20150930">September 30, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000610">Ms. Plaskett</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000179">Mr. Engel</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000187">Ms. Maxine Waters of California</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the United States Government should
			 provide additional relief and assistance to the island of Dominica.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
 <whereas><text>Whereas Tropical Storm Erika brought calamitous flooding, damage, and wreaked havoc to the island of Dominica on August 27, 2015;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Tropical Storm Erika sustained winds of 50 mph and gusts up to 65 mph and dumped over 15 inches (38 centimeters) of rain on the mountainous island;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the population of the island of Dominica is about 72,000 people;</text> </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas during a televised address, Dominica Prime Minister Roosevelt Skerrit said Hurricane Erika set the nation's developmental progress back 20 years, as hundreds of homes and multiple other structures were destroyed;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Tropical Storm Erika whipped the island of Dominica for more than 5 hours on Wednesday, bringing strong winds and a torrent of intense rain that provoked flooding and landslides;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Tropical Storm Erika has caused Dominica to be set back 20 years in the damage inflicted by the storm;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Tropical Storm Erika washed away bridges and numerous roads and left several communities cut off from the rest of the island;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Tropical Storm Erika has left infrastructural damages estimated at $612,700,000 and 371 houses have been destroyed in a population of approximately 72,000 people;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas according to the Government of the Commonwealth of Dominica, clean-up is currently estimated at $12,000,000;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas cost of reconstruction of tourism infrastructure is estimated at $19 million and the reconstruction of 300 homes, as well as bridges, miles of roadway and water systems;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas with a total reconstruction bill estimated at $300 million and already carrying a debt burden amounting to 80 percent of GDP;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas in response, USAID’s Office of U.S. Foreign Disaster Assistance (USAID/OFDA) provided an initial $50,000 through USAID to the Dominica Red Cross Society to support the local procurement of relief items;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas since then and as of September 18, it is estimated that a total of $165,000 of United States Government disaster relief assistance has been targeted to Dominica for additional household staples, relocation assistance, and other aid; and</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas assessment teams from the USAID/OFDA are still working on the ground with the government and the Dominica Red Cross to assess and address additional needs as they surface: Now, therefore, be it</text>
		</whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body id="HDB0B3014733B43D2A82F675BA1BD01C4" style="traditional">
 <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H569C6A1E3B6C4A55862DDFB71F96D755" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That it is the sense of the House of Representatives that the United States Government should provide additional relief and assistance to the island of Dominica.</text>
		</section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


