<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="H827BF6DE160847D4AD3E5928910DBAE0" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Reported-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HRES 19 RH: Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 3) to approve the Keystone XL Pipeline, and providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 30) to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to repeal the 30-hour threshold for classification as a full-time employee for purposes of the employer mandate in the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act and replace it with 40 hours.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<calendar>House Calendar No. 1</calendar><congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 19</legis-num>
		<associated-doc>[Report No. 114–1]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20150107">January 7, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001248">Mr. Burgess</sponsor>, from the <committee-name committee-id="HRU00"> Committee on Rules</committee-name>, reported the following resolution; which was referred to the House Calendar and ordered to be
			 printed</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 3) to approve the Keystone XL Pipeline, and providing
			 for consideration of the bill (H.R. 30) to amend the Internal Revenue Code
			 of 1986 to repeal the 30-hour threshold for classification as a full-time
			 employee for purposes of the employer mandate in the Patient Protection
			 and Affordable Care Act and replace it with 40 hours.</official-title>
	</form>
	<resolution-body id="H979EED5D8CE14C8FB97C389CFCB3AB03" style="traditional">
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H71695695D6B64ACA8EAC608B10D74786" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That upon adoption of this resolution it shall be in order to consider in the House the bill (H.R.
			 3) to approve the Keystone XL Pipeline. All points of order against
			 consideration of the bill are waived. The bill shall be considered as
			 read. All points of order against provisions in the bill are waived. The
			 previous question shall be considered as ordered on the bill and on any
			 amendment thereto to final passage without intervening motion except: (1)
			 one hour of debate equally divided among and controlled by the chair and
			 ranking minority member of the Committee on Transportation and
			 Infrastructure and the chair and ranking minority member of the Committee
			 on Energy and Commerce; and (2) one motion to recommit.</text>
		</section><section id="HEF8378F9139A491EBB29D617DDF1CE68"><enum>2.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon adoption of this resolution it shall be in order to consider in the House the bill (H.R. 30)
			 to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to repeal the 30-hour threshold
			 for classification as a full-time employee for purposes of the employer
			 mandate in the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act and replace it
			 with 40 hours. All points of order against consideration of the bill are
			 waived. The bill shall be considered as read. All points of order against
			 provisions in the bill are waived. The previous question shall be
			 considered as ordered on the bill and on any amendment thereto to final
			 passage without intervening motion except: (1) one hour of debate equally
			 divided and controlled by the chair and ranking minority member of the
			 Committee on Ways and Means; and (2) one motion to recommit.</text>
		</section></resolution-body>
	<endorsement><action-date>January 7, 2015</action-date><action-desc>Referred to the House Calendar and ordered to be
			 printed</action-desc></endorsement></resolution>


