<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="H6088D40F628D4D799A46E8059B9B7C55" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HRES 348 IH: Supporting the right of the people of Ukraine to freely elect their government and determine their future.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 348</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20150707">July 7, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001084">Mr. Cicilline</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001165">Mr. Sires</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000179">Mr. Engel</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000487">Mr. Royce</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000610">Mr. Deutch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000579">Mr. Lowenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001296">Mr. Brendan F. Boyle of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000616">Mr. DesJarlais</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="I000057">Mr. Israel</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000795">Mr. Wilson of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000480">Ms. Slaughter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000462">Ms. Frankel of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001179">Mr. Marino</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000587">Mr. Ribble</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001248">Mr. Burgess</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000378">Mr. Kinzinger of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000291">Mrs. Ellmers of North Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000615">Mr. Duncan of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000592">Mr. Rokita</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000585">Mr. Reed</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000592">Mr. Poe of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000065">Mr. Yoho</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001270">Ms. Bass</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Al Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000435">Ms. Ros-Lehtinen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000559">Mr. Langevin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001083">Mr. Carney</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Supporting the right of the people of Ukraine to freely elect their government and determine their
			 future.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
 <whereas><text>Whereas a pro-democratic reform government emerged in Ukraine after then-President Viktor Yanukovych signed an agreement on February 21, 2014, transferring power to the opposition and then fled the country;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas following the resignation of President Yanukovych, Russian President Vladimir Putin ordered the forcible and illegal occupation of the Crimean region of Ukraine in March 2014;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Russian-led separatists have forcibly seized large areas of Ukraine and continue their attacks on Ukrainian forces;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Russian Federation has continued to engage in relentless political, economic, and military aggression to subvert the independence and violate the territorial integrity of Ukraine;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States has supported the democratically elected Government of Ukraine, as it represents the will of the people of Ukraine, and Congress has passed multiple pieces of legislation to provide support to Ukraine;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Congress passed the Sovereignty, Integrity, Democracy, and Economic Stability of Ukraine Act of 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/95">Public Law 113–95</external-xref>), which authorized loan guarantees for the Government of Ukraine;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Congress passed the Ukraine Freedom Support Act of 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/272">Public Law 113–272</external-xref>), which authorized the Administration to provide the Ukrainian Government with support to facilitate necessary reforms, and stated that it is U.S. policy to assist the Government of Ukraine in restoring its sovereignty and territorial integrity;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas in September 2014, a cease-fire agreement was brokered between the Government of Ukraine, Russian officials, and Russian-led insurgents, but fighting has continued and the agreement was never fully implemented;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas in February 2015, Ukraine, Russia, and Russian-led insurgents agreed to an additional cease-fire, known as the Minsk Implementation Agreement or Minsk 2;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas pursuant to the Minsk agreements, local elections are to be held by the end of 2015 in regions controlled by Russian-led insurgents and legal and constitutional reforms are to be negotiated to give a special status to the region;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States continues to receive reports of extensive violations by Russia and Russian-led forces in the eastern region of Ukraine;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States has assisted in many elections around the world, including Ukraine’s Presidential election in May 25, 2014, to ensure that international election standards are upheld;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas early parliamentary elections were held on October 26, 2014, but 29 of the 450 seats in parliament were not filled due to the inability to hold elections in districts controlled by separatists;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, despite the disenfranchisement of people living in separatist-controlled regions, international election observers declared the parliamentary elections to have met international standards;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Ukraine and Russia are members of the Organization for Security and Cooperation in Europe and party to its commitments, including the 1990 Copenhagen Document which states that member states <quote>will respect each other’s right freely to choose and develop, in accordance with international human rights standards, their political, social, economic and cultural systems</quote> and that <quote>free elections that will be held at reasonable intervals by secret ballot or by equivalent free voting procedure, under conditions which ensure in practice the free expression of the opinion of the electors in the choice of their representatives</quote>;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the next local elections are scheduled to take place in Ukraine on October 25, 2015;</text> </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas these elections are critical to continued legislative and constitutional reform in Ukraine; and</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States is supporting efforts to promote citizen engagement in the constitutional reform process, educating voters, and election monitoring: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body id="HDB464B2F5DF34595A07FA3EB3F3C6BC2" style="traditional">
 <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H32D1762AF17F46569C9A77ABBF162858" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="HE19C7BD7E22049EABC7AD48714675615"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">strongly supports the right of the people of Ukraine to freely elect their government and determine their future;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8DD143A41FD54CDE8417A60D4B1ED8A7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>urges the Administration to expedite assistance to Ukraine to facilitate the political, economic, and social reforms necessary for free and fair elections that meet international standards; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H94C3EB59508F4597BDD3B7AC9235F00F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>condemns attempts on the part of any outside forces, including the Government of Russia, its agents or supporters, to interfere in Ukraine’s elections, including through interference, intimidation, violence, or coercion.</text>
			</paragraph></section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


