<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="H2D035DD23BC14C3192166D30F1EC62F0" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HRES 552 IH: Expressing support for health and wellness coaches and “National Health and Wellness Coach Recognition Week”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-12-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 552</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20151203">December 3, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000604">Mr. Payne</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001190">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001260">Mr. Buchanan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000179">Mrs. Napolitano</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000577">Mr. Ryan of Ohio</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Expressing support for health and wellness coaches and <quote>National Health and Wellness Coach Recognition Week</quote>.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
 <whereas><text>Whereas, January 11, 2016, through January 17, 2016, is <quote>National Health and Wellness Coach Recognition Week</quote>;</text> </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas lifestyle-related chronic diseases are at the heart of the current health care crisis in the United States;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States Centers for Disease Control and Prevention has deemed chronic disease <quote>the public health challenge of the 21st century</quote>;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas decades of research have linked lifestyle factors, such as inactivity, poor diet, tobacco smoking, and sustained stress, with increased risk for major illnesses and death;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas attempts to reduce these lifestyle-related chronic disease and costs have proven to be financially un­sus­tain­able within a system that rewards hospitalizations and invasive procedures;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas incentives for interventions and technologies that achieve desired outcomes such as outpatient care, risk management, patient support, and health coaching should be encouraged;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas a large gap exists between health care provider recommendations and sustainable health-related behavior change;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas health coaches are a new type of health care worker who serve as wellness guides and supportive mentors that motivate individuals to cultivate positive health choices and move them toward those specific goals;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas health coaches serve a vital role in improving an individual’s wellness that complements and does not replace the work of health care professionals; and</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas there are an increasing number of studies that show the effectiveness of health and wellness coaches in improving individual health and wellness and reducing health care costs: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body id="H3766AA68423F4FFBB8F51F78E9CDBC95" style="traditional">
 <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H266D8BA1F7D9470A8F10B27A95C623EF" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="HFCB0788C48E84C748D3A6777F7AB8D6C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supports the designation of <quote>National Health and Wellness Coach Recognition Week</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H61D91B03792B45FBBEB25935EDB60C72"><enum>(2)</enum><text>support the efforts of health and wellness coaches of the United States on their important work to improve the health and wellness of the Nation.</text>
			</paragraph></section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


