<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="HF55410BF274741ACB72E5AE5ACAA2CDD" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HRES 45 IH: Amending the Rules of the House of Representatives to require each report of a committee on a public bill or public joint resolution to include an analysis of whether the bill or joint resolution creates a program, office, or initiative that would duplicate or overlap with an existing program, office, or initiative, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress> 
<session display="yes">1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. RES. 45</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action display="yes"> 
<action-date date="20150122">January 22, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000570">Mr. Guinta</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000575">Ms. Graham</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001094">Mr. Cook</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001106">Mr. Costello of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001282">Mr. Barr</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000588">Mr. Pearce</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Z000018">Mr. Zinke</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000754">Mr. Cooper</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000258">Mr. Peterson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001191">Mr. Murphy of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001180">Mr. Schrader</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000296">Mr. Jolly</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001191">Ms. Sinema</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Committee on Rules</committee-name></action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">Amending the Rules of the House of Representatives to require each report of a committee on a public bill or public joint resolution to include an analysis of whether the bill or joint resolution creates a program, office, or initiative that would duplicate or overlap with an existing program, office, or initiative, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<resolution-body style="traditional" id="H08CDA45660364CCD8CCC486A4EC35994"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HA4365B8492AF44E686ED9DB449836744"><text>That clause 3 of rule XIII of the Rules of the House of Representatives is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H4E5697912DA9471AB36FBDC1F9922532" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <rules-paragraph id="H926C4D2B72FB4EF88CC296A33531C2EF" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum> <subparagraph id="H52876B3B46934085B1442C848B539982" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Each report of a committee on a public bill or public joint resolution shall contain the following:</text> 
<clause id="H399E9C8D42324E74B24FA59F3073EED9" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An analysis by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) to determine if the bill or joint resolution creates any new Federal program, office, or initiative that would duplicate or overlap with any existing Federal entity with similar mission, purpose, goals, or activities, along with a listing of all such instances of duplication or overlapping created by the bill or joint resolution.</text></clause> <clause id="H57DDBEFD265D47C983BDC4931CB7D2DB" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the analysis provided under subdivision (A) indicates that the new program, office, or initiative would create duplication or overlapping, an explanation provided by the committee as to why the creation of the new program, office, or initiative is necessary.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H66D670380DBC4AB99CCF0E22C8DF67D7" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>It shall not be in order to consider a public bill or public joint resolution reported by a committee unless the committee has posted on its public website the analysis provided under subparagraph (1)(A) and (if necessary) the explanation provided under subparagraph (1)(B). </text></subparagraph></rules-paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> </resolution-body> </resolution> 

