<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="HE8AA0E884FD64CE7B364A68D48AB2DF9" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HRES 314 IH: Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives regarding the eligibility of veterans service organizations for community development block grant funding.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-06-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 314</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20150612">June 12, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000372">Mr. Frelinghuysen</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans’ Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives regarding the eligibility of veterans service
			 organizations for community development block grant funding.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
 <whereas><text>Whereas the Veterans of Foreign Wars, the American Legion, and other veterans service organizations, through local posts, provide a host of invaluable services to veterans across the United States, including benefits assistance, career services, financial assistance, homeless outreach, and supporting services;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas veteran service organizations also provide several important services for local communities, including various educational programs, and providing shelter during public emergencies; and</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas notwithstanding the critical services provided by veteran service organizations to veterans and the public, some posts may be deemed ineligible for Federal community development block grant funding for public facilities and improvements; Now, therefore, be it—</text></whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body id="H18DEBD231C254CEAB8B753F86022E4DD" style="traditional">
 <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H45ECCFC68BDA4C4EAABB0E350FD04547" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That it is the sense of the House of Representatives that—</text> <paragraph id="HC54DA403907746DE8D0D2C7B07AFFD1D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>veterans service organizations provide invaluable services to the veterans and local communities across the United States; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE58E376084454BF5815C94AFBA9C4577"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Congress should seek changes to Federal law to ensure that all veteran service organizations are eligible for community development block grant funding for public facilities and improvements funding.</text>
			</paragraph></section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


