<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="H599BBE28888E4BE0976BAC4F3110CC30" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Engrossed-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HRES 30 EH: Electing Members to certain standing committees of the House of Representatives.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">IV</distribution-code> 
<congress display="no">114th CONGRESS</congress> 
<session display="no">1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. RES. 30</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="yes">In the House of Representatives, U. S.,</current-chamber>
<action>
<action-date date="20150113">January 13, 2015</action-date>
</action> 
<legis-type display="yes">RESOLUTION</legis-type> 
<official-title display="no">Electing Members to certain standing committees of the House of Representatives.</official-title> 
</form> 
<resolution-body style="traditional" id="HAE32E98154A445BCBD776B347E6F5CC3"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HDF79F46CE2AD438ABBE76DCE3602BEE6"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the following named Members be, and are hereby, elected to the following standing committees of the House of Representatives: </text> <committee-appointment-paragraph><header>Committee on Appropriations:</header><text>Mr. Kilmer.</text></committee-appointment-paragraph>

<committee-appointment-paragraph><header>Committee on Agriculture:</header><text>Mr. David Scott of Georgia; Mr. Costa; Mr. Walz; Ms. Fudge; Mr. McGovern; Ms. DelBene; Mr. Vela; Ms. Michelle Lujan Grisham of New Mexico; Ms. Kuster; Mr. Nolan; Mrs. Bustos; Mr. Sean Patrick Maloney of New York; Mrs. Kirkpatrick; Mr. Aguilar; and Ms. Plaskett.</text></committee-appointment-paragraph> <committee-appointment-paragraph><header>Committee on Armed Services:</header><text>Ms. Loretta Sanchez of California; Mr. Brady of Pennsylvania; Mrs. Davis of California; Mr. Langevin; Mr. Larsen of Washington; Mr. Cooper; Ms. Bordallo; Mr. Courtney; Ms. Tsongas; Mr. Garamendi; Mr. Johnson of Georgia; Ms. Speier; Mr. Castro of Texas; Ms. Duckworth; Mr. Peters; Mr. Veasey; Ms. Gabbard; Mr. Walz; Mr. O'Rourke; Mr. Norcross; Mr. Gallego; Mr. Takai; Ms. Graham; Mr. Ashford; Mr. Moulton; and Mr. Aguilar.</text></committee-appointment-paragraph>

<committee-appointment-paragraph><header>Committee on the Budget:</header><text>Mr. Pascrell; Mr. Ryan of Ohio; Ms. Moore; Ms. Castor of Florida; Mr. McDermott; Ms. Lee; Mr. Pocan; Ms. Michelle Lujan Grisham of New Mexico; Mrs. Dingell; and Mr. Lieu of California.</text></committee-appointment-paragraph> <committee-appointment-paragraph><header>Committee on Education and the Workforce:</header><text>Mr. Hinojosa; Mrs. Davis of California; Mr. Grijalva; Mr. Courtney; Ms. Fudge; Mr. Polis; Mr. Sablan; Ms. Wilson of Florida; Ms. Bonamici; Mr. Pocan; Mr. Takano; Mr. Jeffries; Ms. Clark of Massachusetts; Ms. Adams; and Mr. DeSaulnier.</text></committee-appointment-paragraph>

<committee-appointment-paragraph><header>Committee on Ethics:</header><text>Ms. Linda T. Sánchez of California.</text></committee-appointment-paragraph> <committee-appointment-paragraph><header>Committee on Foreign Affairs:</header><text>Mr. Sherman; Mr. Meeks; Mr. Sires; Mr. Connolly; Mr. Deutch; Mr. Higgins; Ms. Bass; Mr. Keating; Mr. Cicilline; Mr. Grayson; Mr. Bera; Mr. Lowenthal; Ms. Meng; Ms. Frankel of Florida; Ms. Gabbard; Mr. Castro of Texas; Ms. Kelly of Illinois; and Mr. Brendan F. Boyle of Pennsylvania.</text></committee-appointment-paragraph>

<committee-appointment-paragraph><header>Committee on Homeland Security:</header><text>Ms. Loretta Sanchez of California; Ms. Jackson Lee; Mr. Langevin; Mr. Higgins; Mr. Richmond; Mr. Keating; Mr. Payne; Mr. Vela; Mrs. Watson Coleman; Miss Rice of New York; and Mrs. Torres.</text></committee-appointment-paragraph> <committee-appointment-paragraph><header>Committee on the Judiciary:</header><text>Mr. Nadler; Ms. Lofgren; Ms. Jackson Lee; Mr. Cohen; Mr. Johnson of Georgia; Mr. Pierluisi; Ms. Chu of California; Mr. Deutch; Mr. Gutiérrez; Ms. Bass; Mr. Richmond; Ms. DelBene; Mr. Jeffries; Mr. Cicilline; and Mr. Peters. </text></committee-appointment-paragraph>

<committee-appointment-paragraph><header>Committee on Natural Resources:</header><text>Mrs. Napolitano; Ms. Bordallo; Mr. Costa; Mr. Sablan; Ms. Tsongas; Mr. Pierluisi; Mr. Huffman; Mr. Ruiz; Mr. Lowenthal; Mr. Cartwright; and Mr. Beyer.</text></committee-appointment-paragraph> <committee-appointment-paragraph><header>Committee on Oversight and Government Reform:</header><text>Mrs. Carolyn B. Maloney of New York; Ms. Norton; Mr. Clay; Mr. Lynch; Mr. Cooper; Mr. Connolly; Mr. Cartwright; Ms. Duckworth; Ms. Kelly of Illinois; and Mrs. Lawrence.</text></committee-appointment-paragraph>

<committee-appointment-paragraph><header>Committee on Science, Space, and Technology:</header><text>Ms. Lofgren; Mr. Lipinski; Ms. Edwards; Ms. Wilson of Florida; Ms. Bonamici; Mr. Swalwell of California; Mr. Grayson; Mr. Bera; Ms. Esty; Mr. Veasey; and Ms. Clark of Massachusetts.</text></committee-appointment-paragraph> <committee-appointment-paragraph><header>Committee on Small Business:</header><text>Ms. Chu of California; Ms. Hahn; Mr. Payne; and Ms. Meng.</text></committee-appointment-paragraph>

<committee-appointment-paragraph><header>Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure:</header><text>Ms. Norton; Mr. Nadler; Ms. Brown of Florida; Ms. Eddie Bernice Johnson of Texas; Mr. Cummings; Mr. Larsen of Washington; Mr. Capuano; Mrs. Napolitano; Mr. Lipinski; Mr. Cohen; Mr. Sires; Ms. Edwards; Mr. Garamendi; Mr. Carson of Indiana; Ms. Hahn; Mr. Nolan; Mrs. Kirkpatrick; Ms. Titus; Mr. Sean Patrick Maloney of New York; Ms. Esty; Ms. Frankel of Florida; Mrs. Bustos; Mr. Huffman; and Ms. Brownley of California.</text></committee-appointment-paragraph> <committee-appointment-paragraph><header>Committee on Veterans’ Affairs:</header><text>Mr. Takano; Ms. Brownley of California; Ms. Titus; Mr. Ruiz; Ms. Kuster; and Mr. O'Rourke.</text></committee-appointment-paragraph>

</section> 
</resolution-body> 
<attestation><attestation-group><attestor display="no">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation>
</resolution> 


