<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="H996B9F6F277946B7B0021AD5DEBFD81F" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HRES 313 IH: Expressing support for designation of May 23rd as “National Rosie the Riveter Day”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-06-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 313</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20150612">June 12, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000451">Mr. Fitzpatrick</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001175">Ms. Speier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Expressing support for designation of May 23rd as <quote>National Rosie the Riveter Day</quote>.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
 <whereas><text>Whereas National Rosie the Riveter Day is a collective national effort to raise awareness of the 16 million women working during World War II;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Americans have chosen to honor female workers who contributed on the home front during World War II;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas these women left their homes to work or volunteer full-time in factories, farms, shipyards, airplane factories, banks, and other institutions in support of the military overseas;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas these women worked with the USO and Red Cross, drove trucks, riveted airplane parts, collected critical materials, rolled bandages, and served on rationing boards;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas it is fitting and proper to recognize and preserve the history and legacy of working women, including volunteer women, during World War II to promote cooperation and fellowship among such women and their descendants;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas these women and their descendants wish to further the advancement of patriotic ideas, excellence in the workplace, and loyalty to the United States of America; and</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas May 23rd would be an appropriate date to designate as <quote>National Rosie the Riveter Day</quote>: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble> <resolution-body id="H11F500E2D0B2478593982B2A583C3FA2" style="traditional"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H8C10594FBB174B908CE1B2CF9D473739" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That the House of Representatives—</text>
 <paragraph id="H7B62037E0C32498089348654978A4959"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the designation of <quote>National Rosie the Riveter Day</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4510FB366A0A47FCAF7F10001E8C8673"><enum>(2)</enum><text>acknowledges the important role played by women in World War II.</text>
			</paragraph></section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


