<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="HBF9BBE710BAE49F7B3FFB9AA41B97A9A" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HRES 203 IH: Expressing support for designation of June 2015 as “National Men’s Cancer Awareness Month”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 203</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20150415">April 15, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="H000324">Mr. Hastings</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="R000053">Mr. Rangel</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001191">Mr. Murphy of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000581">Mrs. Lawrence</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000604">Mr. Payne</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Expressing support for designation of June 2015 as <quote>National Men’s Cancer Awareness Month</quote>.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
 <whereas><text>Whereas 1 in 2 men will be diagnosed with cancer over the course of their lifetimes;</text> </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas according to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), cancer claims the lives of nearly 300,000 men annually in the United States;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the CDC also reports that the incidence of cancer for men varies by race and ethnicity, with minority men having the highest cancer incidence and mortality rates;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas statistics show that a higher percentage of men will die from cancer than women because they are typically diagnosed at a later stage;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas despite advances in medical technology and research, men continue to live an average of 5 fewer years compared to their female counterparts;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas “National Men’s Health Week”, which is annually celebrated as the week leading up to, and including Father’s Day, was established in 1994 by the United States Congress, to show how simple diagnostic and screening tests can save lives;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas promoting awareness and education about men’s cancer is crucial to improving the health and well-being of men across the Nation, facilitating early detection, improving the prognoses of men who have been diagnosed with the disease, and ultimately preventing further loss of life; and</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas June 2015 would be an appropriate month to designate as <quote>National Men’s Cancer Awareness Month</quote>: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble> <resolution-body id="H66A4F0C3D74A461F80BD1164CF00BF03" style="traditional"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H21126EC0C73441548C1F24B17D8541DE" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That the House of Representatives—</text>
 <paragraph id="H1F439B51A3964D978CB5AB06AF0A2A75"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supports the designation of <quote>Men’s Cancer Awareness Month</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H9E54E725D7324CA58DB4C5E8C4DADC5F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>encourages the Federal Government, States, localities, and nonprofit organizations to observance the month with appropriate awareness programs and educational activities, with the goal of increasing public knowledge of cancers disproportionately affecting men;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H771F3A76B4614BEC9A4B0A9AC17C9EBE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recognizes the profound toll a diagnosis of cancer has on men, families, and communities and pledges to make its prevention and cure a public health priority; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H147AAAA98B00413496ABC500913729A0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>urges public and private sector efforts to promote awareness, invest in research, and improve treatments for men’s cancers.</text>
			</paragraph></section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


