<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="HB1F9E19978EA4EFBB7EF8BF778315375" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HRES 372 IH: Recognizing the importance of the 2015 Special Olympics World Games hosted by the United States of America in Los Angeles, California.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 372</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20150723">July 23, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="B000287">Mr. Becerra</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Recognizing the importance of the 2015 Special Olympics World Games hosted by the United States of
			 America in Los Angeles, California.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
 <whereas><text>Whereas the Special Olympics improves the lives of those with developmental and intellectual disabilities;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the 2015 Special Olympics World Games will illustrate our Nation’s continued commitment to making our society more inclusive;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the first Special Olympics World Games held in 1968 featured 1,000 athletes from 26 States and Canada competing in track and field, swimming, and floor hockey;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the 2015 World Games will draw 6,500 athletes from 165 countries competing in 25 different sporting events;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the 2015 World Games will allow courageous athletes from around the world to experience the joy of displaying their talents and abilities;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the first medals will be awarded on the 25th anniversary of the Americans with Disabilities Act; and</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the 2015 World Games will continue the tradition of bringing health care services to those most in need: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body id="H6AF9B39476E045E78D384FBDBE549287" style="traditional">
 <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HE95701CF4F6E44ED92D9CF594E7A927B" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="H09DD9273D8BC4DE1BCDEC91AB6B04231"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes the importance of the Special Olympics World Games to the millions of people with intellectual disabilities and their loved ones;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEE88DABC0B144BD89E49B4C05C7B0EB4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>supports the efforts of the athletes, coaches, educators, volunteers, leaders, and workers who make the Games possible; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA269F226AAC44BB3B8F870CE50CA5036"><enum>(3)</enum><text>celebrates the return of the World Games to the United States and the city of Los Angeles.</text> </paragraph></section></resolution-body> </resolution> 

