<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="H49FF61F1097C44DDBC68B3580B8FD3BD" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HRES 460 IH: Supporting the goals and ideals of the International Day of Non-Violence.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-10-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num>H. RES. 460</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action display="yes"> 
<action-date date="20151002">October 2, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">Supporting the goals and ideals of the International Day of Non-Violence.</official-title> 
</form>
<preamble>
<whereas><text>Whereas the United Nations General Assembly established the International Day of Non-Violence on June 15, 2007, to disseminate the message of non-violence, through means such as education and public awareness;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, the United Nations General Assembly has stated that “non-violence, tolerance, full respect for all human rights and fundamental freedoms for all, democracy, development, mutual understanding and respect for diversity are interlinked and mutually reinforcing”;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas the annual International Day of Non-Violence celebration date, October 2, was chosen to commemorate the birthday of Mohandas K. Gandhi, more commonly known as “Mahatma”, which means “great soul”;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Mahatma Gandhi was a world-renowned civil rights and spiritual leader, who experienced injustices early in life, and learned to embrace the principles of non-violence as a vehicle for social and political change;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas Mahatma Gandhi was influenced by religious teachings in Hinduism, Jainism, and Christianity in the development of his philosophy;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Mahatma Gandhi was a major influence for Martin Luther King, Jr., whose emphasis on non-violence is credited with ushering in our Nation’s civil rights; and</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas people around the world commemorate the International Day of Non-Violence by participating in volunteer projects as a way to give back to their communities: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble> <resolution-body style="traditional" id="H6918ECC698F5405CA772808020B35C17"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H59A1E7922BAA416193D038708854F90F"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text>
<paragraph id="HC04AF8B7C1204179B1B369CFC2AEF6DA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supports the goals and ideals of the International Day of Non-Violence; and </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H16FEA69E1BFD486FAC4A28B832279945"><enum>(2)</enum><text>encourages the people of the United States to observe the International Day of Non-Violence with appropriate ceremonies, programs, and activities.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body> 
</resolution> 


