<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="H7A7F1BB345C54F7BAA191CBFBE0D06EF" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HRES 391 IH: Expressing support for designation of August 22, 2015, as national “Chuck Brown Day” and honoring his contributions to music and to the District of Columbia.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 391</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20150728">July 28, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Expressing support for designation of August 22, 2015, as national <quote>Chuck Brown Day</quote> and honoring his contributions to music and to the District of Columbia.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
 <whereas><text>Whereas Chuck Brown, who was born on August 22, 1936, and passed away on May 16, 2012, at the age of 75, was a District of Columbia resident most of his life;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Chuck Brown, who taught himself to play guitar, became a virtuoso singer, songwriter, guitarist, and band leader;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Chuck Brown's go-go beat gave the District of Columbia a musical identity of its own and reminds the Nation that Washington, DC, has always been the hometown of talented artists such as Duke Ellington and Marvin Gaye;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Chuck Brown's musical catalogue spans 22 studio albums over 3 decades;</text> </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Chuck Brown's hit <quote>Bustin' Loose</quote> with his group the Soul Searchers was the top song on the Billboard Top 100 R&amp;B Chart for 4 weeks in 1979;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Chuck Brown earned a Grammy nomination in 2010 for the song <quote>Love</quote>, from his album entitled <quote>We Got This</quote>, and was awarded a National Endowment for the Arts National Heritage Fellowship in 2005;</text> </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Chuck Brown's go-go has been passed from generation to generation with undiminished popularity;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Chuck Brown has influenced jazz, rap, and go-go musicians such as the bands Trouble Funk, Rare Essence, and Experience Unlimited (also known as E.U.);</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Chuck Brown was so committed to securing statehood and equal voting rights for the residents of the District of Columbia that he played a concert on a very hot, humid day on the Capitol grounds in 2010;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the District of Columbia has named a street near the Howard Theatre and a park in Northeast DC for Chuck Brown;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Chuck Brown is admired for having risen from humble beginnings and overcoming time in prison to become a devoted father and family man;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Chuck Brown was a great, multi-talented musician who brought joy through his music, never stopping until his death; and</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas August 22, 2015, is Chuck Brown’s birthday and would be an appropriate date to designate as <quote>Chuck Brown Day</quote>: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble> <resolution-body id="H0E890061926D47CDA08BCF6AF14C8080" style="traditional"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H1910E3379C2648E58B6454AB21E4DDA0" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives supports the designation of <quote>Chuck Brown Day</quote>, and honors Chuck Brown's contributions to music and to the District of Columbia.</text>
		</section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


