<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="HEB8FDA72AAFF49F0AEB9CAB7172DA7A3" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HRES 469 IH: Urging North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) member countries to meet or exceed the two percent gross domestic product commitment to spending on defense.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-10-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 469</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20151008">October 8, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001293">Mr. Bishop of Michigan</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="T000463">Mr. Turner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Z000018">Mr. Zinke</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000625">Mr. Donovan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001197">Ms. McSally</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000587">Mr. Ribble</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Ted Lieu of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000795">Mr. Wilson of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000591">Mrs. Roby</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000604">Mr. Russell</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001289">Mr. Byrne</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Urging North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) member countries to meet or exceed the two percent
			 gross domestic product commitment to spending on defense.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
 <whereas><text>Whereas in 2006, the defense ministers of North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) Alliance member countries agreed to commit a minimum of two percent, as a percentage of gross domestic product (GDP) to spending on defense;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas in 2006, the defense ministers of NATO Alliance member countries further agreed to commit a minimum of 20 percent of defense expenditures to major equipment spending;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas these commitments were reaffirmed in the Wales Summit Declaration of 2014 issued by Heads of State and Government participating in the meeting of the North Atlantic Council;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Article 3 of the North Atlantic Treaty states that, <quote>in order more effectively to achieve the objectives of this Treaty, the Parties, separately and jointly, by means of continuous and effective self-help and mutual aid, will maintain and develop their individual and collective capacity to resist armed attack.</quote>;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas member nations that meet or exceed the GDP commitment and member nations with a plan of action to move toward the GDP commitment are commended and encouraged;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the aggressive actions of Russia against Ukraine challenge global freedom, security, and stability critical to the NATO Alliance;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the instability in the Middle East and North Africa and the continued threat of global terrorism pose a threat to security and prosperity;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas emerging security challenges such as cyber-attacks threaten the resilience and integrity of NATO networks and infrastructure assets; and</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the resolute commitment of the United States to NATO is steadfast and the efforts of member nations that have met GDP commitments is applauded: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body id="H86819E3045A54FA1BEEF06F603573A04" style="traditional">
 <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H5953E6E5833D4F399E10319574021CB9" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="H74E1AB037A9F4B5B9BBA8751DA65D12B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">calls on North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) member countries to meet or exceed the two percent gross domestic product commitment to spending on defense;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC897EFAB0B4F4981BEA46061539A2D20"><enum>(2)</enum><text>calls on NATO member countries to meet or exceed the 20-percent commitment to defense expenditures on major equipment spending; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H720AC832018149278CF4E601823FEF47"><enum>(3)</enum><text>reaffirms the United States longstanding and resolute commitment to NATO and the peace through strength it advances.</text>
			</paragraph></section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


