<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="H93CBA26C3EB34D0ABC65E8929389A455" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HRES 112 IH: Supporting the goals and ideals of the Secondary School Student Athletes’ Bill of Rights.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 112</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20150213">February 13, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001106">Mr. Costello of Pennsylvania</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S001157">Mr. David Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Supporting the goals and ideals of the Secondary School Student Athletes’ Bill of Rights.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
		<whereas>
 <text>Whereas over 7,790,000 student athletes participated in secondary school athletics during the 2013 to 2014 academic year;</text>
		</whereas><whereas>
 <text>Whereas it is estimated that in 2013, over 1.24 million children aged 19 and under visited emergency rooms for injuries sustained as a result of participation in 14 of the most commonly played sports, including football, boys’ and girls’ soccer, girls’ volleyball, boys’ and girls’ basketball, wrestling, baseball, and softball;</text>
		</whereas><whereas>
 <text>Whereas every 3 minutes, a child is treated in an emergency department for a sports-related concussion, accounting for more than 8 percent of all sports-related emergency cases;</text>
		</whereas><whereas>
 <text>Whereas the number of sports-related concussion injuries has doubled in the last 15 years among student athletes aged 8 to 19, despite an overall decrease in the number of students participating in sports;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas sudden cardiac arrest (SCA) is the leading cause of death for youth participating in sports or exercising, with upwards of 80 percent of those suffering from SCA being asymptomatic prior to cardiac arrest;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas instances of heat-related illness have more than doubled since 1997 and affect high school football players at an average rate that is 10 times higher than that of participants in other sports;</text>
		</whereas><whereas>
 <text>Whereas secondary school student athletes with access to certified athletic health care professionals have lower overall injury rates, lower recurrent injury rates, and lower concussion rates than student athletes without access to certified athletic health care professionals;</text>
		</whereas><whereas>
 <text>Whereas in light of the increase in athletic-related injuries to student athletes, schools are encouraged to develop and adopt best practices and standards to prevent and address student athlete injury;</text>
		</whereas><whereas>
 <text>Whereas the Secondary School Student Athletes’ Bill of Rights sets forth that secondary school student athletes have the right to—</text>
			<paragraph id="H5F8688AEF8DC4422BE49CC46F51C0C84">
				<enum>(1)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be coached by individuals who are well-trained in sport-specific safety and to be monitored by athletic health care team members;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H92625AC3AB234157BB883C2BD8D5DA60">
				<enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>quality, regular pre-participation examinations and each athlete has the right to participate under a comprehensive concussion management plan;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H31216BAFE0694D04B56133B3CA23F954">
				<enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>participate in sporting activities on safe, clean playing surfaces, in both indoor and outdoor facilities;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H9DCCEE1E648247AAB98E98D1105176B4">
				<enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>utilize equipment and uniforms that are safe, fitted appropriately, and routinely maintained, and to appropriate personnel trained in proper removal of equipment in case of injury;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H6E9744AD17F04D21B01E4AA6AF77B536">
				<enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>participate safely in all environmental conditions where play follows approved guidelines and medical policies and procedures, with a hydration plan in place;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H2C9B87ED44A9488F94236FECC5DAF682">
				<enum>(6)</enum>
 <text>a safe playing environment with venue-specific emergency action plans that are coordinated by the athletic health care team and regularly rehearsed with local emergency personnel;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H4423A2D0547E457B848FACDF37CCACE7">
				<enum>(7)</enum>
 <text>privacy of health information and proper referral for medical, psychosocial, and nutritional counseling;</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H965EEA7396A548F6B9B66F869DE842DA">
				<enum>(8)</enum>
 <text>participate in a culture that finds <quote>playing through pain</quote> unacceptable unless there has been a medical assessment;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC84175B381914175BB9A2097E8EDC83E"> <enum>(9)</enum> <text>immediate, on-site injury assessments with decisions made by qualified sports medicine professionals; and</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H9EA7CDBD28554857B6B81151F3DD322B">
				<enum>(10)</enum>
 <text>along with their parents, the latest information about the benefits and potential risks of participation in competitive sports, including access to statistics on fatalities and catastrophic injuries to youth athletes; and</text>
			</paragraph></whereas><whereas>
 <text>Whereas the Secondary School Student Athletes’ Bill of Rights, which sets forth goals and ideals to improve the health, well-being, and athletic experience of secondary school students, can serve as a valuable resource to reduce injury, promote athlete safety, and encourage well-being: Now, therefore, be it</text>
		</whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body id="HCA3241A8224A43D4BB28E0CF2B5264F8" style="traditional">
 <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HD45A4D3E37984756890F90F586B964A4" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="HA499CC17FF6E41EAA81D991D1BB3E659"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">expresses support for the principles and values set forth in the Secondary School Student Athletes’ Bill of Rights;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H290AC13D785A469280A219E1B62D8657"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the importance of proper safety measures, timely medical assessments, and appropriate environmental conditions in ensuring the health and well-being of secondary school student athletes;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H467CEB9686FF439D95693E168EBB1B66"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognizes the role that teachers, parents, coaches, and athletic health care team members play in ensuring the safety and well-being of secondary school student athletes;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0039224559894878B7A743AEFB896366"><enum>(4)</enum><text>expresses support for secondary schools that have successfully implemented programs, policies, and practices to emphasize and encourage student athlete safety and well-being; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H269E3966283B434C9435A2823C1E136E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>encourages secondary schools to continue to take all available and reasonable efforts to ensure student athlete safety.</text>
			</paragraph></section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


