<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="HA7B2BF30E03142249C1FB4B22E044252" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HRES 323 IH: Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the Government of Mexico should forthwith repatriate the remains of those American Soldiers who fought in the battle of Monterrey in 1846.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-06-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 323</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20150617">June 17, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000616">Mr. DesJarlais</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the Government of Mexico should forthwith
			 repatriate the remains of those American Soldiers who fought in the battle
			 of Monterrey in 1846.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
 <whereas><text>Whereas 169 years ago this September, Brigadier General Zachary Taylor led a 6,000 man military force consisting of United States Regulars, Volunteers and Texas Rangers to capture the strategic town of Monterrey;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas after three days of fighting, Taylor’s forces captured Monterrey on September 23, 1846;</text> </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States suffered 120 casualties during the battle, while 368 were wounded and 43 were reported missing;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Mexican Government’s Instituto Nacional de Antropologia y Historia (INAH), in cooperation with the United States Department of State and the United States Department of the Army’s Armed Forces Medical Examiner (AFME), has positively identified the remains of 11 United States soldiers who fought in the battle of Monterrey in 1846; and</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas United States Department of State is working with the Mexican Government to secure the repatriation of these remains: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body id="H614DE63321D94F8C8430C0CAFFE55546" style="traditional">
 <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HF34D792225FC48ED9FFE041CEDE0A2F4" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="H251C411BDC4042A78C985BD7AA9EAEB0"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">commends the archaeologists, the Instituto Nacional de Antropologia y Historia, the United States Consulate General Monterrey and all those individuals whose diligent work led to the identification and recovery of these remains; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3AB41AB3123D42E1A21AE362BFF1B670"><enum>(2)</enum><text>calls upon the Government of Mexico and the Mexican Secretariat of Foreign Affairs to expeditiously release and repatriate the identified remains of these United States soldiers.</text>
			</paragraph></section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


