<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="H1E17883DF1034F24AD434449A07B15BF" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HRES 140 IH: Expressing support for designation of August 2015 as “Blue Star Mothers of America Month”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. RES. 140</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20150303">March 3, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000578">Mr. LaMalfa</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001191">Ms. Sinema</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000591">Mrs. Roby</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell of California</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Expressing support for designation of August 2015 as <quote>Blue Star Mothers of America Month</quote>.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
 <whereas><text>Whereas Blue Star Mothers of America, Inc. was founded as a patriotic service organization on February 2, 1942, with the purpose of uniting mothers with sons or daughters in the United States Armed Forces;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the nonpartisan, nonsectarian, nondiscriminatory, and nonprofit organization was chartered in 1960 by the Congress of the United States;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas persons eligible for membership in the Blue Star Mothers of America include any woman who filled the role of birthmother, adoptive mother, step-mother, foster-mother, grandmother, legal guardian of a servicemember at any time in that servicemember’s life who is currently serving in any branch of the United States Armed Forces, or has served and been discharged;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the work of the Blue Star Mothers of America includes—</text> <paragraph id="HE05B24C0C8914E75BD14ED2E440CBA96"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supporting members of the United States Armed Forces and veterans;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD4F92018347C4E2A8250122F165A266D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>advocating for the United States Armed Forces and those men and women who have served the Nation with honor;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE9516D4ED4024AABAB2252D2830E14C7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>maintaining allegiance to the United States;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H9ED0A1A1829E433EA773D703555D464E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>educating its members and others not to divulge military or other government information;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB89F5A8AAE94449EB5A9BADE2A8647AB"><enum>(5)</enum><text>assisting and participating in ceremonies which honor, remember, and support members of the United States Armed Forces and veterans;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H20F5FF0A70C44078A4D1B784B6B9BBA5"><enum>(6)</enum><text>honoring those families whose children have died in service to the Nation;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H268A730703164FFB8140E420AB3CD8A4"><enum>(7)</enum><text>assisting in the care of unsupported mothers who gave their children to the service of the Nation;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H93375DC77CAD464D9F7021F5932503C0"><enum>(8)</enum><text>fostering true democracy;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H844E0CD351034CFDA4C87C443B1E52AE"><enum>(9)</enum><text>assisting in homeland security;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H16172D56877844C2B39BA4757C69E7A3"><enum>(10)</enum><text>upholding the United States principles of freedom, justice, and equal rights; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF121453DD757463290A57A9A2ABA8B03"><enum>(11)</enum><text>defending the United States from all enemies, foreign and domestic;</text>
 </paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the dedication of Blue Star Mothers of America is increasingly important with over 11,000 active members in 42 States of the United States with sons and daughters serving in the United States Air Force, Army, Marine Corps, Navy, and Coast Guard;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Blue Star Service Flag is the official banner authorized by the Department of Defense for display by families who have members serving in the United States Armed Forces during any period of war or armed hostilities the Nation may be engaged in for the duration of such hostilities;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 6,764 members of the United States Armed Forces died in Operation Iraqi Freedom and Operation Enduring Freedom;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the loyalty, dedication, sacrifice, and hard work of the devoted members of Blue Star Mothers of America merit the utmost respect, acknowledgment, and recognition of the public; and</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas August 2015 would be an appropriate month to designate as <quote>Blue Star Mothers of America Month</quote>: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body id="HDD84B4ED82C24903B0A274B453F9ECF7" style="traditional">
 <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H57F46044680847CB8A64F4E86C15B0E7" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="H47599E0F545241D7AB9F717781FD50BD"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supports the designation of <quote>Blue Star Mothers of America Month</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H42FCDFAE18A7472CA7FCBE742462EF12"><enum>(2)</enum><text>encourages all citizens to take time during the month to reflect and honor the dedication and sacrifice of the mothers of members of the United States Armed Forces and celebrate the rich history and contributions they have made to the great Nation.</text>
			</paragraph></section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


