<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 SRES 170 ATS: Supporting the goals and ideals of National Travel and Tourism Week and honoring the valuable contributions of travel and tourism to the United States.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 170</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date>May 6, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S342">Mr. Blunt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S353">Mr. Schatz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S339">Mr. Kirk</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S198">Mr. Reid</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S327">Mr. Warner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S352">Mr. Heller</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S363">Mr. King</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S381">Mr. Rounds</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S373">Mr. Cassidy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S332">Mr. Franken</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S303">Mr. Thune</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Supporting the goals and ideals of National Travel and Tourism Week and honoring the valuable
			 contributions of travel and tourism to the United States.</official-title></form>
	<preamble>
 <whereas><text>Whereas National Travel and Tourism Week was established in 1983 through the enactment of the Joint Resolution entitled <quote>Joint Resolution to designate the week beginning May 27, 1984, as <quote>National Tourism Week</quote></quote>, approved November 29, 1983 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/98/178">Public Law 98–178</external-xref>; 97 Stat. 1126), which recognized the value of travel and tourism;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas National Travel and Tourism Week is celebrated across the United States from May 2 through May 10, 2015;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas more than 120 travel destinations throughout the United States are holding events in honor of National Travel and Tourism Week;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 1 out of every 9 jobs in the United States depends on travel and tourism, and the industry supports 15,000,000 jobs in the United States;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the travel and tourism industry employs individuals in all 50 States, the District of Columbia, and all the territories of the United States;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas international travel to the United States is the single largest export industry in the country, generating a trade surplus balance of approximately $74,000,000,000;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the travel and tourism industry, Congress, and the President have worked to streamline the visa process and make the United States welcoming to visitors from other countries;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas travel and tourism provide significant economic benefits to the United States by generating nearly $2,100,000,000,000 in annual economic output;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas leisure travel allows individuals to experience the rich cultural heritage and educational opportunities of the United States and its communities; and</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the immense value of travel and tourism cannot be overstated: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body>
 <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="S1" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That the Senate—</text> <paragraph id="idccbdb73e4f014f19a61eb28428eb30fd"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the goals and ideals of National Travel and Tourism Week;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id55f72e8e12ed4b2a85a45e6ea1a5af87"><enum>(2)</enum><text>commends the travel and tourism industry for its important contributions to the United States; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idE8A49F5B307F47109229F52BE0C3BB38"><enum>(3)</enum><text>commends the employees of the travel and tourism industry for their important contributions to the United States.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution>


