<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 SRES 206 ATS: Congratulating the Golden State Warriors for winning the 2015 National Basketball Association Championship.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-06-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. RES. 206</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20150618">June 18, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S223">Mrs. Boxer</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S221">Mrs. Feinstein</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Congratulating the Golden State Warriors for winning the 2015 National Basketball Association
			 Championship.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
 <whereas><text>Whereas, on June 16, 2015, the Golden State Warriors won their second National Basketball Association (referred to in this preamble as the <quote>NBA</quote>) Championship as a California team by defeating the Cleveland Cavaliers with a score of 105-97 in the sixth game of the NBA Finals;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas during the 2015 NBA playoffs, the Warriors defeated the New Orleans Pelicans, the Memphis Grizzlies, the Houston Rockets, and the Cleveland Cavaliers en route to the NBA Championship;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas during the playoffs, the Golden State Warriors twice overcame 2-1 series deficits and, in both series, responded with 3 straight victories to win the series;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas in the regular season, the Warriors won a league-best 67 games;</text> </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas all 15 players on the 2014-2015 Warriors roster should be congratulated, including NBA Finals MVP Andre Iguodala, the NBA regular season MVP Stephen Curry, as well as, Leandro Barbosa, Harrison Barnes, Andrew Bogut, Festus Ezeli, Draymond Green, Justin Holiday, Ognjen Kuzmic, David Lee, Shaun Livingston, James Michael McAdoo, Brandon Rush, Marreesse Speights, and Klay Thompson;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas first-year coach, Steve Kerr, did a tremendous job leading the Warriors to the NBA Title and, through his coaching, built a team that is the best in the NBA; and</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the fans of the Warriors have been ever-loyal in their support of the team, waiting 40 years for their second NBA title, but can now again call their team a champion: Now, therefore, be it</text>
		</whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body>
 <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="S1" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That the Senate—</text> <paragraph id="id2A53667BBD6E40E597D7033BC27E8E27"><enum>(1)</enum><text>congratulates the Golden State Warriors for winning the 2015 National Basketball Association Championship because of their selfless teamwork;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idE54AED6014364CA4A6FC20A299F3614D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the achievements of all the players, coaches, and staff who contributed to the 2014-2015 season; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id78EB6C04A3DB43B18105035C5D6A00B3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>celebrates the unique contributions of the Warriors fan base, who, through its unremitting and vocal support of the Warriors came to be known as <quote>Dub Nation</quote>.</text>
			</paragraph></section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


