<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 SRES 287 IS: Condemning the senseless murder and wounding of 18 individuals (sons, daughters, fathers, mothers, uncles, aunts, cousins, students, and teachers) in Roseburg, Oregon, on October 1, 2015.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-10-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 287</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20151008">October 8, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Condemning the senseless murder and wounding of 18 individuals (sons, daughters, fathers, mothers,
			 uncles, aunts, cousins, students, and teachers) in Roseburg, Oregon, on
			 October 1, 2015.</official-title></form>
	<preamble>
 <whereas><text>Whereas, on October 1, 2015, an armed gunman opened fire on the Umpqua Community College campus in Roseburg, Oregon, killing 9 individuals and wounding 9 other individuals;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas deceased and surviving victims demonstrated acts of heroism and sacrifice for the safety and sake of others;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the first responders were swift and professional in their response to the initial call, which avoided even more bloodshed; and</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas local, State, and Federal law enforcement, firefighter, and medical service professionals performed their duties with utmost skill and coordination: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body>
 <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="S1" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That the Senate—</text> <paragraph id="idaaf43954ce704733b46be8b2c2dbdb96"><enum>(1)</enum><text>offers condolences to the families and friends of individuals who were murdered by an armed gunman on the Umpqua Community College campus in Roseburg, Oregon, on October 1, 2015;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idE0707D688F864BEFAEC320821DF50E7D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>expresses hope for the swift and complete recovery of individuals who were wounded by the gunman;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idfafc13f97dca483387dfb2d8657529cf"><enum>(3)</enum><text>applauds the swift response and professional conduct of—</text> <subparagraph id="id51BEAAB51E954A99A6BDBEA6C7D6C4F6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the first responders to the scene; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id52C65D17C4234EF8AEDA28D2AC6B0BFE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the investigating officers following the neutralization of the gunman, including local, State, and Federal officials and others who offered their support and assistance; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5ada3bbec6a6402ebe67441ef36985c1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>remains committed to reducing the likelihood of this kind of event happening again.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution>


