<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 SRES 171 ATS: Congratulating the students, parents, teachers, and administrators of charter schools across the United States for making ongoing contributions to education, and supporting the ideals and goals of the 16th annual National Charter Schools Week, to be held May 3 through May 9, 2015. </dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. RES. 171</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date>May 6, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S289">Mr. Alexander</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S300">Mr. Burr</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S277">Mr. Carper</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S373">Mr. Cassidy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S287">Mr. Cornyn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S355">Mr. Cruz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S221">Mrs. Feinstein</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S293">Mr. Graham</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S118">Mr. Hatch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S305">Mr. Isakson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S339">Mr. Kirk</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S378">Mr. Lankford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S197">Mr. McCain</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S174">Mr. McConnell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S379">Mr. Perdue</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S350">Mr. Rubio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S365">Mr. Scott</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S384">Mr. Tillis</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S299">Mr. Vitter</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Congratulating the students, parents, teachers, and administrators of charter schools across the
			 United States for making ongoing contributions to education, and
			 supporting the ideals and goals of the 16th annual National Charter
			 Schools Week, to be held May 3 through May 9, 2015. </official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
 <whereas><text>Whereas charter schools are public schools that do not charge tuition and enroll any student who wants to attend, often through a random lottery when the demand for enrollment is outmatched by the supply of available charter school seats;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas high-performing public charter schools deliver a high-quality public education and challenge all students to reach the students’ potential for academic success;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas public charter schools promote innovation and excellence in public education;</text> </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas public charter schools throughout the United States provide millions of families with diverse and innovative educational options for children of the families;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas high-performing public charter schools and charter management organizations are increasing student achievement and attendance rates at institutions of higher education;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas public charter schools are authorized by a designated entity and—</text> <paragraph id="idE86D24929B4742D9BCCAB2AB6C644721"><enum>(1)</enum><text>respond to the needs of communities, families, and students in the United States; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id3428B17748BC44FEA3FE9A4A846BE419"><enum>(2)</enum><text>promote the principles of quality, accountability, choice, high-performance, and innovation;</text> </paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in exchange for flexibility and autonomy, public charter schools are held accountable by the authorizers of the charter schools for improving student achievement and for sound financial and operational management;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas public charter schools are required to meet the student achievement accountability requirements under the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6301">20 U.S.C. 6301 et seq.</external-xref>) in the same manner as traditional public schools;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas public charter schools often set higher expectations for students, beyond the requirements of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6301">20 U.S.C. 6301 et seq.</external-xref>), to ensure that the charter schools are of high quality and truly accountable to the public;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 43 States and the District of Columbia have enacted laws authorizing public charter schools;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, as of the 2014–2015 school year, more than 6,700 public charter schools served more than 2,900,000 children;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas in the United States—</text> <paragraph id="idF8B069CD7EF1423E8657DA418558BE0C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in 150 school districts, more than 10 percent of public school students are enrolled in public charter schools; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id03CAB0E8ADF14584B5620CD66AF88FC4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in 12 school districts, at least 30 percent of public school students are enrolled in public charter schools;</text>
 </paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas public charter schools improve the achievement of students enrolled in the charter schools and collaborate with traditional public schools to improve public education for all students;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas public charter schools—</text> <paragraph id="id4B5050C3208F418DA1781FBE73DA9B04"><enum>(1)</enum><text>give parents the freedom to choose public schools;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idA4C126456618409BA0D11EEF015A0602"><enum>(2)</enum><text>routinely measure parental satisfaction levels; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id17F8897EAD0C48E09191C4669B2D1598"><enum>(3)</enum><text>must prove the ongoing success of the charter schools to parents, policymakers, and the communities served by the charter schools or risk closure;</text>
 </paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, between 2010 and 2015, research studies have found that students attending public charter schools perform better academically than their peers;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas at least 500,000 students are on waiting lists to attend public charter schools across the country before the start of the 2014–2015 school year; and</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the 16th annual National Charter Schools Week is scheduled to be celebrated the week of May 3 through May 9, 2015: Now, therefore, be it</text>
		</whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body>
 <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="S1" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That the Senate—</text> <paragraph id="id0DDB4F4937564346B985D0B9A868ABAB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>congratulates the students, families, teachers, administrators, and staff of public charter schools across the United States for—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id21C0C17CDEE04740B0EE533271FA6533"><enum>(A)</enum><text>making ongoing contributions to public education;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id010946F188924E339BAFF9BA8EF25F4E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>making impressive strides in closing the academic achievement gap in schools in the United States, particularly in schools with some of the most disadvantaged students in both rural and urban communities; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idECDD6B0E7A0F4559AA223C681C9314D3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>improving and strengthening the public school system throughout the United States;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id6F4ED0C3F87946408D2CDDC36F621A6D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>supports the ideals and goals of the 16th annual National Charter Schools Week, a week-long celebration to be held May 3 through May 9, 2015, in communities throughout the United States; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id15F603AB44D549EBB203836CFE6A6260"><enum>(3)</enum><text>encourages the people of the United States to hold appropriate programs, ceremonies, and activities during National Charter Schools Week to demonstrate support for public charter schools.</text>
			</paragraph></section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


