<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 SRES 253 ATS: Welcoming King Felipe VI and Queen Letizia of Spain on their official visit to the United States, including visits to Miami and St. Augustine, Florida.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-09-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. RES. 253</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20150915">September 15, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S282">Mr. Nelson</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S350">Mr. Rubio</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<action><action-date>September 17, 2015</action-date><action-desc>Committee discharged; considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Welcoming King Felipe VI and Queen Letizia of Spain on their official visit to the United States,
			 including visits to Miami and St. Augustine, Florida.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
 <whereas><text>Whereas King Felipe VI and Queen Letizia of Spain are visiting St. Augustine, Florida, to celebrate the 450th Commemoration of the city and to participate in the annual United States-Spain Council forum;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Spanish explorer Ponce de León landed on the east coast of Florida in 1513 and named the land he discovered La Florida;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas St. Augustine was founded by Spanish admiral Pedro Menéndez de Avilés on September 8, 1565;</text> </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas St. Augustine is the oldest continuously occupied European settlement in the United States;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States-Spain Council serves an important purpose in bringing the United States and Spain closer through trade, investment, education, and culture, as well as by fostering military cooperation between the 2 countries;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States-Spain Council is holding its annual forum in St. Augustine from September 18–20, 2015;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the people and Governments of the United States and Spain have both benefitted from strong economic and cultural ties;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Spain has played a special role in the history and culture of St. Augustine and Florida; and</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas King Felipe VI and Queen Letizia met with President Barack Obama on September 15, 2015, for their first official visit to the White House: Now, therefore, be it</text>
		</whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body>
 <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="S1" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That the Senate—</text> <paragraph id="idA2DF84E4EA7E46B295855332E94141AC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>welcomes King Felipe VI and Queen Letizia of Spain during their visit to the United States; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idb98acef23fa840d6a5d0a42b28a5c107"><enum>(2)</enum><text>expresses its appreciation for the efforts of King Felipe VI and Queen Letizia to strengthen the bonds between the people and Governments of the United States and Spain.</text>
			</paragraph></section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


