<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 SRES 205 ATS: Congratulating the Chicago Blackhawks on winning the 2015 Stanley Cup.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-06-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. RES. 205</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20150618">June 18, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S339">Mr. Kirk</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Congratulating the Chicago Blackhawks on winning the 2015 Stanley Cup.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
 <whereas><text>Whereas, on June 15, 2015, the Chicago Blackhawks Hockey Team won the Stanley Cup;</text> </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the 2015 Stanley Cup title is the third Stanley Cup title for the Blackhawks in 6 years;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Blackhawks fans at the <quote>Madhouse on Madison</quote> witnessed Duncan Keith and Patrick Kane score show-stopping goals while goaltender Corey Crawford seemed to stand on his head at times, stopping all 25 shots he faced;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Blackhawks won their sixth Stanley Cup, tying the Boston Bruins for fourth on the franchise list of most titles won;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Blackhawks joined the National Hockey League (referred to in this preamble as <quote>NHL</quote>) in 1926 and have a rich history in the NHL;</text> </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Blackhawks were 1 of the 6 original teams in the NHL;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Blackhawks won the Stanley Cup in 1934, 1938, 1961, 2010, and 2013;</text> </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas for the first time in 77 years, the Blackhawks fans saw their heroes win the Stanley Cup on home ice;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Blackhawks began the playoffs with a double-overtime victory against the Nashville Predators;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas a goal scored by Brent Seabrook in triple-overtime of Game 4 helped the Blackhawks defeat the Predators in 6 games;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas a sweep of the Minnesota Wild followed in the second round of the playoffs, setting up a showdown with the Anaheim Ducks in the Western Conference Finals;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Blackhawks earned triple and double-overtime victories against the Anaheim Ducks in Games 2 and 4 on their way to winning the series in 7 games and clinching a berth in the Stanley Cup Finals;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Blackhawks followed a familiar pattern in dropping Games 2 and 3 of the Stanley Cup Finals against the Tampa Bay Lightning, but took a 3-2 series lead into Game 6 on home ice on the night of Monday, June 15, 2015;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas in another close contest, Patrick Kane scored a goal during Game 6 that marked the first time either team led by more than 1 goal in the series;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas it was a great night for fans of the Blackhawks and the culmination of a tremendous team effort;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Antoine Vermette, acquired at the trade deadline, scored 2 game-winning goals in the Stanley Cup Finals;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Goaltender Scott Darling, when called upon in relief of Corey Crawford, stood tall in net when his team needed him the most against the Predators;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Duncan Keith was an <quote>ironman</quote>, earning the Conn Smythe Trophy for Most Valuable Player in the playoffs while logging more than 700 minutes of ice time in 23 games;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Niklas Hjalmarsson blocked shots left and right and seemed to be in the right place at all times;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas General Manager Stan Bowman, Head Coach Joel Quenneville, President John F. McDonough, and owner Rocky Wirtz have put together and led one of the greatest dynasties in NHL history;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Stanley Cup returns to the City of Chicago and gives Blackhawks fans across the State of Illinois a chance to celebrate championship hockey;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Nashville Predators, Minnesota Wild, Anaheim Ducks, and Tampa Bay Lightning proved to be worthy and honorable adversaries and also deserve recognition: Now, therefore, be it</text>
		</whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body>
 <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="S1" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That the Senate—</text> <paragraph id="idDB07C24156AD4723971EEC620A632413"><enum>(1)</enum><text>congratulates the Chicago Blackhawks on winning the 2015 Stanley Cup;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idC8771DB96564497C90AA96DBB36040FD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>commends the fans, players, and management of the Tampa Bay Lightning for an outstanding series; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id3EC58F45587C44ADBCDBE176A58676C0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>respectfully directs the Secretary of the Senate to transmit an enrolled copy of this resolution to the 2015 Chicago Blackhawks hockey organization and Blackhawks owner Rocky Wirtz.</text>
			</paragraph></section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


