<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 SRES 267 IS: Expressing support for the continuation of the Federal Perkins Loan program.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-09-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 267</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20150924">September 24, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S354">Ms. Baldwin</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S349">Mr. Portman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S309">Mr. Casey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S252">Ms. Collins</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S284">Ms. Stabenow</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S259">Mr. Reed</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S275">Ms. Cantwell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S307">Mr. Brown</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S221">Mrs. Feinstein</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S332">Mr. Franken</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S339">Mr. Kirk</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S182">Ms. Mikulski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S223">Mrs. Boxer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S359">Mr. Heinrich</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S380">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S229">Mrs. Murray</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S327">Mr. Warner</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the continuation of the Federal Perkins Loan program.</official-title></form>
	<preamble>
 <whereas><text>Whereas the Federal Perkins Loan program is the longest running Federal student loan program in the United States, created in 1958 as the National Defense Student Loan Program and later called the National Direct Loan Program;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Federal Perkins loans are efficient, need-based, low-interest loans that serve 500,000 low-income college students with high need at approximately 1,500 colleges and universities each year;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Federal Perkins loans have favorable terms for students, including—</text> <paragraph id="id8CB485C5AA1C4064AE3A5E567926305A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>interest is not charged while a student is in school;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idFFF3B25188FD4E72B1DFD2E76CC80853"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the interest rate is low and fixed; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idE1FD0E2F7B144570A0ED7A8999216071"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a borrower may have all or part of a Federal Perkins loans cancelled if the borrower undertakes certain public service jobs for a period of 1 to 5 years;</text>
 </paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas participating colleges and universities share the risk of the Federal Perkins Loan Program because the colleges and universities provide a <fraction>1/3</fraction> match to Federal capital contributions and loans are made using funds repaid by previous borrowers;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Federal Perkins loans feature the human touch of campus-based servicing, which allows on-campus administrators to provide Federal Perkins borrowers with 1-on-1 service;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Federal Perkins loans have made higher education possible for millions of people of the United States; and</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas without Federal Perkins loans, thousands of people in the United States will lose the chance at a higher education and a better life: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body id="H0966436AFE0F4D0AABF0ED69964A3A36" style="traditional">
 <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HA9CCE1FAFBBD4B5195776C4CE41ABE7A" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That the Senate strongly supports the continuation of the Federal Perkins Loan program in order to provide educational opportunities to future generations of students who need low-cost financing to make their dreams of higher education possible.</text></section></resolution-body></resolution>


