<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="first-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 SRES 35 ATS: Commemorating the 70th anniversary of the liberation of the Auschwitz extermination camp in Nazi-occupied Poland.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 35</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20150122">January 22, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S182">Ms. Mikulski</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S308">Mr. Cardin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S339">Mr. Kirk</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S223">Mrs. Boxer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S331">Mrs. Gillibrand</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S307">Mr. Brown</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S323">Mr. Risch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S381">Mr. Rounds</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S347">Mr. Moran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S118">Mr. Hatch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S282">Mr. Nelson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S353">Mr. Schatz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S306">Mr. Menendez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S355">Mr. Cruz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S364">Mr. Murphy</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S354">Ms. Baldwin</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSFR00" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><action stage="Reported-in-Senate"><action-date>January 28, 2015</action-date><action-desc>Reported by <sponsor name-id="S310">Mr. Corker</sponsor>, with an amendment</action-desc></action><action><action-date>January 30, 2015</action-date><action-desc>Considered, amended, and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Commemorating the 70th anniversary of the liberation of the Auschwitz extermination camp in
 Nazi-occupied Poland.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, on January 27, 1945, the Auschwitz extermination camp in Nazi-occupied Poland was liberated by Allied Forces during World War II after almost 5 years of murder, rape, and torture at the camp;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 1,100,000 innocent civilians were murdered at the Auschwitz extermination camp;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas nearly 1,300,000 innocent civilians were deported to Auschwitz from their homes across Eastern and Western Europe, particularly from Hungary, Poland, and France;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 1,000,000 of the civilians who perished at the camp were Jews, along with 100,000 non-Jewish Poles, Roma and Sinti individuals, Soviet prisoners of war, Jehovah’s Witnesses, gay men and women, and other ethnic minorities;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas these civilians included farmers, tailors, seam­stres­ses, factory hands, accountants, doctors, teachers, small-business owners, clergy, intellectuals, government officials, and political activists;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas these civilians were subjected to torture, forced labor, starvation, rape, medical experiments, and being separated from loved ones;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the names of many of these civilians who perished have been lost forever;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Auschwitz extermination camp symbolizes the extraordinary brutality of the Holocaust;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the people of the United States must never forget the terrible crimes against humanity committed at the Auschwitz extermination camp;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the people of the United States must educate future generations to promote understanding of the dangers of intolerance in order to prevent similar injustices from happening again; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas commemoration of the liberation of the Auschwitz extermination camp will instill in all people of the United States a greater awareness of the Holocaust: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body display-resolving-clause="yes-display-resolving-clause"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idc29fc264-a3a7-4437-b006-8fb884139b7b" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id626c57ad-8314-404c-bae9-9d7402506f08"><enum>(1)</enum><text>commemorates January 27, 2015, as the 70th anniversary of the liberation of the Auschwitz extermination camp by Allied Forces during World War II;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfa76bce8-e8eb-41ca-8742-b8be871c187a"><enum>(2)</enum><text>calls on all people of the United States to remember the 1,100,000 innocent victims murdered at the Auschwitz extermination camp as part of the Holocaust;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf24e5cb1-8c10-4703-bcbe-46038fcd7cfb"><enum>(3)</enum><text>honors the legacy of the survivors of the Holocaust and of the Auschwitz extermination camp; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb60d7265-081a-490c-acdb-6b2764b1e6b3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>calls on the people of the United States to continue to work toward tolerance, peace, and justice and to continue to work to end all genocide and persecution.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution>


