<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 SRES 263 ATS: Supporting the goals and ideals of National Retirement Security Week, including raising public awareness of the various tax-preferred retirement vehicles, increasing personal financial literacy, and engaging the people of the United States on the keys to success in achieving and maintaining retirement security throughout their lifetimes. </dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-09-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. RES. 263</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20150922">September 22, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S254">Mr. Enzi</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S308">Mr. Cardin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S252">Ms. Collins</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Supporting the goals and ideals of National Retirement Security Week, including raising public
			 awareness of the various tax-preferred retirement vehicles, increasing
			 personal financial literacy, and engaging the people of the United States
			 on the keys to success in achieving and maintaining retirement security
			 throughout their lifetimes. </official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
 <whereas><text>Whereas people in the United States are living longer, and the cost of retirement is increasing significantly;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Social Security remains the bedrock of retirement income for the great majority of the people of the United States but was never intended by Congress to be the sole source of retirement income for families;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas recent data from the Employee Benefit Research Institute indicates that, in the United States—</text>
 <paragraph id="id3BBC873D6E9D4622BD7907C543B24AB8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>only approximately <fraction>2/3</fraction> of workers or the spouses of the workers are saving for retirement; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id798474B58B78433CA748010AF41445D4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the amount that workers have saved for retirement is much less than the amount the workers need to adequately fund their retirement years;</text>
 </paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the financial literacy of workers in the United States is important for the workers to understand the need to save for retirement;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas saving for retirement is a key component of overall financial health and security during retirement years, and the importance of financial literacy in planning for retirement must be advocated;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas many workers may not—</text> <paragraph id="id60DF72B08D97422191A059BAE24D4EC7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be aware of the various options in saving for retirement; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idBAAA592E7FF54C0ABF9277FA2F225E80"><enum>(2)</enum><text>have focused on the importance of, and need for, saving for retirement and successfully achieving retirement security;</text>
 </paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, although many employees have access through their employers to defined benefit and defined contribution plans to assist the employees in preparing for retirement, many of the employees may not be taking advantage of those plans at all or to the full extent allowed by Federal law;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas saving for retirement is necessary even during economic downturns or market declines, which makes continued contributions all the more important;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas all workers, including public and private sector employees, employees of tax-exempt organizations, and self-employed individuals, can benefit from developing personal budgets and financial plans that include retirement savings strategies that take advantage of tax-preferred retirement savings vehicles;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas effectively and sustainably withdrawing retirement resources throughout the retirement years of an individual is as important and crucial as saving and accumulating funds for retirement; and</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the week of October 18 through October 24, 2015 has been designated as <quote>National Retirement Security Week</quote>: Now, therefore, be it</text>
		</whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body>
 <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="S1" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That the Senate—</text> <paragraph id="id6B91AC260C064A8EB97101ADC454B785"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the goals and ideals of National Retirement Security Week, including raising public awareness of the importance of saving adequately for retirement;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id03C6400D5D8544A09763441F6C8D10D9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>acknowledges the need to raise public awareness of a variety of tax-preferred retirement vehicles that are used by many people in the United States but could be used by more; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id02B6D416EEDA482DAD1EA5727122B29F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>calls on States, localities, schools, universities, nonprofit organizations, businesses, other entities, and the people of the United States to observe National Retirement Security Week with appropriate programs and activities, with the goal of increasing the retirement savings and personal financial literacy of all people in the United States, thereby enhancing the retirement security of the people of the United States.</text>
			</paragraph></section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


