<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 SRES 230 IS: Designating September 25, 2015, as “National Lobster Day”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. RES. 230</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20150727">July 27, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S363">Mr. King</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S252">Ms. Collins</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S259">Mr. Reed</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S340">Ms. Ayotte</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S364">Mr. Murphy</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Designating September 25, 2015, as <quote>National Lobster Day</quote>.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
 <whereas><text>Whereas lobster from the United States is recognized around the world as a prized culinary delicacy;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas lobster fishing has served as an economic engine and a family tradition in the United States for centuries;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas thousands of families in the United States make their livelihoods from lobster fishing and processing;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas more than 120,000,000 pounds of lobster are caught each year in waters of the United States, representing one of the Nation’s most valuable catches;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the lobster industry is booming abroad, with profits climbing from $335,800,000 in 2009 to $738,600,000 in 2014;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas historical lore notes that lobster likely joined turkey on the table at the very first Thanksgiving Day feast in 1621;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas responsible lobstering practices, beginning in the 1600s, have created one of the world’s most sustainable fisheries;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Lobster Newburg was featured on the menu at the inaugural dinner celebration for President John F. Kennedy;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas lobsters are one of the most healthy and nutritious sources of protein;</text> </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the peak of the lobstering season in the United States occurs in the late summer;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas lobster has become a culinary icon, with the lobster roll being featured at the 2015 World Food Expo in Milan, Italy; and</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas lobster is featured on more and more restaurant menus, growing by 35 percent from 2009 to 2013: Now, therefore, be it</text>
		</whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body>
 <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="S1" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That the Senate—</text> <paragraph id="id88ca5da7f9754163b1e9a6c22c824e11"><enum>(1)</enum><text>designates September 25, 2015,<italic> </italic> as <quote>National Lobster Day</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idbef2daeee6a54958ac60cf394b26f391"><enum>(2)</enum><text>encourages the people of the United States to observe the day with appropriate ceremonies and activities.</text>
			</paragraph></section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


