<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 SRES 325 ATS: Permitting the collection of clothing, toys, food, and housewares during the holiday season for charitable purposes in Senate buildings.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-12-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. RES. 325</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20151202">December 2, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S305">Mr. Isakson</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Permitting the collection of clothing, toys, food, and housewares during the holiday season for
			 charitable purposes in Senate buildings.</official-title>
	</form>
	<resolution-body>
		<section id="id15fe1af944b340bc963cc0b30a02ce05" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Collection of clothing, toys, food, and housewares during the holiday season for charitable
			 purposes in Senate buildings</header>
 <subsection id="id518114cdef244a058dcc6af96b3ea7a9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of the rules or regulations of the Senate—</text> <paragraph id="id92a09e999a1f4f36ad75b0dc251b7643"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a Senator, officer of the Senate, or employee of the Senate may collect from another Senator, officer of the Senate, or employee of the Senate within Senate buildings nonmonetary donations of clothing, toys, food, and housewares for charitable purposes related to serving persons in need or members of the Armed Forces and the families of those members during the holiday season, if the charitable purposes do not otherwise violate any rule or regulation of the Senate or of Federal law; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id6e76f3c65bae4d2c9885f43f252b2572"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a Senator, officer of the Senate, or employee of the Senate may work with a nonprofit organization with respect to the delivery of donations described under paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id20df765b22da4078acabffc50ce5d98f"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Expiration</header><text>The authority provided by this resolution shall expire at the end of the first session of the 114th Congress.</text>
			</subsection></section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


