<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 SRES 236 ATS: Designating July 30, 2015, as “National Whistleblower Appreciation Day”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. RES. 236</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20150730">July 30, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S153">Mr. Grassley</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S252">Ms. Collins</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S384">Mr. Tillis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S339">Mr. Kirk</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S345">Mr. Johnson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S277">Mr. Carper</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S312">Mrs. McCaskill</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Designating July 30, 2015, as <quote>National Whistleblower Appreciation Day</quote>.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
 <whereas><text>Whereas, in 1777, before the passage of the Bill of Rights, 10 sailors and marines blew the whistle on fraud and misconduct harmful to the United States;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Founding Fathers unanimously supported the whistleblowers in words and deeds, including by releasing government records and providing monetary assistance for reasonable legal expenses necessary to prevent retaliation against the whistleblowers;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on July 30, 1778, in demonstration of their full support for whistleblowers, the members of the Continental Congress unanimously enacted the first whistleblower legislation in the United States that read: <quote><italic>Resolved</italic>, That it is the duty of all persons in the service of the United States, as well as all other the inhabitants thereof, to give the earliest information to Congress or other proper authority of any misconduct, frauds or misdemeanors committed by any officers or persons in the service of these states, which may come to their knowledge</quote> (legislation of July 30, 1778, reprinted in <italic>Journals of the Continental Congress, 1774–1789</italic>, ed. Worthington C. Ford et al. (Washington, D.C., 1904-37), 11:732);</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas whistleblowers risk their careers, jobs, and reputations by reporting waste, fraud, and abuse to the proper authorities;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, when providing proper authorities with lawful disclosures, whistleblowers save taxpayers in the United States billions of dollars each year and serve the public interest by ensuring that the United States remains an ethical and safe place;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas whistleblowing is generally defined as the lawful disclosure of information reasonably believed to evidence a violation of law, rule, or regulation, or gross mismanagement, a gross waste of funds, an abuse of authority, or a danger to public health or safety—and is in contrast to the unlawful disclosure of classified information that threatens the national security of the United States and that violates criminal law; and</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas it is the public policy of the United States to encourage, in accordance with Federal law (including the Constitution, rules, and regulations) and consistent with the protection of classified information (including sources and methods of detection of classified information), honest and good faith reporting of misconduct, fraud, misdemeanors, and other crimes to the appropriate authority at the earliest time possible: Now, therefore, be it</text>
		</whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body>
 <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="S1" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That the Senate—</text> <paragraph id="id308dceffa72a414e8e9d143a8e76f52c"><enum>(1)</enum><text>designates July 30, 2015, as <quote>National Whistleblower Appreciation Day</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idb1f0b263bcab49569ec4ebb4e1edcb3d"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ensures that the Federal Government implements the intent of the Founding Fathers, as reflected in the legislation enacted on July 30, 1778, by encouraging each executive agency to recognize National Whistleblower Appreciation Day by—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id9dbb011c6f5c48e1aec76ffe37cbc0e1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>informing employees, contractors working on behalf of United States taxpayers, and members of the public about the legal rights of citizens of the United States to <quote>blow the whistle</quote> by honest and good faith reporting of misconduct, fraud, misdemeanors, or other crimes to the appropriate authorities; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7a6714eca43f4b3e92c8714fa4899d05"><enum>(B)</enum><text>acknowledging the contributions of whistleblowers to combating waste, fraud, abuse, and violations of laws and regulations in the United States.</text>
				</subparagraph></paragraph></section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


