<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 SRES 296 IS: Congratulating Army Reserve Major Lisa Jaster on her graduation from the Army Ranger School.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-10-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. RES. 296</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20151026">October 26, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S345">Mr. Johnson</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S354">Ms. Baldwin</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Congratulating Army Reserve Major Lisa Jaster on her graduation from the Army Ranger School.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
 <whereas><text>Whereas the Army Ranger School (referred to in this preamble as <quote>Ranger School</quote>) was established in 1950 during the Korean War to develop elite leaders to command difficult combat missions;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Ranger School is one of the most challenging training courses for which members of the Armed Forces may volunteer;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Ranger School pushes the physical and mental limits of students for more than two months;</text> </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas on average—</text>
 <paragraph id="id73B07843DC6B48C28DCE2716EF2BF33E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>36 percent of Ranger School students fail the course during the first four days after the date on which the course begins; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idECE4E37F00A645BA91FEDEDC99B15F29"><enum>(2)</enum><text>only approximately 45 percent of Ranger School students ultimately graduate from the course;</text> </paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Army Reserve is—</text>
 <paragraph id="id25E1B955F86F4E49B1FF9F91DC351633"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a highly trained force that comprises approximately 20 percent of the total Army; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id6DBDEF37539D4FECAC8B773B5A87EF88"><enum>(2)</enum><text>always available to meet the needs of the Army and Joint Force;</text>
 </paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on August 21, 2015, Army Captain Kristen Griest and First Lieutenant Shaye Haver became the first two women to graduate from Ranger School;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on October 16, 2015, Major Lisa Jaster became the third woman, and the first Army Reserve woman and mother, to graduate from Ranger School and earn the distinctive black and gold Ranger tab;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Major Lisa Jaster overcame the extreme fatigue, hunger, and stress involved in Ranger training in order to graduate from Ranger School; and</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Major Lisa Jaster has—</text> <paragraph id="idAC4D4A155074458786281377666EF78F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>dedicated her life to serving and protecting the United States;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id9109B42E6E3D4F798A16583F9E43CD91"><enum>(2)</enum><text>deployed to both Iraq and Afghanistan; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id653DCC5B34484F3A8C0EDE17D64A63B8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>earned the Bronze Star and the Combat Action Badge: Now, therefore, be it</text>
			</paragraph></whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body>
 <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="S1" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That the Senate—</text> <paragraph id="id9cbaeb5b59f64369b1cdac86b81975c9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>honors Major Lisa Jaster for the accomplishment of becoming the first Army Reserve woman and first mother to graduate from Ranger School;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idCD540A00EAAD41109638C350A379E4C0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>commends the groundbreaking achievements of the first three women to graduate from Ranger School—</text> <subparagraph id="id9A033882BEEA4B0FA68B00A27CF8E424"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Captain Kristen Griest;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id60D69FAB62754316A6240E87322D3AFD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>First Lieutenant Shaye Haver; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA1C7EAB406164D70BDA661DE4EF16C0F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Major Lisa Jaster;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idF848755EE2CA4E248A13913CB2882067"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recognizes the vital role that the Army Reserve plays in protecting and defending the United States; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id549633fc12bd462ab4044585f7a37d64"><enum>(4)</enum><text>celebrates the determination, patriotism, and willingness to lead of all Ranger School graduates.</text> </paragraph></section></resolution-body> </resolution> 

