<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 SRES 186 ATS: Designating the week of May 17 through May 23, 2015, as “National Public Works Week”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. RES. 186</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20150521">May 21, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S236">Mr. Inhofe</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S223">Mrs. Boxer</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Designating the week of May 17 through May 23, 2015, as <quote>National Public Works Week</quote>.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
 <whereas><text>Whereas public works infrastructure, facilities, and services are of vital importance to the health, safety, and well-being of the people of the United States;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the public works infrastructure, facilities, and services could not be provided without the dedicated efforts of public works professionals, including engineers and administrators, who represent State and local governments throughout the United States;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas public works professionals design, build, operate, and maintain the transportation systems, water infrastructure, sewage and refuse disposal systems, public buildings, and other structures and facilities that are vital to the people and communities of the United States; and</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas understanding the role that public infrastructure plays in protecting the environment, improving public health and safety, contributing to economic vitality, and enhancing the quality of life of every community of the United States is in the interest of the people of the United States: Now, therefore, be it</text>
		</whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body>
 <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="S1" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That the Senate—</text> <paragraph id="id6af328fd1cbb458cbf7c0cc56d6a0e3a"><enum>(1)</enum><text>designates the week of May 17 through May 23, 2015, as <quote>National Public Works Week</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idc93f2f14e6a04c8fa242bfdcb57b48e5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes and celebrates the important contributions that public works professionals make every day to improve—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id6d0bb262b06b4f3d98b01d5abcc4acd1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the public infrastructure of the United States; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3d5cac3bc62c47adb944f9f348450707"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the communities that public works professionals serve; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id6e69ea2253e0494e934b30168bc68028"><enum>(3)</enum><text>urges individuals and communities throughout the United States to join with representatives of the Federal Government and the American Public Works Association in activities and ceremonies that are designed—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id254b985a1efc44f8be130a6e83e7fd22"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to pay tribute to the public works professionals of the United States; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9b35449226e9471395b6b099841b8ebd"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to recognize the substantial contributions that public works professionals make to the United States.</text>
				</subparagraph></paragraph></section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


