<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 SRES 319 ATS: Designating November 29, 2015, as “Drive Safer Sunday”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-11-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 319</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20151119">November 19, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S305">Mr. Isakson</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Designating November 29, 2015, as <quote>Drive Safer Sunday</quote>.</official-title></form>
	<preamble>
 <whereas><text>Whereas motor vehicle travel is the primary means of transportation in the United States;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas every individual traveling on the roads and highways needs to drive in a safer manner to reduce deaths and injuries that result from motor vehicle accidents;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas according to the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration, wearing a seat belt saves as many as 15,000 lives each year; and</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Sunday after Thanksgiving is the busiest highway traffic day of the year: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body>
 <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="S1" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That the Senate—</text> <paragraph id="ID94e6889d6e724dd4af505ec719c280d8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>encourages—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id8F121805D0564064A9953809CE8E4A65"><enum>(A)</enum><text>high schools, colleges, universities, administrators, teachers, primary schools, and secondary schools to launch campus-wide educational campaigns to urge students to focus on safety when driving;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID399b661d3b1945658a04d6c525560ab9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>national trucking firms to alert their drivers to be especially focused on driving safely on the Sunday after Thanksgiving, and to publicize the importance of the day through use of the Citizens Band Radio Service and at truck stops across the United States;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="IDa672d17cca1e47159796cb1c6e3544e6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>clergies to remind their congregations to travel safely when attending services and gatherings;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID7d71db600ee04ff18a5532e9ec228fda"><enum>(D)</enum><text>law enforcement personnel to remind drivers and passengers to drive safely, particularly on the Sunday after Thanksgiving;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD48CE68732494C0BAA01B657F495BD58"><enum>(E)</enum><text>motorists to drive safely, not just during the holiday season, but every time they get behind the wheel; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID0c57af24cd0c4364956797d924b63c56"><enum>(F)</enum><text>all people of the United States to understand the life-saving importance of wearing a seat belt and to use the Sunday after Thanksgiving as an opportunity to educate themselves about highway safety; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID268f69e773c84ca8b3d0db5f2365183a"><enum>(2)</enum><text>designates November 29, 2015, as <quote>Drive Safer Sunday</quote>.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution>


