<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 SRES 6 ATS: Expressing the thanks of the Senate to the Honorable Patrick J. Leahy for his service as President Pro Tempore of the United States Senate and to designate Senator Leahy as President Pro Tempore Emeritus of the United States Senate.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. RES. 6</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20150106">January 6, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S174">Mr. McConnell</sponsor> (for <cosponsor name-id="S198">Mr. Reid</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Expressing the thanks of the Senate to the Honorable Patrick J. Leahy for his service as President
			 Pro Tempore of the United States Senate and to designate Senator Leahy as
			 President Pro Tempore Emeritus of the United States Senate.</official-title>
	</form>
	<resolution-body>
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="S1" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the United States Senate expresses its deepest gratitude to Senator Patrick J. Leahy for his
			 dedication and commitment during his service to the Senate as the
			 President Pro Tempore.</text>
		</section><section id="id0111F2B5EEA846E8B11A81091291C596" section-type="undesignated-section"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Further, as a token of appreciation of the Senate for his long and faithful service, Senator
			 Patrick J. Leahy is hereby designated President Pro Tempore Emeritus of
			 the United States Senate.</text>
		</section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


