<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 SRES 99 IS: Calling on the Government of Iran to fulfill its promises of assistance in the case of Robert Levinson, the longest held United States civilian in our Nation’s history.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. RES. 99</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20150310">March 10, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S282">Mr. Nelson</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S350">Mr. Rubio</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Calling on the Government of Iran to fulfill its promises of assistance in the case of Robert
			 Levinson, the longest held United States civilian in our Nation’s history.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
 <whereas><text>Whereas United States citizen Robert Levinson is a retired agent of the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI), a resident of Coral Springs, Florida, the husband of Christine Levinson, and father of their seven children;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Robert Levinson traveled from Dubai, United Arab Emirates, to Kish Island, Iran, on March 8, 2007;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, after traveling to Kish Island and checking into the Hotel Maryam, Robert Levinson disappeared on March 9, 2007;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in December 2007, Robert Levinson's wife, Christine, traveled to Kish Island to retrace Mr. Levinson's steps and met with officials of the Government of Iran who pledged to help in the investigation;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, for more than eight years, the United States Government has continually pressed the Government of Iran to provide any information on the whereabouts of Robert Levinson and to help ensure his prompt and safe return to his family;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas officials of the Government of Iran promised their continued assistance to the relatives of Robert Levinson during the visit of the family to the Islamic Republic of Iran in December 2007;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in November 2010, the Levinson family received a video of Mr. Levinson in captivity, representing the first proof of life since his disappearance and providing some initial indications that he was being held somewhere in southwest Asia;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in April 2011, the Levinson family received a series of pictures of Mr. Levinson, which provided further indications that he was being held somewhere in southwest Asia;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Secretary of State John Kerry stated on August 28, 2013, <quote>The United States respectfully asks the Government of the Islamic Republic of Iran to work cooperatively with us in our efforts to help U.S. citizen Robert Levinson.</quote>;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on September 28, 2013, during the first direct phone conversation between the leaders of the United States and Iran since 1979, President Barack Obama raised the case of Robert Levinson to President of Iran Hassan Rouhani and urged the President of Iran to help locate Mr. Levinson and reunite him with his family;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on August 29, 2014, Secretary of State Kerry again stated that the United States <quote>respectfully request the Government of the Islamic Republic of Iran work cooperatively with us to find Mr. Levinson and bring him home</quote>;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States Government is currently engaged in regular, direct negotiations with the Government of Iran over its nuclear program;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas March 9, 2015, marks the 2,922nd day since Mr. Levinson's disappearance, and he is now the longest held United States civilian in our Nation's history; and</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Federal Bureau of Investigation has announced a $5,000,000 reward for information leading to Mr. Levinson's safe return: Now, therefore, be it</text>
		</whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body>
 <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="S1" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That the Senate—</text> <paragraph id="id811d0735b05c4ff78e33f015cfe6c170"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes that Robert Levinson is the longest held United States civilian in our Nation's history;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id35e5cbb893e94a4a8ac3f19c244123af"><enum>(2)</enum><text>notes the pledges by current officials of the Government of Iran to provide their Government's assistance in the case of Robert Levinson;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id04733bcdaa024422a2013015780884e6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>urges the Government of Iran, as a humanitarian gesture, to intensify its cooperation on the case of Robert Levinson and to immediately share the results of its investigation into the disappearance of Robert Levinson with the United States Government;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id5b5b4e11be1a45af8c72587b43555ec8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>urges the President and the allies of the United States to continue to raise with officials of the Government of Iran the case of Robert Levinson at every opportunity, notwithstanding serious disagreements the United States Government has with the Government of Iran on a broad array of issues, including human rights, the nuclear program of Iran, the Middle East peace process, regional stability, and international terrorism; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idf194cbf8307a4003abb62b991fac5c15"><enum>(5)</enum><text>expresses sympathy to the family of Robert Levinson for their anguish and expresses hope that their ordeal can be brought to an end in the near future.</text>
			</paragraph></section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


