<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 SRES 342 ATS: Congratulating the women's volleyball team of Wheeling Jesuit University on winning the Division II National Championship.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-12-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. RES. 342</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20151218">December 18, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S372">Mrs. Capito</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S338">Mr. Manchin</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Congratulating the women's volleyball team of Wheeling Jesuit University on winning  the Division
			 II National Championship.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
 <whereas><text>Whereas on Saturday, December 12, 2015, the Wheeling Jesuit Cardinals won the Division II National Championship women's volleyball trophy in 3 straight sets, defeating the Palm Beach Atlantic Sailfish of Tampa, Florida, by scores of—</text>
 <paragraph id="id09F83FFAF8BD4989A33884FE163A78B4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>25 to 22;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id8C7EC969BBE34F30BD9B46FEB47FC017"><enum>(2)</enum><text>26 to 24; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idCC042A3C03B04139B172A24FFDA02463"><enum>(3)</enum><text>26 to 24;</text> </paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Wheeling Jesuit Cardinals setter Andrea Thobe earned the Most Outstanding Player award;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Wheeling Jesuit Cardinals volleyball players Jessica Thobe, Haley Kindall, and Kayce Krucki were recognized by being named to the All-Tournament team;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas head volleyball coach Christy Benner, assistant volleyball coach Matt Benner, and graduate assistant coach Allissa Ware brilliantly created successful game plans throughout the 2015 season; and</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas all members of the Wheeling Jesuit Cardinals women’s volleyball team, including Abby Moffit, Alexa Brown, Sydney Obringer, Maddy Smyth, Allegra Shippy, Julie Henderson, Samantha Obringer, Maddy Kassen, Emily Blank, Katie Campbell, Emma Schluecher, and Lauren Graves successfully worked together to help deliver the first National Championship for Wheeling Jesuit University: Now, therefore, be it</text>
		</whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body>
 <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="S1" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That the Senate congratulates the women's volleyball team of Wheeling Jesuit University on winning the Division II National Championship.</text>
		</section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


