<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 SRES 118 IS: Amending rule XXXI of the Standing Rules of the Senate, to provide for timely consideration of nominations.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. RES. 118</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20150326">March 26, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSRA00">Committee on Rules and Administration</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Amending rule XXXI of the Standing Rules of the Senate, to provide for timely consideration of
			 nominations.</official-title>
	</form>
	<resolution-body>
 <section id="idF51EF11A3EDA45E6A0491FA626C0891B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Timely consideration of nominations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Rule XXXI of the Standing Rules of the Senate is amended—</text> <paragraph id="id3D60D6E79DC940E9A495F91A3B529175"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs 3 through 7 as paragraphs 4 through 8, respectively; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idF7CA35897B5740F99035D39659746BB7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph 2 the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id41F7D16738424D43B9A768359CAD4DB3" style="OLC"> <subsection id="id4C1A29CF0C204E7E979998EEB9E18259"><enum>3. (a)<?LEXA-Enum 1.(a)?></enum><text>In this paragraph, the term <term>covered nomination</term> means a nomination other than a nomination—</text>
 <paragraph id="id506E3D16FDF54FCA8D2AEC7A7D04C5DA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>of an individual to serve as a justice of the Supreme Court of the United States or as Chief Justice of the United States; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idAE4635CC1F6B4340AC68DDE364D51517"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to a position entitled to expedited procedures under S. Res. 116 (112th Congress).</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id8CB65E03A03B4ED0A8271DFEE0731A5D"><enum>(b)<?LEXA-Enum (b)?></enum><text>Subject to subparagraph (c), if a covered nomination has been on the Executive Calendar for more than 14 calendar days, the covered nomination shall be eligible for expedited consideration in accordance with subparagraph (d).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id1D6AEC6D518C4066A5D1703AAACFC899"><enum>(c)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idF2592E0EBA4B458E990854A5282B354F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>For a covered nomination described in clause (3), unless not less than 10 Senators have submitted written requests for the record that the covered nomination be considered by the full Senate in executive session before the end of the 14 calendar day period described in subparagraph (b)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id6EC364D04D2B4275AE3EB57F12216A82" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the nomination shall be deemed to be confirmed by the Senate; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id39F7B61878A2413CA436927CB53AAC41" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary shall send to the President a notification of the confirmation.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id30A0A255EC014315BF7DAD23C8E32442" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>If not less than 10 Senators submit a written request in accordance with clause (1) with respect to a covered nomination described in clause (3), the covered nomination shall be eligible for expedited consideration in accordance with subparagraph (d).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id6E9F23C551994A9EADED323D657818EB" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A covered nomination described in this clause is a covered nomination other than the nomination of an individual—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id5B1A5BE93CF048D2A05A5F753BEFF00F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to serve as a judge or justice appointed to hold office during good behavior; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id39CF3276D1A54C1EB115483265BC4135"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to a position at level I of the Executive Schedule under section 5312 of title 5, United States Code.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id053086A0013347E790BF8F565A515B54"><enum>(d)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id1AAE2C557EBE41CF8C987DC0D3F41041"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The majority leader may provide notice that a covered nomination that is eligible for expedited consideration in accordance with this subparagraph shall be considered on an expedited basis.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id2F65FD11FA4546A8AFC63D51A1257975" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Except as provided in clauses (3) and (4), 24 hours after the majority leader provides notice under clause (1) with respect to a covered nomination, the Senate shall proceed to executive session and begin consideration of the covered nomination.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id0DF4A79112D34911BA2D57F39A91CAC5" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Forty-eight hours after the majority leader provides notice under clause (1) with respect to a covered nomination to serve as a judge appointed to hold office during good behavior or a nomination to a position at level I of the Executive Schedule under section 5312 of title 5, United States Code, the Senate shall proceed to executive session and begin consideration of the nomination.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idF1D4E9A994494A2EB5C28904A104D5B8" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>If the majority leader provides notice with respect to more than 1 covered nomination during any 24 hour period, the covered nominations shall be considered in accordance with clause (5) in the order in which notice was provided.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id1B6FEE1A61854FC88197EAF4A6933E20" indent="up1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Notwithstanding rule XXII, expedited consideration of a covered nomination under this subparagraph, including consideration of any debatable motion or appeal in connection therewith—</text>
 <subparagraph id="id68E68B813AAF46AC8BC3A930AA8183D8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall be limited to 4 hours, evenly divided in the usual form, in the case of a nomination to serve as a judge of a circuit court of the United States or a nomination to a position at level I of the Executive Schedule under section 5312 of title 5, United States Code; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id42EEFC774E3E4ADB80BEEE5658143C0B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall be limited to 2 hours, evenly divided in the usual form, in the case of any other covered nomination.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution>


