<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 SRES 260 ATS: Honoring the life and legacy of Calvin G. Moret.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-09-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. RES. 260</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20150921">September 21, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S299">Mr. Vitter</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S373">Mr. Cassidy</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Honoring the life and legacy of Calvin G. Moret.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
 <whereas><text>Whereas Calvin G. Moret was born on August 15, 1925, in New Orleans, Louisiana;</text> </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 1943, Calvin G. Moret joined the Tuskegee Airmen and completed his advanced training in P–51 Mustangs;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Tuskegee Airmen were the first African-American military airmen;</text> </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on November 20, 1944, Calvin G. Moret graduated as a Flight Officer as part of class 44–I–SE in the Tuskegee Airmen program;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to the Veterans History Project of the Library of Congress, Calvin G. Moret served as a flight instructor;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Calvin G. Moret was a recipient of the Congressional Gold Medal, presented in the rotunda of the United States Capitol, for his service to the United States;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Calvin G. Moret was the last surviving Tuskegee Airman pilot in Louisiana;</text> </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Calvin G. Moret contributed oral histories to the collection of the National WWII Museum;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on June 29, 2013, the Urban League of Greater New Orleans presented Calvin G. Moret with the Whitney M. Young Legacy Award;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2014, Calvin G. Moret became the fifth honorary member of the Black Pilots of America; and</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Calvin G. Moret was a distinguished speaker for the National WWII Museum at major exhibits, including the <quote>Fighting for the Right to Fight: African American Experiences in World War II</quote> exhibit: Now, therefore, be it</text>
		</whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body>
 <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="S1" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That the Senate—</text> <paragraph id="id80A80B895B6446A6B07069109D36E10B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>honors the life of Calvin G. Moret, who was dedicated to serving the community and recording the experiences of the members of the Tuskegee Airmen;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id0b33a991a0ac44c0b34fffe73752c4f5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the lasting contributions made by Calvin G. Moret to World War II educational programming and the National WWII Museum; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idb23b8f151eae4c96819a10648d287d46"><enum>(3)</enum><text>requests that the Secretary of the Senate prepare an official copy of this resolution for presentation to the family of Calvin G. Moret.</text>
			</paragraph></section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


