<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 SRES 138 ATS: Congratulating the Providence College Men’s Ice Hockey team for winning the 2015 NCAA Division I National Championship.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. RES. 138</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20150416">April 16, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S259">Mr. Reed</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Congratulating the Providence College Men’s Ice Hockey team for winning the 2015 NCAA Division I
			 National Championship.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
 <whereas><text>Whereas on Saturday, April 11, 2015, the Providence College Friars won the 2015 NCAA Division I Men’s Ice Hockey National Championship by defeating the Boston University Terriers by a score of 4 to 3 at TD Garden in Boston, Massachusetts;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas numbers 16, 10, and 6 scored the first three goals for the Friars to keep the game close;</text> </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the extraordinary goal by number 22 in the third period put Providence College in the lead for good;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the superb goaltending of number 32 held back Boston University’s scoring attacks and sealed the victory for the Friars, earning him Most Outstanding Player honors of the NCAA Division I Men’s Ice Hockey Tournament;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the season-long contributions and dedication of all players and coaches of the Friars’ hockey team contributed to this National Championship season;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas this is the first NCAA Championship for the Providence College Men’s Ice Hockey team;</text> </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Providence College Friars finished the season with 26 wins and outscored its opponents 19 to 10 in the NCAA Division I Men’s Ice Hockey Tournament; and</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Providence College Men’s Ice Hockey team became the latest Rhode Island college team to win a National Championship and earn the pride of the State: Now, therefore, be it</text>
		</whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body>
 <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="S1" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That the Senate—</text> <paragraph id="id30B0C53888434E14ADF35F782D8F72A0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>congratulates the Providence College Men’s Ice Hockey team for winning the 2015 NCAA Division I National Championship;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idDA1926DDF3EB48CBB6CA04F12E3B93B2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>commends the players, coaches, and staff of the Providence College Men’s Ice Hockey team for their hard work and dedication in making this the most successful season in team history; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id94EF9E4F8D31429F81E99978C70491A0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recognizes the Providence College students, alumni, and fans who supported the Men’s Ice Hockey team in its pursuit of a National Championship.</text>
			</paragraph></section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


