<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 SRES 149 ATS: Recognizing the importance and inspiration of the Hubble Space Telescope.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. RES. 149</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20150423">April 23, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S350">Mr. Rubio</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Recognizing the importance and inspiration of the Hubble Space Telescope.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
 <whereas><text>Whereas the launch of the Hubble Space Telescope on April 24, 1990, from the Kennedy Space Center marked a historic moment in space discovery and observation;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the National Aeronautics and Space Administration designed, built, and placed the Hubble Space Telescope into orbit;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Space Shuttle Discovery transported the Hubble Space Telescope on the STS-31 mission and placed the Telescope into orbit at 380 statute miles;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the crew on the Space Shuttle Discovery consisted of Commander Loren J. Shriver, Pilot Charles F. Bolden, Jr., Mission Specialist Bruce McCandless II, Mission Specialist Kathryn D. Sullivan, and Mission Specialist Steven A. Hawley;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Hubble Space Telescope weighed more than 24,000 pounds at launch, currently weighs 27,000 pounds following the final servicing mission in 2009, and measures more than 43 feet in length;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Hubble Space Telescope orbits the Earth at 17,000 miles per hour and has completed more than 3,000,000,000 miles of orbit around the Earth;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Hubble Space Telescope continues to provide more than 10 Terabytes of data annually and has been heralded as one of the most productive scientific instruments known to man;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the spirit of discovery, innovation, and exploration is enshrined in the productivity of the Hubble Space Telescope; and</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Hubble Space Telescope has made significant advancements and discoveries in planetary sciences, cosmology, and galactic sciences: Now, therefore, be it</text>
		</whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body>
 <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="S1" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That the Senate—</text> <paragraph id="id002D34EA8B4742FFB8B97A06A414D304"><enum>(1)</enum><text>congratulates the National Aeronautics and Space Administration on the 25th anniversary of the Hubble Space Telescope launch;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id4081712bb9fb4bc892832593dc4df630"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the scientists, crew, engineers, and staff who contributed to the success of the Hubble Space Telescope;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id413d80c5277442bda2a2f8a699c08663"><enum>(3)</enum><text>notes the significance of the discoveries and contributions to science of the Hubble Space Telescope as well as the subsequent innovations that were derived from the data collected from the Hubble Space Telescope; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idc820ed9cb43e4823b407843393c86eed"><enum>(4)</enum><text>acknowledges that the Hubble Space Telescope has captured images from and answered questions about space and has inspired generations of young people to go into the fields of science, technology, engineering, mathematics, and research.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


