<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 SRES 125 ATS: Designating the first week of April 2015 as “National Asbestos Awareness Week”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 125</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150327" legis-day="20150326">March 27 (legislative day, March 26), 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S223">Mrs. Boxer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S229">Mrs. Murray</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S308">Mr. Cardin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S221">Mrs. Feinstein</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S198">Mr. Reid</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S314">Mr. Tester</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S305">Mr. Isakson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S270">Mr. Schumer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S375">Mr. Daines</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S266">Mr. Crapo</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S331">Mrs. Gillibrand</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Designating the first week of April 2015 as <quote>National Asbestos Awareness Week</quote>.</official-title></form>
	<preamble>
 <whereas><text>Whereas dangerous asbestos fibers are invisible and cannot be smelled or tasted;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the inhalation of airborne asbestos fibers can cause significant damage;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas asbestos fibers can cause cancer such as mesothelioma, asbestosis, and other health problems;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas symptoms of asbestos-related diseases can take 10 to 50 years to present themselves;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the projected life expectancy for an individual diagnosed with mesothelioma is between 6 and 24 months;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas generally, little is known about late-stage treatment of asbestos-related diseases, and there is no cure for such diseases;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas early detection of asbestos-related diseases may give some patients increased treatment options and might improve their prognoses;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States has substantially reduced its consumption of asbestos, yet continues to consume hundreds of metric tons of the fibrous mineral each year for use in certain products throughout the United States;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas asbestos-related diseases have killed thousands of people in the United States;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas while exposure to asbestos continues, safety and prevention of asbestos exposure already has significantly reduced the incidence of asbestos-related diseases and can further reduce the incidence of such diseases;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas thousands of workers in the United States face significant asbestos exposure, which has been a cause of occupational cancer;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas thousands of people in the United States die from asbestos-related diseases every year;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas a significant percentage of all asbestos-related disease victims were exposed to asbestos on naval ships and in shipyards;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas asbestos was used in the construction of a significant number of office buildings and public facilities built before 1975;</text>
 </whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas people in the small community of Libby, Montana, suffer from asbestos-related diseases, including mesothelioma, at a significantly higher rate than people in the United States as a whole; and</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the designation of a <term>National Asbestos Awareness Week</term> will raise public awareness about the prevalence of asbestos-related diseases and the dangers of asbestos exposure: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body>
 <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idAE56BD798B2443D886240BE12180196C" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That the Senate—</text> <paragraph id="id12d2829d06d24f13a347e1cbceadbe82"><enum>(1)</enum><text>designates the first week of April 2015 as <term>National Asbestos Awareness Week</term>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idd115d25e1a644ba4a4147d6ccc530463"><enum>(2)</enum><text>urges the Surgeon General of the United States to warn and educate people about the public health issue of asbestos exposure, which may be hazardous to their health; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id44ddab6ff89343c79de00b73ba7b23a4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>respectfully requests that the Secretary of the Senate transmit a copy of this resolution to the Office of the Surgeon General.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution>


