<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 SRES 81 ATS: Expressing the sense of the Senate that children trafficked for sex in the United States should not be treated or regarded as child prostitutes because there is no such thing as a “child prostitute”, only children who are victims or survivors of rape and sex trafficking. </dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. RES. 81</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20150212">February 12, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S331">Mrs. Gillibrand</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S350">Mr. Rubio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S221">Mrs. Feinstein</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S153">Mr. Grassley</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Expressing the sense of the Senate that children trafficked for sex in the United States should not
			 be treated or regarded as child prostitutes because there
			 is no such thing as a <quote>child prostitute</quote>, only children who are victims or survivors of rape and sex trafficking.	</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
 <whereas><text>Whereas the Federal Bureau of Investigation estimates that hundreds of thousands of children in the United States are at risk of being commercially exploited through sex trafficking;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas children as young as 11 years old may be subjected to the commercial sex market as victims of sex trafficking;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas many child victims of sex trafficking have experienced previous physical or sexual abuse, vulnerabilities that traffickers exploit to manipulate the victims into a life of sexual slavery through sex trafficking;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas many child victims of sex trafficking are hidden in plain view, standing at bus stops, in runaway and homeless youth shelters, and advertised online; and</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas many child victims of sex trafficking who have not yet attained the age of consent are arrested and detained for juvenile prostitution or status offenses directly related to their exploitation: Now, therefore, be it</text>
		</whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body>
 <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="S1" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That the Senate—</text> <paragraph id="ida552140d165046a998cba0cfc78c446c"><enum>(1)</enum><text>encourages the Departments of Justice, Health and Human Services, and Labor, and all other relevant Federal entities, to treat children trafficked for sex as victims or survivors of rape and sex trafficking;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id22f6367756374cc999118dcec6d0f5d5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>supports efforts to arrest and prosecute sex traffickers and buyers of children trafficked for sex, in accordance with applicable State and Federal sex trafficking statutes, and State child protection laws against abuse and statutory rape, in order to take all necessary measures to protect the most vulnerable children in the United States;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id8f1314d07d1b45c0982215bb0e04cd1c"><enum>(3)</enum><text>supports survivors of child sex trafficking, including efforts to raise awareness of this tragedy and of the comprehensive services necessary to heal from the trauma of sexual violence and exploitation;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id20832992966c49b198f2d5ef0b218b63"><enum>(4)</enum><text>urges lawmakers, law enforcement, the media, and the public to reframe the trafficking of children for sex as an act of violence against children and not as mere vice, prostitution, or sex work, because there is no such thing as a <quote>child prostitute</quote>, only children who are victims or survivors of rape and sex trafficking; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddcbb982cb92e41e59829e5228eadff79"><enum>(5)</enum><text>supports an end to the demand for children in the commercial sex market, by supporting efforts to ensure that children in the United States are not for sale and that any person who is trafficking or purchasing a child for sex shall be punished under the full force of the law.</text>
			</paragraph></section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


