<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="second-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 SRES 22 ATS: To constitute the minority party’s membership on certain committees for the One Hundred Fourteenth Congress, or until their successors are chosen.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. RES. 22</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20150107">January 7, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</sponsor> (for <cosponsor name-id="S198">Mr. Reid</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To constitute the minority party’s membership on certain committees for the One Hundred Fourteenth
			 Congress, or until their successors are chosen.</official-title>
	</form>
 <resolution-body display-resolving-clause="yes-display-resolving-clause" style="traditional"><section commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="S1" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the following shall constitute the minority party's membership on the following committees for the One Hundred Fourteenth Congress, or until their successors are chosen:</text><committee-appointment-paragraph><header><committee-name>Committee on Agriculture,
 Nutrition, and Forestry:</committee-name></header><text>Ms. Stabenow (Ranking), Mr. Leahy, Mr. Brown, Ms. Klobuchar, Mr. Bennet, Mrs. Gillibrand, Mr. Donnelly, Ms. Heitkamp, Mr. Casey.</text></committee-appointment-paragraph><committee-appointment-paragraph><header><committee-name>Committee on Appropriations:</committee-name></header><text>Ms. Mikulski (Ranking), Mr. Leahy, Mrs. Murray, Mrs. Feinstein, Mr. Durbin, Mr. Reed, Mr. Tester, Mr. Udall, Mrs. Shaheen, Mr. Merkley, Mr. Coons, Mr. Schatz, Ms. Baldwin, Mr. Murphy.</text></committee-appointment-paragraph><committee-appointment-paragraph><header><committee-name>Committee on Armed Services:</committee-name></header><text>Mr. Reed (Ranking), Mr. Nelson, Mrs. McCaskill, Mr. Manchin, Mrs. Shaheen, Mrs. Gillibrand, Mr. Blumenthal, Mr. Donnelly, Ms. Hirono, Mr. Kaine, Mr. King, Mr. Heinrich.</text></committee-appointment-paragraph><committee-appointment-paragraph><header><committee-name>Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs:</committee-name></header><text>Mr. Brown (Ranking), Mr. Reed, Mr. Schumer, Mr. Menendez, Mr. Tester, Mr. Warner, Mr. Merkley, Ms. Warren, Ms. Heitkamp, Mr. Donnelly.</text></committee-appointment-paragraph><committee-appointment-paragraph><header><committee-name>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation:</committee-name></header><text>Mr. Nelson (Ranking), Ms. Cantwell, Mrs. McCaskill, Ms. Klobuchar, Mr. Blumenthal, Mr. Schatz, Mr. Markey, Mr. Booker, Mr. Udall, Mr. Manchin, Mr. Peters.</text></committee-appointment-paragraph><committee-appointment-paragraph><header><committee-name>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources:</committee-name></header><text>Ms. Cantwell (Ranking), Mr. Wyden, Mr. Sanders, Ms. Stabenow, Mr. Franken, Mr. Manchin, Mr. Heinrich, Ms. Hirono, Mr. King, Ms. Warren.</text></committee-appointment-paragraph><committee-appointment-paragraph><header><committee-name>Committee on Environment and Public Works:</committee-name></header><text>Mrs. Boxer (Ranking), Mr. Carper, Mr. Cardin, Mr. Sanders, Mr. Whitehouse, Mr. Merkley, Mrs. Gillibrand, Mr. Booker, Mr. Markey.</text></committee-appointment-paragraph><committee-appointment-paragraph><header><committee-name>Committee on Finance:</committee-name></header><text>Mr. Wyden (Ranking), Mr. Schumer, Ms. Stabenow, Ms. Cantwell, Mr. Nelson, Mr. Menendez, Mr. Carper, Mr. Cardin, Mr. Brown, Mr. Bennet, Mr. Casey, Mr. Warner.</text></committee-appointment-paragraph><committee-appointment-paragraph><header><committee-name>Committee on Foreign Relations:</committee-name></header><text>Mr. Menendez (Ranking), Mrs. Boxer, Mr. Cardin, Mrs. Shaheen, Mr. Coons, Mr. Udall, Mr. Murphy, Mr. Kaine, Mr. Markey.</text></committee-appointment-paragraph><committee-appointment-paragraph><header><committee-name>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions:</committee-name></header><text>Mrs. Murray (Ranking), Ms. Mikulski, Mr. Sanders, Mr. Casey, Mr. Franken, Mr. Bennet, Mr. Whitehouse, Ms. Baldwin, Mr. Murphy, Ms. Warren.</text></committee-appointment-paragraph><committee-appointment-paragraph><header><committee-name>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs:</committee-name></header><text>Mr. Carper (Ranking), Mrs. McCaskill, Mr. Tester, Ms. Baldwin, Ms. Heitkamp, Mr. Booker, Mr. Peters.</text></committee-appointment-paragraph><committee-appointment-paragraph><header><committee-name>Select Committee on Intelligence:</committee-name></header><text>Mrs. Feinstein (Vice Chairman), Mr. Wyden, Ms. Mikulski, Mr. Warner, Mr. Heinrich, Mr. King, Ms. Hirono.</text></committee-appointment-paragraph><committee-appointment-paragraph><header><committee-name>Committee on the Judiciary:</committee-name></header><text>Mr. Leahy (Ranking), Mrs. Feinstein, Mr. Schumer, Mr. Durbin, Mr. Whitehouse, Ms. Klobuchar, Mr. Franken, Mr. Coons, Mr. Blumenthal.</text></committee-appointment-paragraph><committee-appointment-paragraph><header><committee-name>Committee on the Budget:</committee-name></header><text>Mr. Sanders (Ranking), Mrs. Murray, Mr. Wyden, Ms. Stabenow, Mr. Whitehouse, Mr. Warner, Mr. Merkley, Ms. Baldwin, Mr. Kaine, Mr. King.</text></committee-appointment-paragraph><committee-appointment-paragraph><header><committee-name>Committee on Rules and Administration:</committee-name></header><text>Mr. Schumer (Ranking), Mrs. Feinstein, Mr. Durbin, Mr. Udall, Mr. Warner, Mr. Leahy, Ms. Klobuchar, Mr. King.</text></committee-appointment-paragraph><committee-appointment-paragraph><header><committee-name>Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship:</committee-name></header><text>Mr. Cardin, (Ranking), Ms. Cantwell, Mrs. Shaheen, Ms. Heitkamp, Mr. Markey, Mr. Booker, Mr. Coons, Ms. Hirono, Mr. Peters.</text></committee-appointment-paragraph><committee-appointment-paragraph><header><committee-name>Committee on Veterans' Affairs:</committee-name></header><text>Mr. Blumenthal (Ranking), Mrs. Murray, Mr. Sanders, Mr. Brown, Mr. Tester, Ms. Hirono, Mr. Manchin.</text></committee-appointment-paragraph><committee-appointment-paragraph><header><committee-name>Special Committee on Aging:</committee-name></header><text>Mrs. McCaskill (Ranking), Mr. Nelson, Mr. Casey, Mr. Whitehouse, Mrs. Gillibrand, Mr. Blumenthal, Mr. Donnelly, Ms. Warren, Mr. Kaine.</text></committee-appointment-paragraph><committee-appointment-paragraph><header><committee-name>Joint Economic Committee:</committee-name></header><text>Mrs. Klobuchar, Mr. Casey, Mr. Heinrich, Mr. Peters.</text></committee-appointment-paragraph><committee-appointment-paragraph><header><committee-name>Select Committee on Ethics:</committee-name></header><text>Mrs. Boxer (Vice Chairman), Mr. Coons, Mr. Schatz.</text></committee-appointment-paragraph><committee-appointment-paragraph><header><committee-name>Committee on Indian Affairs:</committee-name></header><text>Mr. Tester (Vice Chairman), Ms. Cantwell, Mr. Udall, Mr. Franken, Mr. Schatz, Ms. Heitkamp.</text></committee-appointment-paragraph></section></resolution-body> </resolution> 

