<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="constitutional-amendment"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 SJ 7 IS: Proposing an amendment to the Constitution of the United States to clarify the authority of Congress and the States to regulate corporations, limited liability companies, and other corporate entities established by the laws of any State, the United States, or any foreign state.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IIA</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. J. RES. 7</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150204">February 4, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S314">Mr. Tester</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</cosponsor>) introduced the following joint resolution; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>
			</action-desc></action><legis-type>JOINT RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title>Proposing an amendment to the Constitution of the United States to clarify the authority of
			 Congress and the States to regulate corporations, limited liability
			 companies, and other corporate entities established by the laws of any
 State, the United States, or any foreign state.</official-title></form><resolution-body><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H472E0CC1EF3545CF860655844D0545E5" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That the following article is proposed as an amendment to the Constitution of the United States, which shall be valid to all intents and purposes as part of the Constitution when ratified by the legislatures of three-fourths of the several States:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD6680F42C1944575861A36F13146AA13" style="traditional"><constitution-article id="H1234"><enum> —</enum><section id="HFCD6489E5FFC4C769C598C8EAE198250" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The rights enumerated in this Constitution and other rights retained by the people shall be the rights of natural persons.</text></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H096DC9DCB9E94CDBB7640F066F94EBCD" section-type="section-one"><enum>2.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As used in this Constitution, the terms <term>people</term>, <term>person</term>, and <term>citizen</term> shall not include a corporation, a limited liability company, or any other corporate entity established by the laws of any State, the United States, or any foreign state.</text></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idEDEA56F16CF8474BABBF242CC1C429D3" section-type="section-one"><enum>3.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A corporate entity described in section 2 shall be subject to such regulation as the people, through representatives in Congress and State representatives, may determine reasonable, consistent with the powers of Congress and the States under this Constitution.</text></section><section id="HB9134A8D54C94B2EA1B49668BACDB18C" section-type="section-one"><enum>4.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Constitution shall be construed to limit the rights enumerated in this Constitution and other rights retained by the people, which are unalienable.</text></section></constitution-article><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></resolution-body></resolution>


