<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hconres" measure-number="134" measure-id="id114hconres134" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-05-26" update-date="2016-06-01">
<title>Expressing the sense of the Congress regarding the need for increased diversity and inclusion in the tech sector, and increased access to opportunity in science, technology, engineering, arts, and mathematics (STEAM) education.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hconres134v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-06-01">
<action-date>2016-05-26</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Declares that Congress supports efforts to:</p> <ul> <li>increase diversity and inclusion in the technology sector;</li> <li>eliminate barriers faced by people of color and other underrepresented groups when breaking into the technology sector;</li> <li>ensure all students have access to science, technology, engineering, arts, and mathematics (STEAM) education for a 21st century economy;</li> <li>strengthen investments in and collaborations with minority-serving educational institutions to sustain a pipeline of diverse STEAM graduates ready to enter the technology sector; and</li> <li>improve data collection, disaggregation, and dissemination of information for greater understanding and transparency of diversity in STEAM education and across the workforce. </li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
