<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hconres" measure-number="88" measure-id="id114hconres88" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-10-28" update-date="2016-05-26">
<title>Reaffirming the Taiwan Relations Act and the Six Assurances as cornerstones of United States-Taiwan relations.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hconres88v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-05-26">
<action-date>2016-05-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p> Affirms that the Taiwan Relations Act and the Six Assurances are both cornerstones of U.S.-Taiwan relations.</p> <p> Urges the President and Department of State to publicly, proactively, and consistently affirm the Six Assurances as a cornerstone of U.S.-Taiwan relations. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hconres88v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-10-30">
<action-date>2015-10-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Expresses the sense of Congress that the Taiwan Relations Act and the Six Assurances together form the cornerstone of U.S. relations with Taiwan.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
