<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hconres" measure-number="80" measure-id="id114hconres80" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-09-30" update-date="2015-10-14">
<title>Expressing the sense of the Congress on Hunger in our Communities.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hconres80v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-10-14">
<action-date>2015-09-30</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Expresses the sense of Congress on hunger in our communities by resolving that Congress should: </p> <ul> <li> increase support for programs that will strengthen wages and move the nation toward full employment; </li> <li>increase funding for programs such as Unemployment Insurance, Temporary Assistance for Needy Families (TANF), refundable tax credits, and the Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP, formerly known as the food stamp program); </li> <li>appropriate funds for the Department of Agriculture to operate and manage programs that are authorized as part of the Healthy Food Financing Initiative; </li> <li>permit nonprofit organizations that serve children through the Child and Adult Care Food Program and the Summer Food Service Program to operate one program year-round; and</li> <li>waive the on-site requirement for after-school and summer meals programs to allow communities to develop more effective ways to serve children outside of the school day. </li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
