<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hconres" measure-number="122" measure-id="id114hconres122" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-03-02" update-date="2016-10-07">
<title>PROTECT Patrimony Resolution</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hconres122v35" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-10-07">
<action-date>2016-09-29</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed Senate amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Protection of the Right of Tribes to stop the Export of Cultural and Traditional Patrimony Resolution or the PROTECT Patrimony Resolution</b></p> <p>(Sec. 4) Condemns the theft, illegal possession or sale, transfer, and export of tribal cultural items.<br> <br> Calls upon the Departments of the Interior, State, Commerce, Homeland Security, and Justice to consult with Native Americans in addressing these practices, to take affirmative action to stop these practices, and to secure repatriation of tribal cultural items.</p> <p>Supports the efforts of the Government Accountability Office to determine the scope of illegal trafficking in tribal cultural items and to discuss with Native Americans and others the steps required to end such trafficking.</p> Expresses support for restrictions on the export of tribal cultural items.]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hconres122v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-09-29">
<action-date>2016-09-21</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Protection of the Right of Tribes to stop the Export of Cultural and Traditional Patrimony Resolution or the PROTECT Patrimony Resolution</b></p> <p>Condemns the theft, illegal possession or sale, transfer, and export of tribal cultural items.<br> <br> Calls upon the Departments of the Interior, State, Commerce, Homeland Security, and Justice to consult with tribes and traditional Native American religious leaders in addressing this issue, to take affirmative action to stop these practices, and to secure repatriation of tribal cultural items.</p> Expresses support for restrictions on the export of tribal cultural items.]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hconres122v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-03-21">
<action-date>2016-03-02</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Protection of the Right of Tribes to stop the Export of Cultural and Traditional Patrimony Resolution or the PROTECT Patrimony Resolution</b></p> <p>Condemns the theft, illegal possession or sale, transfer, and export of tribal cultural items.<br> <br> Calls upon: (1) the Departments of the Interior, State, Commerce, Homeland Security, and Justice to consult with tribes and traditional Native American religious leaders in addressing this issue, to take affirmative action to stop these practices, and to secure repatriation of tribal cultural items; and (2) the Government Accountability Office to determine the scope of illegal trafficking in tribal cultural items and identify steps required to end such trafficking.</p> Expresses support for restrictions on the export of tribal cultural items.]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
