<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hconres" measure-number="156" measure-id="id114hconres156" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-09-15" update-date="2016-10-31">
<title>Directing the Joint Committee on the Library to accept a statue commemorating the Hungarian Revolution of 1956 for placement in the United States Capitol, authorizing the use of the rotunda of the Capitol for a ceremony for the presentation of the statue, and directing the Architect of the Capitol to place the statue in a suitable permanent location in the Capitol.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hconres156v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-10-31">
<action-date>2016-09-15</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Directs the Joint Committee on the Library to accept for placement in the United States Capitol the &quot;Lads of Pest&quot; statue provided by Hungary to commemorate the heroes of the Hungarian Revolution of 1956 on the occasion of the Revolution's 60th anniversary.</p> <p>Authorizes the Joint Committee to use the rotunda of the Capitol for a presentation ceremony for the statue.</p> <p>Directs the Architect of the Capitol, for one year after the presentation ceremony, to place the statue in the rotunda, and then provide for its placement in a suitable permanent location in the Capitol.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
