<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hconres" measure-number="144" measure-id="id114hconres144" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-07-13" update-date="2016-07-22">
<title>Recognizing the 75th anniversary of the American Tree Farm System.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hconres144v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-07-22">
<action-date>2016-07-13</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Recognizes the 75th anniversary of the American Tree Farm System. Encourages the public to participate in ceremonies and activities that recognize the importance of this program, working family-owned forests, and the clean water, wildlife habitat, and wood supply they provide. Supports conservation and management of the nation's trees and forests through landowner participation in the Conservation Reserve Program, the Environmental Quality Incentives Program, the Conservation Stewardship Program, and the Forest Stewardship Program.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
