<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hconres" measure-number="46" measure-id="id114hconres46" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-14" update-date="2015-09-29">
<title>Expressing the sense of the Congress that the National Institutes of Health should encourage a global pediatric clinical trial network, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hconres46v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-09-29">
<action-date>2015-05-14</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Expresses the sense of Congress that:</p> <ul> <li> the National Institutes of Health (NIH) should encourage a global pediatric clinical trial network through the allocation of grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements to supplement the salaries of new and early investigators who participate in it;</li> <li>NIH grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements should be awarded to participating entities, solely for the purpose of supplementing the salaries of such investigators; and</li> <li> the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) should engage the European Medicines Agency and other foreign regulatory entities during the formation of such network to encourage their participation and should continue to engage such entities, once such network becomes operational, to encourage and facilitate their participation with the goal of enhancing the network's global reach.</li> </ul> <ul> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
