<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hconres" measure-number="128" measure-id="id114hconres128" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-04-15" update-date="2016-04-18">
<title>Expressing the sense of Congress that the United States should continue to exercise its veto in the United Nations Security Council on resolutions regarding the Israeli-Palestinian peace process.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hconres128v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-04-18">
<action-date>2016-04-15</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Expresses the sense of Congress that:</p> <ul> <li>a durable resolution to the Israeli-Palestinian peace process can only come through direct, bilateral negotiations between Israel and the Palestinians;</li> <li>the U.N. cannot be a truly neutral arbiter of the Israeli-Palestinian conflict; and</li> <li>the United States should veto any U.N. Security Council resolution that inserts the Security Council into the peace process, unilaterally recognizes a Palestinian state, makes declarations concerning Israeli controlled territories, or dictates terms and a time line for the Israeli-Palestinian peace process.</li></ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
