<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hconres" measure-number="145" measure-id="id114hconres145" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-07-13" update-date="2016-09-14">
<title>Celebrating the 25th anniversary of the Albert Einstein Distinguished Educator Fellowship Program and recognizing the significant contributions of Albert Einstein Fellows.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hconres145v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-09-14">
<action-date>2016-07-13</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Recognizes:</p> <ul> <li> the significance of the 25th anniversary of the Albert Einstein Distinguished Educator Fellowship Program;</li> <li> the value of having current science, technology, engineering, and mathematics teachers directly engaged in the policymaking process; </li> <li> the sacrifices made by teachers who interrupt their careers to serve as Einstein Fellows; and</li> <li> the contributions of Einstein Fellows.</li> </ul> <p>Expresses support for the continuation of the program.</p> <p>Encourages federal agencies and congressional offices to host Einstein Fellows and to leverage the expertise of former Einstein Fellows.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
