<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hconres" measure-number="152" measure-id="id114hconres152" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-09-09" update-date="2016-10-28">
<title>Expressing the sense of Congress that the United States and the international community should support the Republic of Iraq and its people to recognize a province in the Nineveh Plain region, consistent with lawful expressions of self-determination by its indigenous peoples.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hconres152v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-10-28">
<action-date>2016-09-09</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Expresses the sense of Congress that:</p> <ul> <li> the return of the displaced indigenous peoples of the Nineveh Plain, including those in Iraq, to their ancestral homeland should be a policy priority of United States and the international community;</li> <li> their fundamental human rights should be fully restored upon their return to their homeland;</li> <li> the indigenous communities of Iraq's Nineveh Plain region have a right to security and self-determination within the federal structure of Iraq; </li> <li> the United States, the Counter ISIL Coalition, the international community, the government of Iraq, and the Kurdish regional government should remain committed to liberation, economic revitalization, and prosperity of that region; </li> <li> the United States, the international community, international observers, the government of Iraq, and the Kurdish regional government should be committed to the territorial integrity and security of the Nineveh Plain; and </li> <li> the United States, the Counter ISIL Coalition, the international community, and international observers should be committed to working with the national and regional governments of Iraq toward a sustainable security settlement in the Nineveh Plain.</li> </ul> <p> Expresses the sense of Congress that the United States and the international community should:</p> <ul> <li> make the peaceful resolution of questions pertaining to Iraq's disputed internal boundaries a priority;</li> <li> work with the national and regional governments of Iraq to oversee the peaceful reintegration of the indigenous peoples of the Nineveh Plain to their ancestral homeland; </li> <li> work with the national and regional governments of Iraq, including the Kurdish regional government, to establish the Nineveh Plain as an undisputed territory, politically represented by the indigenous peoples and communities of the region; and </li> <li>be committed to supporting the Iraqi government in implementing the decision to create a Nineveh Plain Province and support the new provincial administration to attain its full potential.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
