<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="H734F532E208D4D099D3E9222C9B70FB0" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="constitutional-amendment" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HJ 11 IH: Proposing an amendment to the Constitution of the United States to limit the number of consecutive terms that a Member of Congress may serve.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IA</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. J. RES. 11</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20150109">January 9, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001282">Mr. Barr</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="H001052">Mr. Harris</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001189">Mr. Austin Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000582">Mr. Roe of Tennessee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000597">Mr. Rice of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001192">Mr. Stewart</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001289">Mr. Byrne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000804">Mr. Wittman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001184">Mr. Massie</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000819">Mr. Walker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001180">Mr. McKinley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000813">Mrs. Walorski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000598">Mr. Rothfus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000570">Mr. Guinta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000615">Mr. Duncan of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000372">Mr. Allen</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001102">Mr. Clawson of Florida</cosponsor>) introduced the following joint resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>JOINT RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Proposing an amendment to the Constitution of the United States to limit the number of consecutive
			 terms that a Member of Congress may serve.</official-title>
	</form>
	<resolution-body id="H4F3B721F76654A81AB09A14AB634FA2B" style="constitutional-amendment">
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H75A3622B5C1547E8B89399106C7EDE48" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That the following article is proposed as an amendment to the Constitution of the United States,
			 which shall be valid to all intents and purposes as part of the
			 Constitution when ratified by the legislatures of three-fourths of the
			 several States within seven years after the date of its submission for
			 ratification:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC41CCE3246AE43C7AB7E4059378F0F6C" style="traditional">
				<constitution-article id="H1234"><enum> —</enum>
					<section id="H1DEC65919AE14217AFA7D4A7F192739B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No person who has been a Senator for two consecutive terms shall again be eligible for election or
			 appointment to the Senate until the date that is one year after the end of
			 such second consecutive term.</text>
					</section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4718EF8B5F294C1893903BC309C4263E" section-type="section-one"><enum>2.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No person who has been a Representative for six consecutive terms shall again be eligible for
			 election to the House of Representatives until the date that is one year
			 after the end of the sixth consecutive term.</text>
					</section><section id="H65149472925848FBB52DAB20BE0DBF2C" section-type="section-one"><enum>3.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this article, any term a person serves as a Senator or Representative to fill a
			 vacancy shall not be included in determining the number of consecutive
			 terms that the person has been a Senator or Representative unless the
			 period of time for which the person fills the vacancy is greater than
			 three years in the case of a Senator or greater than one year in the case
			 of a Representative.</text>
					</section><section id="HC643B0C864FF475B9FFFBCAF50282E45" section-type="section-one"><enum>4.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purposes of this article, any term that began before the date of the ratification of this
			 article shall not be included in determining the number of consecutive
			 terms that a person has been a Senator or Representative.</text>
					</section></constitution-article><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


