<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="H091C2B8054FB4701A7E4AE187B9D6E96" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="constitutional-amendment" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HJ 79 IH: Proposing a balanced budget amendment to the Constitution of the United States.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-12-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IA</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. J. RES. 79</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20151216">December 16, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001070">Mr. Hardy</sponsor> introduced the following joint resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>JOINT RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Proposing a balanced budget amendment to the Constitution of the United States.</official-title>
	</form>
	<resolution-body id="HDD34DCB93CB24A629332EA6A3C99071E" style="constitutional-amendment">
 <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H55F1C8F9D5CA438791F942CDF47F5433" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That the following article is proposed as an amendment to the Constitution of the United States, which shall be valid to all intents and purposes as part of the Constitution when ratified by the legislatures of three-fourths of the several States within seven years after the date of its submission for ratification:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H414EB5300A4D4AE49267F4B1D0775552" style="traditional">
				<constitution-article id="H1234"><enum> —</enum>
 <section id="H149F6EE7CAE9429EB10091F07C7CF4F9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Total outlays for any fiscal year shall not exceed total receipts for that fiscal year, unless three-fifths of the whole number of each House of Congress provides by law for a specific excess of outlays over receipts by a roll-call vote. Such total outlays do not include those for repayment of debt principal and such total receipts may not include those derived from borrowing.</text>
 </section><section id="H5FB424A2EC3347B78A511A15F79E36BB" section-type="section-one"><enum>2.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Before each fiscal year, the President shall transmit to the Congress a proposed budget for such fiscal year for the Government in which total outlays do not exceed total receipts. If the President fails to perform the duty imposed by this section, no Executive orders may be issued until the earlier of the date on which the President corrects such failure or the first day of such fiscal year.</text>
 </section><section id="H39DBCA53CAC140DBBDCEFF7E44D4548E" section-type="section-one"><enum>3.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The limit on the debt of the United States held by the public shall not be increased unless three-fifths of the whole number of each House of Congress provides by law for such an increase by a roll-call vote.</text>
 </section><section id="HF5A59A32DB3D42A68068ECBDFF55D7DB" section-type="section-one"><enum>4.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Congress may waive this article for any period during which the United States is engaged in military conflict that causes an imminent and serious military threat to national security and is so declared by a joint resolution, adopted by a majority of the whole number of each House of Congress, which becomes law.</text>
 </section><section id="HA70E907EE3F34D48984E61669EF3D03E" section-type="section-one"><enum>5.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Congress shall enforce and implement this article by appropriate legislation, which may rely on estimates of outlays and receipts.</text>
 </section><section id="HA5B68014B3234C3D8A3BE88250226B98" section-type="section-one"><enum>6.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Sections 1, 2, and 3 shall take effect with the beginning of the third fiscal year beginning after its ratification.</text>
					</section></constitution-article><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


