<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="HF1DB254B5566470C9135D5118DE2E993" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="constitutional-amendment" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HJ 34 IH: Proposing an amendment to the Constitution of the United States allowing the States to call a limited convention solely for the purposes of considering whether to propose a specific amendment to the Constitution.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-02-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IA</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. J. RES. 34</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20150213">February 13, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001048">Mr. Culberson</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="C001063">Mr. Cuellar</cosponsor>) introduced the following joint resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>JOINT RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Proposing an amendment to the Constitution of the United States allowing the States to call a
			 limited convention solely for the purposes of considering whether to
			 propose a specific amendment to the Constitution.</official-title>
	</form>
	<resolution-body id="H87B7A1C0BC63496FAD948CC6783ECF63" style="constitutional-amendment">
 <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HE9B9E1095FD8439E9D058E3DE5DB0E69" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the following article is proposed as an amendment to the Constitution of the United States, which shall be valid to all intents and purposes as part of the Constitution when ratified by the legislatures of three-fourths of the several States within seven years after the date of its submission for ratification:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H60223F6D898D4B1BBB2F8D5CD0B842E9" style="traditional">
				<constitution-article id="H1234"><enum> —</enum>
 <section id="H776D6ADBFE304646B84BBC827BD5DC96" section-type="undesignated-section"><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress, on application of the legislatures of two-thirds of the several States, which all contain an identical amendment, shall call a convention solely to decide whether to propose that specific amendment to the States, which, if proposed, shall be valid to all intents and purposes as part of this Constitution when ratified pursuant to Article V.</text>
					</section></constitution-article><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


