<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="H3322EB68B8A045ED8E7F259474D8CFAC" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="constitutional-amendment" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HJ 1 IH: Proposing a balanced budget amendment to the Constitution of the United States.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IA</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. J. RES. 1</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20150106">January 6, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000289">Mr. Goodlatte</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001159">Mrs. McMorris Rodgers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000362">Mr. King of Iowa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000533">Mr. Duncan of Tennessee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000448">Mr. Franks of Arizona</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000798">Mr. Walberg</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000567">Mr. Lance</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000583">Mr. Smith of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000611">Mr. Poliquin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000244">Mr. Sensenbrenner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000601">Mr. Palazzo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001060">Mr. Hurt of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000615">Mr. Duncan of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001150">Mrs. Miller of Michigan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000266">Mr. Chabot</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000603">Mr. Rouzer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000588">Mr. Pearce</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000487">Mr. Royce</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000587">Mr. Ribble</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000445">Mr. Forbes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000601">Mr. Ratcliffe</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001048">Mr. Culberson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001182">Mr. Mulvaney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001179">Mr. Marino</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000065">Mr. Yoho</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001151">Mr. Murphy of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000189">Mr. Newhouse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000570">Mr. Guinta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001093">Mr. Collins of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000821">Mr. Westerman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000470">Mr. Tipton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000568">Mr. Griffith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000576">Mr. Grothman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000552">Mr. Gohmert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000018">Mr. Salmon</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000592">Mr. Poe of Texas</cosponsor>) introduced the following joint resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>JOINT RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Proposing a balanced budget amendment to the Constitution of the United States.</official-title>
	</form>
	<resolution-body id="H2B2EA3950FEC4F7BA7A3F6F838CBBCA4" style="constitutional-amendment">
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H3D992AC1A14244838B5DE6BACC79F008" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That the following article is proposed as an amendment to the Constitution of the United States,
			 which shall be valid to all intents and purposes as part of the
			 Constitution when ratified by the legislatures of three-fourths of the
			 several States within seven years after the date of its submission for
			 ratification:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2B2E4FC6DCBA45FF82A671F0A8AE97DB" style="traditional">
				<constitution-article id="H1234"><enum> —</enum>
					<section id="H03F095C36D454EBEA023A2B23F117F8F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Total outlays for any fiscal year shall not exceed total receipts for that fiscal year, unless
			 three-fifths of the whole number of each House of Congress shall provide
			 by law for a specific excess of outlays over receipts by a rollcall vote.</text>
					</section><section id="HC8673A6BD5D6458787D425CB9144D3F5" section-type="section-one"><enum>2.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Total outlays for any fiscal year shall not exceed one-fifth of economic output of the United
			 States, unless two-thirds of each House of Congress shall provide for a
			 specific increase of outlays above this amount.</text>
					</section><section id="H8D071152DE284F9F9690712E6EEA7A64" section-type="section-one"><enum>3.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The limit on the debt of the United States held by the public shall not be increased unless
			 three-fifths of the whole number of each House shall provide by law for
			 such an increase by a rollcall vote.</text>
					</section><section id="HBCA8E5E1DEA14FED82642B482728A786" section-type="section-one"><enum>4.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Prior to each fiscal year, the President shall transmit to the Congress a proposed budget for the
			 United States Government for that fiscal year in which total outlays do
			 not exceed total receipts.</text>
					</section><section id="HDE02647747BC434F8E05272F71A48B03" section-type="section-one"><enum>5.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A bill to increase revenue shall not become law unless three-fifths of the whole number of each
			 House shall provide by law for such an increase by a rollcall vote.</text>
					</section><section id="HC69EFE47CCA04B8D97BAD04175DBAF30" section-type="section-one"><enum>6.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Congress may waive the provisions of this article for any fiscal year in which a declaration of
			 war is in effect. The provisions of this article may be waived for any
			 fiscal year in which the United States is engaged in military conflict
			 which causes an imminent and serious military threat to national security
			 and is so declared by a joint resolution, adopted by a majority of the
			 whole number of each House, which becomes law. Any such waiver must
			 identify and be limited to the specific excess or increase for that fiscal
			 year made necessary by the identified military conflict.</text>
					</section><section id="HCE3D2B6E34C24BE68895621A53C89777" section-type="section-one"><enum>7.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Congress shall enforce and implement this article by appropriate legislation, which may rely on
			 estimates of outlays and receipts.</text>
					</section><section id="HEEB9CBB25142485DA65FD96142FB52AE" section-type="section-one"><enum>8.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Total receipts shall include all receipts of the United States Government except those derived from
			 borrowing. Total outlays shall include all outlays of the United States
			 Government except for those for repayment of debt principal.</text>
					</section><section id="H7B4DC16524AC4E78B347357BA36EEFAB" section-type="section-one"><enum>9.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This article shall take effect beginning with the fifth fiscal year beginning after its
			 ratification.</text>
					</section></constitution-article><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


