<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2255" measure-id="id114s2255" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-11-05" update-date="2016-03-31">
<title>Stop Debt Collection Abuse Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2255v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-03-31">
<action-date>2015-11-05</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Stop Debt Collection Abuse Act of 2015</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Fair Debt Collection Practices Act to redefine: (1) "debt" to include any obligation or alleged obligation of a consumer to pay a loan, an overpayment, a fine, penalty, a fee, or other money to a federal agency and that is at least 180 days past due; and (2) "debt collector" to include any person who regularly collects debts owed or allegedly owed to a federal agency. </p> <p>A federal agency that is a creditor may sell or transfer a debt to a debt collector beginning 180 days after the obligation or alleged obligation arises. </p> <p>The Act is further amended by making the collection of any amount (including any interest, fee, charge, or expense incidental to the principal obligation) an unfair practice unless:</p> <ul> <li>the amount is expressly authorized by the agreement creating the debt or permitted by law (as under current law); or</li> <li>in the case of a debt owed a federal agency, the collection charge is reasonable in relation to actual collection costs, is authorized by a contract between the debt collector and the federal agency, and does not exceed 10% of the amount the debt collector collects. </li> </ul> <p>The Government Accountability Office must study the use of debt collectors by state and local government agencies. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
