<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2360" measure-id="id114s2360" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-12-07" update-date="2016-10-07">
<title>Omnibus Territories Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2360v35" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-10-07">
<action-date>2016-09-29</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed Senate amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the Senate on August 30, 2016. The summary of that version is repeated here.)</p> <p><strong>Omnibus Territories Act of 2015 </strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Supplemental Appropriations Act, 1982, to eliminate the restriction on the use of resettlement and relocation funds by people of the Bikini Atoll for resettlement and relocation to areas only within the Marshall Islands. </p> <p>The bill limits eligibility for the funds to Bikini people living on Kili and Ejit Islands, but they may use the funds to relocate and resettle outside the Marshall Islands. The use of resettlement funds is subject to the condition that the Department of the Interior submit to Congress a resettlement plan developed in coordination with the Bikini Atoll leadership.</p> <p>Annual fiscal year expenditures from the resettlement fund may not exceed 90% of its average annual earnings for the preceding five years unless for resettlement purposes outside of the Marshall Islands.</p> <p>(Sec. 3) To provide and sustain air transportation in American Samoa between the islands of Tutuila and Manu'a, the Department of Transportation may renew a foreign air carrier's emergency air transportation exemption every 180 days (instead of the current 30-day renewal period that still applies to other areas).</p> <p>(Sec. 4) The bill amends the REAL ID Act of 2005 to provide that citizens of the Republic of the Marshall Islands, the Federated States of Micronesia, and the Republic of Palau who have been admitted as nonimmigrants pursuant to a Compact of Free Association are eligible for driver's licenses or personal identification cards. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114s2360v01" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-10-04">
<action-date>2016-08-30</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to Senate amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Omnibus Territories Act of 2015 </strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Supplemental Appropriations Act, 1982, to eliminate the restriction on the use of resettlement and relocation funds by people of the Bikini Atoll for resettlement and relocation to areas only within the Marshall Islands. </p> <p>The bill limits eligibility for the funds to Bikini people living on Kili and Ejit Islands, but they may use the funds to relocate and resettle outside the Marshall Islands. The use of resettlement funds is subject to the condition that the Department of the Interior submit to Congress a resettlement plan developed in coordination with the Bikini Atoll leadership.</p> <p>Annual fiscal year expenditures from the resettlement fund may not exceed 90% of its average annual earnings for the preceding five years unless for resettlement purposes outside of the Marshall Islands.</p> <p>(Sec. 3) To provide and sustain air transportation in American Samoa between the islands of Tutuila and Manu'a, the Department of Transportation may renew a foreign air carrier's emergency air transportation exemption every 180 days (instead of the current 30-day renewal period that still applies to other areas).</p> <p>(Sec. 4) The bill amends the REAL ID Act of 2005 to provide that citizens of the Republic of the Marshall Islands, the Federated States of Micronesia, and the Republic of Palau who have been admitted as nonimmigrants pursuant to a Compact of Free Association are eligible for driver's licenses or personal identification cards. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114s2360v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-02-05">
<action-date>2015-12-07</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Omnibus Territories Act of 2015 </strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Supplemental Appropriations Act, 1982, to eliminate the restriction on the use of resettlement and relocation funds by people of the Bikini Atoll for resettlement and relocation only to areas within the Marshall Islands. </p> <p>The bill permits the use of foreign aircraft to provide and sustain air commerce in American Samoa between the islands of Tutuila and Manu'a. </p> <p>The bill amends the REAL ID Act of 2005 to provide that citizens of the Republic of the Marshall Islands, the Federated States of Micronesia, and the Republic of Palau who have been admitted as nonimmigrants pursuant to a Compact of Free Association are eligible for driver's licenses or personal identification cards. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
