<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2026" measure-id="id114s2026" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-09-10" update-date="2015-09-30">
<title>Stop Nuclear Waste by Our Lakes Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2026v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-09-30">
<action-date>2015-09-10</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Stop Nuclear Waste by Our Lakes Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>This bill directs the Department of State to request that the International Joint Commission: </p> <ul> <li>review the long-term impacts of the location of the Deep Geological Repository (proposed by the Ontario Power Generation for disposal of 7 million cubic feet of low- and intermediate-level nuclear waste at the Bruce Nuclear Power Plant in Kincardine, Ontario), including an examination of the conclusions reached in the Environmental Assessment Report of the Joint Review Panel, and whether those conclusions would adequately protect Lake Huron and the other Great Lakes from the risks posed by the operation of the Deep Geological Repository for low and intermediate-level nuclear waste; and </li> <li>issue a report on the Commission's findings to the governments of the United States and Canada. </li> </ul> <p>If Canada decides to dispose permanently of high-level nuclear waste at a site in close proximity to the Deep Geological Repository or another site in the Great Lakes Basin the Department shall: </p> <ul> <li> request the Commission to study the risks to the Great Lakes Basin of storing high-level nuclear waste in close proximity to the Deep Geological Repository or another site in the Great Lakes Basin, and </li> <li> bring the matter before the Commission. </li> </ul> <p>The Department shall undertake negotiations with Canada to: </p> <ul> <li>delay the final decision on the Deep Geologic Repository until after the Commission delivers the report required by this Act, </li> <li>delay any final decision to store high-level nuclear waste in close proximity to the Deep Geological Repository or another site in the Great Lakes Basin until after the Commission conducts the study required by this Act, and </li> <li>consent to bringing the matter of such disposal of high-level nuclear waste before the Commission.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
