<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1667" measure-id="id114s1667" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-06-24" update-date="2015-07-21">
<title>A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to clarify the special rules for accident and health plans of certain governmental entities, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1667v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-07-21">
<action-date>2015-06-24</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Amends the Internal Revenue Code, with respect to the exclusion from gross income of payments from an accident or health plan, to: (1) make the exclusion for payments to a beneficiary other than a spouse or dependent child applicable to plans established by or on behalf of a state or political subdivision thereof; and (2) define a "qualified taxpayer," for purposes of the exclusion, as an employee or the spouse, dependent, or child (under age 27) of an employee.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
