<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1823" measure-id="id114s1823" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-07-21" update-date="2015-09-03">
<title>A bill to safeguard military personnel on Armed Forces military installations by repealing bans on military personnel carrying firearms, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1823v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-09-03">
<action-date>2015-07-21</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill repeals (1) Army Regulation 190-14, entitled "Carrying of Firearms and Use of Force for Law Enforcement and Security Duties"; and (2) Department of Defense Directive Number 5210.56, entitled "Use of Deadly Force and the Carrying of Firearms by DOD Personnel Engaged in Law Enforcement and Security Duties." </p> <p>Any provision in any other law, rule, regulation, or executive order that prohibits military personnel trained in firearms use from carrying a firearm on a military installation or Department of Defense (DOD) site within the United States shall have no further force or effect and may not be enforced.</p> <p> Military personnel shall not be prohibited from carrying firearms on military installations or DOD sites. </p> <p>DOD or the commander of a military installation may prohibit a member of the Armed Forces, on a case-by-case basis, from carrying firearms on the military installation or DOD site if necessary to prevent the member from committing bodily harm to the member or others. </p> <p>DOD and the Secretaries of the military departments shall not reinstate the firearm bans repealed in this Act or enact similar firearms restrictions.</p> <p> The President shall not take any executive action or promulgate any rule, or issue any executive order or regulation, to prohibit military personnel from carrying firearms.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
