<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1745" measure-id="id114s1745" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-07-09" update-date="2016-03-16">
<title>Extracurricular Programs for Indian Children Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1745v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-03-16">
<action-date>2015-07-09</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Extracurricular Programs for Indian Children Act of 2015</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act to require the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to provide grants for before-school, after-school, and summer school programs for Indian and Alaska Native students. Entities eligible for grants include Indian tribes, local educational agencies with more than 10% Indian or Alaska Native students, schools within Indian reservations, tribal colleges and universities, and tribal nonprofit organizations.</p> <p>Grants may be used for activities that advance or improve student academic achievement and well-being, including education activities, Native language and culture programs, physical fitness activities, programs that promote parental involvement, substance abuse and violence prevention programs, health and mental health services, and transportation services.</p> The bill amends the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act and the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 to make entities that are eligible for the grants in this Act eligible for the school lunch program, summer food service program for children, child and adult care food program, and school breakfast program.]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
