<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1839" measure-id="id114s1839" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-07-22" update-date="2015-09-03">
<title>Servicemembers Self-Defense Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1839v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-09-03">
<action-date>2015-07-22</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Servicemembers Self-Defense Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>This bill excludes lands and buildings owned or leased by the Department of Defense (DOD) from the the ban against possession of firearms and dangerous weapons on federal facilities with respect to a qualified member of the Armed Forces.</p> <p>The possession of a concealed or open-carry firearm by a member of the Armed Forces on a military installation, if lawful under the laws of the state in which the installation is located, is not a violation of the Uniform Code of Military Justice.</p> <p>DOD shall amend DOD Directive number 5210.56 to allow members of the Armed Forces to possess firearms for defensive purposes on DOD facilities and installations in a manner consistent with the laws of the state in which the facility or installation is located. </p> <p>A qualified member of the Armed Forces carrying DOD-issued photographic identification may carry a concealed firearm that has been shipped or transported in interstate or foreign commerce. Such authorization shall not be construed to supersede or limit the laws of any state that: (1) permit private persons or entities to prohibit or restrict the possession of concealed firearms on their property; or (2) prohibit or restrict the possession of firearms on any state or local government property, installation, building, base, or park.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
