<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2201" measure-id="id114s2201" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-10-22" update-date="2016-05-13">
<title>Global Gateways Trade Capacity Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2201v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-05-13">
<action-date>2015-10-22</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Global Gateways Trade Capacity Act of 2015</b></p> <p>This bill places primary responsibility on the Department of State for coordinating a whole-of-government effort to expand U.S. efforts in trade capacity building.</p> <p>&quot;Trade facilitation&quot; shall mean U.S. bilateral, regional, or multilateral assistance whose primary purpose is to support:</p> <ul> <li>implementation by developing countries of the World Trade Organization Trade Facilitation Agreement, and </li> <li>assistance to reduce non-tariff barriers to trade at national borders in such countries.</li> </ul> <p>&quot;Trade capacity building assistance&quot; shall mean U.S. bilateral, regional, or multilateral assistance whose primary purpose is to support technical assistance to developing countries in:</p> <ul> <li>implementing international trade agreements;</li> <li>improving governance and transparency with respect to imports, exports, and international investment;</li> <li>establishing and implementing internationally recognized standards; and </li> <li>facilitating trade flows in a recipient country.</li> </ul> <p>The President shall establish an interagency coordinating committee to develop a biennial governmentwide joint strategic plan for trade capacity building in developing countries.</p> <p>The State Department shall:</p> <ul> <li>establish a trade capacity advisory committee, and </li> <li>establish a pilot project to coordinate a whole-of-government effort to expand U.S. efforts in trade facilitation assistance for developing countries.</li> </ul> <p>U.S. embassies in trade facilitation pilot countries shall develop biennially a specific trade facilitation assistance component for their mission plans.</p> <p>The State Department may designate developing countries to participate in the trade facilitation assistance pilot program.</p> <p>The Foreign Service Act of 1980 is amended to place on the chief of mission to a foreign country responsibility to coordinate and supervise the implementation of all U.S. trade-related and trade capacity assistance among all federal departments and agencies present in that country (except for assistance under the control of a U.S. area military commander).</p> <p>In developing trade capacity embassy mission plans on trade capacity, the trade capacity mission team shall convene local representatives of the U.S. private sector to consult on issues affecting trade capacity at the borders of participating countries.</p> <p>The Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 is amended to exempt from the prohibition against police training in a foreign country any training and technical assistance for customs and transportation authorities and personnel in recipient countries to implement priority trade capacity building assistance.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
