<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1220" measure-id="id114s1220" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-06" update-date="2015-09-11">
<title>Energy Distribution Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1220v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-09-11">
<action-date>2015-05-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Energy Distribution Act of 2015</b> </p> <p>This bill requires the Department of Energy (DOE) to collaborate with other federal agencies to improve the conceptual development of energy security, considering at a minimum: </p> <ul> <li> development of flexible, transparent, and competitive energy markets, including natural gas and oil markets; </li> <li> diversification of energy fuels, sources, and routes; and </li> <li> encouragement of indigenous sources of energy supply.</li> </ul> <p>DOE must: (1) lead an interagency effort to improve and coordinate data collection and analytical and modeling capabilities for energy distribution on shared energy infrastructure; and (2) coordinate the training of, and enhanced dialogue among, technical staff in federal agencies responsible for cross-border energy projects evaluation and implementation.</p> <p> The Energy Information Administration must collaborate with officials in Canada and Mexico to improve:</p> <ul> <li>the quality and transparency of North American energy data through reconciliation of data on energy trade flows among the U.S., Canada, and Mexico;</li> <li>the extension of energy mapping capabilities in those countries; and</li> <li>the development of common energy data terminology among the three nations. </li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
