<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="3158" measure-id="id114s3158" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-07-12" update-date="2016-09-29">
<title>ALLOW Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s3158v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-09-29">
<action-date>2016-07-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Alternatives to Licensing that Lower Obstacles to Work Act of 2016 or the ALLOW Act</b></p> <p>This bill declares, for purpose of establishing an individual's authorization to engage in an occupation on a military installation located on federally-owned land, that the federal government endorses state (including the District of Columbia) granted occupational licenses and certifications, regardless of whether the military installation is located in the issuing state or DC, provided that:</p> <ul> <li> the license or certification is not expired, revoked, or suspended by the state or DC; and</li> <li> there are no outstanding enforcement actions against the individual brought by the licensing board or certifying authority for that occupation in either of them.</li> </ul> <p><i>District of Columbia Occupational Licensing Reform Act</i></p> <p>The bill declares the DC policy regarding occupational licensing laws.</p> <p>The bill establishes an Office of Supervision of Occupational Boards in the office of the Attorney General for the District of Columbia, or another appropriate DC government agency, to be responsible for exercising active supervision over each covered DC occupational licensing board to ensure compliance with the policy.</p> <p>The bill prescribes procedures for the Office's review, approval, or rejection of occupational licensure actions proposed by each covered board before their adoption. A DC resident or licensee who operates a business in DC may file a complaint to the Office about a covered agency's inconsistency with DC policy. An authorized appeal of the Office's decision shall be to the Superior Court of the District of Columbia.</p> <p>The DC Council shall establish a legislative committee or subcommittee composed exclusively of current Council members to: (1) analyze occupational regulations, and (2) review any proposed legislation to impose or modify them to ensure compliance.</p> <p>The Council may not enact the legislation before it has specifically voted to adopt or reject any modification to such regulations.</p> <p>An individual may engage in a lawful occupation without being subject to occupational regulations that are: (1) arbitrary, or (2) unnecessary and substantially burdensome.</p> <p>The DC government and its covered boards may not require an occupational license, certification, or registration for a person, or impose any other occupational regulation that imposes a substantial burden on a person, unless:</p> <ul> <li> the government has an important interest in protecting against present and recognizable harm to public health, safety, or welfare; and</li> <li>the regulation is substantially related to achievement of that interest.</li> </ul> <p>An individual may assert as a defense in any administrative or judicial proceeding to enforce an occupational regulation that a required standard under this bill has not been met.</p> <p>Any person providing tour guide services for a fee within a national military park, national battlefield, national battlefield park, or national battlefield site or outdoor portions of the National Mall and Memorial Parks, including the Lincoln Memorial and the Jefferson Memorial, shall not be required to obtain a license, certification, or permit of any kind to provide those services.</p> <p>The Department of the Interior shall ensure that specified restrictions apply equally to all persons providing, or attempting to provide, tour guide services, without regard to employment by, or a contractual relationship with, the National Park Service.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
