<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="607" measure-id="id114s607" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-02-27" update-date="2016-02-24">
<title>Rural Community Hospital Demonstration Extension Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s607v35" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-02-24">
<action-date>2016-01-20</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed Senate amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Rural Community Hospital Demonstration Extension Act of 2015</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Medicare Prescription Drug, Improvement, and Modernization Act of 2003, as amended by the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act, to extend the period of the Medicare rural community hospital demonstration program from 5 to 10 years.</p> <p>The Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) shall allow certain rural community hospitals participating in the demonstration program as of December 30, 2014, to continue during the second five years of the 10-year extension period.</p> <p>HHS shall solicit applications to select up to the maximum number of additional rural community hospitals located in any state to participate in this demonstration program for the second five years of the ten-year extension period without exceeding the applicable limitation (30).</p> <p> In determining which applicant rural community hospitals to select for participation in the demonstration program, HHS:</p> <ul> <li>shall give priority to hospitals located in one of the 20 states with the lowest population densities; and</li> <li>may consider closures of hospitals located in rural areas in the state in which the hospital is located during the 5-year period immediately preceding the enactment of this Act, as well as the population density of the state.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114s607v01" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-08-06">
<action-date>2015-07-30</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to Senate amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Rural Community Hospital Demonstration Extension Act of 2015</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Medicare Prescription Drug, Improvement, and Modernization Act of 2003, as amended by the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act, to extend the period of the Medicare rural community hospital demonstration program from 5 to 10 years.</p> <p>Requires the Department of Health and Human Services to allow rural community hospitals participating in the demonstration program as of December 30, 2014, to continue during the second five years of the 10-year extension period.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114s607v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-03-13">
<action-date>2015-02-27</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Rural Community Hospital Demonstration Extension Act of 2015</b></p> <p>Amends the Medicare Prescription Drug, Improvement, and Modernization Act of 2003, as amended by the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act, to extend the period of the rural community hospital demonstration program from 5 to 10 years.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
