<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2121" measure-id="id114s2121" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-10-01" update-date="2015-11-16">
<title>Preserving American Access to Information Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2121v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-11-16">
<action-date>2015-10-01</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Preserving American Access to Information Act </strong></p> <p>This bill directs: (1)&nbsp;the President to take appropriate actions to enhance the authority and capacity of the National Declassification Center under Executive Order 13526, or any successor executive order, to promote a government-wide strategy for the declassification of information; (2) the National Declassification Center to provide for consultation between the Center's advisory panel and the public on a regular basis; (3) federal agencies to make efforts to identify and designate historically valuable records during the initial classification process to ensure preservation and timely access to such records following eventual declassification; (4) the Public Interest Declassification Board to submit reports to Congress on pilot programs to assess the feasibility and&nbsp;advisability of mechanisms to improve the current declassification capabilities of such agencies; and (5) the Public Interest Declassification Board to review the rules of the Senate and the House of Representatives regarding the declassification of classified Committee records and make recommendations to improve declassification efforts.</p> <p>The bill requires federal agency heads that classify information to report to Congress on&nbsp;an assessment of the feasibility and advisability of: (1)&nbsp;replacing the&nbsp;agency's current classification system with a two-tiered system,&nbsp;and&nbsp;(2) declassifying records with classified Formerly Restricted Data. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
