<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1234" measure-id="id114s1234" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-06" update-date="2015-05-28">
<title>FIX Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1234v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-05-28">
<action-date>2015-05-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>FIX Credit Reporting Errors Act or the FIX Act</b></p> <p> Amends the Fair Credit Reporting Act with respect to the procedures followed by consumer reporting agencies when a consumer disputes the completeness or accuracy of information contained in the consumer's credit report.</p> <p>Requires consumer reporting agencies to: (1) expand the dispute notification furnished to any person who provided disputed information to include all documentation provided by the consumer, and (2) consider such consumer documentation when conducting reinvestigations of disputed information. </p> <p>Directs a consumer reporting agency that operates as reseller, if it receives notice from a consumer of a dispute concerning a report that the reseller produced but the reseller determines that the information is not incomplete or inaccurate as a result of an act or omission of the reseller, to convey the notice of the dispute, together with all relevant information and documentation provided by the consumer, to each consumer reporting agency that provided the reseller with the information that is the subject of the dispute.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
