<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2562" measure-id="id114s2562" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-02-22" update-date="2016-10-03">
<title>Heroin and Prescription Drug Abuse Prevention and Reduction Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2562v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-10-03">
<action-date>2016-02-22</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Heroin and Prescription Drug Abuse Prevention and Reduction Act</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Controlled Substances Act to revise requirements for and limitations on practitioners who dispense narcotic drugs for maintenance or detoxification treatment.</p> <p>The Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) must establish grant programs to: (1) encourage prescribing and purchase of opioid overdose reversal drugs (e.g., naloxone), and (2) develop prescribing guidelines for such drugs. (Opioids are drugs with effects similar to opium, such as heroin or certain pain medications.)</p> <p>The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention must provide support to improve drug overdose surveillance and reporting capabilities.</p> <p>HHS may support syringe exchange programs.</p> <p>The Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration must provide support to reduce drug overdose deaths.</p> <p>This bill amends the Public Health Service Act to extend residential treatment programs for pregnant and postpartum women.</p> <p>HHS must: (1) carry out a pilot program to support services for pregnant and postpartum women with a substance use disorder; (2) award grants to expand treatment activities in areas with a high rate of, or a rapid increase in, the use of opioids; (3) support increasing the capacity of substance use disorder services for adolescents; and (4) develop, expand, and enhance substance use recovery support services.</p> <p>This bill amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) and Internal Revenue Code to direct HHS and the Departments of Labor and the Treasury to require disclosures, issue guidance, conduct audits, and publish information regarding the requirement for group health plans and health insurance coverage to have parity between mental health and substance use disorder benefits and medical and surgical benefits. HHS must establish a consumer parity portal website.</p> <p>HHS must establish a loan repayment program for substance use disorder health professionals.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
