<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2928" measure-id="id114s2928" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-05-12" update-date="2016-07-15">
<title>A bill to require an expedited decision with respect to securing land-based missile fields, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2928v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-07-15">
<action-date>2016-05-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill directs the Department of Defense, in order to mitigate the risk posed to U.S. nuclear forces by the failure to replace the UH-1N helicopter, to make (and implement within 60 days) a decision for securing land-based missile fields using alternative helicopters, or making a change in security posture, until the acquisition process for a replacement helicopter has concluded. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
