<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2815" measure-id="id114s2815" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-04-19" update-date="2016-06-21">
<title>United States Semiquincentennial Commission Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2815v82" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-06-21">
<action-date>2016-06-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed Senate without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p><strong>United States Semiquincentennial Commission Act of 2016</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 4) This bill establishes the United States Semiquincentennial Commission to plan, develop, and coordinate the commemoration of U.S. history leading up to the 250th anniversary of the founding of the United States.</p> <p>(Sec. 5) The Commission shall: (1) prepare an overall program for the commemoration; (2) plan, encourage, develop, and coordinate observances and activities commemorating the historic events associated with the Semiquincentennial; (3) emphasize the planning of events in locations of historical significance to the United States; (4) give special emphasis to the role of persons and locations with significant impact on U.S. history beginning on the date of execution of the Declaration of Independence and to the ideas associated with that history; and (5) submit to the President a comprehensive report that includes its specific recommendations for such commemoration.</p> <p>(Sec. 6) The Department of the Interior shall study and report to the Commission on appropriate actions that might be taken to further preserve and develop historic sites and battlefields to ensure that fitting observances and exhibits may be held at such sites during the celebration.</p> <p> The Federal Council on the Arts and the Humanities, the National Endowment for the Arts, the National Endowment for the Humanities, the Library of Congress, the Smithsonian Institution, and the National Archives shall cooperate with the Commission. The Secretary of State shall coordinate the participation of foreign nations in the celebration.</p> <p>(Sec. 9) All expenditures of the Commission shall be made solely from donated funds and from funds specifically appropriated for the Commission. </p> <p>The Commission shall seek to enter into an arrangement with USA 250, Incorporated, to house the administrative offices of the Commission, assume responsibility for Commission funds, and provide financial and administrative services. </p> <p>The Commission shall submit a report annually on its activities, including an accounting of funds received and expended.</p> <p>(Sec. 10) The Commission shall terminate on December 31, 2027.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114s2815v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-05-05">
<action-date>2016-04-19</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>United States Semiquincentennial Commission Act of 2016</strong></p> <p>This bill establishes the United States Semiquincentennial Commission to plan, develop, and coordinate the commemoration of U.S. history leading up to the 250th anniversary of the founding of the United States.</p> <p>The Commission shall: (1) prepare an overall program for the commemoration; (2) plan, encourage, develop, and coordinate observances and activities commemorating the historic events associated with the Semiquincentennial; (3) emphasize the planning of events in locations of historical significance to the United States; and (4) give special emphasis to the role of persons and locations with significant impact on U.S. history beginning on the date of execution of the Declaration of Independence and to the ideas associated with that history. </p> <p>The Department of the Interior shall study and report to the Commission on appropriate actions that might be taken to further preserve and develop historic sites and battlefields to ensure that fitting observances and exhibits may be held at such sites during the celebration.</p> <p> The Federal Council on the Arts and the Humanities, the National Endowment for the Arts, the National Endowment for the Humanities, the Library of Congress, the Smithsonian Institution, and the National Archives shall cooperate with the Commission. The Secretary of State shall coordinate the participation of foreign nations in the celebration.</p> <p>The Commission shall seek to enter into an arrangement with USA 250, Incorporated, to house the administrative offices of the Commission, assume responsibility for Commission funds, and provide financial and administrative services. </p> <p>The Commission shall terminate on December 31, 2027.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
