<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1728" measure-id="id114s1728" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-07-09" update-date="2015-07-21">
<title>Access to Court Challenges for Exempt Status Seekers (ACCESS) Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1728v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-07-21">
<action-date>2015-07-09</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Access to Court Challenges for Exempt Status Seekers (ACCESS) Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>Amends the Internal Revenue Code to expand the availability of the declaratory judgment legal remedy to all organizations that are currently classified as tax-exempt (currently, limited to "c-3" charitable, religious, or educational organizations) and to religious and apostolic organizations, for purposes of determining the initial or continuing qualification of such organizations for a tax exemption. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
