<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1485" measure-id="id114s1485" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-06-02" update-date="2016-08-04">
<title>Water Efficiency Innovation Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1485v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-08-04">
<action-date>2015-06-02</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Water Efficiency Innovation Act of 2015</b></p> <p>This bill requires the Department of Energy (DOE) to expand its Industrial Assessment Centers program to: (1) provide assessment services to water and wastewater treatment facilities comparable to those for other energy efficiency improvements, and (2) equip the centers with the training and tools necessary to provide technical assistance on energy savings to those facilities.</p> <p>A center is located at an institution of higher education that: (1) receives funding from DOE; (2) provides an in-depth assessment of small- and medium-sized manufacturer plant sites to evaluate the facilities, services, and manufacturing operations of the plant sites; and (3) identifies opportunities for potential savings for those sites from energy efficiency improvements, waste minimization, pollution prevention, and productivity improvement. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
