<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1454" measure-id="id114s1454" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-21" update-date="2015-12-07">
<title>Transportation and Logistics Hiring Reform Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1454v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-12-07">
<action-date>2015-05-21</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Transportation and Logistics Hiring Reform Act</strong></p> <p>This bill establishes a national hiring standard for motor carriers.</p> <p>The bill defines an"entity" as a person acting as:</p> <ul> <li>a shipper or a consignee; </li> <li> a broker, a freight forwarder, or a household goods freight forwarder;</li> <li> a non-vessel-operating common carrier, an ocean freight forwarder, or an ocean transportation intermediary;</li> <li> an indirect air carrier authorized to operate under a Standard Security Program approved by the Transportation Security Administration; </li> <li> a federally licensed customs broker;</li> <li>an interchange motor carrier; or</li> <li> a warehouse. </li></ul> <p>Before tendering a shipment, but not more than 35 days before the pickup of a shipment by the hired motor carrier, an entity shall verify that the carrier:</p> <ul> <li> is registered with and authorized by the Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration (FMCSA) to operate as a motor carrier or household goods motor carrier; </li> <li> has the minimum insurance coverage required by federal law; and </li> <li> does not have an unsatisfactory safety fitness rating issued by the FMCSA.</li> </ul> <p>Only evidence of an entity's compliance with this Act may be admitted as evidence in a civil action for damages resulting from a claim of negligent selection or retention of such motor carrier against the entity. No other motor carrier data created or maintained by the FMCSA, including safety measurement system data or analysis of such data, may be admitted in a case or proceeding in which it is asserted or alleged that an entity's selection or retention of a motor carrier was negligent. </p> <p>The Secretary of Transportation shall promulgate safety fitness determination regulations that update and revise the standards for establishing an unsatisfactory safety rating for motor carriers. In the regulations promulgated, the Secretary shall determine if a carrier is not fit to operate a commercial motor vehicle in or affecting interstate commerce.</p> <p> All commercial carriers shall comply with all applicable federal laws pertaining to safety.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
