<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2273" measure-id="id114s2273" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-11-10" update-date="2015-11-19">
<title>STARTUP Vets Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2273v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-11-19">
<action-date>2015-11-10</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Strengthening Technical Assistance, Resources, and Training to Unleash the Potential of Veterans Act of 2015 or the STARTUP Vets Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Small Business Act to require the Small Business Administration (SBA) to make two-year renewable grants to create and operate incubators and accelerators that provide technical assistance and training to covered individuals on how to become successful entrepreneurs and form small business concerns.</p> <p>Such program shall be considered an SBA management and technical assistance training program. </p> <p>Program outreach materials shall be made available at local Department of Veterans Affairs facilities. </p> <p>"Covered individual" means: </p> <ul> <li>a member of the Armed Forces, without regard to whether he or she participates in the Transition Assistance Program of the Department of Defense; </li> <li>an individual who is participating in the Transition Assistance Program; </li> <li>an individual who served on active duty in any branch of the Armed Forces, including the National Guard and Reserves, and was discharged or released under conditions other than dishonorable; and </li> <li>a spouse or dependent.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
