<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1653" measure-id="id114s1653" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-06-23" update-date="2015-09-22">
<title>Equalizing the Playing Field for Agents and Brokers Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1653v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-09-22">
<action-date>2015-06-23</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Equalizing the Playing Field</strong><strong> for Agents and Brokers Act</strong></p> <p> Directs the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to establish a toll-free customer service support help line to enable certified health insurance agents and brokers to seek assistance regarding qualified health plans offered in the federal health insurance marketplace.</p> <p>Amends the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act to require HHS to:</p> <ul> <li>make available on the federal government website for health insurance coverage a list of all certified agents and brokers;</li> <li>contract with the National Insurance Producers Registry to regularly verify the licensure status of all such agents and brokers and develop a mechanism to enable submission of changes to contact and licensure information; and</li> <li>provide trained navigators, agents, and brokers, no later than five business days after promulgation or issuance of any new cost- or enrollment-related policies, with a clear description of such policy changes.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
