<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2385" measure-id="id114s2385" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-12-10" update-date="2016-01-07">
<title>Eliminate, Neutralize, and Disrupt Wildlife Trafficking Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2385v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-01-07">
<action-date>2015-12-10</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Eliminate, Neutralize, and Disrupt Wildlife Trafficking Act</strong></p> <p>This bill directs the Presidential Task Force on Wildlife Trafficking to: </p> <ul> <li> identify countries of concern regarding the supply, poaching, or transit of wildlife and wildlife products;</li> <li>collaborate with the national wildlife service of a country of concern to analyze the threats to wildlife in that country, and to prepare a strategic plan with recommendations for addressing wildlife crime;</li> <li>coordinate efforts to implement strategic plans among federal agencies and non-federal partners; and </li> <li>coordinate with stakeholders qualified to provide assistance regarding anti-poaching activities, law enforcement efforts, and strategies to reduce illicit trade and reduce consumer demand for illegally traded wildlife and wildlife products.</li> </ul> <p>The Task Force shall terminate five years after enactment of this Act.</p> <p>The Department of State may provide defense articles, services, and training to security forces of a country of concern to counter wildlife trafficking and poaching. </p> <p> The State Department and the U.S. Agency for International Development, with respect to countries of concern, may: </p> <ul> <li>provide assistance to carry out strategic plan recommendations, including improving the effectiveness of wildlife law enforcement; </li> <li>design and implement programs to increase the investigational capacity of wildlife law enforcement and customs and border security officers and to combat the transnational trade in illegal wildlife; and </li> <li>take actions to strengthen international cooperation and partnerships to combat the global wildlife crime crisis.</li> </ul> <p>The State Department may also provide support in countries of concern to the development and replication of community-owned wildlife conservancies and community-based conservation programs.</p> <p>It is the sense of Congress that the United States should continue to work with foreign countries, including China, Thailand, and Vietnam to combat global wildlife trafficking.</p> <p>The State Department should implement agreements with China and initiate negotiations with Thailand and Vietnam aimed at reducing demand for ivory and rhinoceros horn (Vietnam), and eliminating illegal trade in wildlife and wildlife products. </p> <p> It is the sense of Congress that efforts to find funds to carry out this Act should not result in an increase in amounts authorized to be appropriated for a fiscal year to provide additional funds for overseas contingency operations.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
