<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2740" measure-id="id114s2740" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-04-04" update-date="2016-04-07">
<title>A bill to prohibit the transfer or release of individuals detained at United States Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba, to state sponsors of terrorism.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2740v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-04-07">
<action-date>2016-04-04</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill prohibits the use of funds available to the Department of Defense (DOD) to transfer, release, or assist in the transfer or release to Libya, Somalia, Yemen, or a country that is a state sponsor of terrorism of Khalid Sheikh Mohammed or any other detainee who: </p> <ul> <li>is not a U.S. citizen or a member of the Armed Forces; and </li> <li> is or was held by DOD on or after January 20, 2009, at Naval Station Guantanamo Bay, Cuba.</li></ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
