<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1224" measure-id="id114s1224" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-06" update-date="2015-09-11">
<title>Condensate Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1224v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-09-11">
<action-date>2015-05-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Condensate Act of 2015</b></p> <p>This bill requires the Department of Energy to develop a standard definition of the term &quot;condensate&quot; and, subsequently, advise relevant federal agencies to adopt that definition in order to clarify U.S. energy policy. </p> <p>The Assistant Secretary for Fossil Energy may assess the suitability of condensate separately from crude oil for use in strategic reserves. </p> <p>The Energy Information Administration must collect data concerning the chemical properties of domestically produced condensate and crude oil.</p> <p>The Department of the Interior must assess condensate separately from crude oil.</p> <p>The bill authorizes:</p><ul> <li>the Bureau of Ocean Energy Management to estimate condensate separately from crude oil as part of the resource assessments regarding domestic geological formations, </li> <li>the Office of Natural Resources Revenue Data Collection to collect condensate data separately from crude oil, and </li> <li>the United States Geological Survey to include estimates of condensate separately from crude oil as part of the resource assessments regarding domestic geological formations. </li> </ul> <p> Congress declares that processed condensate is a petroleum product.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
