<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1232" measure-id="id114s1232" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-06" update-date="2015-09-18">
<title>Smart Grid Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1232v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-09-18">
<action-date>2015-05-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Smart Grid Act of 2015</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007 to direct the Department of Energy (DOE), in collaboration with the National Institute of Standards and Technology of the Department of Commerce, the Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers, and the Smart Grid Interoperability Panel, to establish the Smart Grid Interoperability Working Group.</p> <p>The purpose of the Group is to:</p> <ul> <li> identify additional efforts the federal government can take to better promote the establishment and adoption of open standards that enhance connectivity and interoperability on the electric grid,</li> <li> study the market and policy barriers to deploying responsive appliances at scale, and </li> <li> develop a plan for establishing and promoting the widespread adoption of interoperability standards.</li> </ul> <p>The Smart Grid Regional Demonstration Initiative shall identify best practices for the implementation of the Fair Information Practice Principles (FIPPS) of the Federal Trade Commission for the collection, use, disclosure, and retention of individual customer information.</p> <p>When selecting smart grid demonstration projects to receive assistance, DOE shall ensure: (1) geographical diversity, and (2) diversity among types of electricity markets and regulatory environments.</p> <p>Additionally, DOE must make grants, on a competitive basis, for demonstration projects in any of seven designated program areas, including:</p> <ul> <li>transactive energy,</li> <li> innovation in valuation of new technology grid services and efficiency,</li> <li>rate design-distribution system, and </li> <li>rate design-consumer acceptance of time-based pricing.</li> </ul> <p>As a prerequisite for financial assistance, a participant in a smart grid demonstration project must provide information required by DOE, which shall become available through the smart grid information clearinghouse and for purposes of producing certain reports.</p> <p>DOE must also establish a working group composed of representatives of each project selected to receive assistance within a program area.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
