<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="3068" measure-id="id114s3068" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-06-16" update-date="2016-07-06">
<title>Department of the Interior, Environment, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s3068v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-07-06">
<action-date>2016-06-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Department of the Interior, Environment, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2017 </b></p> <p>Provides FY2017 appropriations for the Department of the Interior, the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), and related agencies. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to Interior for: </p> <ul> <li> the Bureau of Land Management, </li> <li> the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, </li> <li> the National Park Service, </li> <li> the U.S. Geological Survey, </li> <li> the Bureau of Ocean Energy Management, </li> <li> the Bureau of Safety and Environmental Enforcement, </li> <li> the Office of Surface Mining Reclamation and Enforcement, </li> <li> the Bureau of Indian Affairs and Bureau of Indian Education, and</li> <li>Departmental Offices.</li> </ul> <p>Provides appropriations to Interior for Department-Wide Programs, including Wildland Fire Management and Payments in Lieu of Taxes (PILT). </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the EPA. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Department of Agriculture for the Forest Service. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Department of Health and Human Services for: </p> <ul> <li> the Indian Health Service, </li> <li> the National Institutes of Health for the National Institute of Environmental Health Sciences, and </li> <li> the Agency for Toxic Substances and Disease Registry. </li> </ul> <p>Provides appropriations to other related agencies, including: </p> <ul> <li> the Executive Office of the President for the Council on Environmental Quality and the Office of Environmental Quality; </li> <li>the Chemical Safety and Hazard Investigation Board; </li> <li> the Office of Navajo and Hopi Indian Relocation; </li> <li> the Institute of American Indian and Alaska Native Culture and Arts Development; </li> <li> the Smithsonian Institution; </li> <li> the National Gallery of Art; </li> <li> the John F. Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts; </li> <li> the Woodrow Wilson International Center for Scholars; </li> <li> the National Foundation on the Arts and Humanities, including the National Endowment for the Arts and the National Endowment for the Humanities; </li> <li> the Commission of Fine Arts; </li> <li> the Advisory Council on Historic Preservation; </li> <li> the National Capital Planning Commission; </li> <li>the U.S. Holocaust Memorial Museum;</li> <li> Dwight D. Eisenhower Memorial Commission; and</li> <li>the Women's Suffrage Centennial Commission. </li> </ul> <p>Sets forth permissible and prohibited uses for funds provided by this and other appropriations Acts. </p> <p>Amends the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 to require specified adjustments to discretionary spending limits in FY2017-FY2026 to accommodate appropriations for wildfire suppression operations in the Wildland Fire Management accounts at USDA and Interior. </p> <p><i>Alaska Land Use Council Act </i></p> <p>Establishes a new Alaska Land Use Council to facilitate coordination and cooperation among federal, state, and Alaska Native Corporation and tribal land and resource managers in implementing the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act and other land and resource management laws. </p> <p><i>Women's Suffrage Centennial Commission Act </i></p> <p>Authorizes a Women's Suffrage Centennial Commission to commemorate the events that led to women gaining the right to vote, including the passage and ratification of the Nineteenth Amendment to the Constitution. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
