<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1843" measure-id="id114s1843" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-07-22" update-date="2015-09-04">
<title>Criminal Alien Notification Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1843v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-09-04">
<action-date>2015-07-22</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Criminal Alien Notification Act</strong></p> <p>This bill directs the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to establish a law enforcement notification system for every state. </p> <p>&quot;Law enforcement notification system&quot; means a secure information sharing system utilized by federal, state, tribal, and local law enforcement agencies to: </p> <ul> <li>notify the identification bureaus of the state from which an alien is being released and of the state in which the alien is intending to reside of the anticipated release from U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement custody of an alien who is inadmissible or deportable under specified grounds, and </li> <li>notify DHS of the release from custody of an alien who has been arrested for certain offenses the conviction of any one of which would render the alien inadmissible.</li> </ul> <p>DHS shall establish a secure information sharing system that enables state, tribal, and local courts to notify DHS of a protective order issued against an inadmissible or deportable alien who is under DHS supervision.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
