<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1364" measure-id="id114s1364" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-18" update-date="2015-06-04">
<title>Medicaid Generic Drug Price Fairness Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1364v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-06-04">
<action-date>2015-05-18</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Medicaid Generic Drug Price Fairness Act of 2015</b></p> <p>This bill amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to increase the amount of rebate with respect to each generic drug in the manner that the rebate for a dosage form and strength of a single source drug or an innovator multiple source drug is increased, except as provided in special application rules, including a special rule for certain noninnovator multiple source drugs.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
