<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2516" measure-id="id114s2516" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-02-09" update-date="2016-02-25">
<title>Army Arsenal Revitalization Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2516v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-02-25">
<action-date>2016-02-09</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Army Arsenal Revitalization Act of 2016</strong></p> <p>This bill requires the Defense Logistics Agency to report to Congress regarding Department of Defense (DOD) legacy items with a contract value equal to $5 million or more. </p> <p>DOD shall use Army arsenals for the production of these legacy items.</p> <p>DOD shall: (1) report to Congress listing all sole source contracts for the procurement of manufactured items the lack of which would constitute a critical national security issue, and (2) establish Army arsenals as a second source for production of any such manufactured item.</p> <p>DOD shall report to Congress regarding: </p> <ul> <li> DOD contracts awarded during FY2011-FY2015 using noncompetitive procedures for the procurement of equipment, weapons, weapons systems, and components with a contract value of $3 million or more; </li> <li> plans to update practices on Diminishing Manufacturing Sources and Material Shortages (DMSMS), including through the use of the organic industrial base as a resource in the implementation of a DMSMS management plan; and </li> <li> critical capabilities and minimum workloads of the Army arsenals, and fundamental elements for implementing the United States Army Organic Industrial Base Strategic Plan 2012-2022. </li> </ul> <p>DOD shall establish a three-year pilot program to permit Army arsenals to adjust their labor rates periodically throughout the year based upon changes in workload and other factors.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
