<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2141" measure-id="id114s2141" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-10-06" update-date="2016-06-06">
<title>TRUST IT Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2141v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-06-06">
<action-date>2015-10-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Transparent Ratings on Usability and Security to Transform Information Technology Act of 2015 or the TRUST IT Act</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Public Health Service Act to define &quot;information blocking&quot; and &quot;interoperability&quot; for health information technology (IT). Information blocking is preventing, discouraging, or interfering with the access, exchange, or use of electronic health information. Interoperability is the ability of health information systems to exchange information and use exchanged information.</p> <p>The Office of the National Coordinator for Health Information Technology (ONC) may publish information demonstrating how health IT meets the certification criteria of the voluntary health IT certification program. To be certified, health IT must meet security requirements, incorporate user-centered design, and achieve interoperability.</p> <p>Entities seeking certification of health IT must attest to meeting requirements regarding information blocking, communication between users and a certification body, and interoperability.<br> <br> The ONC must: (1) recognize a council to establish a rating program to evaluate the interoperability, usability, and security of health IT; (2) publish ratings from that program; (3) convene stakeholders to develop reporting criteria for entities offering health IT; and (4) establish a process for certification bodies to collect confidential feedback.</p> <p>The ONC may fine entities offering certified health IT that is rated less than satisfactory or entities that do not meet reporting requirements.</p> <p>The ONC may decertify health IT. The ONC must establish a revolving fund to reimburse users of health IT that becomes decertified for the cost of new certified health IT. Such users are exempt for one year from Medicare payment adjustment under the program that incentivizes meaningful use of electronic health records.</p> The ONC must publish information on individuals' rights under the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act (HIPAA).]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
