<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="159" measure-id="id114s159" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-01-13" update-date="2015-03-27">
<title>A bill to improve the operation of the Department of Homeland Security's Unmanned Aircraft System Program.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s159v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-03-27">
<action-date>2015-01-13</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Requires the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to fully utilize surveillance and detection capabilities developed or used by federal agencies to enhance the functioning and operational capability to conduct continuous and integrated manned or unmanned monitoring, sensing, or surveillance of 100% of the southern border of the United States. </p> <p>Prohibits DHS from procuring any additional unmanned aircraft systems (UAS) until it provides written certification that it successfully operated its current UAS fleet at least 23,000 hours during the preceding calendar year. Excepts the procurement of unmanned aircraft that do not weigh more than 150 pounds.</p> <p>Requires DHS to: (1) use the best available radar and surveillance technology to increase awareness of illegal border activities along the southern border and to identify gaps in surveillance capabilities; and (2) consult with the Department of Defense to identify best practices that could be used by DHS to improve the security of the southern border.</p> <p>Directs DHS to report biannually on: </p> <ul> <li>the number of UAS flight hours required, planned, and flown to provide persistent surveillance along the southern border and the number of flight hours cancelled; </li> <li>the number of UAS flight hours planned in support of any federal or state agency; </li> <li>performance measures regarding the number of hours flown, subjects detected, and apprehensions and illicit drug seizures assisted; and </li> <li>the accumulated cost associated with the UAS Program. </li></ul> <p>Terminates this Act five years after its enactment.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
