<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="396" measure-id="id114s396" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-02-05" update-date="2015-02-28">
<title>Proprietary Education Oversight Coordination Improvement Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s396v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-02-28">
<action-date>2015-02-05</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Proprietary Education Oversight Coordination Improvement Act</strong></p> <p>Establishes the Proprietary Education Oversight Coordination Committee to:</p> <ul> <li>coordinate federal oversight of proprietary institutions of higher education (IHEs);</li> <li>coordinate federal activities to protect students from unfair, deceptive, abusive, unethical, fraudulent, or predatory practices, policies, or procedures of proprietary IHEs;</li> <li>encourage information sharing among federal agencies regarding federal investigations, audits, or inquiries of such IHEs;</li> <li>increase coordination and cooperation between federal and state agencies to improve oversight and accountability of proprietary IHEs; and</li> <li>develop best practices and consistency among federal and state agencies in the dissemination of consumer information regarding such IHEs.</li> </ul> <p>Requires the Committee to: (1) meet at least once each quarter of each fiscal year; and (2) meet at least once each fiscal year, and otherwise interact regularly, with state attorneys general, state approval agencies, veterans service organizations, and consumer advocates.</p> <p>Directs the Committee to submit, and make publicly available, an annual report to Congress that includes: (1) recommendations for legislative and administrative actions the Committees deems necessary to improve the enforcement of applicable federal laws, increase the accountability of proprietary IHEs to students and taxpayers, and ensure the promotion of quality education programs; and (2) specified financial and consumer information regarding such IHEs.</p> <p>Requires the Committee, each academic year, to publish the For-Profit College Warning List for Parents and Students, which is to be comprised of proprietary IHEs:</p> <ul> <li>that have engaged in illegal activity during the previous academic year as determined by a federal or state court;</li> <li>that have entered into a settlement resulting in a monetary payment;</li> <li>that have had any higher education program withdrawn or suspended; or</li> <li>for which the Committee has sufficient evidence of widespread or systemic unfair, deceptive, abusive, unethical, fraudulent, or predatory practices, policies, or procedures that threaten the academic success, financial security, or general best interest of students.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
