<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1818" measure-id="id114s1818" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-07-21" update-date="2015-10-27">
<title>Principled Rulemaking Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1818v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-10-27">
<action-date>2015-07-21</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Principled Rulemaking Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>Requires a federal agency to promulgate only a rule that is required by law, necessary to interpret a law, or made necessary by compelling public need.</p> <p>Requires an agency, before promulgating a rule, to:</p> <ul> <li>assess the significance of the problem the agency intends to address; </li> <li>consider the legal authority under which the rule may be proposed; </li> <li>examine whether existing rules have created or contributed to the problem and should be modified to achieve the regulatory objective more effectively; </li> <li>assess available alternatives to direct regulation; </li> <li>consider the risks posed by various substances or activities within the agency's jurisdiction; </li> <li>design the rule to achieve the regulatory objective in the most cost-effective manner; </li> <li>propose or adopt a rule only upon a reasoned determination that its benefits justify its costs and select approaches that maximize net benefits; </li> <li>base decisions on the best reasonably obtainable information concerning the need for, and consequences of, the rule; </li> <li>assess alternative forms of regulation and specify performance objectives; </li> <li>seek views of governmental entities before imposing regulatory requirements that may significantly or uniquely affect them and seek to minimize those burdens; </li> <li>seek to harmonize agency action with related governmental functions; </li> <li>avoid promulgating a rule that is inconsistent, incompatible, or duplicative with other rules; </li> <li>tailor the rule to impose the least burden on society; and </li> <li>draft the rule in a manner that is simple and easy to understand. </li></ul> <p>Directs each agency: (1) to issue rules through a process that involves public participation; (2) before issuing a notice of proposed rule making, to seek the views of those who are likely to be affected; (3) in developing regulatory actions and identifying appropriate approaches, to attempt to promote coordination, simplification, and harmonization and to identify means to achieve regulatory goals that are designed to promote innovation; (4) to consider regulatory approaches that reduce burdens and maintain flexibility and freedom of choice for the public, that include warnings, appropriate default rules, and disclosure requirements, and that provide information that is clear and intelligible; and (5) to ensure the objectivity of any scientific and technological information and processes used to support each regulatory action.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
