<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1626" measure-id="id114s1626" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-06-18" update-date="2016-05-04">
<title>Railroad Reform, Enhancement, and Efficiency Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1626v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-05-04">
<action-date>2015-06-18</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Railroad Reform, Enhancement, and Efficiency Act</b></p> <p>This bill reauthorizes FY2016-FY2019 grants to the National Railroad Passenger Corporation (Amtrak) for:</p> <ul> <li> a Northeast Corridor investment account,</li> <li>a state-supported account,</li> <li>a long-distance account,</li> <li>an other national network activities account, and</li> <li>national infrastructure and safety investments. </li> </ul> <p>Appropriations are also authorized for the same period for:</p> <ul> <li>National Transportation Safety Board rail investigations, and</li> <li> Amtrak's Office of the Inspector General.</li> </ul> <p>The bill revises requirements for the rail cooperative research program. Allocation of a specified amount is made for each fiscal year to the Department of Transportation (DOT) for railroad research and development programs.</p> <p>Amtrak shall establish internal controls to ensure its costs, revenues, and other compensation are allocated to its Northeast Corridor train services or infrastructure, Amtrak-operated state-supported routes and long-distance routes, and other Amtrak national network activities.</p> <p>DOT shall establish substantive and procedural requirements for Northeast Corridor, Amtrak routes, and national network investment capital grant requests.</p> <p>DOT shall establish:</p> <ul> <li>a Northeast Corridor investment account,</li> <li>a state-supported account,</li> <li>a long-distance account, and</li> <li>an other national network activities account.</li> </ul> <p>Amtrak shall prepare:</p> <ul> <li> final five-year business line plans for Northeast Corridor train services, Amtrak-operated state-supported routes and long-distance routes, and Amtrak ancillary services; and </li> <li>five-year asset plans for Amtrack infrastructure and equipment.</li> </ul> <p>DOT shall establish the State-Supported Route Committee.</p> <p>The bill revises alternate passenger rail service pilot program requirements.</p> <p>DOT shall develop a program for issuing three-year competitive operating assistance grants to eligible public and private entities to initiate, restore, or enhance intercity rail passenger service.</p> <p> DOT shall develop a federal-state partnership program for issuing competitive grants to the aforementioned entities for capital projects to replace, rehabilitate, or repair major infrastructure assets for providing intercity passenger rail service. </p> <p>The bill requires the Northeast Corridor Commission to:</p> <ul> <li> develop a capital investment plan for the Northeast Corridor main line between Boston, Massachusetts, and the Virginia Avenue interlocking in the District of Columbia, and the Northeast Corridor branch lines connecting to Harrisburg, Pennsylvania, Springfield, Massachusetts, and Spuyten Duyvil, New York; and</li> <li>update, once every 10 years, a Northeast Corridor service development plan.</li> </ul> <p>DOT shall develop and distribute to each state a state-specific highway-rail grade crossing action plan to improve safety.</p> <p>DOT may make grants to eligible public and private entities to assist in financing the cost of rail projects to improve the safety, efficiency, or reliability of passenger and freight rail transportation systems. </p> <p><i>Track, Railroad, and Infrastructure Network Act</i></p> <p>The bill exempts improvements to, maintenance, rehabilitation, or operation of railroad or rail transit lines (but not stations) that are in use or were historically used for the transportation of goods or passengers from federal policies and requirements for the preservation of public park and recreation lands, wildlife and waterfowl refuges, and historic sites.</p> <p><i>Railroad Infrastructure Financing Improvement Act </i></p> <p>The bill amends the Railroad Revitalization and Regulatory Reform Act of 1976 to revise Railroad Rehabilitation and Improvement Financing program requirements. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
