<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2354" measure-id="id114s2354" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-12-03" update-date="2016-04-07">
<title>Strong Families Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2354v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-04-07">
<action-date>2015-12-03</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Strong Families Act</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1)&nbsp;allow certain employers a business-related tax credit for up to 25% of the amount of wages paid to their employees during any period (not exceeding 12 weeks) in which such employees are on&nbsp;family and medical leave, (2) limit the allowable amount of such credit to $3,000 per employee for any taxable year, and (3) terminate such credit after 2017. </p> <p>The Government Accountability Office shall complete&nbsp;a study on the effectiveness of the tax credit for paid family and medical leave. </p> <p>The Office of Management and Budget shall determine: (1) the dollar amount obligated by each executive agency to purchase and to lease civilian vehicles in FY2010, and (2) the total number of civilian vehicles purchased and leased by each executive agency in FY2010. Executive agencies may not obligate more than 90% of the amount they obligated in FY2010 to purchase or lease civilian vehicles in each of FY2016-FY2020. </p> <p>The bill permanently rescinds all unobligated amounts in the U.S. Enrichment Corporation Fund, except for amounts designated as an emergency requirement. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
