<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1386" measure-id="id114s1386" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-19" update-date="2015-07-09">
<title>Icebreaker Recapitalization Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1386v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-07-09">
<action-date>2015-05-19</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Icebreaker Recapitalization Act</strong></p> <p>This bill directs the Department of the Navy to enter into multiyear contracts for the procurement of up to six heavy duty polar icebreakers and any associated systems and equipment.</p> <p>The Department may enter into one or more contracts, beginning in FY 2016, for advance procurement associated with such vessels, systems, and equipment. </p> <p>The Department and the Department in which the Coast Guard is operating shall enter into a memorandum of agreement under which the Coast Guard shall: </p> <ul> <li>identify the vessel specifications, capabilities, systems, equipment, and other details required for the design of heavy polar icebreakers, with the Coast Guard retaining final decision authority; </li> <li>oversee the construction of authorized heavy polar icebreakers; and </li> <li>to the extent not adequately addressed in the 1965 Revised Memorandum of Agreement between the Department of the Navy and the Department of the Treasury on the Operation of Icebreakers, transfer heavy polar icebreakers from the Navy to the Coast Guard to be maintained and operated by the Coast Guard.</li></ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
