<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="899" measure-id="id114s899" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-04-13" update-date="2015-04-28">
<title>Afterschool and Workforce Readiness Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s899v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-04-28">
<action-date>2015-04-13</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Afterschool and Workforce Readiness Act</strong></p> <p>Amends part A (Teacher and Principal Training and Recruiting Fund) of title II of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (ESEA) to define a &quot;workforce critical subject&quot; as an academic or career and technical education subject, such as:</p> <ul> <li>any subject found in the science, technology, engineering, and mathematics fields;</li> <li>any other subject identified by a state as being critical to the state's current and emerging workforce needs.</li> </ul> <p>Requires a state's application for a grant under part A to recruit, train, and retain highly qualified teachers and principals to describe all of the subjects the state identifies as workforce critical subjects.</p> <p>Amends part B (21st Century Community Learning Centers) of title IV of the ESEA to require states that receive a part B allotment to consider, in evaluating subgrant applications, the likelihood that a subgrant applicant's community learning center will help secondary school students achieve career competencies, complete internships or apprenticeships, or participate in work-based learning opportunities. (Subgrants are awarded on a competitive basis to local educational agencies, community-based organizations, and other public or private entities to establish or expand before school, after school, and summer recess community learning center programs.)</p> <p>Authorizes subgrantees to establish community learning center programs that partner with in-demand fields of the local workforce or build career competencies and career readiness.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
