<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2007" measure-id="id114s2007" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-08-06" update-date="2015-10-05">
<title>Federal Cybersecurity Workforce Assessment Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2007v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-10-05">
<action-date>2015-08-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<div> <div> <div> <div> <div><strong>Federal Cybersecurity Workforce Assessment Act</strong><br /></div><br />This bill requires federal agencies to: (1) identify all personnel positions that require the performance of information technology, cybersecurity, or other cyber-related functions; and <a name="14f936abab5a2d8e_ideb51c5c3f8d544efa4e9e12836241375" />(2) assign a corresponding employment code to such positions using a coding structure that the National Institute of Standards and Technology must include in the National Initiative for Cybersecurity Education's National Cybersecurity Workforce Framework.<br /><br />To implement the coding structure: (1) the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) must coordinate with the Director of National Intelligence to establish procedures to identify such federal civilian positions, and (2) the Department of Defense must establish procedures to identify such federal noncivilian positions.<br /></div><br /></div> <div>Federal agencies must submit to Congress a report identifying: (1) the percentage of personnel with such job functions who currently hold industry-recognized certifications, (2) the preparedness of other civilian and noncivilian cyber personnel without existing credentials to pass certification exams, and (3) a strategy for mitigating any identified gaps with training and certification for existing personnel. <br /></div> <div><br /></div>The agencies must establish procedures to identify all encumbered and vacant positions with such functions and <a name="14f936abab5a2d8e_id18A72A10F2D34C63BF4CBE373DFF569F" />assign the appropriate employment code to each position.<br /><br /></div>Annually through 2022, the agencies must submit a report to the OPM that identifies cyber-related roles designated as critical needs in the agency's workforce. The OPM must provide agencies with guidance for identifying roles with acute and emerging skill shortages. <br /></div> <p>The OPM, within two years after enactment of this Act, must identify critical needs for the cyber workforce across all federal agencies and report to Congress regarding the implementation of this Act.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
