<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="794" measure-id="id114s794" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-03-18" update-date="2015-04-25">
<title>A bill to extend whistleblower protections for defense contractor employees to employees of contractors of the elements of the intelligence community.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s794v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-04-25">
<action-date>2015-03-18</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt" class="MsoNormal">Extends whistleblower protections to employees of contractors, subcontractors, or grantees of elements of the intelligence community who disclose information regarding such an element, or its activities, if the employee complies with procedures to report urgent concerns to Congress by first submitting the information to an appropriate agency Inspector General under the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949 or the Inspector General Act of 1978. (Currently, employees of contractors of the intelligence community are excluded from certain whistleblower protections that are provided to employees of&nbsp;contractors of the&nbsp;Department of Defense and other federal agencies.) </p> <p>Requires courts that receive&nbsp;a disclosure of information required by executive order to be kept classified (in the interests of national defense or the conduct of foreign affairs) to treat the information in a manner consistent with the interests of the national security of the United States, including through the use of summaries or ex parte submissions if the element of the intelligence community concerned advises the court that such procedures are warranted.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
