<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1392" measure-id="id114s1392" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-20" update-date="2015-07-31">
<title>Safer Prescribing of Controlled Substances Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1392v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-07-31">
<action-date>2015-05-20</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Safer Prescribing of Controlled Substances Act</strong></p> <p>Amends the Controlled Substances Act to direct the Attorney General, as a condition of granting or renewing the registration of a covered practitioner to dispense, or conduct research with, controlled substances in schedule II, III, IV, or V, to require such covered practitioner to complete training that the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) determines meets the requirements of this Act. Defines a &quot;covered practitioner&quot; as a practitioner that is not a hospital, pharmacy, or veterinarian.</p> <p>Requires such training to expose covered practitioners to:</p> <ul> <li> best practices for pain management, including alternatives to prescribing controlled substances; </li> <li> responsible prescribing of pain medications; </li> <li> methods for diagnosing, treating, and managing a substance use disorder, including evidence-based nonpharmacological therapies; </li> <li> ways of linking patients to evidence-based treatment for substance use disorders; and </li> <li> tools to manage adherence and diversion of controlled substances. </li> </ul> <p>Directs the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration to establish or support the establishment of at least one free, online training module that meets such requirements to be provided to any covered practitioner registered or applying for registration.</p> <p>Requires HHS: (1) to establish, maintain, and periodically update a publicly available database providing information on such training modules; and (2) within five years after enactment of this Act, to evaluate and make publicly available a report describing how exposure to training required by this Act has changed prescribing patterns of controlled substances.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
