<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1632" measure-id="id114s1632" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-06-18" update-date="2015-09-25">
<title>A bill to require a regional strategy to address the threat posed by Boko Haram.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1632v35" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-09-25">
<action-date>2015-09-22</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed Senate amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(Sec. 1) This bill requires: </p> <ul> <li>the Department of State and the Department of Defense to develop jointly and submit to Congress a five-year strategy to help Nigeria, members of the Multinational Joint Task Force to Combat Boko Haram, and relevant partners to counter Boko Haram, and to assist Nigeria and its neighbors to address legitimate grievances of vulnerable populations in areas affected by Boko Haram; and </li> <li>the Director of National Intelligence to assess the willingness and capability Nigeria and regional partners to implement such strategy.</li> </ul> <p> Such strategy must address the following elements: </p> <ul> <li> enhancing the institutional capacity, including military capabilities, of Nigeria and partner nations in the region to counter Boko Haram; </li> <li> providing humanitarian support to civilian populations impacted by Boko Haram; </li> <li> improving the capacity of Multinational Joint Task Force to Combat Boko Haram partner nations to investigate and prosecute human rights abuses by security forces and promote respect for the rule of law within the military; </li> <li> assisting Nigeria and Multinational Joint Task Force to Combat Boko Haram nations to counter violent extremism; </li> <li> strengthening the rule of law and Nigeria's capacity to enhance school security; and </li> <li> identifying the resources required to achieve such objectives. </li> </ul> <p> It is the sense of Congress that lack of economic opportunity and access to education, justice, and other social services contributes to Boko Haram's ability to radicalize and recruit individuals.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114s1632v01" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-09-04">
<action-date>2015-07-29</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to Senate amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(Sec. 1) This bill requires: </p> <ul> <li>the Department of State and the Department of Defense to develop jointly and submit to Congress a five-year strategy to help Nigeria, members of the Multinational Joint Task Force to Combat Boko Haram, and relevant partners to counter Boko Haram, and to assist Nigeria and its neighbors to address legitimate grievances of vulnerable populations in areas affected by Boko Haram; and </li> <li>the Director of National Intelligence to assess the willingness and capability Nigeria and regional partners to implement such strategy.</li> </ul> <p> Such strategy must address the following elements: </p> <ul> <li> enhancing the institutional capacity, including military capabilities, of Nigeria and partner nations in the region to counter Boko Haram; </li> <li> providing humanitarian support to civilian populations impacted by Boko Haram; </li> <li> improving the capacity of Multinational Joint Task Force to Combat Boko Haram partner nations to investigate and prosecute human rights abuses by security forces and promote respect for the rule of law within the military; </li> <li> assisting Nigeria and Multinational Joint Task Force to Combat Boko Haram nations to counter violent extremism; </li> <li> strengthening the rule of law and Nigeria's capacity to enhance school security; and </li> <li> identifying the resources required to achieve such objectives. </li> </ul> <p> It is the sense of Congress that lack of economic opportunity and access to education, justice, and other social services contributes to Boko Haram's ability to radicalize and recruit individuals.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114s1632v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-09-04">
<action-date>2015-06-18</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill requires: </p> <ul> <li>the Department of State and the Department of Defense to jointly develop and submit to Congress a five-year strategy to help Nigeria, members of the Multinational Joint Task Force to Combat Boko Haram, and relevant partners to counter Boko Haram, and to assist Nigeria and its neighbors to address legitimate grievances of vulnerable populations in areas affected by Boko Haram; and </li> <li>the Director of National Intelligence to assess Nigeria's willingness and capability to implement such strategy.</li></ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
