<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="969" measure-id="id114s969" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-04-16" update-date="2015-06-16">
<title>Federal Public Safety Retirement Fairness Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s969v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-06-16">
<action-date>2015-04-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Federal Public Safety Retirement Fairness Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to exempt from the 10% additional tax on early distributions from tax-exempt retirement plans distributions from a thrift savings fund to a qualified law enforcement officer who has reached age 50 or has completed 25 years of credible service, whichever is earlier. The bill defines &quot;qualified law enforcement officer&quot; as an individual who is employed by the federal government as a law enforcement officer or as a firefighter and has completed 20 years of creditable service, or an individual who is employed as an air traffic controller and has completed 20 years of creditable service. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
