<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1753" measure-id="id114s1753" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-07-13" update-date="2015-09-24">
<title>Rebuilding America's Schools Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1753v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-09-24">
<action-date>2015-07-13</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Rebuilding America's Schools Act</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code, with respect to qualified zone academy bonds issued to finance public school facilities, to: (1) extend the&nbsp;national limitation amount for&nbsp;such bonds through calendar year 2014 and then increase such amount and make it permanent after calendar year 2014, (2) expand the enumerated purposes of such bonds to include the&nbsp;construction of public school facilities in a qualified zone academy, (3) lower the private business contribution requirement for such bonds from 10% to 5% of the proceeds of the bond issue, and (4) designate such bonds as specified tax credit bonds.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
