<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="731" measure-id="id114s731" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-03-12" update-date="2015-04-29">
<title>Social Security Expansion Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s731v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-04-29">
<action-date>2015-03-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Social Security Expansion Act</b></p> <p> Amends title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) of the Social Security Act to:</p> <UL> <LI>increase the primary insurance amount for all eligible beneficiaries, beginning in 2021;</LI> <LI>revise computation of cost-of-living adjustments to use the Consumer Price Index for Elderly Consumers;</LI> <LI>increase the special minimum primary insurance amount for lifetime low earners based on years in the workforce.</LI> </UL> <p>Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) apply employment and self-employment taxes to remuneration up to the contribution and benefit base and to remuneration in excess of $250,000; and (2) increase the tax on investment gain from 3.8% to 10% of the lesser of net investment income for such taxable year or the excess (if any) of the modified adjusted gross income for such taxable year, over the threshold amount, with 62% of such tax allocated to the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund and 9% allocated to the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
