<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2833" measure-id="id114s2833" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-04-21" update-date="2016-10-28">
<title>Visa Transparency Anti-Trafficking Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2833v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-10-28">
<action-date>2016-04-21</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Visa Transparency Anti-Trafficking Act of 2016</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to expand nonimmigrant employer annual data reporting requirements to include all nonimmigrant worker categories and compensated cultural exchange, training, and business classifications.</p> <p>Expanded reporting requirements include information regarding: (1) the age and gender of admitted nonimmigrants, (2) categories and numbers of visas issued, (3) numbers of persons admitted under each visa classification and subclassification, (4) blanket petitions, (5) the occupation and country of origin of beneficiaries, (6) nonimmigrant worker employers, (7) compensation, and (8) citizens of nations with Compacts of Free Association with the United States who are authorized to reside permanently in the United States as nonimmigrants and their ports of U.S. entry.</p> <p>The Department of Labor shall: (1) submit such report and post the information along with the corresponding raw data and a searchable database to a public website, and (2) ensure that such posted information does not include information that would identify a specific person with reasonable certainty. </p> <p>Any government official who uses such information shall take steps to: (1) protect individual identities, and (2) prevent the information from being disaggregated into its component parts. </p> <p> The Department of State or the Department of Homeland Security, if requested by Labor, shall share information necessary for Labor to file its annual report regarding employer petitions for H-, P-, O-, and Q-visa nonimmigrant aliens.</p> <p>&quot;Employment&quot; means employment in the United States and includes cultural exchanges, training, or business activities for which the nonimmigrant receives any form of compensation.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
