<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="414" measure-id="id114s414" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-02-09" update-date="2015-07-06">
<title>California Desert Conservation and Recreation Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s414v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-07-06">
<action-date>2015-02-09</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>California Desert Conservation and Recreation Act of 2015 </b></p> <p> Amends the California Desert Protection Act of 1994 to, among other things: (1) establish or designate national monuments, wilderness areas, a special management area, off-highway vehicle recreation areas, a national scenic area, and an area of critical environmental concern; (2) release specified wilderness study areas; (3) adjust national park and preserve boundaries; and (4) specify land withdrawals, exchanges, and acquisitions. </p> <p>Directs that specified federal land be taken into trust for the Lone Pine Paiute-Shoshone Tribe. </p> <p>Authorizes the acquisition of lands and interests in land, including improvements, outside the boundary of Joshua Tree National Park in California for the purpose of operating a visitor center. </p> <p>Makes amendments to the California Desert Protection Act of 1994 regarding the California State School lands. </p> <p>Amends the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to designate specified segments of rivers and creeks as components of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System. </p> <p>Sets forth requirements for the disposition of revenues collected as payments for the development of wind and solar energy on lands managed by the Bureau of Land Management. Establishes the Renewable Energy Resource Conservation Fund. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
