<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="307" measure-id="id114s307" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-01-29" update-date="2015-03-02">
<title>ConTACT Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s307v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-03-02">
<action-date>2015-01-29</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Concussion Treatment and Care Tools Act of 2015 or the ConTACT Act of 2015</b></p> <p>Amends the Public Health Service Act to direct the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to establish guidelines for states on the implementation of best practices for diagnosis, treatment, and management of mild traumatic brain injuries (MTBIs) in school-aged children, including best practices relating to student athletes returning to play after an MTBI.</p> <p>Requires the Pediatric MTBI Guideline Expert Panel of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention to issue a final report on best practices by July 31, 2015.</p> <p>Authorizes HHS to make grants to states to: (1) adopt, disseminate, and ensure schools implement the guidelines; and (2) ensure elementary and secondary schools implement computerized preseason baseline and post-injury neuropsychological testing for student athletes.</p> <p>Directs HHS to require states receiving grants to utilize, to the extent practicable, applicable expertise and services offered by local chapters of national brain injury organizations.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
