<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1088" measure-id="id114s1088" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-04-27" update-date="2015-05-20">
<title>Voter Registration Modernization Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1088v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-05-20">
<action-date>2015-04-27</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Voter Registration Modernization Act </b></p> <p> Amends the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 to require each state to make available official public websites for online voter registration. </p> <p>Directs the appropriate state or local election official to ensure that information on the computerized statewide voter registration list may be updated through the official public website. </p> <p>Directs the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology to study best practices for implementing the requirements for Internet registration and the online updating of voter registration information.</p> <p>Authorizes the provision of election information by electronic mail to individuals registered to vote who have requested to receive it.</p> <p>Directs the Election Assistance Commission to make an implementation payment each year to enable each state to meet the requirements of this Act and to carry out activities to improve the administration of federal elections.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
