<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2568" measure-id="id114s2568" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-02-23" update-date="2016-03-10">
<title>California Desert Conservation, Off-Road Recreation, and Renewable Energy Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2568v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-03-10">
<action-date>2016-02-23</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>California Desert Conservation, Off-Road Recreation, and Renewable Energy Act </b></p> <p>This bill designates specified lands in the California Desert Conservation Area or San Bernardino National Forest in California as wilderness areas. </p> <p>Specified wilderness study areas are released from further study. </p> <p> There is established the Vinagre Wash Special Management Area. </p> <p>Boundaries are revised for Death Valley National Park, Mojave National Preserve, and Joshua Tree National Park. </p> <p>The bill designates specified off-highway vehicle recreation areas within the Conservation Area in San Bernardino County, California. </p> <p>The Department of the Interior or the Department of Agriculture (USDA), as appropriate, shall complete a study to identify Bureau of Land Management (BLM) lands within the Conservation Area suitable for addition to: (1) the national off-highway vehicle recreation areas designated by this Act, or (2) the Johnson Valley Off-Highway Vehicle Recreation Area. </p> <p>There is established the Alabama Hills National Scenic Area in Inyo County, California. </p> <p>Specified federal land in California shall be taken into trust for the Lone Pine Paiute-Shoshone Tribe's reservation. </p> <p>The bill authorizes:</p> <ul> <li>a conveyance of specified federal land to Reginald Cook,</li> <li>a specified transfer of certain BLM land to Anza-Borrego Desert State Park, and</li> <li>a conveyance of specified BLM land to Imperial County Holtville Airport. </li> </ul> <p> Interior or USDA (as appropriate) shall:</p> <ul> <li>assess the impacts of climate change on the Conservation Area, and </li> <li>establish policies and procedures to ensure preservation of wildlife corridors and facilitate species migration likely to occur due to climate change. </li> </ul> <p>Interior and USDA shall ensure that members of specified tribes have access to designated areas for traditional and cultural purposes. </p> <p>The bill releases federal reversionary interests in certain land in the Metropolitan Water District of Southern California. </p> <p>The California Desert Protection Act of 1994 is amended to authorize the acquisition of land for the Joshua Tree National Park for purposes of operating a visitor center. </p> <p>The bill revises certain requirements of that Act for specified California state school land. </p> <p>The Wild and Scenic Rivers Act is revised to designate certain wild, scenic, and recreational rivers in California. </p> <p>Interior shall take no action within the Conservation Area with regard to the distribution of groundwater for municipal, commercial, or industrial use from specified aquifers in quantities that exceed the estimated perennial safe yield or annual recharge rate, as determined by the U.S. Geological Survey. </p> <p>The bill prescribes the disposition of revenues received from the development of wind and solar energy on BLM-managed lands, and establishes a Renewable Energy Resource Conservation Fund to address the impacts of wind and solar development on federal lands.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
