<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="3213" measure-id="id114s3213" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-07-14" update-date="2016-07-27">
<title>Judgment Fund Transparency and Terrorism Financing Prevention Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s3213v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-07-27">
<action-date>2016-07-14</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Judgment Fund Transparency and Terrorism Financing Prevention Act </b></p> <p>This bill requires the Department of the Treasury to disclose details after payments are made from the Judgment Fund. (The Judgment Fund is a permanent and indefinite appropriation to pay judgments against the United States.) </p> <p>Unless the disclosure is prohibited by law or a court order, Treasury must disclose to the public on a website: </p> <ul> <li>the agency or entity whose actions gave rise to the claim or judgment, </li> <li>the plaintiff or claimant, </li> <li>the counsel for the plaintiff or claimant, </li> <li>the amount paid, </li> <li>a description of the facts that gave rise to the claim, and </li> <li>the agency that submitted the claim. </li> </ul> <p>If the payment is made to a foreign state, Treasury must also disclose:</p> <ul> <li>the method of payment;</li> <li>the currency denomination used for the payment; and </li> <li>the name and location of each financial institution owned or controlled by a foreign state or an agent of a foreign state through which the payment passed, from which the payment was withdrawn, or that is holding the payment. </li> </ul> <p>No payments from the fund may be made to a state sponsor of terrorism. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
