<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1821" measure-id="id114s1821" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-07-21" update-date="2016-01-19">
<title>Armed Forces Self-Defense Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1821v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-01-19">
<action-date>2015-07-21</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Armed Forces Self-Defense Act</strong></p> <p> This bill states U.S. policy that Department of Defense (DOD) personnel shall be appropriately armed and have the inherent right to self-defense.</p> <p> Current regulations and directives, or any provision in any other rule, regulation, or executive order prohibiting military personnel trained in firearms from carrying personal firearms on U.S. military installations shall have no further force or effect with regard to such military personnel, and they shall not be prohibited from carrying personal firearms on U.S. military installations. </p> <p>The bill directs DOD to establish a process by which the commander of a military installation in the United States may authorize a qualifying member of the Armed Forces assigned to duty at the installation to carry a concealed personal firearm on the installation if the commander determines it to be necessary as a personal-protection or force-protection measure.</p> <p>The commander of the installation shall consult with appropriate state and local elected officials and take into consideration state and local laws law regarding carrying a concealed personal firearm.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
