<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="821" measure-id="id114s821" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-03-19" update-date="2015-04-02">
<title>BPA in Food Packaging Right to Know Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s821v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-04-02">
<action-date>2015-03-19</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>BPA in Food Packaging Right to Know Act</b></p> <p>Requires the Department of Health and Human Services to: (1) issue a revised safety assessment for food containers composed in whole or in part of bisphenol A (BPA), taking into consideration different types and uses of such containers; and (2) determine whether there is reasonable certainty that no harm will result from aggregate exposure to BPA through food containers or other items composed in whole or in part of BPA, taking into consideration potential adverse effects from low-dose exposure and the effects of exposure on vulnerable populations, including pregnant women, infants, children, the elderly, and populations with high exposure to BPA.</p> <p>Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to prohibit the sale of a food if its container is composed in whole or in part of BPA unless the label includes the following statement: &quot;This food packaging contains BPA, an endocrine-disrupting chemical, according to the National Institutes of Health.&quot;]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
