<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1120" measure-id="id114s1120" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-04-28" update-date="2016-03-31">
<title>A bill to make aliens associated with a criminal gang inadmissible, deportable, and ineligible for various forms of relief.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1120v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-03-31">
<action-date>2015-04-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to define &quot;criminal gang.&quot;</p> <p>An alien who is or was a member of a criminal gang, or who participated in gang activity knowing that such participation will promote the gang's illegal activity, shall be inadmissible and deportable.</p> <p>The Department of Homeland Security may designate a group or association as a criminal gang. </p> <p>Detention shall be mandatory for anyone found inadmissible or deportable for criminal street gang membership. </p> <p>Individuals found inadmissible or deportable for criminal gang membership shall be barred from: </p> <ul> <li>asylum; </li> <li>withholding of removal; </li> <li>temporary protected status;</li> <li>special immigrant juvenile status;</li> <li>deferred action; and </li> <li>parole, unless assisting the United States in a law enforcement matter and required by the government to be present with respect to such assistance. </li> </ul> <p>An alien found at a U.S. land border or port of entry who is determined to be inadmissible and a threat to public safety (certain criminals, terrorists, street gang members) shall be subject to expedited removal.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
