<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1357" measure-id="id114s1357" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-14" update-date="2015-05-20">
<title>A bill to extend authority relating to roving surveillance, access to business records, and individual terrorists as agents of foreign powers under the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 until July 31, 2015, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1357v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-05-20">
<action-date>2015-05-14</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Amends the USA PATRIOT Improvement and Reauthorization Act of 2005 and the Intelligence Reform and Terrorism Prevention Act of 2004 to extend until July 31, 2015, expiring provisions of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (FISA) concerning: (1) FISA court orders approving roving electronic surveillance, (2) requests for FISA court orders that allow the government to require the production of business records and other tangible things for foreign intelligence and international terrorism investigations, and (3) a revised definition of &quot;agent of a foreign power&quot; that allows surveillance of individual non-U.S. persons who engage in international terrorism or preparatory activities (commonly referred to as the &quot;lone wolf&quot; provision). (Currently, such provisions are scheduled to expire on June 1, 2015.)</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
