<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1520" measure-id="id114s1520" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-06-04" update-date="2016-07-01">
<title>Protecting Domestic Violence and Stalking Victims Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1520v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-07-01">
<action-date>2015-06-04</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong></strong><b>Protecting Domestic Violence and Stalking Victims Act of 2015</b></p> <p>This bill amends the federal criminal code to: </p> <ul> <li> state that the term &quot;intimate partner&quot; includes a dating partner and any other person subject to a protection order under state domestic or family violence law; and</li> <li> expand the term &quot;misdemeanor crime of domestic violence&quot; to include the use or attempted use of physical force, or the threatened use of a deadly weapon, by a current or former intimate partner. </li> </ul> <p>The bill makes it a crime to knowingly sell or dispose of a firearm to a person who has been convicted of a misdemeanor crime of stalking. It also makes it a crime for such convicted stalker to receive or possess a firearm. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
