<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2778" measure-id="id114s2778" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-04-12" update-date="2016-04-14">
<title>Directed Energy Weapon Systems Acquisition Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2778v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-04-14">
<action-date>2016-04-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Directed Energy Weapon Systems Acquisition Act of 2016</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Bob Stump National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2003 to state that, if supplies or support services are urgently needed to eliminate a deficiency in directed energy weapon systems, the Department of Defense (DOD) may use specified rapid acquisition procedures to acquire and deploy needed offensive or defensive directed energy weapon systems capabilities, supplies, and associated support services. </p> <p>&quot;Directed energy weapon system&quot; means military action using highly focused sound, electromagnetic, or particle-beam energy to incapacitate, damage, or destroy enemy equipment, facilities, or personnel.</p> <p>The bill redesignates DOD's High Energy Laser Joint Technology Office as the Joint Directed Energy Program Office.</p> <p>The Office shall: (1) develop a strategic plan for development and transition of directed energy weapons capabilities, and (2) use new and revised DOD policies to accelerate the development and transition of directed energy capabilities toward fielding.</p> </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
