<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2630" measure-id="id114s2630" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-03-03" update-date="2016-05-03">
<title>Pay Stub Disclosure Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2630v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-05-03">
<action-date>2016-03-03</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Pay Stub Disclosure Act</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to require each employer to provide an initial disclosure to each employee who is not subject to exemption from minimum wage and maximum hour requirements within 15 days after: (1) the employee is hired, or (2) specified information in the initial disclosure changes.</p> <p>The information specified in that initial disclosure shall include:</p> <ul> <li>the pay rate and form of compensation; <li>the name of the employer and any other name used by the employer to conduct business; and <li>the physical address and telephone number of the employer's main office or principal place of business, and a mailing address if different from the first one. </li> </ul> <p>The bill specifies additional disclosures that must be in each pay stub, including the pay period covered, the employee's name, the total hours worked by the employee, benefits, allowances, and reimbursements.</p> <p>The bill also prescribes the form of the pay stub as well as employer notice requirements.</p> <p>An employer shall keep records of the information disclosed in an employee's pay stub for three years from each stub's issuance.</p> <p>In the event that an employee who is not subject to minimum wage and maximum hourexemptions requests an inspection of his or her records, the employer shall provide copies of them for up to three years before the request.</p> <p>The bill prescribes civil penalties for employer failure to comply with this Act.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
