<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1258" measure-id="id114s1258" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-07" update-date="2016-06-23">
<title>Local Energy Supply and Resiliency Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1258v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-06-23">
<action-date>2015-05-07</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Local Energy Supply and Resiliency Act of 2015</b></p> This bill requires the Department of Energy (DOE) to establish certain programs to support distributed energy systems, which are energy sources and systems that: (1) produce electric or thermal energy close to the point of use using renewable energy resources or waste thermal energy, (2) generate electricity using a combined heat and power system, (3) distribute electricity in microgrids, (4) store electric or thermal energy, or (5) distribute or transfer thermal energy to building heating and cooling systems through a district energy system. <p>DOE must establish: (1) a loan program to provide funding for deploying distributed energy systems to states and other government entities, institutions of higher education, and electric utilities; and (2) a technical assistance and grant program to disseminate information and provide technical assistance to nonprofit and profit entities for identifying, evaluating, planning, and designing distributed energy systems. </p> <ul> </ul> <ul> <ul> </ul> </ul> <ul> <ul> </ul> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
