<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2751" measure-id="id114s2751" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-04-06" update-date="2016-08-08">
<title>Support Startup Businesses Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2751v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-08-08">
<action-date>2016-04-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Support Startup Businesses Act of 2016</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Small Business Act to authorize a small business concern receiving a Phase II award (grants of up to $1 million, for up to 2 years, to facilitate expansion of Phase I startup results) under the Small Business Innovation Research program, for FY2017-FY2019, to use up to 5% of the Phase II award for commercialization-related services, including market validation, intellectual property protection, business model development, market research, and other reasonable services that support market entry.</p> <p>These services may be performed directly by the small business concern or obtained from a public or private nonprofit organization, a state agency, or another state-funded entity that facilitates or accelerates the commercialization of technologies or assists in the creation and growth of private enterprises that are commercializing technology.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
