<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="3109" measure-id="id114s3109" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-06-29" update-date="2016-08-18">
<title>Inspector General Recommendation Transparency Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s3109v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-08-18">
<action-date>2016-06-29</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Inspector General Recommendation Transparency Act of 2016</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Inspector General Act of 1978 to require each Inspector General, within one year after the first deadline for the semiannual report on its activities after enactment of this bill, to make available on its website a list of any recommendations by such Inspector General that have been open for more than one year. An &quot;open&quot; recommendation is one that has been made publicly available on such website but has not been adopted or implemented by such Inspector General's establishment.</p> <p>The list shall include:</p> <ul> <li>the number of recommendations issued by the Inspector General for the fiscal year and the number that are open, </li> <li> each report in which an open recommendation was issued,</li> <li> the assigned number and a short description of each open recommendation,</li> <li> the date the open recommendation was first issued and its current status, and</li> <li> any comments of the Inspector General relating to why the recommendation remains open and any response from the establishment.</li> </ul> <p>The list shall be updated by the Inspector General at least every six months.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
