<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1867" measure-id="id114s1867" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-07-27" update-date="2016-10-03">
<title>International Megan's Law to Prevent Child Exploitation Through Advanced Notification of Traveling Sex Offenders</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1867v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-10-03">
<action-date>2015-07-27</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>International Megan's Law to Prevent Child Exploitation Through Advanced Notification of Traveling Sex Offenders</b></p> <p> This bill directs the Department of Homeland Security to establish the Angel Watch Center. The Center must identify outbound sex offender travelers who failed to provide advanced notice of international travel and provide a list of such individuals to the U.S. Marshals Service to investigate. </p> <p>The Department of Justice (DOJ) must designate the Center as the central repository for incoming notifications of sex offender travel. </p> <p>The bill authorizes the Center and the Marshals Service to transmit notification to a destination country of a sex offender's international travel. The Center and the Marshals Service must comply with certain procedures, collect specified data, and establish a complaint process for sex offenders affected by notifications. </p> <p>It amends the Sex Offender Registration and Notification Act to require a registered sex offender to report additional information on intended international travel. In addition, the bill amends the federal criminal code to make it a crime for a sex offender to knowingly fail to report such intended international travel information. </p> <p>DOJ may notify a destination country of a sex offender's international travel. </p> <p>This bill amends the William Wilberforce Trafficking Victims Protection Reauthorization Act of 2008 to prohibit the Department of State from issuing a passport to a sex offender applicant, unless the passport contains a unique identifier. A "unique identifier" is any visual sex offender designation that is conspicuously affixed to a passport. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
