<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2548" measure-id="id114s2548" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-02-11" update-date="2016-10-14">
<title>400 Years of African-American History Commission Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2548v01" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-10-14">
<action-date>2016-09-13</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to Senate amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>400 Years of African-American History Commission Act</b></p> <p>(Sec. 3) This bill establishes the 400 Years of African-American History Commission to develop and carry out activities throughout the United States to commemorate the 400th anniversary of the arrival of Africans in the English colonies at Point Comfort, Virginia, in 1619.</p> <p>The commission must:</p> <ul> <li>plan programs to acknowledge the impact that slavery and laws that enforced racial discrimination had on the United States; </li> <li>encourage civic, patriotic, historical, educational, artistic, religious, and economic organizations to organize and participate in anniversary activities; </li> <li>assist states, localities, and nonprofit organizations to further the commemoration; and </li> <li>coordinate for the public scholarly research on the arrival of Africans in the United States and their contributions to this country. </li></ul> <p>(Sec. 5) The commission may provide: (1) grants to communities and nonprofit organizations for the development of programs; (2) grants to research and scholarly organizations to research, publish, or distribute information relating to the arrival of Africans in the United States; and (3) technical assistance to states, localities, and nonprofit organizations to further the commemoration.</p> <p>(Sec. 7) The commission must prepare a strategic plan and submit a final report to Congress that contains a summary of its activities, an accounting of its received and expended funds, and its recommendations.</p> <p>(Sec. 9) The commission shall terminate on July 1, 2020.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114s2548v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-03-18">
<action-date>2016-02-11</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>400 Years of African-American History Commission Act</b></p> <p>This bill establishes the 400 Years of African-American History Commission to develop and carry out activities throughout the United States to commemorate the 400th anniversary of the arrival of Africans in the English colonies at Point Comfort, Virginia, in 1619.</p> <p>The commission must:</p> <ul> <li>plan programs to acknowledge the impact that slavery and laws that enforced racial discrimination had on the United States;</li> <li> encourage civic, patriotic, historical, educational, artistic, religious, and economic organizations to organize and participate in anniversary activities;</li> <li> assist states, localities, and nonprofit organizations to further the commemoration; and </li> <li> coordinate for the public scholarly research on the arrival of Africans in the United States and their contributions to this country.</li> </ul> <p>The commission may provide grants to: (1) communities and nonprofit organizations for the development of programs; and (2) research and scholarly organizations to research, publish, or distribute information relating to the arrival of Africans in the United States.</p> <p>The commission shall terminate on July 1, 2020.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
