<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1989" measure-id="id114s1989" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-08-05" update-date="2016-06-30">
<title>Primary Care Enhancement Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1989v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-06-30">
<action-date>2015-08-05</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Primary Care Enhancement Act of 2015</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) permit an individual to pay primary care service arrangement costs from a health savings account; (2) allow an eligible taxpayer enrolled in a high-deductible health plan to take a tax deduction for cash paid into a health savings account, even if the taxpayer is simultaneously enrolled in a primary care service arrangement; and (3) for purposes of certain tax-deductible expenses for medical care, expand the definition of "medical care" to include periodic provider fees. A &quot;primary care service arrangement&quot; is an exchange of ongoing primary care services for a fixed periodic fee which is not billed to any third party on a fee-for-service basis. </p> <p>The bill also amends title XI of the Social Security Act to require the Center for Medicare and Medicaid Innovation (CMI) to test a primary care medical home model for payment and service delivery. Under this type of model, qualified direct primary care medical home practices are reimbursed a periodic fee for serving Medicare enrollees. In selecting qualified direct primary care medical home practices to participate, CMI shall give priority to practices seeking to enroll dual-eligible individuals. </p> <p>CMI must conduct the model for at least three years, but, if specified conditions are met, CMI shall expand the model on a nationwide basis and a participating practice may continue permanently.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
