<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2869" measure-id="id114s2869" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-04-28" update-date="2016-08-15">
<title>Boost Saving for College Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2869v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-08-15">
<action-date>2016-04-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Boost Saving for College Act </b></p> <p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to modify the tax treatment of qualified tuition programs (known as 529 plans). </p> <p>The bill allows: (1) a nonrefundable tax credit for contributions of an individual to a 529 plan, and (2) an exclusion from the gross income of an employee of up to $1000 per year of employer contributions to a 529 plan. </p> <p>The bill also permits savings from a 529 plan to be rolled over tax-free into: (1) a Roth Individual Retirement Account of the owner or the beneficiary of a 529 plan that has been maintained for 10 years, and (2) an ABLE account of the designated beneficiary of the 529 plan. </p> <p>(Tax-favored ABLE [Achieving a Better Life Experience] accounts are designed to enable individuals with disabilities to save for and pay for disability-related expenses.)</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
