<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="814" measure-id="id114s814" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-03-19" update-date="2015-11-17">
<title>Oregon Coastal Land Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s814v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-11-17">
<action-date>2015-03-19</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Oregon Coastal Land Act</b></p> <p> Requires all interest of the United States in approximately 14,408 acres of land (Oregon Coastal land) to be held in trust for, and to be part of the reservation of, the Confederated Tribes of Coos, Lower Umpqua, and Siuslaw Indians (Tribes). </p> <p>Applies federal law relating to the export of unprocessed logs harvested from federal land to any unprocessed logs harvested from such land. Prohibits gaming on such land. Requires commercial forestry activity on such land to be managed in accordance with applicable federal laws. Exempts such land from the land use planning requirements of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976. </p> <p>Directs the Tribes to consult with the Department of the Interior and other parties to develop agreements to provide for access to such land that provide for: (1) honoring existing reciprocal right-of-way agreements, (2) administrative access by the Bureau of Land Management, and (3) management of any such land acquired or developed under the Land and Water Conservation Fund. </p> <p>Directs the Department of Agriculture and Interior to identify any land conveyed under this Act that is Oregon and California Railroad grant land. </p> <p>Directs Interior to: (1) identify public domain land in Oregon that is approximately equal in acreage and condition to such Oregon and California Railroad grant land, and (2) reclassify the public domain land as Oregon and California Railroad grant land. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
