<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="264" measure-id="id114s264" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-01-27" update-date="2016-01-04">
<title>Federal Reserve Transparency Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s264v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-01-04">
<action-date>2015-01-27</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Federal Reserve Transparency Act of 2015 </b></p> <p>This bill directs the Government Accountability Office (GAO) to: (1) commence and complete an audit of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System and of the Federal Reserve Banks within 12 months of enactment of this Act, and (2) report findings and conclusions to Congress within 90 days of completing the audit.</p> <p>The bill also repeals certain limitations upon such an audit.</p> <p>GAO shall audit and report on the review of loan files of homeowners in foreclosure in 2009 or 2010, required as part of the enforcement actions taken by the Board against supervised financial institutions.</p> <p>Audit contents shall include: (1) the guidance given by the Board to independent consultants retained by the supervised financial institutions regarding procedures to be followed in conducting the file reviews; (2) the factors considered by independent consultants when evaluating loan files and the results obtained pursuant to those reviews; and (3) the determinations made by such consultants regarding the nature and extent of financial injury sustained by each homeowner, as well as the level and type of remediation offered. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
