<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="883" measure-id="id114s883" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-03-26" update-date="2015-05-07">
<title>American Mineral Security Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s883v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-05-07">
<action-date>2015-03-26</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>American Mineral Security Act of 2015</b></p> <p> This bill amends the National Materials and Minerals Policy, Research and Development Act of 1980 to direct the President to: (1) establish an analytical and forecasting capability for identifying critical mineral market factors so as to avoid supply shortages, mitigate price volatility, and prepare for demand growth and other market shifts; and (2) encourage federal agencies to facilitate development and production of domestic resources to meet national critical material and minerals needs. </p> <p>The Director of the U.S. Geological Survey (Director) shall publish in the Federal Register a methodology for determining which minerals qualify as critical minerals, and review it at least every two years. </p> <p>The Director is also required, within four years after enactment of this Act, to complete a comprehensive national assessment of each critical mineral. </p>   <p>Both the Bureau of Land Management of the Department of the Interior and the Forest Service of the Department of Agricultureshall: (1) complete federal permitting and review processes governing critical mineral production on federal land with maximum efficiency and effectiveness, and (2) report to Congress on additional measures and implementation options.</p>   <p> Prescribes a Federal Register notice process for the issuance of a critical mineral exploration or mine permit. </p> <p>The Department of Energy shall conduct research and development to promote: (1) the production, use, and recycling of critical minerals throughout the supply chain; and (2) develop alternatives to critical minerals that do not occur in significant abundance in the United States.</p> <p>The Director shall publish an annual report that includes, as part of the Mineral Commodity Summaries, a comprehensive review of critical mineral production, consumption, and recycling patterns. </p> <p>The Department of Labor (DOL) must assess the domestic availability of technically trained personnel with the necessary skillset for critical mineral activities. </p> <p>The Director and the DOL shall jointly arrange with the National Academy of Sciences and the National Academy of Engineering to coordinate with the National Science Foundation on a study to design an interdisciplinary program on critical minerals that will support the critical mineral supply chain and increase domestic critical mineral development.</p> <p>The Director and the DOL shall also jointly conduct a competitive grant program for institutions of higher education to implement integrated critical mineral education, training, and workforce development programs. </p> <p>The National Critical Materials Act of 1984 is repealed.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
