<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="769" measure-id="id114s769" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-03-18" update-date="2015-06-04">
<title>Track, Railroad, and Infrastructure Network Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s769v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-06-04">
<action-date>2015-03-18</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Track, Railroad, and Infrastructure Network Act</strong></p> <p>This bill exempts improvements to, maintenance, rehabilitation, or operation of railroad or rail transit lines (but not stations) that are in use or were historically used for the transportation of goods or passengers from federal policies and requirements for the preservation of public park and recreation lands, wildlife and waterfowl refuges, and historic sites. This permits such activities without the necessity to: (1) demonstrate there is no feasible and prudent alternative to the use of such land, and (2) plan to minimize harm to a historic site.</p> <p>The Secretary of Transportation (DOT) may make a finding of de minimis impact on such preservation as a result of mitigation undertaken pursuant to a review of a transportation program or project pursuant to the National Historic Preservation Act.</p> <p>Any rail project that requires DOT approval shall be subject to specified environmental project development procedures.</p> <p>Any environmental impact statement, categorical exclusion, or other decision relating to a transportation project that is issued by a DOT agency under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 shall be available to any rail project to which that statement, exclusion, or decision reasonably applies.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
