<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="3214" measure-id="id114s3214" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-07-14" update-date="2016-08-03">
<title>Vote By Mail Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s3214v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-08-03">
<action-date>2016-07-14</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Vote by Mail Act of 2016</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to:</p> <ul> <li>prohibit a state from imposing any additional conditions or requirements on the eligibility of an individual to cast a vote in a federal election by mail, except to the extent of setting a deadline for returning the ballot to the appropriate state or local election official; and</li> <li>require each state to mail ballots, not later than two weeks before the election, and at no charge, to individuals registered to vote in it.</li> </ul> <p>The National Voter Registration Act of 1993 is amended to revise requirements for simultaneous application for voter registration and for a motor vehicle driver's license to authorize automatic voter registration of individuals through state motor vehicle authorities.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
