<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2610" measure-id="id114s2610" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-03-01" update-date="2016-03-30">
<title>A bill to approve an agreement between the United States and the Republic of Palau.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2610v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-03-30">
<action-date>2016-03-01</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill approves, with specified exceptions, the agreement and appendices signed by the United States and the Republic of Palau on September 3, 2010, in connection with the Compact of Free Association between the United States and Palau.</p> <p>If Palau withdraws more than $5 million from the trust fund set up by the Compact in FY2016, or more than $8 million in FY2017, certain amounts will be withheld from Palau until it reimburses the fund for the total amounts withdrawn that exceeded $5 million in FY2016 or $8 million in FY2017.</p> <p> The bill authorizes appropriations to: (1) subsidize postal services to Palau, the Republic of the Marshall Islands, and the Federated States of Micronesia for FY2017-FY2024; and (2) carry out specified federal responsibilities under the Compact through FY2023.</p> <p>The bill repeals specified offset requirements.</p> <p>Funding is provided through: </p> <ul> <li>FY2018 to reduce government arrears of Palau, </li> <li> FY2023 for additional economic assistance, and </li> <li> FY2024 for infrastructure projects.</li> </ul> <p> Funding is provided through FY2024 to create an Infrastructure Maintenance Fund for routine and periodic maintenance of major capital improvement projects. (Palau is required to provide specified quarterly amounts for the Fund.)</p> <p>The bill revises specified passport requirements.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
