<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1610" measure-id="id114s1610" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-06-18" update-date="2016-04-05">
<title>BALTIMORE Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1610v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-04-05">
<action-date>2015-06-18</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Building and Lifting Trust In order to Multiply Opportunities and Racial Equality Act of 2015 or the BALTIMORE Act</b></p> <p><i>End Racial Profiling Act of 2015</i></p> <p>This bill prohibits racial profiling by federal, state, local, or tribal law enforcement agents or agencies. </p> <p>The Department of Justice (DOJ) or an individual may bring a civil action for declaratory or injunctive relief. Proof of disparate impact constitutes prima facie (i.e., sufficient) evidence of racial profiling.</p> <p>This bills sets forth provisions to eliminate racial profiling, including creating administrative complaint procedures, increasing data collection, and making certain federal funds contingent on law enforcement agencies instituting appropriate policies and procedures.</p> <p><i>Police Creating Accountability by Making Effective Recording Available Act of 2015 or the Police CAMERA Act</i></p> <p>The DOJ Office of Justice Programs may award grants to states, local, governments, and Indian tribes to acquire body-worn cameras. Grant recipients must establish certain policies and protocols related to body-worn cameras. </p>  <p> <p><i>Democracy Restoration Act of 2015</i></p> <p>The bill prohibits denial of the right to vote in any federal election due to a criminal conviction, unless the individual is serving a felony sentence in a correctional institution at election time. It also makes convicted felons eligible for federal jury service.</p> <p><i>Reclassification to Ensure Smarter and Equal Treatment Act of 2015 or the RESET Act</i></p> <p>The bill reduces the penalties for simple possession of a controlled substance by a person with one or more prior drug convictions. It establishes penalties for simple possession of a date rape drug, including flunitrasepam, by person with one or more prior drug conviction.</p> <p> It eliminates the sentencing disparity between trafficking in powder cocaine and trafficking in crack cocaine. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
