<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2619" measure-id="id114s2619" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-03-02" update-date="2016-06-17">
<title>Startup Entrepreneur Empowerment Delivery Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2619v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-06-17">
<action-date>2016-03-02</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Startup Entrepreneur Empowerment Delivery Act of 2016</b></p> <p>This bill directs the Department of Commerce to carry out a one-year pilot program to assess the feasibility and advisability of awarding financial assistance of up to $120,000, on a competitive basis, to up to 10 local governments to support the development of startup businesses.</p> <p>Such a local government must represent a population of 200,000 or less and be eligible to participate in the Experimental Program to Stimulate Competitive Research (&quot;EPSCoR&quot;) of the National Science Foundation.</p> <p>An eligible startup business must be under the local government's jurisdiction, have fewer than five full-time employees, and intend to produce a technology or product that may result in intellectual property vesting in an entity of the United States that can commercialize the technology in a timely manner.</p> <p>Each local government receiving a grant shall ensure that the financial assistance it gives to a startup is used to assist with direct costs related to successfully growing a business.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
