<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="964" measure-id="id114s964" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-04-15" update-date="2015-05-05">
<title>Nuclear Plant Decommissioning Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s964v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-05-05">
<action-date>2015-04-15</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Nuclear Plant Decommissioning Act of 2015</b></p> <p> Amends the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 to require a Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC) licensee, after consulting affected state and local governments, to submit to the NRC a post-shutdown decommissioning activities report (PSDAR) regarding the licensee's shutdown facilities for which a PSDAR is required.</p> <p>Conditions public availability of the PSDAR upon NRC discretion to redact information necessary to protect the national security.</p> <p>Requires the NRC to: (1) solicit public comments on the proposed PSDAR; (2) conduct at least two public hearings within the facility's host state; and (3) invite the host state to file a statement of either support, nonsupport, or of conditional support, including specific recommendations for changes.</p> <p>Directs the NRC, upon receipt of the state's response, to determine, based upon specified considerations, the adequacy or inadequacy of the proposed PSDAR and to issue a decision accordingly.</p> <p>Prescribes criteria for determining whether a proposed PSDAR is permissible if the host state files a statement of conditional support.</p> <p>Requires a licensee to submit a new proposed PSDAR if the first one is rejected.</p> <p>Conditions NRC approval of a proposed PSDAR upon inclusion in the document of a requirement that the licensee comply with applicable state law relating to air, water, or soil quality or radiological standards if that law is more restrictive than its federal counterpart.</p> <p>Requires the NRC, in the case of existing decommissioning activities, to notify: (1) each licensee of the opportunity to develop a revised PSDAR for any facility for which a PSDAR has been submitted but for which decontamination and dismantlement activities have either not been commenced, or have been commenced for less than one year; and (2) each state within 50 miles of the facility of the opportunity to consult with the licensee.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
