<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2058" measure-id="id114s2058" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-09-17" update-date="2016-09-29">
<title>Metropolitan Weather Hazards Protection Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2058v01" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-09-29">
<action-date>2016-09-15</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to Senate amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Metropolitan Weather Hazards Protection Act of 2015</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill directs the Department of Commerce to complete, within 90 days after enactment of this bill, a study on gaps in the coverage of the Next Generation Weather Radar (NEXRAD) of the National Weather Service (NWS).</p> <p>Under this study Commerce shall identify areas in the United States with limited or no NEXRAD coverage below 6,000 feet above ground level of the surrounding terrain.</p> <p>For those areas identified, for Charlotte, North Carolina, and its surrounding counties, central Washington state, northwest New Mexico, and Columbus, Ohio, Commerce shall also:</p> <ul> <li>identify the key weather effects for which prediction would improve with improved radar detection;</li> <li>identify additional sources of observations for high impact weather available and operational for such areas, including Terminal Doppler Weather Radar (TDWR), air surveillance radars of the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA), and cooperative network observers; and </li> <li>assess the feasibility and advisability of efforts to integrate and upgrade federal radar capabilities in such areas that are not owned or controlled by the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, including radar capabilities of the FAA and the Department of Defense. </li> </ul> <p>In addition, under such study Commerce shall:</p> <ul> <li>assess the feasibility and advisability of incorporating state-operated and other nonfederal radars into the operations of the NWS,</li> <li>identify options to improve radar coverage in all of the areas identified as having limited or no NEXRAD coverage below 6,000 feet above ground level of the surrounding terrain, and </li> <li>estimate the cost of, and develop a timeline for, carrying out each of the options identified. </li> </ul> <p>After completing the study Commerce shall submit a plan for improving radar coverage in the identified areas by integrating, and upgrading where practicable, additional observation solutions to improve hazardous weather detection and forecasting.</p> <p>Commerce shall seek third-party reviews on scientific methodology related to, and the feasibility and advisability of, implementing such plan, including the extent to which warning and forecast services of the NWS would be improved by additional NEXRAD coverage.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114s2058v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-10-13">
<action-date>2015-09-17</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Metropolitan Weather Hazards Protection Act of 2015</b></p> <p>This bill directs the Department of Commerce to: (1) maintain and operate at least one Doppler weather radar site within 55 miles of each city in the United States with a population of more than 700,000, and (2) ensure that each such radar is available to the office of the National Weather Service that provides services to that city. </p> <p>Commerce shall ensure that each such radar conforms with the same standards that apply to radars operated by Commerce, through the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, including standards relating to the use of dual-polarization technology or other technologies included in Weather Surveillance Radar, 1988, Doppler (WSR-88D) radars.</p> <p>When determining the location for construction of a radar meeting the requirements of this Act, Commerce shall consider nearby counties that have populations over 130,000 and do not otherwise have radar beam coverage below 10,00 feet from such Doppler radars.</p> <p>Commerce shall report to Congress on the Doppler weather radar sites that need to be constructed or acquired to meet this Act's requirements. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
