<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1689" measure-id="id114s1689" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-06-25" update-date="2015-12-16">
<title>A bill to amend title 23, United States Code, to reduce the funding available for a State under the national highway performance program and the surface transportation program if the State issues a license plate that contains an image of a flag of the Confederate States of America, including the Battle Flag of the Confederate States of America.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1689v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-12-16">
<action-date>2015-06-25</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill requires the amounts apportioned to a state under the national highway performance program and the surface transportation program to be reduced by 5% for: (1) each fiscal year beginning after enactment of this Act in which the state issues a license plate that contains an image of a flag of the Confederate States of America; and (2) each fiscal year beginning with the second fiscal year after enactment of this Act in which the state allows such a license plate issued before the fiscal year beginning after enactment of this Act to be displayed on a motor vehicle registered in the state.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
