<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="381" measure-id="id114s381" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-02-05" update-date="2015-03-20">
<title>Bringing Missing Children Home Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s381v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-03-20">
<action-date>2015-02-05</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Bringing Missing Children Home Act of 2015</b></p> <p>Amends the Missing Children's Assistance Act to require the Office of Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention's annual grant to the National Center for Missing and Exploited Children to be used (among other things) to operate a cyber tipline to provide online users and electronic service providers an effective means of reporting Internet-related child sexual exploitation in the area of child sex trafficking (currently, child prostitution).</p> <p>Amends the Crime Control Act of 1990 to require each state reporting on missing children to: (1) provide, with respect to each missing child report, a recent photograph of the child, if available; (2) direct the law enforcement agency that entered the report into the National Crime Information Center (NCIC) to verify and update such record with any additional information no later than 30 days after the original entry of the record into the state law enforcement system and NCIC computer networks and to maintain close liaison with state and local child welfare systems for the exchange of information and technical assistance; and (3) grant permission to the NCIC Terminal Contractor for the state to update the missing person record in the NCIC computer networks with additional information learned during the investigation relating to the missing person.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
