<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="3161" measure-id="id114s3161" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-07-12" update-date="2016-07-20">
<title>A bill to include the Secretary of Agriculture on the Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States and to provide for the consideration by that Committee of the national security effects of foreign investment on agricultural assets.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s3161v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-07-20">
<action-date>2016-07-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Securing American Food Equity Act of 2016 or the SAFE Act of 2016 </b></p> <p>This bill amends the Defense Production Act of 1950 to include the Secretary of Agriculture on the Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States (CFIUS) and to require CFIUS to consider the national security-related effects on agricultural assets in reviewing transactions. </p> <p>(CFIUS is an interagency committee authorized under current law to review transactions that could result in control of a U.S. business by a foreign person in order to determine the effects of the transactions on national security.)</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
