<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2663" measure-id="id114s2663" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-03-10" update-date="2016-04-05">
<title>Reforming CFPB Indirect Auto Financing Guidance Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2663v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-04-05">
<action-date>2016-03-10</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Reforming CFPB Indirect Auto Financing Guidance Act </b></p> <p> This bill declares without force or effect Consumer Financial Protection Bureau (CFPB) Bulletin 2013-02 (Indirect Auto Lending and Compliance with the Equal Credit Opportunity Act), published March 21, 2013.</p> <p> The Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010 is amended to direct the CFPB, when proposing and issuing guidance primarily related to indirect auto financing, to:</p> <ul> <li>provide for a public notice and comment period before issuing the guidance in final form;</li> <li>make publicly available all information relied on by the CFPB;</li> <li>redact any information exempt from disclosure under the Freedom of Information Act;</li> <li>consult with the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Federal Trade Commission, and the Department of Justice; and <li>study the costs and impacts of the guidance to consumers and women-owned, minority-owned, veteran-owned, and small businesses, including consumers and small businesses in rural areas. </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
