<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2087" measure-id="id114s2087" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-09-28" update-date="2016-09-23">
<title>Fort Scott National Historic Site Boundary Modification Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2087v01" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-09-23">
<action-date>2016-09-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to Senate amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Fort Scott National Historic Site Boundary Modification Act</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill allows the Department of the Interior to acquire by purchase with appropriated funds or by donation (as under current law) the lands and interests in land, together with buildings and improvements, known as Fort Scott in the city of Fort Scott in Bourbon County, Kansas. </p> <p>The proviso that the buildings so acquired shall not include the structure known as &quot;Lunette Blair&quot; is repealed (thereby allowing its acquisition). </p> <p>The boundary of the Fort Scott National Historic Site in Kansas shall be modified accordingly. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114s2087v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-02-23">
<action-date>2015-09-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Fort Scott National Historic Site Boundary Modification Act</b></p> <p>This bill allows the Department of the Interior to acquire by purchase with appropriated funds or by donation (as under current law) the lands and interests in land, together with buildings and improvements, known as Fort Scott in the city of Fort Scott in Bourbon County, Kansas. </p> <p>The proviso that the buildings so acquired shall not include the structure known as &quot;Lunette Blair&quot; is repealed (thereby allowing its acquisition). </p> <p>The boundary of the Fort Scott National Historic Site in Kansas shall be modified accordingly. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
