<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1018" measure-id="id114s1018" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-04-21" update-date="2015-07-15">
<title>SWAT Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1018v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-07-15">
<action-date>2015-04-21</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Swatting Won't be Accepted or Tolerated Act of 2015 or the SWAT Act</strong></p> <p>Amends the federal criminal code to: (1) impose a term of imprisonment of up to eight years for making a false, fictitious, or fraudulent statement or representation to a federal law enforcement agency that causes an emergency federal law enforcement response; and (2) require the court to order a defendant convicted of such an offense to reimburse any federal, state, or local government for up to $10,000 in expenses incurred in responding to that conduct.</p> <p>Extends the requirement that a court order a person convicted of conveying false or misleading information indicating that conduct involving specified criminal violations has taken, is taking, or will take place (including violations regarding biological and chemical weapons, firearms, sabotage of nuclear facilities, importation of explosive materials, terrorism, and damaging or destroying pipeline facilities) to reimburse state and local governments and not-for-profit organizations for expenses incident to fire and rescue service provided in any emergency or investigative response to such conduct to also require reimbursement of law enforcement service and any such services provided by the federal government.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
