<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1920" measure-id="id114s1920" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-08-04" update-date="2015-12-17">
<title>A bill to require the Comptroller General of the United States to develop and submit to Congress a biennial report on the current state of the skills gap in the United States, as of the date of the report, that includes an analysis of the effectiveness of efforts to close the skills gap and policy recommendations to improve such efforts, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1920v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-12-17">
<action-date>2015-08-04</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Biennial Report on the Skills Gap Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>This bill directs the Government Accountability Office to submit a biennial report on the current state of the skills gap in the United States, including: (1) an analysis of the effectiveness of efforts to close such gap, and (2) policy recommendations to improve such efforts.</p> <p>The bill defines &quot;skills gap&quot; as the difference between the specific skills set of employees and the skills desired by employers.</p> <p>Each report may include:</p> <ul> <li>an analysis of employer participation in apprenticeships and on-the-job training in the United States;</li> <li>an assessment of the Department of Labor's Registered Apprenticeship program to determine if it can be better utilized;</li> <li>an analysis of the prevalence and portability of recognized postsecondary credentials that align with occupations that are in demand;</li> <li>a comparison of policies and strategies addressing the current skills gap in the United States with those employed by other large countries; and </li> <li>an analysis of the specific barriers preventing the U.S. workforce from acquiring the skills desired by U.S. employers, including an assessment of opportunities to reduce those barriers.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
