<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2642" measure-id="id114s2642" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-03-03" update-date="2016-04-18">
<title>Stop Trafficking on Planes (STOP) Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2642v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-04-18">
<action-date>2016-03-03</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Stop Trafficking on Planes (STOP) Act of 2016</b></p> <p><strong></strong>This bill requires each air carrier providing passenger air transportation to train flight attendants and pilots who are employees or contractors of the carrier to combat human trafficking in the course of carrying out their duties. Such training shall cover: (1) common indicators of human trafficking, and (2) best practices for reporting suspected human trafficking to law enforcement officers.</p> <p>An air carrier may provide such training using modules and materials developed by the Department of Transportation and the Department of Homeland Security (DHS), including the training modules and associated materials of the Blue Lightning Initiative of the DHS U.S. Customs and Border Protection and subsequent modules and materials developed and recommended by such Departments with respect to combating human trafficking.</p> <p>The Federal Aviation Administration shall report recommendations for improving the identification and reporting of human trafficking by air carrier personnel while protecting the civil liberties of passengers.</p> <p>The bill grants immunity to an air carrier for reporting any suspicious transaction relevant to a possible violation of law or regulation relating to human trafficking.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
