<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2954" measure-id="id114s2954" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-05-19" update-date="2016-09-27">
<title>Ste. Genevieve National Historical Park Establishment Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2954v01" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-09-27">
<action-date>2016-09-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to Senate amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Ste. Genevieve National Historical Park Establishment Act of 2016</b></p> <p>(Sec. 3) This bill establishes the Ste. Genevieve National Historical Park in Missouri as a unit of the National Park System. </p> <p>The historical park shall not be established until: </p> <ul> <li>sufficient land has been acquired for the Historical Park to constitute a manageable unit; and</li> <li>the Department of the Interior has entered into an agreement providing that land owned by Missouri, the city of Ste. Genevieve, or other entity within the Ste. Genevieve Historic District National Historic Landmark (historic district) shall be managed consistent with this bill's purposes. </li> </ul> <p>Interior may acquire, by donation, purchase, or exchange, any land or interest in land located within the boundary of the historical park or any nationally significant property identified in the special resource study that is within the historic district. </p> <p> Interior shall revise the boundary of the historical park to include any property from within the historic district that is acquired by Interior. </p> <p>Interior shall prepare and submit a general management plan for the historical park.</p> <p>Interior may arrange for interpretive tours and educational programs at related historic and cultural sites within the historic district.</p> <p>Interior may furnish technical assistance and enter into cooperative agreements with the owner of a nationally significant property within the historical park or the historic district, for the identification, marking, interpretation, improvement, and restoration of such property. </p>  <p>The federal cost share of any activity carried out under a cooperative agreement under this bill shall be a maximum of 50% of the total cost of that activity. The nonfederal share of an activity may be in the form of fairly valued donated property, goods, or services.</p>  <p>Any payment made by Interior under this bill shall be subject to an agreement that the conversion, use, or disposal of a property or project for purposes contrary to this bill's purposes shall entitle the federal government to reimbursement in any amount equal to the greater of:</p> <ul> <li>the amounts made available to the property or project by the federal government; or</li> <li>the portion of the increased value of the property or project attributable to those amounts, as determined at the time of conversion, use, or disposal. </li> </ul> <p>Nothing in this bill authorizes Interior to assume overall financial responsibility for the operation, maintenance, or management of the historic district.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114s2954v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-05-26">
<action-date>2016-05-19</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Ste. Genevieve National Historic Site Establishment Act of 2016</b></p> <p>This bill establishes the Ste. Genevieve National Historic Site in Missouri as a unit of the National Park System.</p>  <p>Interior may acquire, by donation, purchase, or exchange, any land or interest in land located within the boundary of the Historic Site or any nationally significant property identified in the special resource study that is within the Ste. Genevieve Historic District National Historic Landmark. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
