<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="407" measure-id="id114s407" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-02-05" update-date="2015-03-24">
<title>Large Capacity Ammunition Feeding Device Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s407v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-03-24">
<action-date>2015-02-05</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Large Capacity Ammunition Feeding Device Act of 2015</b></p> <p> Amends the Brady Handgun Violence Prevention Act to prohibit the importation, sale, manufacture, transfer, or possession, in or affecting interstate or foreign commerce, of a large capacity ammunition feeding device. </p> <p>Defines a &quot;large capacity ammunition feeding device&quot; to: (1) mean a magazine, belt, drum, feed strip, helical feeding device, or similar device that has an overall capacity of, or that can be readily changed to accept, more than 10 rounds of ammunition; and (2) exclude an attached tubular device designed to accept, and capable of operating only with, .22 caliber rimfire ammunition.</p> <p>Provides exemptions for: (1) devices lawfully possessed before this Act's enactment; (2) federal, state, and local agencies and law enforcement officers; (3) licensees under the Atomic Energy Act for on-site security, off-site training, and transportation of nuclear materials; and (4) authorized testing or experimentation by a licensed firearms manufacturer or importer.</p> <p>Requires a device manufactured after this Act's enactment to be identified by a serial number and the date it was manufactured conspicuously engraved or cast on the device.</p> <p>Sets penalties for violations. Subjects devices used or involved in knowing violation of such Act to seizure and forfeiture.</p> <p>Amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to authorize the use of Edward Byrne Memorial Justice Assistance Grants for buy-back programs for surrendered large capacity ammunition feeding devices.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
