<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2889" measure-id="id114s2889" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-04-28" update-date="2016-05-17">
<title>American Innovators and Entrepreneurs Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2889v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-05-17">
<action-date>2016-04-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>American Innovators and Entrepreneurs Act</b></p> <p>This bill amends the National Science Foundation Authorization Act of 2010 to direct the National Science Foundation (NSF) to: </p> <ul> <li>carry out an Innovation Corps (I-Corps) program to award grants for entrepreneurship and commercialization education to science and engineering researchers and students and institutions of higher education to increase the economic impact of federally funded research; and </li> <li>develop and provide access through specified Nodes, Sites, and Teams to I-Corps program curriculum by supporting entrepreneurship and commercialization education and training for faculty, students, postdoctoral fellows, and other science and engineering researchers. </li> </ul> <p>The purpose of grants shall be to increase the capacity of science and engineering researchers and students to engage successfully in entrepreneurial activities and to help transition the results of federally funded research into the marketplace.</p>  <p>The Treasury may:</p> <ul> <li>locate and recover U.S. government assets on behalf of any executive, judicial, or legislative agency; and </li> <li>retain a portion of recovered amounts to cover administrative and operational costs associated with locating and recovering those assets.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
