<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1448" measure-id="id114s1448" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-21" update-date="2016-09-27">
<title>Frank Moore Wild Steelhead Sanctuary Designation Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1448v01" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-09-27">
<action-date>2016-09-08</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to Senate amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Frank Moore Wild Steelhead Special Management Area Designation Act</b></p> (Sec. 4) This bill designates approximately 99,653 acres of Forest Service land in Oregon as the Frank Moore Wild Steelhead Special Management Area. <p>The special management area shall be administered by the Department of the Agriculture, through the Forest Service, to:</p> <ul> <li>conserve and enhance the natural character, scientific use, and the botanical, recreational, ecological, fish and wildlife, scenic, drinking water, and cultural values of the special management area;</li> <li>maintain and seek to enhance the wild salmonid habitat of the special management area; </li> <li>maintain or enhance the watershed as a thermal refuge for wild salmonids; and </li> <li>preserve opportunities for recreation, including primitive recreation. </li> </ul> <p>Nothing in this bill creates any protective perimeter or buffer zone around the special management area.</p> <p>Nothing in this bill prohibits the Department of the Interior, in cooperation with other federal, state, and local agencies, from conducting wildland fire operations in the special management area, including the use of aircraft, machinery, mechanized equipment, fire breaks, backfires, and retardant.</p> <p>Nothing in this bill prohibits Interior from conducting vegetation management projects within the special management area. </p> <p>Nothing in this bill diminishes any treaty rights of Indian tribes.</p> <p>The bill withdraws the federal land within the boundaries of the special management area's river segments from:</p> <ul> <li>entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws;</li> <li>location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and </li> <li>disposition under all laws relating to mineral and geothermal leasing or mineral materials.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114s1448v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-07-31">
<action-date>2015-05-21</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Frank Moore Wild Steelhead Sanctuary Designation Act</b></p> <p>Designates the approximately 104,000 acres of Forest Service land in Oregon as the Frank Moore Wild Steelhead Sanctuary. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
