<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1113" measure-id="id114s1113" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-04-28" update-date="2015-05-27">
<title>A bill to amend title 28, United States Code, to remand certain civil actions transferred by the judicial panel on multidistrict litigation.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1113v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-05-27">
<action-date>2015-04-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Amends the federal judicial code to revise the process for remanding civil actions involving common questions of fact pending in different districts that the judicial panel on multidistrict litigation transfers to a single district for consolidated pretrial proceedings. </p> <p>Requires each action, upon a motion of a plaintiff, to be remanded back to the district court from which it was transferred if the panel does not remand the action at or before the conclusion of such pretrial proceedings within five years after the action is transferred.</p> <p>Directs the district court receiving a remanded action to then schedule the completion of discovery and a trial date in accordance with the civil justice expense and delay reduction plan implemented by the court.</p> <p>Makes this Act applicable to any civil action pending in a transferee district court on or after August 1, 2010.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
