<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2413" measure-id="id114s2413" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-12-17" update-date="2016-01-28">
<title>TOTAL Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2413v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-01-28">
<action-date>2015-12-17</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Tallying of the Actual Liabilities Act of 2015 or the TOTAL Act of 2015</b></p> <p>This bill prohibits a retailer under the jurisdiction of the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) from selling a product or service through an Internet website without presenting the total transaction amount it expects to collect from the potential purchaser (including all fees, taxes, and shipping and handling charges) before the person commits to the purchase.</p> <p>The bill sets forth authority for: (1) the FTC to enforce a violation of this Act as an unfair or deceptive act or practice, and (2) states to bring civil actions on behalf of residents threatened or adversely affected by such a violation.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
