<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2312" measure-id="id114s2312" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-11-19" update-date="2016-09-15">
<title>DME Access and Stabilization Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2312v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-09-15">
<action-date>2015-11-19</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>DME Access and Stabilization Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>This bill amends titles XVIII (Medicare) and XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to modify provisions relating to payment for durable medical equipment (DME) under the Medicare and Medicaid programs. (DME includes&nbsp;certain medically necessary equipment such as walkers, wheelchairs, and hospital beds.)</p> <p>With respect to DME furnished in areas that are not competitive acquisition areas, current regulations require the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid (CMS) to phase in, over a two-year period,&nbsp;Medicare payment adjustments using information from competitive&nbsp;acquisition programs. (Through such programs, payment amounts for each area are determined based on competitive bids submitted by suppliers, rather than&nbsp;according to an&nbsp;established fee schedule.) The bill codifies this requirement and specifies that CMS&nbsp;shall adjust fee schedule amounts to the lesser of: (1) a specified percentage of the regional amount; and (2) the amount that would otherwise be determined according to the fee schedule, with specified&nbsp;adjustments. </p> <p>In determining&nbsp;Medicare payment&nbsp;adjustments for areas that are not competitive acquisition areas,&nbsp;CMS shall&nbsp;solicit stakeholder input and take into account several specified factors.</p> <p>CMS&nbsp;may not establish&nbsp;a ceiling on competitive bids submitted for DME that is less than the amount that would otherwise be paid under Medicare.</p> <p>The Medicare Beneficiary Ombudsman shall evaluate the impact of the competitive&nbsp;acquisition&nbsp;program on beneficiary health status and health outcomes.</p> <p>The bill limits federal Medicaid reimbursement rates to states for DME to the rates that would be paid for such items under Medicare.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
