<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2517" measure-id="id114s2517" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-02-09" update-date="2016-08-25">
<title>Combat Terrorist Use of Social Media Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2517v01" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-08-25">
<action-date>2016-07-11</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to Senate amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Combat Terrorist Use of Social Media Act of</b> <b>2016</b></p> <p>(Sec. 3) This bill requires the President to transmit to Congress a report, an evaluation, and a strategy on U.S. efforts to combat terrorists' and terrorist organizations' use of social media. </p> <p>The report, to be submitted within 90 days after enactment of this bill, must include: </p> <ul> <li>an evaluation of the role social media plays in the radicalization of individuals to facilitate or commit international or domestic terrorism; </li> <li>an analysis of how terrorists and terrorist organizations are using social media; </li> <li>the federal government's efforts to monitor, review, disrupt, and counter the use of social media by terrorists and terrorist organizations; </li> <li>an assessment of the value to law enforcement and the intelligence community of reviewing terrorists' social media posts; </li> <li>an overview of local, state, and federal training available to combat terrorists' use of social media, the required qualifications of trainers, the intended participants of each program, and recommendations for improving or expanding existing training participation and incorporating training on civil rights and liberties;</li> <li>an assessment of the value to the federal government of collaborating with civil society to counter terrorist propaganda and radicalization; and</li> <li>an assessment of any impact the efforts of the federal government to combat terrorists' and terrorist organizations' use of social media may have upon the civil rights and liberties of U.S. persons who are not engaged in terrorist activities.</li> </ul> <p>The evaluation, to be submitted within 180 days after enactment of this bill, must:</p> <ul> <li>recommend improvements to the federal government's efforts to monitor, review, disrupt, and counter the use of social media by terrorists and terrorist organizations;</li> <li>analyze how the federal government is using social media to counter terrorist propaganda and radicalization, and how such tactics fit within the broader efforts of the federal government to combat domestic terrorism and international terrorism; and</li> <li>assess again any impact the efforts of the federal government to combat terrorists' and terrorist organizations' use of social media may have upon the civil rights and liberties of U.S. persons who are not engaged in terrorist activities.</li> </ul> <p>(Sec. 4) The President, within 180 days after enactment of this bill, must also transmit to Congress a comprehensive strategy to counter terrorists' and terrorist organizations' use of social media, as committed to in the President's 2011 Strategic Implementation Plan for Empowering Local Partners to Prevent Violent Extremism in the United States. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114s2517v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-03-16">
<action-date>2016-02-09</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Combat Terrorist Use of Social Media Act of</b> <b>2016</b></p> <p>This bill requires the President to transmit to Congress a report on U.S. strategy to combat terrorists' and terrorist organizations' use of social media. </p> <p>The report must include: </p> <ul> <li>an evaluation of the role social media plays in radicalization domestically and abroad; </li> <li>an analysis of how terrorists and terrorist organizations are using social media; </li> <li>recommendations to improve the federal government's efforts to monitor, review, disrupt, and counter the use of social media by terrorists and terrorist organizations; </li> <li>an analysis of how the federal government is using social media to counter terrorist propaganda and radicalization; </li> <li>an assessment of the value to law enforcement and the intelligence community of reviewing terrorists' social media posts; and </li> <li>an overview of local, state, and federal training available to combat terrorists' use of social media, the required qualifications of trainers, the intended students of each program, and recommendations for improving or expanding existing training participation. </li></ul> <p>The President must also transmit to Congress a comprehensive strategy to counter terrorists' and terrorist organizations' use of social media, as committed to in the President's 2011 Strategic Implementation Plan for Empowering Local Partners to Prevent Violent Extremism in the United States. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
