<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="3016" measure-id="id114s3016" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-05-26" update-date="2016-07-15">
<title>Recovering Missing Children Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s3016v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-07-15">
<action-date>2016-05-26</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Recovering Missing Children Act</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to permit federal law enforcement officials to seek an ex parte order in federal court for the disclosure of tax returns or return information for criminal investigations pertaining to missing or exploited children.</p> <p> If the order is granted, the information may be disclosed to federal officers and employees who are personally and directly engaged in judicial or administrative proceedings, investigations, or federal grand jury proceedings to enforce a federal criminal statute pertaining to a missing or exploited child. </p> <p>A federal agency may disclose to state and local law enforcement agencies information obtained under the authority provided by this bill if: </p> <ul> <li> the state or local agency is part of a team with the federal agency in the investigation, and </li> <li>the information is disclosed only to officers and employees who are personally and directly engaged in the investigation. </li> </ul> <p>The state or local agency may only use the disclosed information in locating the missing child, in a grand jury proceeding, or in any preparation for, or investigation which may result in, a judicial or administrative proceeding. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
