<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="3333" measure-id="id114s3333" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-09-15" update-date="2016-11-02">
<title>Mohave County Federal Land Management Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s3333v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-11-02">
<action-date>2016-09-15</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Mohave County Federal Land Management Act</b></p> <p>This bill directs the Department of the Interior to conduct sales of eligible lands in Mohave County, Arizona, which are administered by the Bureau of Land Management and have been designated for disposal by Interior.</p> <p>Interior and Mohave County shall jointly select which parcels of eligible land to offer for sale.</p> <p>Before carrying out a sale, Mohave County shall certify to Interior that qualified bidders have agreed to comply with:</p> <ul> <li>local zoning ordinances; and</li> <li>any master plan for the area approved by the county. </li> </ul> <p>Each sale of eligible land shall be:</p> <ul> <li>through a competitive bidding process, under which adjoining landowners are offered the first option, unless otherwise determined by Interior;</li> <li>for not less than fair market value, based on an appraisal; and </li> <li>conducted in accordance with the requirements regarding the administration of a sale of such land pursuant to this bill. </li> </ul> <p>The bill sets forth requirements for the disposition of proceeds from the sales of eligible lands under this bill. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
