<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="348" measure-id="id114s348" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-02-03" update-date="2015-04-13">
<title>PLANT Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s348v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-04-13">
<action-date>2015-02-03</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Protecting Lands Against Narcotics Trafficking Act of 2015 or the PLANT Act</b></p> <p> Amends the Controlled Substances Act to: (1) impose an additional term of up to ten years' imprisonment for cultivating or manufacturing controlled substances on federal property; and (2) apply the prohibition against assembling, maintaining, or placing a booby trap on federal property where a controlled substance is being manufactured to federal property where a controlled substance is being cultivated. </p> <p>Directs the U.S. Sentencing Commission to amend and review the Federal Sentencing Guidelines to provide for a penalty enhancement of not less than one offense level for manufacturing, distributing, or dispensing, or possessing with intent to manufacture, distribute, or dispense a controlled substance or a counterfeit substance while on federal property or while intentionally trespassing on the property of another if such offense: (1) creates a hazard to humans, wildlife, or domestic animals; (2) degrades or harms the environment or natural resources; (3) pollutes an aquifer, spring, stream, river, or body of water; (4) involves the diversion, redirection, obstruction, or draining of an aquifer, spring, stream, river, or body of water or the clear cut of timber while cultivating or manufacturing a controlled substance; or (5) involves the possession of a firearm while cultivating or manufacturing controlled substances.</p> <p>Prohibits, and sets penalties of up to $500,000 for an individual or $1 million for other than an individual for, diverting, redirecting, obstructing, or draining an aquifer, spring, stream, river, or body of water or clear cutting timber while cultivating or manufacturing a controlled substance on federal property or while cultivating or manufacturing a controlled substance while intentionally trespassing on the property of another. Requires such fines to be transferred to the Department of the Interior for use in addressing the environmental damage caused by the offense.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
