<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="830" measure-id="id114s830" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-03-23" update-date="2015-11-13">
<title>LDRD Enhancement Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s830v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-11-13">
<action-date>2015-03-23</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>LDRD Enhancement Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>Amends the Energy and Water Development and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2009 to increase from 8% to 10% the percentage of Department of Energy (DOE) funding for government-owned, contractor-operated laboratories that may be used for laboratory directed research and development. </p> <p>Amends the Atomic Energy Defense Act to increase from 6% to 10% the maximum percentage of DOE funding to government-owned, contractor-operated laboratories for national security activities that DOE may provide to such laboratories for laboratory directed research and development.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
