<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2417" measure-id="id114s2417" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-12-17" update-date="2016-09-12">
<title>Tribal Veterans Health Care Enhancement Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2417v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-09-12">
<action-date>2015-12-17</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Tribal Veterans Health Care Enhancement Act</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Indian Health Care Improvement Act to allow the Indian Health Service (IHS) to pay copayments owed to the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) by Indian veterans for services authorized under the Purchased/Referred Care program.</p> <p>The IHS and the VA, in consultation with impacted Indian tribes, must enter into a memorandum of understanding that authorizes the IHS to pay such copayments unless it would decrease the quality of, or access to, health care for individuals receiving care from the IHS or the VA.</p> The IHS and the VA must report on veterans who are IHS beneficiaries and have received care from the VA.]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
