<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1545" measure-id="id114s1545" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-06-10" update-date="2015-07-10">
<title>A bill to require a quarterly report by the Federal Communications Commission on the Lifeline program funded by the Universal Service Fund.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1545v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-07-10">
<action-date>2015-06-10</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Requires the Federal Communications Commission to submit a quarterly report to Congress&nbsp;regarding the Lifeline program, which provides discounts on telephone service to qualifying low-income consumers. Requires the reports to include: (1) aggregate expenditures on the program; (2) a list of each payment made to a participating telecommunications&nbsp;carrier for the provision of service through the program, including, in the case of a participating carrier that is reimbursed for the provision of service to both wireless and wireline subscribers, the amount of the payment that corresponds to each type of service; and (3) the average cost per subscriber, across all the participating carriers, to provide the service that the program subsidizes, broken down by wireless and wireline subscribers and averaged per subscriber.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
