<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="3147" measure-id="id114s3147" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-07-07" update-date="2016-08-25">
<title>Patsy T. Mink Gender Equity in Education Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s3147v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-08-25">
<action-date>2016-07-07</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Patsy T. Mink Gender Equity in Education Act of 2016</b></p> <p>This bill requires the Department of Education (ED) to establish an Office for Gender Equity to support state and local educational agencies, institutions of higher education, and elementary and secondary schools in fully implementing title IX of the Education Amendments of 1972, which prohibits discrimination on the basis of sex in federally funded education programs or activities. The office may provide grants and perform activities to reduce or prevent discrimination, bias, harassment, or violence based on actual or perceived sex, sexual orientation, gender, gender identity, pregnancy, childbirth, or related medical conditions or stereotypes in all areas of education.</p> <p>The office must: (1) provide technical assistance and annual training to title IX coordinators, and (2) develop a handbook for conducting self-evaluations of title IX compliance. The training must address &quot;compound discrimination&quot; (defined as discrimination based on sex and other characteristics, including race, ethnicity, national origin, disability status, religion, or age).</p> <p>The office may award grants to educational entities and partnerships to:</p> <ul> <li> train students, teachers, faculty, and personnel; </li> <li>increase campus resources, facilities, and course offerings; </li> <li>support title IX coordinators in performing outreach, advocacy, and education;</li> <li> identify patterns or systemic problems in title IX compliance;</li> <li> strengthen prevention education and awareness programs; </li> <li> conduct campus climate and victimization surveys; </li> <li> identify gender inequities; and</li> <li>improve data collection and reporting of gender equity indicators from academic assessments, civil rights data, campus data, employment data, attendance and absenteeism data, or title IX coordinator-to-student ratios.</li> </ul> <p>ED must coordinate with the Institute of Education Sciences and other federal offices and entities to investigate, identify, and disseminate best practices to: (1) reduce and prevent sex stereotyping, bias, and discrimination in curricula and educational materials; (2) address sex-based harassment and violence on campuses; (3) develop counseling and career guidance training; (4) mitigate implicit bias in teaching and discipline; and (5) address the needs of students who face compound discrimination.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
