<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="324" measure-id="id114s324" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-01-30" update-date="2015-03-03">
<title>SEAL Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s324v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-03-03">
<action-date>2015-01-30</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Shrinking Emergency Account Losses Act of 2015 or the SEAL Act</strong> </p> <p>Amends the Internal Revenue Code, with respect to loans made from a qualified employer pension plan, to: (1) extend the period for repayment of loans if a plan terminates or a plan participant becomes unemployed, and (2) prohibit plans from allowing the use of credit cards or similar arrangements to access loan amounts.</p> <p>Requires the Secretary of the Treasury to modify regulations governing hardship distributions from qualified employer pension plans to allow participants to make additional contributions to a plan during the six month period following a hardship distribution.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
