<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2746" measure-id="id114s2746" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-04-05" update-date="2016-04-07">
<title>Detaining Terrorists to Protect Americans Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2746v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-04-07">
<action-date>2016-04-05</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Detaining Terrorists to Protect Americans Act of 2016</strong></p> <p>This bill prohibits the use of funds to transfer, release, or assist in the transfer or release to or within the United States, its territories, or possessions of Khalid Sheikh Mohammed or any other detainee who: (1) is not a U.S. citizen or a member of the Armed Forces; and (2) is or was held by the Department of Defense (DOD) on or after January 20, 2009, at Naval Station Guantanamo Bay, Cuba.</p> <p>No funds may be used: </p> <ul> <li>to construct or modify any facility in the United States, its territories, or possessions to house any individual detained at Guantanamo under DOD custody or control unless expressly authorized by Congress; or </li> <li>through FY2017 to transfer, release, or assist in the transfer or release of an individual detained at Guantanamo to any foreign country or foreign entity unless expressly authorized by Congress.</li> </ul> <p> &quot;Individual detained at Guantanamo&quot; means any individual located at Guantanamo as of October 1, 2009, who: (1) is not a U.S. citizen or a member of the Armed Forces; and (2) is under DOD custody or control, or otherwise under detention at Guantanamo. </p> <p>No funds may be used to: (1) close or abandon Guantanamo, (2) relinquish control of Guantanamo to Cuba, or (3) implement a material modification to the Treaty Between the United States of America and Cuba that constructively closes Guantanamo.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
