<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2997" measure-id="id114s2997" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-05-26" update-date="2016-07-20">
<title>A bill to direct the Federal Communications Commission to commence proceedings related to the resiliency of critical telecommunications networks during times of emergency, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2997v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-07-20">
<action-date>2016-05-26</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Securing Access to Networks in Disasters Act of 2016</b></p> <p>This bill requires the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to create a master point of contact directory for effective communications between public safety answering points and telecommunications service providers.</p> <p>The FCC must submit a study on the public safety benefits, technical feasibility, and cost of providing the public with access to 9-1-1 services during times of emergency when mobile service is unavailable, through:</p> <ul> <li>telecommunications service provider-owned WiFi access points and other communications technologies operating on unlicensed spectrum, without requiring any login credentials; </li> <li>non-telecommunications service provider-owned WiFi access points; and</li> <li>other alternative means. </li> </ul> <p>The types of emergencies subject to this bill are: (1) occasions or instances under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act for which the President determines that federal assistance is needed to supplement state and local efforts and capabilities to save lives and to protect property and public health and safety, or to lessen or avert the threat of a catastrophe in any part of the United States; or (2) an emergency declared by the governor of a state or U.S. territory.</p> <p>The Government Accountability Office must report on: (1) how federal agencies can ensure critical telecommunications networks remain operational during emergencies, and (2) whether to add points of contact for local utilities to the master directory.</p> <p>The Stafford Act is amended to include all categories of communications service providers (currently, only telecommunications service providers) among the essential service providers that may access a disaster site to restore and repair essential services in an emergency or major disaster without being denied or impeded by a federal agency. Communications services include wireline and mobile telephone, Internet, radio and television broadcasting, cable, and direct broadcast satellite services.</p> <p>The Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) must encourage the adoption of mutual aid agreements recognizing the credentials of essential service providers issued by all parties to such an agreement.</p> <p>At the direction of the President, federal agencies may provide assistance essential to meeting immediate threats to life and property resulting from a major disaster by establishing temporary, or restoring, communications service.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
