<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="582" measure-id="id114s582" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-02-26" update-date="2015-05-19">
<title>No Taxpayer Funding for Abortion and Abortion Insurance Full Disclosure Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s582v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-05-19">
<action-date>2015-02-26</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>No Taxpayer Funding for Abortion and Abortion Insurance Full Disclosure Act of 2015</b></p> <p>This bill prohibits federal funds, including funds in the budget of the District of Columbia, from being expended for abortion or health coverage that includes coverage of abortion. Abortions are eligible for federal funding only in cases of rape or incest, or where a physical condition endangers a woman's life unless an abortion is performed. Currently, federal funding of abortion and health coverage that includes abortion is prohibited, with the same exceptions.</p> <p>Health care provided in a federal health care facility or by a federal employee may not include abortions that are ineligible for federal funding.</p> <p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to disallow premium assistance tax credits or health insurance tax credits for qualified health plans that cover abortions ineligible for federal funding.</p> <p>This bill amends the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act to require the Office of Personnel Management to ensure that multi-state qualified health plans offered on health insurance exchanges do not cover abortions ineligible for federal funding.</p> <p>A qualified health plan's coverage of abortion must be disclosed to enrollees at the time of enrollment and must be prominently displayed in marketing materials, comparison tools, or any summary of benefits and coverage made available by the plan issuer, a health insurance exchange, or the Department of Health and Human Services. The amount of a plan's premium that is attributable to coverage of abortions ineligible for federal funding must be disclosed in material where the premium is disclosed. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
