<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1101" measure-id="id114s1101" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-04-27" update-date="2015-10-28">
<title>MEDTECH Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1101v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-10-28">
<action-date>2015-04-27</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Medical Electronic Data Technology Enhancement for Consumers&rsquo; Health Act or the MEDTECH Act</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to exclude from regulation by the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) as a medical device:</p> <ul> <li>administrative, operational, or financial records software used in health care settings;</li> <li> software for maintaining or encouraging a healthy lifestyle unrelated to medical treatment;</li> <li>electronic patient records, excluding software for interpreting or analyzing medical image data;</li> <li>software for clinical laboratory testing, excluding software for interpreting or analyzing test data; and</li> <li> software that provides medical recommendations and the basis for those recommendations to health care professionals, excluding software for acquiring, processing, or analyzing medical images or signals. </li> </ul> <p>The FDA may assess a software function excluded from regulation above when determining the safety and effectiveness of a medical device with multiple functions.</p> <p>The FDA must classify a medical device accessory based on its intended function, not based on the classification of the medical device with which it is used.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
