<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1189" measure-id="id114s1189" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-05" update-date="2015-06-22">
<title>Conrad State 30 and Physician Access Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1189v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-06-22">
<action-date>2015-05-05</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Conrad State 30 and Physician Access Act</strong> </p> <p>Amends the Immigration and Nationality Technical Corrections Act of 1994 to make the J-1 visa waiver (Conrad state 30/medical services in underserved areas) program permanent.</p> <p>Excludes from numerical immigration limitations alien physicians who have completed national interest waiver requirements by working in a health care shortage area (including alien physicians who completed such service before the date of enactment of this Act and any spouses or children of such alien physicians).</p> <p>Sets forth specified employment protections and contract requirements for alien physicians working in underserved areas, including a six-month status extension for a physician whose application his been denied by an oversubscribed state who then agrees to work in an undersubscribed state.</p> <p>Increases the number of alien physicians that a state may be allocated from 30 to 35 per fiscal year under specified circumstances. Provides for additional increases or decreases based upon demand.</p> <p>Provides up to three visa waivers per fiscal year per state for physicians in academic medical centers. </p> <p>Permits dual intent for an alien coming to the United States to receive graduate medical education or training, or to take examinations required for graduate medical education or training. </p> <p>Exempts H-1B nonimmigrant aliens seeking to enter the United States to pursue graduate medical education or training from specified entry limitations.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
