<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="715" measure-id="id114s715" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-03-11" update-date="2015-06-16">
<title>Military and Veterans Mental Health Provider Assessment Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s715v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-06-16">
<action-date>2015-03-11</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Military and Veterans Mental Health Provider Assessment Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>Directs the Department of Defense and the Department of Veterans Affairs to ensure that all health care providers under their respective jurisdictions receive, at least once every three years, empirically supported training on the recognition and assessment of individuals at risk for suicide and the management of such risk.</p> <p>Requires such Departments to: (1) conduct annual evaluations of the implementation by mental health care providers under their jurisdictions of Department-recommended clinical practice guidelines and other evidence-based treatments and approaches, and (2) incorporate such evaluations into the employee evaluation process of such providers.</p> <p>Directs such Departments to jointly submit: (1) a report assessing their mental health work forces and the long-term mental health care needs of members of the Armed Forces and veterans for purposes of determining long-term needs of such Departments for mental health care providers; and (2) a plan to jointly develop procedures to compile and assess data relating to outcomes for mental health care provided by the Departments, variations in such outcomes among different Department medical facilities, and barriers to the implementation by Department mental health care providers of recommended clinical practice guidelines and other evidence-based treatments and approaches.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
