<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1854" measure-id="id114s1854" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-07-23" update-date="2015-10-08">
<title>Postal Innovation Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1854v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-10-08">
<action-date>2015-07-23</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Postal Innovation Act</strong></p> <p>This bill expands the powers of the U.S. Postal Service (USPS) by allowing it to offer nonpostal services, including financial services, warehousing, public Internet access, experimental postal products market testing, shipment of beer, wine, and spirits, and community support services. The bill also authorizes USPS to: (1) furnish property and services to states, local governments, and tribal governments; and (2) conduct a pilot program to assess the most cost-effective implementation of providing nonpostal services to communities through public-private partnerships at post offices in five cities, including at least one post office in a rural area and one in an urban area. </p> <p>The bill authorizes USPS to enter into contracts to upgrade its fleet of vehicles to increase long-term savings by reducing collision, maintenance, fuel, or other costs. USPS is required to develop fuel economy guidelines for its vehicles and to reduce the petroleum consumption of its vehicles by not less than 2% annually through the end of FY2025. </p> <p>USPS may use cost savings from offering nonpostal services to reinvest in innovation, research and development, and operations. USPS must use commercially available crash avoidance technologies to improve the safety of its vehicle fleet. </p> <p>The bill requires the Government Accountability Office to conduct a study on USPS providing access to public broadband Internet service and Internet voting. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
