<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1433" measure-id="id114s1433" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-21" update-date="2016-03-17">
<title>Improving Driver Safety Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1433v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-03-17">
<action-date>2015-05-21</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Improving Driver Safety Act of 2015</b></p> <p>This bill adds a new requirement for distracted driving grants to states under national priority highway safety programs. To receive a grant a state's prohibition on texting while driving must:</p> <ul> <li> include distracted driving issues as part of their driver's license examination, and</li> <li>not make an exception that specifically allows a driver, especially one under age 18, to text through a personal wireless communication device while stopped in traffic.</li> </ul> <p>DOT may use up to 50% of amounts available for grants to states that: </p> <ul> <li> in FY2016 certify that they have enacted a basic text messaging statute for drivers of all ages, make violation of the statute a primary offense, participate in the annual distracted driving law enforcement mobilization, and are otherwise ineligible for a grant; and </li> <li> in FY2017 meet the aforementioned requirements, impose increased fines for repeat violations, and have a statute that prohibits a driver younger than 18 from using a personal wireless communications device while driving.</li> </ul> <p>States may use grant funds for: </p> <ul> <li> enforcement of distracted driving laws, and </li> <li> highway safety program projects.</li> </ul> <p>The National Highway Traffic Safety Administration shall report to Congress on any legal and technical barriers to capturing data on the prevalence of the use of wireless communications devices while driving, including recommendations on how to address those barriers.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
