<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="3081" measure-id="id114s3081" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-06-21" update-date="2016-07-08">
<title>WINGMAN Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s3081v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-07-08">
<action-date>2016-06-21</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Working to Integrate Networks Guaranteeing Member Access Now Act or the WINGMAN Act</strong></p> <p>This bill directs the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to provide an accredited, permanent congressional employee with read-only remote access to the electronic Veterans Benefits Administration (VBA) claims records system of a represented veteran, regardless of whether the employee is acting under a power of attorney executed by the veteran. </p> <p>The VA shall ensure that access does not allow the employee to modify system data.</p> <p>An employee must complete the VA certification process required of agents or attorneys in order to have system access.</p> <p> Each Member of Congress who elects to have an employee have access to the system shall bear the certification cost, which shall be paid from the Member's representational allowance.</p> <p>Information access by an employee shall be deemed: (1) a covered disclosure requiring prior consent, with specified exceptions; and (2) a permitted disclosure relating to the privacy of individually identifiable health information. </p> <p>The VA may not recognize an employee for purposes of preparation, presentation, and prosecution of VA claims by reason of such system access. </p> <p>&quot;Accredited, permanent congressional employee&quot; means an employee of a Member of Congress who assists constituents with issues regarding federal departments or agencies.</p> <p>&quot;Electronic VBA claims records system&quot; means the VA system that provides claim status information, including information about medical records, compensation and pension exams records, rating decisions, a statement of the case and a supplementary statement of the case, a notice of disagreement, and Form-9. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
