<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="3193" measure-id="id114s3193" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-07-13" update-date="2016-08-03">
<title>CONNECT Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s3193v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-08-03">
<action-date>2016-07-13</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Childhood Outcomes Need New Efficient Community Teams or the CONNECT Act</b></p> <p>This bill amends title IV of the Social Security Act to authorize the Department of Health and Human Services to make grants to state child welfare and juvenile justice agencies to:</p> <ul> <li>collaborate in the collection of data relating to dual status youth (who come into contact with both the child welfare and juvenile justice systems and occupy various statuses in his or her relationship to those systems); and</li> <li>develop practices, policies, and protocols to confront the challenges presented and experienced by such youth.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
