<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="200" measure-id="id114s200" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-01-21" update-date="2015-05-15">
<title>Accurate Budgeting Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s200v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-05-15">
<action-date>2015-01-21</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Accurate Budgeting Act </b></p> <p>This bill amends the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 to require the Joint Committee on Taxation (JCT) to prepare a macroeconomic impact analysis for major revenue legislation. The estimates are required for revenue legislation considered on the floor of the House or Senate or reported by the House Ways and Means Committee or the Senate Finance Committee. </p> <p>The macroeconomic impact analysis, commonly referred to as dynamic scoring, includes: </p> <ul> <li>the changes in economic output, employment, interest rates, capital stock, and tax revenues expected to result from the proposal;</li> <li>revenue feedback (changes in revenue resulting from changes in economic growth as a result of the proposal); and </li> <li>the assumptions and data used for the estimate. </li> </ul> <p>The bill requires JCT to prepare the analysis as a supplement to the revenue estimates currently required by the Congressional Budget Act of 1974. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
