<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2716" measure-id="id114s2716" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-03-17" update-date="2016-06-30">
<title>A bill to update the oil and gas and mining industry guides of the Securities and Exchange Commission.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2716v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-06-30">
<action-date>2016-03-17</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill directs the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC), within 180 days of enactment of this bill, to update:</p> <ul> <li>the Securities Act industry guides entitled &quot;Prospectuses relating to interests in oil and gas programs&quot; and &quot;Description of Property by Issuers Engaged or To Be Engaged in Significant Mining Operations,&quot; </li> <li>the Exchange Act industry guide entitled &quot;Description of Property by Issuers Engaged or To Be Engaged in Significant Mining Operations,&quot; and </li> <li>regulations concerning disclosure by registrants engaged in oil and gas producing activities.</li> </ul> <p>In making such updates, the SEC shall work with the Investor Advisory Committee, which shall solicit and consider public input or appropriate disclosures to include and make specific recommendations to the SEC. </p> <p>If the SEC fails to meet the deadline, it must report to and testify before specified congressional committees explaining why it failed to meet it. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
