<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="241" measure-id="id114s241" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-01-22" update-date="2015-02-12">
<title>Military Family Relief Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s241v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-02-12">
<action-date>2015-01-22</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Military Family Relief Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>Authorizes the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA) to pay temporary (not to exceed six months) dependency and indemnity compensation (DIC) to the surviving spouse of a veteran if, at the time of death, the veteran was in receipt of or entitled to receive compensation for a service-connected disability rated as total for at least one year preceding the veteran's death. </p> <p>Authorizes the payment to such survivor, for the same period, of any veteran's pension that the deceased was receiving at the time of death, without regard to the annual income and net worth of the surviving spouse.</p> <p>Allows a surviving spouse who is entitled to a pension or DIC under any other VA provision to be paid the amount by which such pension or DIC exceeds the amount of pension paid under this Act.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
