<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="938" measure-id="id114s938" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-04-14" update-date="2015-04-28">
<title>America Star Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s938v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-04-28">
<action-date>2015-04-14</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>America Star Act </b></p> <p>This bill directs the Secretary of Labor to establish within the Department of Labor a voluntary America Star program under which the Secretary annually shall designate certain companies, based on specified performance categories, as America Star companies for their support for the U.S. workforce.</p> <p>Companies are ineligible to participate in the program if they commit serious, repeated, or willful violations of specified federal labor law.</p> <p>The Secretary shall: (1) market the America Star program annually to the public through the Department's website, and (2) design a label for designated America Star companies to use by displaying it next to the company's logo.</p> <p>The Federal Trade Commission shall treat as an unfair or deceptive practice the use of a label by a company not designated as an America Star company in violation with the requirements of this Act.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
