<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1403" measure-id="id114s1403" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-20" update-date="2016-10-20">
<title>Florida Fisheries Improvement Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1403v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-10-20">
<action-date>2015-05-20</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Florida Fisheries Improvement Act </b></p> <p>This bill amends the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (MSA) to revise requirements for fishery management in the Gulf of Mexico and the South Atlantic.</p> <p> Regional fishery management councils may use alternative fishery management measures in a recreational fishery. </p> <p>This bill revises requirements for fishery management plans, including by exempting certain species from fishery rebuilding requirements, changing how to determine the timelines for rebuilding fisheries, and repealing the requirement for plans to contain catch limits for red snapper.</p> <p>Funds received as fines, penalties, and forfeitures of property for violations of marine resource law may be used for the cost of stock assessments, surveys, and data collection on fisheries. A citizen owning or leasing an eligible fishery facility may make an agreement with the Department of Commerce to establish a capital construction fund to provide for the acquisition, construction, or reconstruction of a qualified facility. </p> <p>Commerce must make a decision on whether there is a commercial fishery failure because of a fishery resource disaster within 90 days of a receiving a complete estimate of the economic impact of the disaster. </p> <p>The Gulf of Mexico Fishery Management Council and the South Atlantic Council must review, at least every five years, the allocation of fishing privileges. Councils may delay the review for three one-year periods. </p> <p>Commerce must: (1) arrange for the National Academy of Sciences to study the process of allocating fishing privileges; (2) develop and publish a plan to conduct stock assessments for all stocks of fish for which a MSA fishery management plan is in effect, unless the assessment is not necessary; and (3) report on facilitating greater incorporation of data, analysis, stock assessments, and surveys from nongovernmental sources. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
