<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1435" measure-id="id114s1435" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-21" update-date="2015-11-13">
<title>Organ Donation Awareness and Promotion Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1435v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-11-13">
<action-date>2015-05-21</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Organ Donation Awareness and Promotion Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>This bill expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) the federal government should carry out programs to educate the public with respect to organ donation, and (2) organ and tissue donors should be honored.</p> <p>The bill amends the Public Health Service Act to authorize the appropriation of specified amounts for FY2015-FY2019 for: (1) the Organ Donation Public Awareness Program; (2) studies and demonstration projects to increase organ donation and recovery rates; (3) grants to assist states in carrying out organ donor awareness, public education, and outreach activities and programs designed to increase the number of organ donors within the state; and (4) support for the development and dissemination of educational materials to inform health care and other appropriate professionals in issues surrounding organ, tissue, and eye donation.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
