<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="302" measure-id="id114s302" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-01-29" update-date="2015-02-10">
<title>International Human Rights Defense Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s302v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-02-10">
<action-date>2015-01-29</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>International Human Rights Defense Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>Directs the Secretary of State to establish in the Department of State's Bureau of Democracy, Human Rights, and Labor a Special Envoy for the Human Rights of LGBT Peoples who shall: </p> <ul> <li> direct U.S. government efforts regarding the human rights of LGBT people (lesbian, gay, bisexual, or transgender); </li> <li> represent the United States in diplomatic matters relevant to the human rights of LGBT people, including discrimination and violence against LGBT people; </li> <li> serve as the principal advisor to the Secretary of State regarding human rights for LGBT people; and </li> <li> implement activities regarding support, education, resettlement, and empowerment of LGBT people.</li> </ul> <p>Directs the Special Envoy to develop or update annually for five years a U.S. global strategy to prevent and respond to discrimination and violence against LGBT people.</p> <p>Authorizes the Secretary and the Administrator of the U.S. Agency for International Development to provide assistance to prevent and respond to discrimination and violence against LGBT people.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
