<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1976" measure-id="id114s1976" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-08-05" update-date="2015-08-24">
<title>Children and Firefighters Protection Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1976v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-08-24">
<action-date>2015-08-05</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Children and Firefighters Protection Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>Prohibits manufacturers, distributors, or retailers from selling, manufacturing for sale, distributing in commerce, or importing into the United States any children's product or upholstered furniture that contains a flame retardant exceeding a specified amount of the total chemical content by weight for any part of the product or furniture. Specifies flame retardants that are subject to such prohibitions.</p> <p>Requires the Consumer Product Safety Commission (CPSC) to appoint a chronic hazard advisory panel to study the effects on human health of all chemical flame retardants as used in such products or upholstered furniture.</p> <p>Directs the CPSC, after receiving a report from the advisory panel evaluating the full range of such retardants, to promulgate a final rule specifying retardants that are not already listed in this Act that may cause substantial personal injury or illness. Makes such CPSC-specified retardants subject to the prohibitions of this Act. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
