<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="3027" measure-id="id114s3027" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-06-07" update-date="2016-06-15">
<title>Acadia National Park Boundary Clarification Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s3027v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-06-15">
<action-date>2016-06-07</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Acadia National Park Boundary Clarification Act</b></p> <p>This bill modifies the boundary of Acadia National Park in Maine to include approximately 1,441 acres of land and interests in the Schoodic Peninsula.</p> <p>The Department of the Interior may only acquire land or interests in land within the boundaries of the Park in accordance with specified law. </p> <p>No land or interest in land outside the Park's boundaries may be acquired except as already allowed by that law. </p>  <p>Interior shall reestablish and appoint members to the Acadia National Park Advisory Commission.</p> <p>Certain land in the Park, known as NPS Tract 06-126, that was conveyed by the National Park Service to the town of Tremont, Maine, shall no longer be required to be used exclusively and perpetually for school purposes so long as it is being used for public purposes. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
