<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2211" measure-id="id114s2211" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-10-27" update-date="2015-12-01">
<title>Spectrum Relocation Fund Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2211v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-12-01">
<action-date>2015-10-27</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Spectrum Relocation Fund Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the National Telecommunications and Information Administration Organization Act to make amounts available from the Spectrum Relocation Fund (SRF) for the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) to pay federal entities for research and development activities to improve the efficiency and effectiveness of their use of electromagnetic spectrum under government station licenses in order to make frequencies available for: (1) reallocation for nonfederal use, shared federal and nonfederal use, or a combination of such uses; and (2) auctions in accordance with such reallocation.</p> <p>As a condition to the OMB paying a federal entity for such activities, the federal entity must have a plan: (1) approved by a technical panel within the National Telecommunications and Information Administration, and (2) submitted by the OMB to the appropriate congressional committees for a period of 60 days.</p> <p>The bill also provides for&nbsp;incumbent federal entities to receive payment from the SRF&nbsp;for relocation and sharing costs&nbsp;incurred to accommodate sharing spectrum frequencies assigned to such entity with another federal entity the operations of which are being relocated from other frequencies.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
