<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2607" measure-id="id114s2607" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-03-01" update-date="2016-10-26">
<title>DIGIT Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2607v01" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-10-26">
<action-date>2016-09-27</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to Senate amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Developing Innovation and Growing the Internet of Things Act or the DIGIT Act</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill expresses the sense of Congress that policies governing the Internet of Things (IoT) should maximize the potential and development of the growing number of connected and interconnected devices to benefit businesses, governments, and consumers.</p> <p>(Sec. 4) The bill requires the Department of Commerce to convene a working group of federal stakeholders to provide recommendations and a report to Congress regarding the IoT. The bill establishes a steering committee to be composed of stakeholders outside the federal government to advise the working group. </p> <p>The working group must: (1) identify federal laws and regulations, grant practices, budgetary or jurisdictional challenges, and other sector-specific policies that inhibit IoT development; (2) consider policies or programs that encourage and improve coordination among federal agencies with IoT jurisdiction; (3) implement recommendations from the steering committee; (4) examine how federal agencies can benefit from, use, and prepare for the IoT; and (5) consult with nongovernmental stakeholders. </p> <p>The steering committee must advise the working group about laws, budgets, spectrum needs, individual privacy, security, small business challenges, and any international proceedings or negotiations affecting the IoT. </p> <p>Within 18 months after enactment of this bill, the working group must report its findings and recommendations, its reasons for inaction on steering committee recommendations, and an accounting of any progress by federal agencies to implement recommendations. </p> <p>(Sec. 5) The Federal Communications Commission must: (1) seek public comment on the IoT's spectrum needs, regulatory barriers, and growth with licensed and unlicensed spectrum; and (2) submit a summary of those comments to Congress.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114s2607v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-03-29">
<action-date>2016-03-01</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Developing Innovation and Growing the Internet of Things Act or the DIGIT Act</b></p> <p>This bill requires the Department of Commerce to convene a working group of federal stakeholders to provide recommendations to Congress on how to plan for and encourage the proliferation of the Internet of Things (IoT) in the United States for the growing number of connected and interconnected devices.</p> <p>The working group must consult with nongovernmental stakeholders, including industry experts, technology manufacturers, businesses, and consumer groups. </p> <p>The bill expresses the sense of Congress that IoT policies should maximize the potential and development of the IoT to benefit businesses, governments, and consumers.</p> <p>Within one year after enactment of this Act: (1) the working group must submit a report regarding IoT spectrum needs, regulations, federal grant practices, budgetary challenges, consumer protections, privacy and security, and the current use of the technology by federal agencies and their preparedness to adopt it in the future; and (2) the Federal Communications Commission must submit recommendations concerning the IoT's current and future spectrum needs, the role of licensed and unlicensed spectrum, and any regulatory barriers.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
