<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1219" measure-id="id114s1219" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-06" update-date="2015-06-16">
<title>A bill to amend the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 to provide for the safe and reliable interconnection of distributed resources and to provide for the examination of the effects of net metering.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1219v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-06-16">
<action-date>2015-05-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill amends the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 to define &quot;distributed resource&quot; as an electric power source connected directly to the distribution network or on the customer side of the meter.</p> <p>State regulatory authorities shall by certain deadlines:</p> <ul> <li>establish proceedings to examine the degree to which distributed resources contribute specified ancillary services, such as reactive supply, energy imbalance, and flexibility and ramping services, among others; </li> <li>prescribe measures to ensure adequate ancillary services so that grid interconnection for distributed resources is safe, reliable, and efficient;</li> <li>examine the effects of net metering and customer-owned distributed generation on resource planning of each electric utility, and </li> <li>determine whether electricity rates established for net metering service are just and reasonable and not unduly preferential or discriminatory.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
