<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="893" measure-id="id114s893" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-03-26" update-date="2016-05-06">
<title>EPIC Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s893v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-05-06">
<action-date>2015-03-26</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Energy Productivity Innovation Challenge Act of 2015 or the EPIC Act of 2015</b></p> <p>This bill requires the Department of Energy (DOE) to establish a voluntary electric and thermal energy productivity challenge grant program for providing support to states for: </p> <ul> <li>advancing industrial energy efficiency, waste heat recovery, combined heat and power, and waste heat-to-power utilization; </li> <li>advancing energy efficiency construction and retrofits for commercial buildings, schools, hospitals, and residential buildings; </li> <li>expanding residential policies and programs designed to implement best practice policies and tools for residential retrofit programs that reduce administrative and delivery costs for energy efficiency projects, encourage streamlining and automation to support contractor engagement, and implement systems that encourage private investment and market innovation;</li> <li>establishing or expanding incentives in the electric utility sector to enhance demand response and energy efficiency; and </li> <li>promoting state activities involving both facilities and vehicle fleets than can be a model for other action to promote energy efficiency. </li> </ul> <p>DOE must: (1) provide subsequent grants for activities to assist energy policy innovation in the states and to promote the goal of doubling electric and thermal energy productivity by January 1, 2030, and (2) invite Indian tribes to participate in the productivity challenge grant program.</p> <p>As an offset to the cost of this bill, the bill amends the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007 to reduce the authorized amount of appropriations for FY2016-FY2017 for the Zero Net Energy Commercial Buildings Initiative.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
