<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1789" measure-id="id114s1789" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-07-16" update-date="2015-10-29">
<title>United States-Jordan Defense Cooperation Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1789v80" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-10-29">
<action-date>2015-10-27</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to Senate without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p><strong>United States-Jordan Defense Cooperation Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) Specifies the findings of Congress that: </p> <ul> <li> as of January 22, 2015, the United States has provided over $3 billion in assistance to respond to the Syria humanitarian crisis, of which nearly $467 million has been provided to Jordan; </li> <li> as of January 2015, according to the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees, there were 621,937 registered Syrian refugees in Jordan, 83.8% of whom lived outside refugee camps; </li> <li> in 2000 the United States and Jordan signed a free-trade agreement that went into force in 2001; </li> <li> in 1996 the United States granted Jordan major non-NATO ally status; and </li> <li> Jordan is suffering from the Syrian refugee crisis and the threat of the Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant (ISIL).</li> </ul> <p>(Sec. 3) Urges that U.S. policy should be to: </p> <ul> <li> support Jordan in its response to the Syrian refugee crisis, </li> <li> provide necessary assistance to support the basic needs of the assimilated Syrian refugees, </li> <li> cooperate with Jordan to combat the terrorist threat from ISIL or other terrorist organizations, and </li> <li> help secure the border between Jordan and Syria and Iraq. </li> </ul> <p>(Sec. 4) Expresses the sense of Congress that expeditious consideration of certifications of letters of offer to sell defense articles, defense services, design and construction services, and major defense equipment to Jordan is fully consistent with U. S. security and foreign policy interests and the objectives of world peace and security.</p> <p>(Sec. 5) Amends the Arms Export Control Act to include Jordan among the countries eligible for certain streamlined defense sales for three years.</p> <p>(Sec. 6) Authorizes the Department of State to enter into a Memorandum of Understanding with Jordan to increase economic support funds and military cooperation, including joint military exercises, personnel exchanges, support for international peacekeeping missions, and enhanced strategic dialogue.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114s1789v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-09-03">
<action-date>2015-07-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>United States-Jordan Defense Cooperation Act of 2015 </strong></p> <p>Expresses the sense of Congress that expeditious consideration of certifications of letters of offer to sell defense articles, defense services, design and construction services, and major defense equipment to the Hashemite Kingdom of Jordan is fully consistent with U. S. security and foreign policy interests and the objectives of world peace and security.</p> <p>Amends the Arms Export Control Act to include Jordan among the countries eligible for certain streamlined defense sales for three years.</p> <p>Authorizes the Department of State to enter into a Memorandum of Understanding with Jordan to increase economic support funds and military cooperation, including joint military exercises, personnel exchanges, support for international peacekeeping missions, and enhanced strategic dialogue.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
