<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1723" measure-id="id114s1723" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-07-09" update-date="2015-10-26">
<title>Promoting Renewable Energy with Shared Solar Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1723v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-10-26">
<action-date>2015-07-09</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p> <b>Promoting Renewable Energy with Shared Solar Act of 2015</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 (PURPA) to require an electric utility, upon the request of an electric consumer, to make available to the consumer interconnection service and net billing service for a solar photovoltaic system allocating electricity to multiple individual electric consumers of the utility and meeting other specified characteristics (community solar facility).</p> <p>Each state regulatory authority and each nonregulated utility must, within specified time limitations, commence consideration of and finally determine ratemaking standards.</p> <p>The bill makes conforming technical amendments to the Energy Policy Act of 2005.</p> <p>Certain ratemaking time limitations set out in PURPA, and requirements in case of a failure to comply with them, shall not apply in the case of any electric utility in a state if before enactment of this Act:</p> <ul> <li> the state has implemented the standard under this Act (or a comparable one) for the electric utility; </li> <li> the state regulatory authority or the relevant nonregulated electric utility has conducted a proceeding to consider implementation of the standard (or a comparable one) for the electric utility; or </li> <li> the state legislature has voted on the implementation of the standard (or a comparable one). </li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
