<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1603" measure-id="id114s1603" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-06-17" update-date="2015-09-22">
<title>Born-Alive Abortion Survivors Protection Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1603v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-09-22">
<action-date>2015-09-18</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Born-Alive Abortion Survivors Protection Act</b></p> <p>(Sec. 3) This bill amends the federal criminal code to require any health care practitioner who is present when a child is born alive following an abortion or attempted abortion to: (1) exercise the same degree of care as reasonably provided to any other child born alive at the same gestational age, and (2) ensure that such child is immediately admitted to a hospital. The term &quot;born alive&quot; means the complete expulsion or extraction from his or her mother, at any stage of development, who after such expulsion or extraction breathes or has a beating heart, pulsation of the umbilical cord, or definite movement of voluntary muscles, regardless of whether the umbilical cord has been cut. </p> <p>Also, a health care practitioner or other employee who has knowledge of a failure to comply with these requirements must immediately report such failure to an appropriate law enforcement agency. </p> <p>An individual who violates the provisions of this Act is subject to a criminal fine, up to five years in prison, or both. </p> <p>An individual who commits an overt act that kills a child born alive is subject to criminal prosecution for murder. </p> <p>The legislation bars the criminal prosecution of a mother of a child born alive for conspiracy to violate the provisions of this Act, for being an accessory after the fact, or for concealment of felony. </p> <p>A woman who undergoes an abortion or attempted abortion may file a civil action for damages against an individual who violates this Act. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114s1603v35" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-09-22">
<action-date>2015-09-09</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed Senate amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Border Jobs for Veterans Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 3) Directs the Department of Homeland Security (DHS): (1) in conjunction with the Department of Defense (DOD), to identify Military Occupational Specialty Codes and Officer Branches, Air Force Specialty Codes, Naval Enlisted Classifications and Officer Designators, and Coast Guard Competencies (qualifications) that are transferable to the requirements and duties assigned to Customs and Border Protection (CBP) Officers; and (2) to consider hiring qualified candidates with such qualifications who are eligible for veterans recruitment appointment.</p> <p>(Sec. 4) Directs DHS, in conjunction with DOD, acting through existing programs, authorities, and agreements, to enhance DHS efforts to recruit members of the Armed Forces who are separating from military service to serve as CBP Officers. Requires such enhanced efforts to:</p> <ul> <li>include CBP Officer opportunities in relevant job assistance efforts under the Transition Assistance Program;</li> <li> place CBP officials or other relevant DHS officials at recruiting events and jobs fairs involving separating members of the Armed Forces; </li> <li> provide opportunities for local CBP field offices to partner with military bases in the region; </li> <li>include outreach efforts to educate members of the Armed Forces with qualifications that are transferable to CBP Officer requirements; </li> <li> require DOD and DHS to work cooperatively to identify shared activities and opportunities for reciprocity related to steps in hiring CBP officers with the goal of minimizing the time required to hire qualified applicants; </li> <li> require DOD and DHS to work cooperatively to ensure the streamlined interagency transfer of relevant background investigations and security clearances; and </li> <li> include other elements to ensure that separating members of the Armed Forces are aware of opportunities to fill vacant CBP Officer positions.</li> </ul> <p>(Sec. 5) Directs DHS and DOD, within 180 days after enactment of this Act and by December 31 of each of the three successive years, to jointly submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees on DHS efforts to hire separating service members as CBP Officers.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114s1603v01" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-08-12">
<action-date>2015-08-05</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to Senate amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Border Jobs for Veterans Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 3) Directs the Department of Homeland Security (DHS): (1) in conjunction with the Department of Defense (DOD), to identify Military Occupational Specialty Codes, Air Force Specialty Codes, Naval Enlisted Classifications and Officer Designators, and Coast Guard Competencies (qualifications) that are transferable to the requirements and duties assigned to Customs and Border Protection (CBP) Officers; and (2) to consider hiring qualified candidates with such qualifications who are eligible for veterans recruitment appointment.</p> <p>(Sec. 4) Directs DHS, in conjunction with DOD, to establish a program to actively recruit members of the Armed Forces who are separating from military service to serve as CBP Officers. Requires such program to:</p> <ul> <li>include CBP Officer opportunities in relevant job assistance efforts under the Transition Assistance Program;</li> <li> place CBP officials or other relevant DHS officials at recruiting events and jobs fairs involving separating members of the Armed Forces; </li> <li> provide opportunities for local CBP field offices to partner with military bases in the region; </li> <li> conduct outreach efforts to educate members of the Armed Forces with qualifications that are transferable to CBP Officer requirements; </li> <li> require DOD and DHS to work cooperatively to identify shared activities and opportunities for reciprocity related to steps in hiring CBP officers with the goal of minimizing the time required to hire qualified applicants; </li> <li> require DOD and DHS to work cooperatively to ensure the streamlined interagency transfer of relevant background investigations and security clearances; and </li> <li> include other elements to ensure that separating members of the Armed Forces are aware of opportunities to fill vacant CBP Officer positions.</li> </ul> <p>(Sec. 5) Directs DHS and DOD, within 180 days after enactment of this Act and by December 31 of each of the three successive years, to jointly submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees on the program, including the number of CBP Officer vacancies filled with separating service members.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114s1603v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-08-12">
<action-date>2015-06-17</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Border Jobs for Veterans Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>Directs the Department of Homeland Security (DHS): (1) in conjunction with the Department of Defense (DOD), to identify Military Occupational Specialty Codes, Air Force Specialty Codes, Naval Enlisted Classifications and Officer Designators, and Coast Guard Competencies (qualifications) that are transferable to the requirements and duties assigned to Customs and Border Protection (CBP) Officers; and (2) to consider hiring qualified candidates with such qualifications who are eligible for veterans recruitment appointment.</p> <p>Directs DHS, in conjunction with DOD, to establish a program to actively recruit members of the Armed Forces who are separating from military service to serve as CBP Officers. Requires such program to:</p> <ul> <li>include CBP Officer opportunities in relevant job assistance efforts under the Transition Assistance Program;</li> <li> place CBP officials or other relevant DHS officials at recruiting events and jobs fairs involving separating members of the Armed Forces; </li> <li> provide opportunities for local CBP field offices to partner with military bases in the region; </li> <li> conduct outreach efforts to educate members of the Armed Forces with qualifications that are transferable to CBP Officer requirements; </li> <li> require DOD and DHS to work cooperatively to identify shared activities and opportunities for reciprocity related to steps in hiring CBP officers with the goal of minimizing the time required to hire qualified applicants; </li> <li> require DOD and DHS to work cooperatively to ensure the streamlined interagency transfer of relevant background investigations and security clearances; and </li> <li> include other elements to ensure that separating members of the Armed Forces are aware of opportunities to fill vacant CBP Officer positions.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
