<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1335" measure-id="id114s1335" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-13" update-date="2016-09-28">
<title>Ensuring Access to Fisheries Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1335v80" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-09-28">
<action-date>2016-03-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to Senate without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p><b>North Pacific Fisheries Convention Implementation Act</b></p> <p>This bill authorizes the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) to promulgate regulations to implement U.S. participation in the North Pacific Fisheries Convention. The convention is designed to ensure the long-term conservation and sustainable use of fishery resources and marine ecosystems in the North Pacific Ocean.</p> <p>(Sec. 3) The United Statesmust be represented by five commissioners on the North Pacific Fisheries Commission. </p> <p>In addition, a permanent advisory committee is established, which shall be comprised of 11 members. Advisory committee members shall represent groups concerned with fishery resources covered by the North Pacific Fisheries Convention.</p><p>(Sec. 4)The Department of State has the authority to receive and transmit various communications concerning the North Pacific commission, and can approve or disapprove bylaws and rules adopted by the commission.</p> <p>(Sec. 5) This bill details NOAA's authority in implementing this bill and measures adopted by the commission.</p> <p>(Sec. 6)NOAA and the U.S. Coast Guard are required to administer and enforce this bill.</p> <p>(Sec. 7)This bill lists 16 fishing and shipping activities that are prohibited in the North Pacific Ocean.</p> <p>(Sec. 8)NOAA may cooperate with public and private institutions in the United Statesand abroad to carry out this bill. Federal agencies are authorized to cooperate with NOAA in conducting research and providing facilities and personnel to assist the commission.</p> <p>(Sec. 9)The State Department must ensure the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands participates with the commission in the same manner as territories of other nations.</p> <p>(Sec. 10)Operators of commercial fishing vessels that do not carry vessel monitoring systems capable of communicating with U.S. enforcement authorities must:</p> <ul> <li>notify the U.S. Coast Guard prior to or within a reasonable time after entering the exclusive economic zone of the convention area;</li> <li>ensure that all fishing gear is stowed below deck and not readily available for fishing; and</li> <li>if requested, proceed to a specified location so that a vessel inspection can be conducted.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114s1335v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-07-19">
<action-date>2015-05-13</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>North Pacific Fisheries Convention Implementation Act</b></p> <p>This bill authorizes the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) to promulgate regulations to implement U.S. participation in the North Pacific Fisheries Convention. The convention is designed to ensure the long-term conservation and sustainable use of fishery resources and marine ecosystems in the North Pacific Ocean.</p> <p>The United Statesmust be represented by five commissioners on the North Pacific Fisheries Commission. </p> <p>In addition, a permanent advisory committee is established. Advisory committee members shall represent groups concerned with fishery resources covered by the North Pacific Fisheries Convention.</p><p>The Department of State has the authority to receive and transmit various communications concerning the North Pacific commission, and can approve or disapprove bylaws and rules adopted by the commission.</p> <p>This bill details NOAA's authority in implementing this bill and measures adopted by the commission.</p> <p>NOAA and the U.S. Coast Guard are required to administer and enforce this bill.</p> <p>This bill lists 16 fishing and shipping activities that are prohibited in the North Pacific Ocean</p>  <p> <p>Operators of commercial fishing vessels that do not carry vessel monitoring systems capable of communicating with U.S. enforcement authorities must:</p> <ul> <li>notify the U.S. Coast Guard prior to or within a reasonable time after entering the exclusive economic zone of the convention area;</li> <li>ensure that all fishing gear is stowed below deck and not readily available for fishing; and</li> <li>if requested, proceed to a specified location so that a vessel inspection can be conducted.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
