<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="297" measure-id="id114s297" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-01-28" update-date="2015-03-14">
<title>Frontlines to Lifelines Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s297v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-03-14">
<action-date>2015-01-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Frontlines to Lifelines Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA) to revive, for a three-year period, VA's Intermediate Care Technician Pilot Program that was carried out between January 2013 and February 2014. Requires VA to: (1) expand the pilot program to include at least 250 intermediate care technicians, and (2) give priority in assigning those technicians to VA facilities at which veterans have the longest wait times.</p> <p>Requires the Secretary of Defense (DOD) to transfer credentialing data regarding DOD health care providers that are hired by VA to VA.</p> <p>Authorizes VA to allow a covered nurse to practice independently, without the supervision or direction of others, under a set of VA-approved privileges, regardless of the state in which VA employs the covered nurse. Defines a &quot;covered nurse&quot; as an advanced practice registered nurse who is employed by VA as: (1) a nurse midwife; (2) a clinical nurse specialist, with respect to the provision of mental health care; or (3) a nurse practitioner.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
