<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2458" measure-id="id114s2458" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-01-20" update-date="2016-05-03">
<title>A bill to amend section 217(a)(12) of the Immigration and Nationality Act, relating to the restriction of the use of the Visa Waiver Program for aliens who travel to certain countries.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2458v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-05-03">
<action-date>2016-01-20</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill amends the Immigration and Nationality Act, as amended by the Visa Waiver Program Improvement and Terrorist Travel Prevention Act of 2015, to include Department of State designation of a country or area as a country or area of concern among the criteria for visa waiver program ineligibility based upon an alien's nationality or presence.</p> <p>Exceptions to program ineligibility shall include include an alien who was present in a prohibited country to perform official duties as an employee of an international organization for a program country.</p> <p> Visa waiver program disqualification under the Visa Waiver Program Improvement and Terrorist Travel Prevention Act of 2015 shall not take effect until 180 days after enactment of such Act for an alien: (1) who, regardless of whether the alien is a national of a program country, is a national of Iraq or Syria, a national of a country designated as supporting terrorism, or a national of any other country or area of concern; or (2) who has been present in such countries or areas on or after March 1, 2011.</p> <p>The Department of Homeland Security or the State Department may waive such prohibition for a period of up to 90 days if either determines that the waiver is in U.S. national security interests.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
