<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="927" measure-id="id114s927" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-04-14" update-date="2015-05-05">
<title>CLEAR Plus Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s927v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-05-05">
<action-date>2015-04-14</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>CLEAR Plus Act of 2015</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to: (1) subject a savings and loan holding company to registration requirements for securities whose issuer has total assets exceeding $10 million and a class of non-exempt equity security held of record by 2,000 or more persons; and (2) apply the automatic termination of registration, and suspension of the duty to file supplementary and periodic information, to a savings and loan holding company whose securities are found to be held by less than 1,200 persons. </p> <p>The Federal Deposit Insurance Act is amended to require the federal banking agencies to issue regulations allowing for a reduced reporting requirement for certain depository institutions when making the first and third report of condition for a year. These reporting requirements apply to any insured depository institution that:</p> <ul> <li>as of the most recent examination has a CAMELS composite rating of 1 or 2 under the Uniform Financial Institutions Rating System (or an equivalent rating under a comparable rating system) for capital adequacy, assets, management capability, earnings, liquidity or asset liability management, and sensitivity to market risk; and</li> <li>satisfies other appropriate criteria as such agencies determine.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
