<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="770" measure-id="id114s770" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-03-18" update-date="2015-08-12">
<title>Escambia County Land Conveyance Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s770v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-08-12">
<action-date>2015-03-18</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Escambia County Land Conveyance Act</b></p> <p>Authorizes Escambia County, Florida, to convey its interest in any part of the former Santa Rosa Island National Monument land that was conveyed to it by the federal government in 1947 to any person or entity, without restriction. </p> <p>Prohibits any person or entity holding a leasehold interest in such land from being required to involuntarily accept a fee interest to such land in place of the leasehold interest. </p> <p> Allows Escambia County to convey any interest in any part of such land that is within the jurisdictional boundaries of Santa Rosa County, Florida, to such county. </p> <p>Permits Santa Rosa County or any other person to whom such county reconveys such land to reconvey any part of it. Requires any proceeds from the conveyance of such land by either county to be considered windfall profits that shall revert to the United States.</p> <p> Instructs Escambia County and Santa Rosa County to preserve those areas of the land conveyed under this Act that, as of the enactment of this Act, are dedicated for conservation, preservation, public recreation access, and public parking. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
