<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2206" measure-id="id114s2206" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-10-26" update-date="2016-10-25">
<title>National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration Sexual Harassment and Assault Prevention Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2206v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-10-25">
<action-date>2015-10-26</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration Sexual Harassment and Assault Prevention Act</b></p> <p>This bill requires the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) to develop policies on the prevention of and response to sexual harassment or assaults involving its employees, NOAA's commissioned officer corps, and individuals who work with or conduct business on behalf of NOAA. Those policies must include procedures for reporting incidents, including those occurring after-hours, at sea, or in remote locations.</p> <p>NOAA must: (1) ensure that at least one of its employees who handle matters relating to equal employment opportunity or sexual harassment is stationed in each of its regions of operation and in each of its marine and aviation centers, (2) establish victim advocates to aid victims of sexual assault, and (3) submit an annual report on sexual assaults.</p> <p>The bill establishes protections for victims, including through a change of duty station of an alleged perpetrator.</p> <p>The bill revises the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration Commissioned Officer Corps Act of 2002. The bill sets forth new requirements under that Act concerning obligated service requirements, training and physical fitness, education loan assistance, recruitment, hiring and promotions, and other workforce issues.</p> <p>NOAA must develop and implement a charter vessel safety policy applicable to the acquisition by NOAA of charter vessel services.</p> <p> The bill revises and reauthorizes through FY2020 the Hydrographic Services Improvement Act of 1998.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
