<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2256" measure-id="id114s2256" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-11-05" update-date="2016-07-25">
<title>Co-Prescribing Saves Lives Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2256v01" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-07-25">
<action-date>2016-04-27</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to Senate amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Co-Prescribing Saves Lives Act of 2016</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill requires the Department of Health and Human Services to provide information to certain prescribers on best practices for prescribing naloxone for patients receiving chronic opioid therapy or being treated for opioid use disorders. (Naloxone is a prescription drug used to rapidly reverse an overdose of opioids, which are drugs with effects similar to opium, such as heroin and certain pain medications.) The information must be provided to prescribers in federally qualified health centers and the health care facilities of the Indian Health Service.</p> The Department of Defense and the Department of Veterans Affairs must provide such information to prescribers in their medical facilities.]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114s2256v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-07-08">
<action-date>2015-11-05</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Co-Prescribing Saves Lives Act of 2015</b></p> <p>This bill requires the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA), and the Department of Defense (DOD) to: (1) establish training guidelines for federal health care facilities and federally qualified health centers; and (2) train certain health care providers at federal health care facilities on best practices for prescribing pain medications, principles of pain management, the misuse potential of controlled substances, identification of potential substance use disorders and referral to further evaluation and treatment, and disposal of controlled substances.</p> <p>HHS, the VA, and DOD must establish, for certain health care facilities, guidelines for the prescription of naloxone to individuals at an elevated risk of overdose. (Naloxone is a prescription drug used to rapidly reverse an overdose of opioids, which are drugs with effects similar to opium, such as heroin and certain pain medications.)</p> <p>HHS must award grants to state departments of health for the development and application of guidelines for the prescription of opioid overdose reversal drugs and to increase access to naloxone. Grants may be used to:</p> <ul> <li>establish a program for purchasing, prescribing, and distributing opioid overdose reversal drugs;</li> <li>expand innovative models of naloxone distribution;</li> <li>train and provide resources to health care providers and pharmacists on prescribing opioid overdose reversal drugs;</li> <li>offset individuals' cost-sharing for opioid overdose reversal drugs;</li> <li>conduct community outreach to raise awareness of the availability of opioid overdose reversal drugs; and</li> <li> establish protocols to connect patients who have experienced a drug overdose with treatment. </li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
