<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="749" measure-id="id114s749" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-03-17" update-date="2015-06-30">
<title>Honest Scoring Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s749v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-06-30">
<action-date>2015-03-17</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>The Honest Scoring Act of 2015</b> </p> <p>This bill requires the Congressional Budget Office (CBO) and the Joint Committee on Taxation (JCT) to provide estimates of the macroeconomic effects of major legislation. These estimates are frequently referred to as dynamic scoring and include estimates of the budgetary effects from changes in economic output, employment, capital stock, interest rates, and other macroeconomic variables resulting from the legislation. </p> <p>The CBO and the JCT must provide the estimates for legislation that has a budgetary effect exceeding $15 billion in any fiscal year before incorporating macroeconomic effects, or is designated as major legislation by either the Chairman of the House Budget Committee or the Chairman of the Senate Budget Committee. The CBO and the JCT must also continue to provide estimates of budgetary effects without macroeconomic effects. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
