<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2930" measure-id="id114s2930" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-05-12" update-date="2016-07-21">
<title>Limiting Contributions to the United Nations and Affiliated Organizations that Accord the Palestine Liberation Organization the Same Standing as Member States Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2930v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-07-21">
<action-date>2016-05-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Limiting Contributions to the United Nations and Affiliated Organizations that Accord the Palestine Liberation Organization the Same Standing as Member States Act</strong></p> <p>This bill directs the Department of State to ensure that the use of federal funding supporting the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change, including the Green Climate Fund, complies with applicable federal law, including: </p> <ul> <li>provisions of the United Nations Participation Act of 1945 authorizing appropriations for the U.S. annual payment to the U.N. and for necessary salaries and expenses of U.S. representatives to the U.N.,</li> <li>provisions of the Foreign Relations Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 1990 and 1991 prohibiting making funds authorized under such Act available to the U.N. or any specialized agency that accords the Palestine Liberation Organization the same standing as member states, and </li> <li> provisions of the Foreign Relations Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 1994 and 1995 prohibiting contributions to the U.N. or to any affiliated U.N. organization that grants full state membership to a group that does not have internationally recognized attributes of statehood.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
