<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="105" measure-id="id114s105" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-01-07" update-date="2015-03-18">
<title>Red Snapper Management Improvement Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s105v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-03-18">
<action-date>2015-01-07</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Red Snapper Management Improvement Act</b></p> <p>This bill gives Alabama, Florida, Louisiana, Mississippi, and Texas (Gulf coastal states) exclusive authority to manage and conserve the red snapper in both the waters of each Gulf coastal state and the exclusive economic zone in the Gulf of Mexico if each of those states agree to a fishery management plan for the stainability of the red snapper and the economic and community benefits of the Gulf coastal states.</p> <p>If each of those states agrees to a fishery management plan, Department of Commerce must provide appropriate funding to them for stock assessments and data collection related to the red snapper fishery.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
