<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1846" measure-id="id114s1846" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-07-23" update-date="2016-07-21">
<title>Critical Infrastructure Protection Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1846v01" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-07-21">
<action-date>2016-05-09</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to Senate amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Critical Infrastructure Protection Act of 2016 or the CIPA</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to add as responsibilities of the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) relating to intelligence and analysis and infrastructure protection: (1) conducting an intelligence-based review and comparison of the risk and consequences to critical infrastructures of threats and hazards, including a geomagnetic disturbance (GMD) caused by a solar storm or another naturally occurring phenomenon and an electromagnetic pulse (EMP) caused by a nuclear device or non-nuclear device, including such a pulse caused by an act of terrorism; and (2) submitting and biennially updating a recommended strategy to protect and prepare the critical infrastructure of the American homeland against such threats. </p> <p>The strategy: (1) shall be developed in consultation with the relevant federal sector-specific agencies and coordinating councils for critical infrastructures, and (2) may be incorporated into a broader DHS recommendation to help protect and prepare critical infrastructure from terrorism, cyber attacks, and other threats and hazards.</p> <p>The Under Secretary for Science and Technology shall conduct research and development to mitigate the consequences of EMP and GMD threats, including:</p> <ul> <li>an objective scientific analysis of the risks to critical infrastructures from a range of such threats;</li> <li>determination of the critical utilities and national security assets and infrastructures that are at risk from such threats;</li> <li>an evaluation of emergency planning and response technologies that would address the findings and recommendations of experts, including those of the Commission to Assess the Threat to the United States from Electromagnetic Pulse Attack;</li> <li>an analysis of available technology options to improve the resiliency of critical infrastructure to such threats;</li> <li>research regarding the restoration and recovery capabilities of critical infrastructure under differing levels of damage and disruption from such threats; and</li> <li>an analysis of the feasibility of a real-time alert system to inform electric grid operators and other stakeholders within milliseconds of a high-altitude nuclear explosion.</li> </ul> <p>The bill requires the Secretary to: (1) develop an incident annex or similar response and planning strategy that guides the response to a major GMD or EMP event; and (2) conduct outreach to educate owners and operators of critical infrastructure, emergency planners, and emergency response providers at all levels of government regarding EMP and GMD threats. </p> <p>The Secretary shall submit a report to Congress within 180 days on the progress made in, and an estimated completion date for: (1) including threats of EMP and GMD in national planning; (2) conducting the research and development, and developing the strategy, required under this bill; and (3) beginning to conduct outreach to educate emergency planners and emergency response providers at all levels of government regarding EMP and GMD threats. </p>  <ul> </ul> <ul> </ul> <ul> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114s1846v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-10-28">
<action-date>2015-07-23</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Critical Infrastructure Protection Act of 2015 or CIPA</strong></p> <p> This bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to include among the responsibilities of the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS), relating to intelligence and analysis and infrastructure protection, to submit to specified congressional committees and biennially update a recommended strategy to protect and prepare the critical infrastructure of the American homeland against EM threats, including from acts of terrorism. &quot;EM threat&quot; is defined as an electromagnetic pulse caused by: (1) a nuclear or non-nuclear device, including by an act of terrorism; or (2) a geomagnetic disturbance caused by solar storms or other naturally occurring phenomena.</p> <p>The Under Secretary for Science and Technology shall conduct research and development to mitigate the consequences of EM threats, including: (1) an objective scientific analysis of the risks to critical infrastructures from a range of EM threats; (2) determination of the critical national security assets and vital civic utilities and infrastructures that are at risk from EM threats; (3) an evaluation of emergency planning and response technologies that would address the findings and recommendations of experts, including those of the Commission to Assess the Threat to the United States from Electromagnetic Pulse Attack; (4) an analysis of available technology options to improve the resiliency of critical infrastructure to EM threats; (5) research regarding the restoration and recovery capabilities of critical infrastructure under differing levels of damage and disruption from various EM threats; and (6) an analysis of the feasibility of a real-time alert system to inform electric grid operators and other stakeholders within milliseconds of a high-altitude nuclear explosion.</p>  <p>The bill requires the the Under Secretary for the National Protection and Programs Directorate to: (1) include EM threats in national planning frameworks; and (2) conduct outreach to educate owners and operators of critical infrastructure, emergency planners, and emergency response providers at all levels of government about EM threats. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
