<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1690" measure-id="id114s1690" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-06-25" update-date="2016-09-27">
<title>Mountains to Sound Greenway National Heritage Area Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1690v01" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-09-27">
<action-date>2016-09-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to Senate amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Mountains to Sound Greenway National Heritage Area Act</b></p> (Sec. 4) This bill establishes the Mountains to Sound Greenway National Heritage Area in the state of Washington. <p> The bill designates the Mountains to Sound Greenway Trust as the local coordinating entity for the heritage area, which shall prepare and submit a management plan for it.</p> <p>(Sec. 6) The Mountains to Sound Greenway Trust shall not use federal funding made available under this bill for the acquisition of real property or any interest in real property.</p> <p>(Sec. 8) Nothing in this bill:</p> <ul> <li>abridges the rights of any public or private property owners;</li> <li>alters any adopted land use regulations, approved land use plans, or other regulatory authorities of any federal, state, tribal, or local agencies; </li> <li>conveys any land use or other regulatory authority to the Mountains to Sound Greenway Trust; or</li> <li>alters, modifies, diminishes, or extinguishes any Indian tribe's treaty rights within the heritage area. </li> </ul> <p>(Sec. 10) The bill authorizes appropriations.</p> <p>The federal cost share of any activity carried out under this bill shall be 50% of that activity's total cost. </p> <p>The authority of Department of the Interior to furnish assistance under this bill terminates 15 years after this bill's enactment.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114s1690v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-08-31">
<action-date>2015-06-25</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Mountains to Sound Greenway National Heritage Area Act</b></p> Establishes the Mountains to Sound Greenway National Heritage Area in the state of Washington. <p>Designates the Mountains to Sound Greenway Trust as the local coordinating entity for the Heritage Area, which shall prepare and submit a management plan for it.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
