<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1945" measure-id="id114s1945" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-08-05" update-date="2015-12-29">
<title>Mental Health Reform Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1945v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-12-29">
<action-date>2015-08-05</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Mental Health Reform Act of 2015</b></p> <p>This bill creates the position of Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use Disorders to oversee the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration (SAMHSA). Mental health programs are extended and training regarding mental health is expanded.</p> <p>SAMHSA must establish the National Mental Health Policy Laboratory and the Interagency Serious Mental Illness Coordinating Committee.</p> <p>This bill amends the Public Health Service Act to require the National Institute of Mental Health to translate evidence-based interventions and the best available science into systems of care.</p> <p>The Health Resources and Services Administration must support the creation and expansion of child psychiatry access programs. </p> <p>Certain mental health care professional volunteers are provided liability protection.</p> <p>Pediatric mental health subspecialists are eligible for National Health Service Corps programs.</p> <p>An underserved population of children or a site for training in child psychiatry can be designated as a health professional shortage area.</p> <p>SAMHSA must award primary care and behavioral health care integration grants to state entities to fund improvements in settings with integrated care.</p> <p>The Department of Health and Human Services must develop a model program and materials for training health care providers regarding the disclosure of the protected health information of patients with a mental illness.</p> This bill amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to conditionally expand coverage of mental health services.]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
