<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2966" measure-id="id114s2966" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-05-23" update-date="2016-09-28">
<title>District of Columbia Judicial Financial Transparency Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2966v01" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-09-28">
<action-date>2016-09-27</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to Senate amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>District of Columbia Judicial Financial Transparency Act </b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends the District of Columbia Code to revise the financial disclosure requirements for District of Columbia judges. The revisions establish new dollar thresholds and requirements for reporting to the District of Columbia Commission on Judicial Disabilities and Tenure the financial interests of the judges and specified family members with respect to: </p> <ul> <li> income; </li> <li> dividends, rents, interest, and capital gains; </li> <li> liabilities; </li> <li> gifts; </li> <li>real and personal property;</li> <li> honoraria; </li> <li> expense accounts or reimbursements for expenses; and </li> <li> waivers or partial waivers of fees or charges. </li> </ul> <p>The financial disclosure reports must be available for public inspection and copying, unless revealing personal and sensitive information could endanger the judge or a family member. A report may be redacted only: (1) to the extent necessary to protect the individual or family member, and (2) as long as the danger to the individual exists.</p> <p>(Sec. 3) The Probate Divisions of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia may use magistrate judges. <p>(Sec. 4) DC courts may accept payment of fines, fees, escrow payments, restitution, bonds, and other payments by credit card or electronic funds transfer. The executive officer of the courts may contract with a bank or credit card vendor, or other third party provider, to accept such payments, making every effort to find the lowest cost vendor among them. <p>(Sec. 5) The maximum amount in controversy for cases under the Small Claims and Conciliation Branch of DC Superior Court shall increase from $5,000 to $10,000. <p>(Sec. 6) Each chief judge of the Superior Court or of the Court of Appeals, as appropriate, may delegate to an active or senior judge (in the court in which the chief judge sits) the authority to approve any compensation for court-appointed criminal defense or child abuse and neglect attorneys exceeding the usual maximum.]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114s2966v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-06-01">
<action-date>2016-05-23</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>District of Columbia Judicial Financial Transparency Act </b></p> <p>This bill amends the District of Columbia Code to revise the financial disclosure requirements for District of Columbia judges. The revisions establish new dollar thresholds and requirements for reporting to the District of Columbia Commission on Judicial Disabilities and Tenure the financial interests of the judges and specified family members with respect to: </p> <ul> <li> income; </li> <li> dividends, rents, interest, and capital gains; </li> <li> liabilities; </li> <li> gifts; </li> <li>real and personal property;</li> <li> honoraria; </li> <li> expense accounts or reimbursements for expenses; and </li> <li> waivers or partial waivers of fees or charges. </li> </ul> <p>The financial disclosure reports must be available for public inspection and copying, unless revealing personal and sensitive information could endanger the judge or a family member. A report may be redacted only: (1) to the extent necessary to protect the individual or family member, and (2) as long as the danger to the individual exists.</p> <p>The Probate Divisions of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia may use magistrate judges. <p>DC courts may accept payment of fines, fees, escrow payments, restitution, bonds, and other payments by credit card or electronic funds transfer. The executive officer of the courts may contract with a bank or credit card vendor, or other third party provider, to accept such payments, making every effort to find the lowest cost vendor among them. <p>The maximum amount in controversy for cases under the Small Claims and Conciliation Branch of DC Superior Court shall increase from $5,000 to $10,000. <p>The chief judge of the Superior Court or of the Court of Appeals, as appropriate, may delegate to an active or senior judge the authority to approve any compensation for court-appointed attorneys exceeding the usual maximum. <p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
