<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="673" measure-id="id114s673" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-03-04" update-date="2015-08-19">
<title>Winding Down ObamaCare Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s673v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-08-19">
<action-date>2015-03-04</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Winding Down ObamaCare Act</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Public Health Service Act to require health insurers to offer at least 18 months of continuation coverage to enrollees who lose their health insurance coverage or federal premium assistance as a result of the Supreme Court's decision in <em>King v. Burwell</em>. Continuation coverage must be the same as an enrollee's coverage at the time of the decision, unless the health insurer modifies coverage for all similar enrollees. Individuals must elect continuation coverage within 60 days of the decision.</p> <p>Health insurers cannot raise premiums during the period of continuation coverage.</p> <p>The Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) cannot enter into a new contract with a state to provide the state with technology from the federal health insurance exchange.</p> <p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to establish a new tax credit for individuals with continuation coverage that is equal to 65% of the amount paid for continuation coverage, with the percentage decreasing by 5% each month after six months. The Department of the Treasury must pay advance payments on the tax credit. </p> This bill amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to prohibit HHS from waiving state Medicaid plan requirements in order to allow a state to undertake a demonstration project unless HHS establishes project spending limits that are reviewed by actuaries.]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
