<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="679" measure-id="id114s679" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-03-09" update-date="2015-04-02">
<title>Quality Data, Quality Healthcare Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s679v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-04-02">
<action-date>2015-03-09</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Quality Data, Quality Healthcare Act of 2015</b></p> <p> Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act with respect to the use of certain data by qualified public or private entities to evaluate the performance of service providers and suppliers under Medicare insurance programs.</p> <p>Authorizes a qualified entity to: (1) use Medicare data, and information derived from service provider and supplier performance evaluations, for additional non-public analyses; or (2) provide or sell such data and analyses to specified health care-related entities for non-public use (including for purposes of assisting service providers and suppliers to develop and participate in quality and patient care improvement activities, particularly development of new models of care).</p> <p>Conditions such authorization upon a data use agreement between a qualified entity and a specified health care-related entity under which the latter: (1) may not re-sell such data or analyses, and (2) shall comply with the qualified entity's privacy and security policies in using such data or analyses.</p> <p>Prescribes a civil money penalty for unauthorized use of data and analyses.</p> <p>Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to provide Medicare claims data to qualified clinical data registries for purposes of linking it with clinical outcomes data and performing and disseminating risk-adjusted, scientifically valid research to support quality improvement.</p> <p>Prohibits a qualified clinical data registry from reporting publicly any claims data thus made available that individually identifies a service provider or supplier without prior consent.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
