<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="972" measure-id="id114s972" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-04-16" update-date="2015-08-11">
<title>Browns Canyon National Monument Clarification Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s972v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-08-11">
<action-date>2015-04-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Browns Canyon National Monument Clarification Act</b></p> <p>Declares that the designation of a national monument on land on which the Arkansas Headwaters Recreation Area in Colorado is located shall not affect: (1) the arrangements for cooperative administration of the Area by the Bureau of Land Management and the state of Colorado, (2) grazing on the land on which the monument is located, or (3) the use or allocation of any water, water right, or interest in water.</p> <p>Requires the Department of the Interior to complete a comprehensive management plan for the conservation and protection of the monument.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
