<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="238" measure-id="id114s238" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-01-22" update-date="2016-07-11">
<title>Eric Williams Correctional Officer Protection Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s238v49" currentChamber="BOTH" update-date="2016-07-11">
<action-date>2016-03-09</action-date>
<action-desc>Public Law</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The expanded summary of the Senate passed version is repeated here.)</p> <p><b>Eric Williams Correctional Officer Protection Act of 2015</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends the federal criminal code to require the Bureau of Prisons (BOP) to issue oleoresin capsicum spray (i.e., pepper spray) to officers and employees who respond to emergency situations at high-security, medium-security, and administrative facilities.</p> <p> Officers and employees may use pepper spray to reduce violent acts by prisoners and visitors. </p> <p>An officer of employee must complete a training course prior to receiving pepper spray and annually thereafter on its use.&nbsp;</p> <p>(Sec. 3) The Government Accountability Office must: (1) evaluate the effect of issuing pepper spray on reducing crime and violence in high-security, medium-security, and administrative facilities; (2) evaluate the advisability of issuing pepper spray at low- or minimum-security facilities; and (3) recommend safety improvements for BOP officers and employees. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114s238v81" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-07-07">
<action-date>2016-02-24</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The expanded summary of the Senate passed version is repeated here.)</p> <p><b>Eric Williams Correctional Officer Protection Act of 2015</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends the federal criminal code to require the Bureau of Prisons (BOP) to issue oleoresin capsicum spray (i.e., pepper spray) to officers and employees who respond to emergency situations at high-security, medium-security, and administrative facilities.</p> <p> Officers and employees may use pepper spray to reduce violent acts by prisoners and visitors. </p> <p>An officer of employee must complete a training course prior to receiving pepper spray and annually thereafter on its use.&nbsp;</p> <p>(Sec. 3) The Government Accountability Office must: (1) evaluate the effect of issuing pepper spray on reducing crime and violence in high-security, medium-security, and administrative facilities; (2) evaluate the advisability of issuing pepper spray at low- or minimum-security facilities; and (3) recommend safety improvements for BOP officers and employees. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114s238v82" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-05-27">
<action-date>2015-12-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed Senate without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p><b>Eric Williams Correctional Officer Protection Act of 2015</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends the federal criminal code to require the Bureau of Prisons (BOP) to issue oleoresin capsicum spray (i.e., pepper spray) to officers and employees who respond to emergency situations at high-security, medium-security, and administrative facilities. <br /></p> <p>Officers and employees may use pepper spray to reduce violent acts by prisoners and visitors. <br /></p> <p>An officer of employee must complete a training course prior to receiving pepper spray and annually thereafter on its use.&nbsp;</p> <p>(Sec. 3) The Government Accountability Office must: (1) evaluate the effect of issuing pepper spray on reducing crime and violence in high-security, medium-security, and administrative facilities; (2) evaluate the advisability of issuing pepper spray at low- or minimum-security facilities; and (3) recommend safety improvements for BOP officers and employees. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114s238v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-02-09">
<action-date>2015-01-22</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Eric Williams Correctional Officer Protection Act of 2015</b></p> <p> Amends the federal criminal code to require the Director of the Bureau of Prisons to issue oleoresin capsicum spray to: (1) any Bureau officer or employee employed in a prison that is not a minimum or low security prison who may respond to an emergency situation in such prison; and (2) such additional prison officers and employees as the Director deems appropriate, subject to specified requirements.</p> <p>Requires any such officer or employee to complete a training course before being issued such spray and annual training on the use of such spray. </p> <p>Authorizes Bureau officers and employees issued such spray to use&nbsp;it to reduce acts of violence committed by prisoners and prison visitors against themselves, other prisoners and visitors, and Bureau officers and employees.</p> <p>Directs the Comptroller General, not later than three years after the date on which the Director begins to issue oleoresin capsicum spray to Bureau officers and employees, to submit to Congress a report that includes: (1) an evaluation of the effectiveness of issuing such spray on reducing crime in such prisons and acts of violence committed by prisoners against themselves and others, (2) an evaluation of the advisability of issuing such spray, and (3) recommendations to improve the safety of Bureau officers and employees in prisons.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
