<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2104" measure-id="id114s2104" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-09-30" update-date="2016-06-06">
<title>A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide relief to Medicare Advantage plans with a significant number of dually eligible or low-income subsidy beneficiaries and to prevent the termination of two star plans.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2104v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-06-06">
<action-date>2015-09-30</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Preserving Medicare Advantage for all Medicare Beneficiaries Act of 2015</b></p> <p>This bill amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to: (1) temporarily prohibit the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid from terminating a Medicare Advantage (MA) plan contract solely because the MA plan fails to achieve a certain minimum quality rating, provided that the MA plan achieves a quality rating of at least two out of five stars; and (2) establish a demonstration project to provide funds to MA organizations for the development or expansion of programs or services to improve health care delivery and outcomes for enrollees of low socioeconomic status.</p> <p>To qualify for demonstration project funding, an MA plan must meet specified requirements with respect to quality ratings and the percentage of plan enrollees either eligible for a low-income subsidy or dually eligible for Medicare and Medicaid. MA organizations receiving funds under the demonstration project must use those funds to target improvement by the MA plan with respect to certain quality rating measures.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
