<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2319" measure-id="id114s2319" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-11-19" update-date="2016-09-13">
<title>A bill to amend the Communications Act of 1934.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2319v80" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-09-13">
<action-date>2016-08-30</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to Senate without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p>(Sec. 1) This bill amends the Communications Act of&nbsp;1934 to require any deposits that the Federal Communications Commission may require for the qualification of bidders in a system of competitive bidding for spectrum licenses to be deposited directly in the Treasury instead of in an interest bearing account at a financial institution. The bill removes a provision that requires the interest accrued to such a&nbsp;financial institution account to be dedicated for the sole purpose of deficit reduction. </p> <p>The deposits of successful bidders must be credited to the deposit fund of the Treasury, unless existing exceptions apply. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114s2319v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-04-05">
<action-date>2015-11-19</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill amends the Communications Act of&nbsp;1934 to require any deposits that the Federal Communications Commission may require for the qualification of bidders in a system of competitive bidding for spectrum licenses to be deposited directly in the Treasury instead of in an interest bearing account at a financial institution. The bill removes a provision that requires the interest accrued to such a&nbsp;financial institution account to be dedicated for the sole purpose of deficit reduction. </p> <p>The deposits of successful bidders must be credited to the deposit fund of the Treasury, unless existing exceptions apply. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
