<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1561" measure-id="id114s1561" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-06-11" update-date="2015-09-22">
<title>Captive Insurers Clarification Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1561v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-09-22">
<action-date>2015-06-11</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Captive Insurers Clarification Act</b> </p> <p> Amends the Nonadmitted and Reinsurance Reform Act of 2010 to define &quot;captive insurance company&quot; as an insurance company wholly owned directly or indirectly: (1) by a single parent company and whose primary purpose is to insure the risks of that single parent company or its affiliates; (2) by a group of companies and whose primary purpose is to insure the risks of that group or its affiliates; and (3) by an industry, trade, or service group or association, and whose primary purpose is to insure the risks of any member in that group or association, including any member affiliate.</p> <p>Excludes a captive insurance company from the meaning of a &quot;nonadmitted insurer&quot; (that is not licensed to engage in the business of insurance in a state), and from any requirements (including state tax requirements) applying to a nonadmitted insurer.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
