<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2267" measure-id="id114s2267" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-11-10" update-date="2016-09-19">
<title>Higher Education Access and Success for Homeless and Foster Youth Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2267v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-09-19">
<action-date>2015-11-10</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Higher Education Access and Success for Homeless and Foster Youth Act</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 to revise provisions related to financial aid and educational programs for children and youths who are homeless or in foster care.</p> <p>With respect to a student's independence for purposes of financial aid, a financial aid administrator must: (1)&nbsp;in the absence of conflicting information,&nbsp;accept a homelessness determination made by an authorized individual; and (2) make such a determination if the student cannot get documentation from a designated authority. A student who is determined to be independent&nbsp;on this basis&nbsp;shall generally be presumed to be independent for a subsequent award year at the same institution.</p> <p>The bill expands the duties of the Student Loan Ombudsman to include the review and resolution of complaints regarding such determinations.</p> <p>To be eligible for&nbsp;certain federal funds, an institution must meet specified requirements related to student housing, coordination, and notice of financial assistance eligibility with respect to children and youths who are homeless or in foster care.</p> <p>In approving applications for&nbsp;entities to carry out specified programs related to higher education,&nbsp;the Department of Education&nbsp;shall require an entity to make specified assurances with respect to the participation of children and youths who are homeless or in foster care. A federal work-study agreement must prioritize employment for such students.</p> <p>For purposes of income-based financial aid determinations, the bill excludes from income: (1) the value of specified vouchers for education and training, and (2) direct payments made through an extended foster care program.</p> <p>With respect to children or youths who are homeless or in foster care, a&nbsp;state may not charge a tuition rate that is higher than the in-state tuition rate.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
