<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2145" measure-id="id114s2145" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-10-06" update-date="2015-10-27">
<title>Middle East Refugee Emergency Supplemental Appropriations Act, 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2145v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-10-27">
<action-date>2015-10-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Middle East Refugee Emergency Supplemental Appropriations Act, 2016</b></p> <p> This bill provides $1 billion in FY2016 supplemental appropriations to the Department of State's Migration and Refugee Assistance account for expenses to respond to the refugee crisis resulting from conflict in the Middle East, including costs associated with the resettlement of refugees in the United States. The funds are designated as an emergency requirement, which exempts the funds from discretionary spending limits and other budget enforcement rules. </p> <p>Prior to using funds provided by this bill, the State Department must submit to Congress a report including specified details regarding the refugees who have fled Syria and Iraq, the costs associated with resettlement, and the proposed uses of funds provided by this bill. </p> <p>The State Department may transfer funds provided by this bill to other federal agencies for the purpose of assisting in the resettlement in the United States of refugees fleeing conflict in the Middle East, subject to congressional notification requirements. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
