<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2674" measure-id="id114s2674" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-03-14" update-date="2016-03-21">
<title>Lead in Drinking Water Disaster Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2674v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-03-21">
<action-date>2016-03-14</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Lead in Drinking Water Disaster Act of 2016</strong></p> <p>This bill authorizes the President, upon request of a governor of a state, to declare a major disaster relating to lead contamination of drinking water from a public water system. The Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) must promulgate regulations to carry out such authority within 60 days of this Act's enactment.</p> <p>In the case of such a declared major disaster, the federal coordinating officer appointed under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act shall ensure that the coordination of administration of relief required under such Act includes coordination with the Department of Health and Human Services, the Army Corps of Engineers, the Environmental Protection Agency, and any other relevant agency.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
