<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1608" measure-id="id114s1608" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-06-18" update-date="2015-10-07">
<title>Consumer Drone Safety Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1608v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-10-07">
<action-date>2015-06-18</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Consumer Drone Safety Act</b></p> <p>This bill directs the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) to publish a final rule containing safety requirements for the operation of consumer drones.</p> <p>The final rule shall apply to consumer drones that are:</p> <ul> <li>flown for hobby or recreational use, and</li> <li>not operated in accordance with a community-based set of safety guidelines and within the programming of a nationwide community-based organization.</li> </ul> <p>The final rule shall also contain requirements that include:</p> <ul> <li>a maximum altitude for flight of consumer drones,</li> <li>circumstances or areas where flights are restricted because of risk of unsafe interactions with manned aircraft and to persons or property on the ground, and</li> <li>conditions that may require limitations on flight (such as weather or time of day). </li> </ul> <p>The FAA must also publish a final rule applicable to the manufacturing of consumer drones. This rule shall require modification, at the manufacturer's expense, of existing consumer drones so that they meet the rule's requirements.</p> <p>The FAA may exempt from the rule applicable to manufacturers certain types of consumer drones if certain conditions concerning feasibility, cost, and safety are met.</p> <p>No person may operate a consumer drone in the national airspace system without specific authority from the FAA.</p>  <p>The U.S. Customs and Border Protection may use existing authority to enforce restrictions on the importation of consumer drones into the United States.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
