<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2865" measure-id="id114s2865" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-04-27" update-date="2016-08-15">
<title>Asia-Pacific Maritime Security Initiative Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2865v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-08-15">
<action-date>2016-04-27</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Asia-Pacific Maritime Security Initiative Act of 2016</strong></p> <p>This bill authorizes the Department of Defense (DOD) to establish the Maritime Security Initiative to provide assistance and training through September 30, 2022, for maritime security and domain awareness for countries in the Asia-Pacific region.</p> <p>DOD shall prioritize assistance in order to: </p> <ul> <li> retain access to international waterways to ensure the free flow of commerce and achieve U.S. national security objectives,</li> <li>improve maritime domain awareness, </li> <li>counter piracy, </li> <li>disrupt illicit maritime trafficking activities of organizations that are a U.S. security threat, and </li> <li>enhance the maritime capabilities of a country or regional organization to respond to emerging maritime security threats.</li> </ul> <p>Assistance and training shall also promote observance of human rights and fundamental freedoms and respect for legitimate civilian authority.</p> <p>DOD may use funds provided for by this bill to pay incremental training-connected expenses if such payment will facilitate the participation of organization personnel in Brunei, Singapore, and Taiwan. </p> <p> The Arms  Export Control Act is amended to extend special foreign military sales status to the Philippines. </p> <p>FY2017 international military education and training funds and foreign military financing assistance funds are authorized for activities in the region.</p> <p>The Department of State may prioritize the provision of maritime capacity building assistance to countries in the region that will contribute to the same objectives as provided in this bill for DOD.</p> <p>FY2017 funds are authorized for support of the Southeast Asia Maritime Law Enforcement Initiative. </p> <p>The Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 is amended to give priority for the transfer of excess defense articles to: (1) other major U.S. non-North American Treaty Organization allies in the region (including Japan, South Korea, Thailand, Australia, and New Zealand); and (2) other Association of Southeast Asian Nations maritime states.</p> <p>The bill authorizes the transfer of one OLIVER HAZARD PERRY class guided missile frigate on a grant basis to a foreign government pursuant to the Maritime Security Initiative.</p> <p>The President shall ensure that the U.S. government treats every proposed arms sale for Taiwan with the same time lines, processes, and procedures accorded to proposed arms transfers for all other countries.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
