<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1306" measure-id="id114s1306" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-12" update-date="2016-07-08">
<title>Energy Independence Investment Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1306v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-07-08">
<action-date>2015-05-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Energy Independence Investment Act of 2015</b></p> <p>This bill requires the Department of Energy (DOE) to study and report on the effectiveness of the advanced fossil loan guarantee incentive program and other DOE incentive programs for advanced fossil energy. In carrying out the study, DOE must:</p> <ul> <li>solicit industry and stakeholder input; </li> <li>evaluate the effectiveness of the advanced fossil loan guarantee incentive program in advancing carbon capture and storage (CCS) technology;</li> <li>review each incentive provided by federal agencies for CCS demonstration projects to determine the adequacy and effectiveness of the combined federal incentives in advancing CCS and advanced fossil energy technologies; </li> <li>assess whether combinations of existing incentive programs could be effective to advance CCS and advanced fossil energy technologies; and</li> <li> evaluate the impact of implementing the recommendations described in the January 2015 National Coal Council report entitled, &quot;Fossil Forward: Revitalizing CCS, Bringing Scale and Speed to CCS Deployment,&quot; on the effectiveness of the advanced fossil loan guarantee program.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
