<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1310" measure-id="id114s1310" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-12" update-date="2015-08-06">
<title>Deficit Reduction Through Fair Oil Royalties Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1310v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-08-06">
<action-date>2015-05-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Deficit Reduction Through Fair Oil Royalties Act</b></p> <p>This bill prohibits the Department of the Interior from issuing new oil or natural gas production leases in the Gulf of Mexico under the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act unless they have been renegotiated to require royalty payments if the price of oil and natural gas is greater than or equal to specified price thresholds. </p> <p>Rentals or royalties received by the United States under covered leases must be deposited in the Treasury and used for federal budget deficit reduction or, if there is no federal budget deficit, federal debt reduction.</p> <p>Interior must agree to a lessee's request to amend a lease to incorporate price thresholds applicable to royalty suspension requirements that are equal to or less than certain statutory price thresholds if the lease was issued for any Central and Western Gulf of Mexico tract on or after January 1, 1996, through November 28, 2000. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
