<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1513" measure-id="id114s1513" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-06-04" update-date="2015-11-12">
<title>Second Chance Reauthorization Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1513v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-11-12">
<action-date>2015-06-04</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Second Chance Reauthorization Act</strong></p> <p>Amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to revise and expand requirements for the Department of Justice (DOJ) grant program for adult and juvenile offender state and local reentry demonstration projects, including for planning and implementation and for promotion of employment opportunities, and to extend the program through FY2020. Sets forth criteria and priority considerations for DOJ to use in awarding grants. </p> <p>Amends the Second Chance Act of 2007 to extend through FY2020 the authorization of appropriations for grants for: (1) family-based substance abuse treatment, (2) the </s>careers training demonstration program, and (3) the offender reentry substance abuse and criminal justice collaboration program. Renames the program of mentoring grants to nonprofit organizations for offender reentry as the program of community-based mentoring and transitional service grants to nonprofit organizations. Provides for enhanced services under such program to assist in the reintegration of offenders into the community. Extends the authorization of appropriations for such program through FY2020.</p> <p>Requires the DOJ Inspector General to conduct annual audits, beginning in FY2016, of grant recipients under the Second Chance Act of 2007 (covered grantees) to prevent waste, fraud, and abuse of grant funds. Prohibits nonprofit organizations that hold money in offshore accounts from receiving grant funds. Imposes restrictions on: (1)&nbsp;DOJ conferences using more than $20,000 in DOJ funds; and (2)&nbsp;lobbying DOJ and other officials regarding the award of grant funding. </p> <p>Amends the Second Chance Act of 2007 to: (1) modify and extend through FY2020 grant programs for reentry of federal prisoners into the community, including the program for placing aging offenders in home detention and for offender reentry research; (2) repeal programs under such Act relating to responsible reintegration of offenders, the study of the effectiveness of Depot Naltrexone for heroin addiction, and the satellite tracking and reentry training program; and (3) establish a program for partnering faith-based or community-based nonprofit organizations with prisons to conduct recidivism reduction activities. </p> <p>Directs DOJ, in consultation with specified federal officials and in collaboration with interested persons and entities, to coordinate on federal programs, policies, and activities relating to the reentry of individuals returning from incarceration to the community, with an emphasis on evidence-based practices and protection against duplication of services.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
