<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2788" measure-id="id114s2788" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-04-13" update-date="2016-05-06">
<title>A bill to prohibit closure of United States Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba, to prohibit the transfer or release of detainees at that Naval Station to the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2788v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-05-06">
<action-date>2016-04-13</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill prohibits the use of any amounts authorized to be appropriated or otherwise made available for any federal department or agency to: (1) close or abandon U.S. Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba; (2) relinquish control of Guantanamo to Cuba; (3) implement a material modification to the 1934 Treaty Between the United States of America and Cuba that constructively closes Guantanamo; or (4) transfer, release, or assist in the transfer or release to or within the United States, its territories, or possessions of Khalid Sheikh Mohammed or any other detainee who is or was held by the Department of Defense (DOD) at Guantanamo on or after January 20, 2009, and who is not a U.S. citizen or a member of the U.S. Armed Forces.</p> <p>Prior to the transfer or release of any such individual, DOD shall make available to the public a specified notice of such intended action.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
