<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="704" measure-id="id114s704" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-03-11" update-date="2015-09-28">
<title>Community Based Independence for Seniors Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s704v01" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-09-28">
<action-date>2015-07-30</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to Senate amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Community Based Independence for Seniors Act </b></p> <p>(Sec. 3) This bill directs the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to establish a five-year Community-Based Institutional Special Needs Plan demonstration program to prevent and delay institutionalization under title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act (SSAct) among eligible low-income Medicare beneficiaries age 65 or older.</p> <p>HHS shall enter into agreements with up to five eligible Medicare Advantage (MA) plans under part C (Medicare+Choice) of SSAct title XVIII (Medicare) to conduct the demonstration program. Each eligible MA plan may enroll up to 1,000 eligible low-income Medicare beneficiaries in such program.</p> <p>A participating MA plan shall use the rebate the plan must provide to eligible low-income Medicare enrollees to furnish certain benefits, including homemaker services, home delivered meals, transportation services, respite care, adult day care services, and non-Medicare-covered safety and other equipment.</p> <p>HHS shall help to educate eligible Medicare beneficiaries about the availability of the demonstration program through State Health Insurance Assistance Programs and other organizations dedicated to assisting seniors with Medicare benefits and enrollment.</p> <p>The demonstration program shall be implemented by January 1, 2018.</p> <p>HHS shall arrange for an independent third party evaluation of the demonstration program, on the basis of which its duration and scope may be expanded.</p> <p>Funding for the demonstration program shall come <dfn> </dfn>out of the Medicare trust funds.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114s704v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-09-28">
<action-date>2015-03-11</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Community Based Independence for Seniors Act </b></p> <p>This bill directs the Department of Health and Human Services to establish a Community-Based Institutional Special Needs Plan demonstration program to target home and community-based care to eligible low-income Medicare beneficiaries age 65 or older.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
