<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="503" measure-id="id114s503" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-02-12" update-date="2015-05-12">
<title>Haitian Partnership Renewal Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s503v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-05-12">
<action-date>2015-02-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Haitian Partnership Renewal Act</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Caribbean Basin Economic Recovery Act to extend: (1) the 60% applicable percentage requirement for duty-free entry of apparel articles assembled in Haiti and imported from Haiti or the Dominican Republic to the United States, and (2) duty-free entry of such articles through December 19, 2030.</p> <p>Duty-free entry for woven articles and certain knit articles assembled in Haiti and imported from Haiti or the Dominican Republic to the United States is extended through September 30, 2030.</p> <p>The special duty-free rules for Haiti are extended through September 30, 2030.</p> <p>The transition period treatment of certain textile and apparel articles is extended through September 30, 2030.</p> <p>Duty-free coverage is provided:</p> <ul> <li>for certain footwear, travel goods, leather wearing apparel, and lamps, lighting, and other electrical components that undergo a change in Haiti and are imported directly from Haiti or the Dominican Republic; and</li> <li>through September 30, 2030, for a qualifying wire harness automotive component that is the product or manufacture of Haiti and is imported directly from Haiti.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
