<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1052" measure-id="id114s1052" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-04-22" update-date="2016-06-06">
<title>A bill to require a study on the impact of State and local performance benchmarking and disclosure policies for commercial and multifamily buildings, to provide for competitive awards to utilities, States, and units of local government, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1052v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-06-06">
<action-date>2015-04-22</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill requires the Department of Energy (DOE) to study and report on: (1) the impact of state and local performance benchmarking and disclosure policies, and associated building efficiency policies, for commercial and multifamily buildings; (2) the impact of programs and systems in which utilities provide aggregated information regarding whole building energy consumption and usage information to owners of multitenant buildings; and (3) the best practice policy approaches studied in those impact analyses that have resulted in the greatest improvements in building energy efficiency.</p> <p>DOE may give grants to: (1) utilities, utility regulators, and utility partners to implement programs to provide aggregated whole building energy consumption information to multitenant building owners; and (2) states and local governments to implement benchmarking and disclosure policies for commercial and multifamily buildings.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
