<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="335" measure-id="id114s335" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-02-02" update-date="2015-07-15">
<title>A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to improve 529 plans.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s335v01" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-07-15">
<action-date>2015-05-21</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to Senate amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(Sec. 2) This section amends the Internal Revenue Code to modify the types of higher education expenses that may be paid from a qualified tuition program (known as a 529 plan) to&nbsp;include expenses for the purchase of computer or peripheral equipment and computer software. This amendment applies to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2014. </p> <p>(Sec. 3) This section repeals, after 2014, the provision of the Internal Revenue Code that requires 529 plan accounts to be aggregated for purposes of calculating the amount of&nbsp;distributions that&nbsp;are&nbsp;includible in taxpayer income. </p> <p>(Sec. 4) This section amends the Internal Revenue Code to provide that a 529 plan beneficiary who receives a refund of higher education expenses after 2014 will not be required to include the amount of such refund in income for tax purposes if such beneficiary recontributes the refunded amount to the 529 plan within 60 days of receiving the refund and the recontribution does not exceed the refunded amount. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114s335v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-02-27">
<action-date>2015-02-02</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code, with respect to qualified tuition programs (529 plans), to: (1) make permanent the allowance for payment of computer technology and equipment expenses from a 529 plan if such technology and equipment is to be used primarily by the plan beneficiary (currently, use is allowed by the beneficiary and the beneficiary's family); (2) eliminate the requirement that distributions to a 529 plan be aggregated for purposes of determining the amount includible in a taxpayer's income; and (3) allow a tax-free recontribution to a 529 plan of amounts refunded to a student who withdraws from an educational institution if the recontribution is made not later than 60 days after the date of such refund and does not exceed the refunded amount. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
