<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1250" measure-id="id114s1250" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-07" update-date="2016-01-28">
<title>Nicholas and Zachary Burt Memorial Carbon Monoxide Poisoning Prevention Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1250v01" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-01-28">
<action-date>2015-12-14</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to Senate amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Nicholas and Zachary Burt Memorial Carbon Monoxide Poisoning Prevention Act of 2015 </b></p> <p>(Sec. 4) This bill directs the Consumer Product Safety Commission (CPSC) to establish a grant program to provide assistance to states or tribal organizations that require compliant carbon monoxide alarms to be installed in dwelling units.</p> <p>A "compliant carbon monoxide alarm" is an alarm that complies with: (1) the Standard for Single and Multiple Station Carbon Monoxide Alarms of the American National Standards Institute and UL (ANSI/UL 2034) or a successor standard, and (2) the Standard for Gas and Vapor Detectors and Sensors of the American National Standards Institute and UL (ANSI/UL 2075) or a successor standard. </p> <p> In selecting grant recipients, the CPSC must give favorable consideration to states or tribal organizations that: (1) require compliant alarms in specified facilities with fuel-burning appliances or attached garages, including educational facilities, childcare facilities, health care facilities, adult dependent care facilities, government buildings, restaurants, theaters, lodging establishments, or dwelling units; and (2) have strategies to protect vulnerable populations such as children, the elderly, or low-income households.</p> <p>States or tribal organizations receiving grants may use such funds to: (1) purchase and install such alarms in dwelling units of low-income families or elderly persons, childcare facilities, public schools, senior centers, or student dwelling units owned by public universities; (2) train state, tribal, or local fire code enforcement officials regarding compliance and installation; or (3) educate the public about the risk of carbon monoxide poisoning.</p> <p>The CPSC must report to Congress regarding the implementation of such grant program. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114s1250v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-06-05">
<action-date>2015-05-07</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Nicholas and Zachary Burt Memorial Carbon Monoxide Poisoning Prevention Act of 2015 </b></p> <p>Directs the Consumer Product Safety Commission to establish a grant program to provide assistance to states that require compliant carbon monoxide alarms to be installed in dwelling units.</p> <p>Defines "compliant carbon monoxide alarm" as an alarm that complies with the American National Standard for Single and Multiple Station Carbon Monoxide Alarms as well as the American National Standard for Gas and Vapor Detectors and Sensors.</p> <p>Permits states receiving grants to use such funds to: (1) purchase and install such alarms in dwelling units of low-income families or elderly persons, childcare facilities, public schools, senior centers, or student dwelling units owned by public universities; (2) train state or local fire code enforcement officials regarding compliance and installation; and (3) educate the public about the risk of carbon monoxide poisoning.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
