<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1518" measure-id="id114s1518" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-06-04" update-date="2016-04-13">
<title>Reinforcing American-Made Products Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1518v80" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-04-13">
<action-date>2016-03-07</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to Senate without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p><b>Reinforcing American-Made Products Act of 2015</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Violent Crime Control and Law Enforcement Act of 1994 to require the Federal Trade Commission's regulation of the labeling of products as &quot;Made in the U.S.A.&quot; or &quot;Made in America&quot; to supersede any state laws regarding the extent to which a product is introduced, delivered, sold, advertised, or offered for sale in interstate or foreign commerce with such a label in order to represent that the product was in whole or substantial part of domestic origin. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114s1518v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-07-10">
<action-date>2015-06-04</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Reinforcing American-Made Products Act of 2015</b></p> <p>Amends the Violent Crime Control and Law Enforcement Act of 1994 to require the Federal Trade Commission's regulation of the labeling of products as &quot;Made in the U.S.A.&quot; or &quot;Made in America&quot; to supersede any state laws regarding the extent to which a product is introduced, delivered, sold, advertised, or offered for sale in interstate or foreign commerce with such a label in order to represent that the product was in whole or substantial part of domestic origin. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
