<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2205" measure-id="id114s2205" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-10-22" update-date="2016-06-06">
<title>Tribal Healing to Wellness Courts Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2205v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-06-06">
<action-date>2015-10-22</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Tribal Healing to Wellness Courts Act of 2015</b></p> <p>This bill permits the Department of Justice (DOJ) to award grants to tribal governments acting in partnership with state or local governments for tribal healing to wellness courts. (A tribal healing to wellness court is a drug court that is a component of a tribal justice system and includes substance abuse treatment and may include cultural activities.)</p> <p>Courts receiving grants must monitor individuals under their jurisdiction and must periodically test each individual for drug use. DOJ may require these courts to increase punitive or treatment responses for an individual who fails a drug test.</p> Violent offenders may not be under the jurisdiction of these courts unless the court has received a waiver from DOJ.]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
