<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2687" measure-id="id114s2687" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-03-15" update-date="2016-05-23">
<title>Plan of Safe Care Improvement Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2687v01" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-05-23">
<action-date>2016-03-15</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to Senate amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Plan of Safe Care Improvement Act</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Child Abuse Prevention and Treatment Act to require a grant-receiving state plan for a child abuse or neglect prevention and treatment program to include policies and procedures requiring systems to monitor the multidisciplinary plan of safe care for an infant born affected by substance abuse or withdrawal symptoms or a Fetal Alcohol Spectrum Disorder in order to:</p> <ul> <li>ensure the safety and well-being of children; <li>address the health, including mental health and substance use disorder treatment, needs of the child, and of the family or affected caregiver, involved; and <li>determine whether and to what extent local entities are capable of providing referrals to and delivery of appropriate services for the child and family. </li> </ul> <p>(Sec. 3) Each grant-receiving state shall work annually with the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to produce a report including the total number of infants identified and the number of infants for whom a plan of safe care was developed.</p> <p>(Sec. 4) HHS shall: (1) monitor states to ensure that each one's policies and procedures meet requirements to improve outcomes among infants born and identified as being affected by substance abuse or withdrawal symptoms or a Fetal Alcohol Spectrum Disorder, and (2) issue guidance to states regarding the requirements and best practices for the development and implementation of plans of safe care.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114s2687v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-05-23">
<action-date>2016-03-15</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Plan of Safe Care Improvement Act</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Child Abuse Prevention and Treatment Act to require a grant-receiving state plan for a child abuse or neglect prevention and treatment program to include policies and procedures requiring systems to monitor the plan of safe care for an infant born affected by illegal substance abuse or withdrawal symptoms, or a Fetal Alcohol Spectrum Disorder, in order to:</p> <ul> <li>ensure the safety and well-being of children;</li> <li>address the health, including mental health, needs of the child and family involved; and</li> <li>determine whether local entities are capable of providing referrals to and delivery of appropriate services for the child and family.</li> </ul> <p>Each grant-receiving state shall work annually with the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to produce a report including the number of infants for whom a plan of safe care was developed.</p> <p>HHS shall: (1) monitor states to ensure that each one is meeting requirements to improve outcomes among children most at risk for child abuse and neglect, and (2) issue guidance to states regarding the requirements and best practices for the development and implementation of plans of safe care.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
