<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1230" measure-id="id114s1230" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-06" update-date="2015-07-24">
<title>A bill to direct the Secretary of the Interior to establish a program under which the Director of the Bureau of Land Management shall enter into memoranda of understanding with States providing for State oversight of oil and gas productions activities.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1230v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-07-24">
<action-date>2015-05-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill requires the Department of the Interior, upon state request, to establish a program under which the Director of the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) shall enter into a memorandum of understanding with a state to create consistent rules and processes for measurement of oil and gas production activities, inspection of meters or other measurement methodologies, and other operational activities. </p> <p> To be eligible for this program, a state must administer oil and gas programs sufficient to fulfill BLM oversight and enforcement responsibilities.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
