<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1820" measure-id="id114s1820" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-07-21" update-date="2016-09-29">
<title>Early Participation in Regulations Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1820v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-09-29">
<action-date>2015-07-21</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Early Participation in Regulations Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>Defines a "major rule" as a rule that the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs (OIRA) determines is likely to impose: (1) an annual effect on the economy of $100 million or more; (2) a major increase in costs or prices for consumers, individual industries, government agencies, or geographic regions; or (3) significant adverse effects on competition, employment, investment, productivity, innovation, or the ability of U.S. enterprises to compete with foreign-based enterprises.</p> <p>Directs an agency, not later than 90 days before publishing a notice of proposed rule making for a major rule in the Federal Register, to publish advance notice of proposed rule making for such rule. Requires such advance notice to: (1) include a written statement identifying the nature and significance of the problem to be addressed, the legal authority under which the rule is proposed, and an achievable objective for the rule and metrics for measuring progress toward that objective; and (2) solicit and provide a period of at least 60 days for submission of written data, views, and argument from interested persons.</p> <p>Makes this Act inapplicable to a major rule: (1) for which the proposing agency is not required to publish a notice of proposed rule making, (2) if the OIRA determines that the requirements described in this Act would not serve the public interest, or (3) if the agency proposing the major rule is otherwise specifically exempted by law from notice and comment rule making procedures.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
