<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="308" measure-id="id114s308" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-01-29" update-date="2015-02-27">
<title>After School for America's Children Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s308v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-02-27">
<action-date>2015-01-29</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>After School for America's Children Act</strong></p> <p>Amends the 21st Century Community Learning Centers program under part B of title IV of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (ESEA). (21st Century Community Learning Centers provide students with before and after school programs to improve their academic performance.)</p> <p>Requires the Centers to provide: (1) students with activities that are targeted to their academic needs and aligned with the instruction they receive during the school day, and (2) students' families with opportunities for active and meaningful engagement in their children's education.</p> <p>Includes Indian tribes or organizations among the local public or private entities that are eligible for grants from states to establish the Centers.</p> <p>Requires states to use at least 93% (currently 95%) of their allotment from the Secretary of Education to provide grants to those entities. </p> <p>Allows states to use up to 5% (currently, 3%) of their allotment for certain state activities.</p> <p>Requires states to: (1) award grants to local entities that serve students who primarily attend schools that are eligible for schoolwide programs under part A of title I of the ESEA, and (2) favor applicants that propose to serve students that have not achieved proficiency in accordance with state academic achievement standards.</p> <p>Requires states to use a rigorous peer review process in reviewing grant applications.</p> <p>Allows states to renew a grant under part B based on the grantee's performance during the original grant period.</p> <p>Prohibits the Secretary or states from giving funding priority to applicants that propose to use the funds to extend the regular school day.</p> <p>Includes among the activities grants may fund: (1) core academic subject education activities, including those that allow students to recover or attain credits; (2) literacy education programs; (3) programs that support a healthy, active lifestyle; (4) services for the disabled; (5) cultural programs; and (6) programs that build science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (STEM) skills and support innovative STEM teaching methods.</p> <p>Reauthorizes the 21st Century Community Learning Centers program through FY2021.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
