<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2416" measure-id="id114s2416" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-12-17" update-date="2016-10-31">
<title>VERIFI Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2416v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-10-31">
<action-date>2015-12-17</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Verifying Electronically the Receipt of In-Home Care For Individuals Act or the VERIFI Act</strong></p> <p>This bill amends titles XVIII (Medicare) and XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to require the use of electronic visit verification systems for certain services under the Medicare and Medicaid programs. An "electronic visit verification system" is a system under which care-related visits are electronically verified with regard to: (1) the type and date of service, (2) the individual receiving the service, (3) the individual providing the service, (4) the location of service delivery, and (5) the time the service begins and ends.</p> <p>With respect to the Medicare program,&nbsp;a home health agency must have such a system in place&nbsp;for home health services as a condition of participation.</p> <p>In the case of a state Medicaid program that does not require the use of such a system for both personal care services and home health services, the federal medical assistance percentage for medical assistance expended on such services shall be reduced beginning in 2019. These reductions increase incrementally from 0.25% to 1.00% through 2023.</p> <p>With respect to the Medicare program, the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services shall establish standards for the systems and must consult with agencies to ensure that such standards: (1) are minimally burdensome, (2) account for existing best practices and electronic visit verifications systems already in use, and (3) require that the systems are conducted in accordance with specified legal requirements related to privacy and security.&nbsp;In regard to&nbsp;a state Medicaid program, a state shall do the same.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
