<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="3164" measure-id="id114s3164" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-07-12" update-date="2016-08-01">
<title>Fair Housing for Domestic Violence and Sexual Assault Survivors Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s3164v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-08-01">
<action-date>2016-07-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Fair Housing for Domestic Violence and Sexual Assault Survivors Act of 2016</b></p> <p> This bill amends the Fair Housing Act to prohibit discrimination against or regarding survivors of domestic violence or sexual assault in:</p> <ul> <li>the sale or rental of housing and related activities, </li> <li>residential real estate-related transactions, and </li> <li>the provision of real estate brokerage services.</li> </ul> <p>This bill declares that nothing in the Act shall prohibit federal, state, or local government or other assistance or a preference program designed to assist or benefit domestic violence or sexual assault survivors in seeking, securing, or maintaining dwellings, shelters or any other form of housing.</p> <p>The Civil Rights Act of 1968 is amended to prohibit intimidation in fair housing tranactions regarding survivors of domestic violence or sexual assault.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
