<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1593" measure-id="id114s1593" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-06-17" update-date="2015-06-25">
<title>Immigration Slush Fund Elimination Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1593v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-06-25">
<action-date>2015-06-17</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Immigration Slush Fund Elimination Act of 2015</strong> <is bill > </p> <p>This bill amends the Immigration and Nationality Act (INA) to provide that the following fees shall be miscellaneous receipts to be deposited in the general fund of the Treasury: </p> <ul> <li>asylum fees, </li> <li>nonimmigrant nurse fees, </li> <li>employer fees, </li> <li>additional employer fees, </li> <li>Department of State and Department of Homeland Security fraud prevention and detection fees, </li> <li>visa waiver program fees, </li> <li>temporary protected status fees, </li> <li>adjustment of status fees, </li> <li>administrative fines and penalties, </li> <li>the genealogy fee, </li> <li>the premium fee for employment-based petitions and applications, </li> <li>biometric entry and data system fees, and </li> <li>nonimmigrant foreign student fees.</li> </ul> <p>Authority for the visa waiver program travel promotion fee is extended through September 30, 2015.</p> <p> Fee disposition provisions are revised.</p> <p>Fee revenues in all of the accounts under section 286 of INA, as of the day before enactment of this Act, shall be transferred to the general fund of the Treasury on the effective date provided for by this Act. </p> <p>All of the accounts authorized under such section (including the Immigration User Fee Account and the Land Border Inspection Account), as of the day before the date of enactment of this Act, shall be terminated on such date.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
