<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1350" measure-id="id114s1350" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-14" update-date="2015-11-30">
<title>Surface Transportation Extension Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1350v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-11-30">
<action-date>2015-05-14</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Surface Transportation Extension Act of 2015</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Highway and Transportation Funding Act of 2014 to extend through July 31, 2015, the authorization, including authorized amount of appropriations, for:</p> <ul> <li>federal-aid highway programs generally,</li> <li>National Highway Traffic Safety Administration highway safety programs, and </li> <li>Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration programs.</li> </ul> <p>The authorization of appropriations for programs under the Dingell-Johnson Sport Fish Restoration Act is also extended through July 31, 2015.</p> <p>The bill extends through the same date the authorization and apportionment of appropriations for formula grants, including those for rural areas, public transportation, and bus and bus facilities.</p> <p>Appropriations are authorized through that date for hazardous materials emergency preparedness and training grants.</p> <p>Expenditure authorities of the Internal Revenue Code are also extended through July 31, 2015, for the Highway, Sport Fish Restoration and Boating, and Leaking Underground Storage Tank Trust Funds.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
