<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="3228" measure-id="id114s3228" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-07-14" update-date="2016-11-04">
<title>Assessing Coastal Areas to Assist States Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s3228v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-11-04">
<action-date>2016-07-14</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Assessing Coastal Areas to Assist States Act</strong></p> <p>This bill directs the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers to conduct a study to identify the risks and vulnerabilities of the coastal areas located within the geographic boundaries of the South Atlantic Division of the Corps of Engineers to increased hurricane and storm damage as a result of sea level rise.</p> <p>In carrying out the study, the Corps of Engineers shall: (1) conduct necessary analyses, with special emphasis on regional sediment management as a method to sustainably maintain or enhance current levels of storm protection to produce a comprehensive understanding of coastal vulnerabilities in the affected areas and to identify initial measures to address such vulnerabilities; and (2) develop a long-term strategy for addressing such increased damage and for identifying opportunities to enhance resiliency, increase sustainability, and lower risks in population centers, areas of concentrated economic development, and areas with vulnerable environmental resources.</p> <ul> <ul> <ul> </ul> </ul> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
