<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1913" measure-id="id114s1913" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-07-30" update-date="2016-04-11">
<title>Stopping Medication Abuse and Protecting Seniors Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1913v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-04-11">
<action-date>2015-07-30</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Stopping Medication Abuse and Protecting Seniors Act of 2015</b></p> <p>This bill amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to: (1) authorize a Medicare prescription drug plan (PDP) sponsor to establish a drug management program under which the PDP sponsor may limit an at-risk beneficiary&rsquo;s access to coverage for frequently abused drugs to include only those drugs that are prescribed by selected prescribers and dispensed by selected pharmacies; and (2) require a PDP sponsor to have in place a utilization management tool to prevent drug abuse.</p> <p>With respect to a drug management program, a PDP sponsor must: (1) provide specified notice to a beneficiary who has been identified by the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid (CMS) as &ldquo;at-risk&rdquo; and consequently enrolled in the program; and (2) in selecting prescribers and dispensers, ensure that the beneficiary continues to have reasonable access to drugs. These determinations shall be subject to expedited reconsideration and appeal. A PDP sponsor must review and consider an at-risk beneficiary&rsquo;s preferences regarding prescriber and pharmacy selection.</p> <p>Certain individuals, including those receiving hospice care or residing in a long-term care facility, are exempted from enrollment in a drug management program.</p> <p>CMS must, for purposes of quality or performance assessments, review and consider complaints received from at-risk beneficiaries regarding lack of access due to their enrollment in a drug management program. In addition, CMS must establish rules and procedures requiring a PDP sponsor to provide specified program data.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
