<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2884" measure-id="id114s2884" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-04-28" update-date="2016-08-18">
<title>EPA Accountability in Flint Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2884v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-08-18">
<action-date>2016-04-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>EPA Accountability in Flint Act</strong></p> <p>This bill makes the Federal Tort Claims Act exemption inapplicable to any claim brought against the federal government relating to an act or omission of, exercise or performance of, or failure to exercise or perform a discretionary function or duty by, the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) relating to the lead contamination of the drinking water of the city of Flint, Michigan, between April 1, 2014, and the date on which the EPA determines that the drinking water of the city complies with federal standards.</p> <p>A civil action relating to the EPA's conduct in relation to such contamination must be commenced within 10 years after the cause of action accrues.</p> <p> Any award against, or compromise settlement by, the government relating to the EPA's conduct in relation to such contamination shall be paid out of unobligated balances in the Environmental Programs And Management account.</p> <p>The EPA shall work with any affected state or local government to implement a program for the long-term monitoring of the quality of Flint's drinking water in response to such contamination.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
