<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2046" measure-id="id114s2046" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-09-17" update-date="2016-06-03">
<title>A bill to authorize the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission to issue an order continuing a stay of a hydroelectric license for the Mahoney Lake hydroelectric project in the State of Alaska, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2046v80" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-06-03">
<action-date>2015-12-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to Senate without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p>(Sec. 1)This bill requires the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC), upon request of the City of Saxman, Alaska, to issue a stay of the statutory deadline by which the city must commence construction on the Mahoney Lake Hydroelectric Project located in Ketchikan Gateway Borough, Alaska.</p> <p>In addition, upon request, FERC must reinstate the construction license and make it effective as of the date the stay is lifted.</p> <p>Subject to certain conditions, FERC is required to extend for up to six years the statutory deadline by which the city must commence construction on the project.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114s2046v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-06-03">
<action-date>2015-09-17</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill requires the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC), upon request of the City of Saxman, Alaska, to issue a stay of the statutory deadline by which the city must commence construction on the Mahoney Lake Hydroelectric Project located in Ketchikan Gateway Borough, Alaska.</p> <p>In addition, upon request, FERC must reinstate the construction license and make it effective as of the date the stay is lifted.</p> <p>Subject to certain conditions, FERC is required to extend for up to six years the statutory deadline by which the city must commence construction on the project.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
