<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1326" measure-id="id114s1326" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-13" update-date="2015-12-09">
<title>Maritime Administration Enhancement Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1326v01" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-12-09">
<action-date>2015-10-27</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to Senate amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Maritime Administration Enhancement Act of 2015</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill revises:</p> <ul> <li>the licensing and service requirements for U.S. Merchant Marine Academy cadet commitment agreements, and </li> <li>requirements for U.S. Merchant Marine Academy student incentive payment agreements related to licensing, the service commitment, and the circumstances under which an individual may be ordered to active duty.</li> </ul> <p>(Sec. 3) Payments to individuals may be modified if the total amount of payments to an individual does not exceed $32,000. </p> <p>(Sec. 4) The Internal Revenue Code is amended to reflect the transfer of the Maritime Administration from the Department of Commerce to the Department of Transportation. </p> <p>(Sec. 5) The definition of "short sea transportation" shall include carriage by a documented vessel of cargo that is: (1) shipped in discrete units or packages that are handled individually, palletized, or unitized for purposes of transportation; or (2) freight vehicles carried aboard commuter ferry boats. </p> (Sec. 6) The national security aspects of the U.S. Merchant Marine are reauthorized through FY2017.]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114s1326v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-11-23">
<action-date>2015-05-13</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Maritime Administration Enhancement Act of 2015</b></p> <p>This bill revises:</p> <ul> <li>the licensing and service requirements for U.S. Merchant Marine Academy cadet commitment agreements, and </li> <li>requirements for U.S. Merchant Marine Academy student incentive payment agreements related to licensing, the service commitment, and the circumstances under which an individual may be ordered to active duty.</li> </ul> <p>Payments to individuals may be modified if the total amount of payments to an individual does not exceed $32,000. </p> <p>The Internal Revenue Code is amended to reflect the transfer of the Maritime Administration from the Department of Commerce to the Department of Transportation. </p> <p>The definition of "short sea transportation" shall include carriage by a documented vessel of cargo that is: (1) shipped in discrete units or packages that are handled individually, palletized, or unitized for purposes of transportation; or (2) freight vehicles carried aboard commuter ferry boats. </p> The national security aspects of the U.S. Merchant Marine are reauthorized through FY2017.]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
