<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2122" measure-id="id114s2122" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-10-01" update-date="2015-12-11">
<title>Invest in Our Communities Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2122v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-12-11">
<action-date>2015-10-01</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Invest in Our Communities Act</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to: (1) exempt spouses and children of EB-5 investor immigrants from worldwide employment-based immigration limits, and (2) revise the fiscal year worldwide level of employment-based immigrant admissions.</p> <p>EB-5 visas are excluded from per country caps.</p> <p>EB-5 visas shall be made available to qualified immigrants who participate in a regional center program in the United States designated by the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) for the promotion of economic growth, including: (1) increased exports, (2) improved regional productivity, (3) job creation, and (4) increased domestic capital investment. </p> <p>A regional center shall: (1) have jurisdiction over a specific geographic area, which shall be consistent with the purpose of concentrating pooled investment in defined economic zones; and (2) certify compliance with U.S. securities laws, and supervise all offers, purchases, and sales of securities made by associated parties to ensure securities compliance. </p> <p>DHS shall establish a procedure for pre-approval of new commercial enterprises. </p> <p>Any person subject to the suspension or termination of EB-5 rights made under the discretion of DHS may appeal such decision and be entitled to a hearing before an administrative law judge. </p> <p>No person may be involved with a regional center as its principal, administrator, owner, officer, board member, manager, executive, general partner, fiduciary, or other similar position of significant authority for the operations or management of the center if he or she: (1) is not a U.S. national or lawful permanent resident; or (2) has been found liable for certain financial or securities crimes, or terrorist, espionage, or human trafficking activities.</p> <p>The bill sets forth DHS suspension or termination authority for a noncomplying regional center. </p> <p>The child of an alien investor whose conditional permanent resident status is terminated shall continue to be considered a child for purposes of a subsequent immigrant petition by the alien investor if the child remains unmarried and the subsequent petition is filed within one year after termination of status. An alien shall not be considered a child with respect to more than 1 petition filed after he or she reaches 21 years old.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
