<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1211" measure-id="id114s1211" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-06" update-date="2015-06-02">
<title>A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide that payment under the Medicare program to a long-term care hospital for inpatient services shall not be made at the applicable site neutral payment rate for certain discharges involving severe wounds, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1211v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-06-02">
<action-date>2015-05-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to prohibit payment at the applicable site neutral payment rate for discharges in a cost reporting period beginning before October 1, 2017, from subsection (d) hospitals and certain long-term care hospitals that involve certain severe wounds.</p> <p>(Generally, a subsection [d] hospital is an acute care hospital, particularly one that receives payments under Medicare's inpatient prospective payment system when providing covered inpatient services to eligible beneficiaries.)</p> <p>The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall study the treatment needs of individuals entitled to benefits under Medicare part A (Hospital Insurance), or enrolled under Medicare part B (Supplementary Medical Insurance), requiring specialized wound care, and the cost, for such individual, and the Medicare program of treating severe wounds in rural and urban areas.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
