<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2769" measure-id="id114s2769" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-04-07" update-date="2016-08-08">
<title>A bill to require the Federal Aviation Administration to establish minimum standards for space for passengers on passenger aircraft.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2769v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-08-08">
<action-date>2016-04-07</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill requires the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) to prohibit any air carrier that transports passengers by aircraft as a common carrier for compensation from reducing the size, width, padding, or pitch of seats; the amount of leg room per seat; or the width of aisles on such aircraft.</p> <p>The FAA must prescribe regulations: (1) establishing minimum standards for space for the safety, health, and comfort of aircraft passengers; and (2) requiring each air carrier to prominently display on its website the amount of space available for each passenger on aircraft it operates. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
