<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1327" measure-id="id114s1327" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-13" update-date="2015-07-28">
<title>SALTS Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1327v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-07-28">
<action-date>2015-05-13</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Synthetic Abuse and Labeling of Toxic Substances Act of 2015 or the SALTS Act</b></p> <p>Amends the Controlled Substances Act to authorize evidence related to the following factors to be considered in determining whether a controlled substance analogue was intended for human consumption: </p> <ul> <li>the marketing, advertising, and labeling of the substance; </li> <li>the known efficacy or usefulness of the substance for the marketed, advertised, or labeled purpose; </li> <li>the difference between the price at which the substance is sold and the price at which the substance it is purported to be or advertised as is normally sold; </li> <li>the diversion of the substance from legitimate channels and the clandestine importation, manufacture, or distribution of the substance; and</li> <li>whether the defendant knew or should have known that the substance was intended to be consumed by injection, inhalation, ingestion, or any other immediate means. </li></ul> <p>Declares that the existence of evidence that a substance was not marketed, advertised, or labeled for human consumption shall not preclude the government from establishing, based on all the evidence, that the substance was intended for human consumption.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
