<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1287" measure-id="id114s1287" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-12" update-date="2015-08-26">
<title>Viral Hepatitis Testing Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1287v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-08-26">
<action-date>2015-05-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Viral Hepatitis Testing Act of 2015</b></p> <p>Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to carry out hepatitis B (HBV) and hepatitis C (HCV) virus infection surveillance, education, and testing programs.</p> <p>Requires HHS to establish a national system regarding HBV and HCV infections, with its goals being to:</p> <ul> <li>determine the prevalence of infections,</li> <li>increase the number of individuals tested and made aware of their status,</li> <li>develop and disseminate public information and education programs,</li> <li>improve the training of health professionals, and</li> <li>provide referrals for counseling and medical treatment and ensure the provision of follow-up services.</li> </ul> <p>Directs HHS to determine the populations that are considered at high risk for HBV or HCV infection.</p> <p>Requires HHS to develop benchmarks for activities conducted under the Action Plan for the Prevention, Care, &amp; Treatment of Viral Hepatitis.</p> <p>Directs HHS to establish and support public-private partnerships that facilitate HBV and HCV surveillance, education, screening, testing, and linkage to care programs.</p> <p>Requires the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality to convene the U.S. Preventive Services Task Force every three years to review its recommendation for HBV and HCV screening.</p> <p>Directs the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to provide certain veterans with an HBV and HCV risk assessment, and, as needed, an evaluation and information regarding their need for treatment, vaccination, or other therapy.</p> <p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
