<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="920" measure-id="id114s920" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-04-14" update-date="2015-05-20">
<title>Military Spouse Job Continuity Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s920v80" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-05-20">
<action-date>2015-04-14</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to Senate without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p><strong>Military Spouse Job Continuity Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow the spouse of a member of the Armed Forces (military spouse) who moves with such member to another state under a permanent change of station order a tax credit for up to $500 of qualified relicensing costs incurred by such spouse for each change of duty station. Defines "qualified relicensing costs" as costs for a state license or certification to engage in the profession that such military spouse engaged in while residing in the former state and which are paid or incurred during the period beginning when the relocation order is issued and ending one year after the reporting date specified in such order. Requires a reduction in the amount of such credit by any tax deduction or other credit allowed for qualified relicensing costs. Makes this tax credit effective for taxable years beginning after 2014. </p> <p>(Sec. 3) Increases from 30% to 40% the rate of the continuous levy on payments to Medicare providers and suppliers for unpaid taxes, effective for payments made after 180 days after the enactment of this Act. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114s920v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-05-20">
<action-date>2015-04-14</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Military Spouse Job Continuity Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow the spouse of a member of the Armed Forces (military spouse) who moves with such member to another state under a permanent change of station order a tax credit for up to $500 of qualified relicensing costs incurred by such spouse. Defines "qualified relicensing costs" as costs for a state license or certification to engage in the profession that such military spouse engaged in while residing in the former state. </p> <p>Increases from 30% to 40% the rate of the continuous levy on payments to Medicare providers and suppliers for unpaid taxes.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
