<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1555" measure-id="id114s1555" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-06-11" update-date="2016-07-25">
<title>Filipino Veterans of World War II Congressional Gold Medal Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1555v82" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-07-25">
<action-date>2016-07-13</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed Senate without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p><strong>Filipino Veterans of World War II Congressional Gold Medal Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 3) This bill defines "Filipino Veterans of World War II" to include an individual who served: </p> <ul> <li> honorably at any time from July 26, 1941, to December 31, 1946; </li> <li> in an active-duty status under the command of the U.S. Armed Forces in the Far East; and </li> <li> within the Philippine Commonwealth Army, the Philippine Scouts, the Philippine Constabulary, Recognized Guerrilla units, the New Philippine Scouts, the First Filipino Infantry Regiment, the Second Filipino Infantry Battalion (Separate), or the First Reconnaissance Battalion; or<br /></li> <li>commanding or serving in such a unit as a U.S. military officer or enlisted soldier.</li> </ul> <p>(Sec. 4) The President pro tempore of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives shall make appropriate arrangements for the award of a single Congressional Gold Medal to the Filipino Veterans of World War II in recognition of their dedicated service during World War II. </p> <p> The medal, following its award, shall be given to the Smithsonian Institution where it will be available for research and display.</p> <p> It is the sense of Congress that the Smithsonian Institution should make the gold medal available for display elsewhere, particularly at other appropriate locations associated with the Filipino Veterans of World War II.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114s1555v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-08-12">
<action-date>2015-06-11</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Filipino Veterans of World War II Congressional Gold Medal Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>Directs the President pro tempore of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives to make appropriate arrangements for the award of a single Congressional Gold Medal to the Filipino Veterans of World War II in recognition of their dedicated service during World War II. </p> <p>Requires that the medal, following its award, be given to the Smithsonian Institution where it will be available for research and for display at other appropriate locations associated with such veterans.</p>  <ul> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
