<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2617" measure-id="id114s2617" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-03-02" update-date="2016-06-17">
<title>MANIFEST for Human Spaceflight Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2617v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-06-17">
<action-date>2016-03-02</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Mapping a New and Innovative Focus on Our Exploration Strategy for Human Spaceflight Act of 2016 or the MANIFEST for Human Spaceflight Act of 2016</b></p> <p>This bill amends the National Aeronautics and Space Administration Authorization Act of 2010 to make it a key U.S. objective to achieve human exploration of Mars, including the establishment of a capability to extend human presence to the surface of Mars. </p> <p>The National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) shall report a strategy to achieve such objective through a series of successive, sustainable, free-standing, but complementary missions making robust use of cislunar space and employing the Space Launch System, Orion crew capsule, and other capabilities provided under specified titles of the Act. </p> <p>NASA shall arrange with the National Academy of Sciences (NAS) to review and comment on each interim report on the strategy and identify matters the NAS agrees with and matters raising NAS concerns, as well as any NAS recommendations.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
