<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2888" measure-id="id114s2888" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-04-28" update-date="2016-08-18">
<title>Janey Ensminger Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2888v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-08-18">
<action-date>2016-04-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Janey Ensminger Act of 2016</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Public Health Service Act to direct the Agency for Toxic Substances and Disease Registry, at least every three years, to: </p> <ul> <li>review the scientific literature relevant to the relationship between the employment or residence of individuals at Camp Lejeune, North Carolina, for at least 30 days during the period of August 1, 1953, to December 21, 1987, and specific illnesses or conditions incurred by those individuals and determine whether and to what extent the evidence shows that toxic substance exposure is a cause of an illness or condition; and </li> <li>publish and update a list of each illness and the categorization of evidence for which a determination of cause has been made.</li> </ul> <p>A veteran who served on active duty at Camp Lejeune for at least 30 days during such period is eligible for hospital care and medical services for any of the illnesses or conditions for which the evidentiary connection between toxic exposure and the illness or condition is categorized in such list as sufficient or modest. Such a veteran who has been furnished hospital care or medical services shall remain eligible for such care or services for such illness or condition even if the evidentiary connection is not categorized as sufficient or modest. A family member of such veteran who has been furnished hospital care or medical services shall remain eligible for hospital care or medical services for such illness or condition. </p> <p>The Department of Veterans Affairs shall transfer for each of FY2017 and FY2018 specified finds to enhance the claims processing system, eligibility system, and web portal for the Camp Lejeune Family Member Program.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
