<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1425" measure-id="id114s1425" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-21" update-date="2016-08-01">
<title>Promoting New Manufacturing Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1425v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-08-01">
<action-date>2015-05-21</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Promoting New Manufacturing Act</b></p> <p> This bill requires the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to publish on its website, with respect to FY2008 and each fiscal year thereafter, estimates of:</p> <ul> <li> the total number of preconstruction permits issued by the EPA under the Clean Air Act's New Source Review Program for the construction or modification of a major stationary source (any stationary facility or source of air pollutants which directly emits, or has the potential to emit, 100 tons per year or more of any regulated air pollutant);</li> <li>the percentage of permits issued within one year of the application; and </li> <li>the average length of time for the EPA's Environmental Appeals Board to decide appeals of decisions to grant or deny a permit.</li> </ul>  <p>A new or revised national ambient air quality standard (NAAQS) may not apply to the review and disposition of a preconstruction permit application until the EPA publishes final implementation regulations and guidance that include information relating to submission and consideration of a preconstruction permit application under the standard.</p> <p>The EPA must submit annually a report on actions to expedite the process for review of preconstruction permits.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
