<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2114" measure-id="id114s2114" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-10-01" update-date="2015-11-02">
<title>A bill to correct inconsistencies in the definitions relating to Native Americans in the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2114v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-11-02">
<action-date>2015-10-01</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill amends title I (Quality, Affordable Health Care for All Americans) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act to add a definition of &ldquo;Indian.&rdquo; This definition includes individuals of Indian descent who are members of an Indian community served by the Indian Health Service and individuals considered by the Department of Health and Human Services to be Indian for purposes of eligibility for Indian health care services, including California Indians, Eskimos, Aleuts, or other Alaska Natives. </p> <p>Individuals included in the above definition are eligible for special monthly enrollment periods on health insurance exchanges and elimination of cost-sharing under individual health coverage for those whose income is not more than 300% of the poverty line. (Currently, only members of Indian tribes are eligible for these benefits.)</p> <p>Indians are exempted from the penalty for not maintaining minimum essential health coverage.</p> <p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
