<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="915" measure-id="id114s915" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-04-14" update-date="2015-06-30">
<title>Real Estate Investment and Jobs Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s915v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-06-30">
<action-date>2015-04-14</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Real Estate Investment and Jobs Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code, with respect to the taxation of stock interests of foreign investors, to: (1) increase from 5% to 10% the stock ownership threshold in a&nbsp;real estate investment trust (REIT)&nbsp;for exempting such stock from treatment&nbsp;as a U.S. real property interest on disposition, (2) increase from from 10% to 15% the rate of withholding of tax on dispositions of U.S. real property interests, (3) require a corporation to notify the Department of the Treasury of its status as a U.S. real property holding corporation and to disclose such status on payee statements, (4) impose a penalty on a corporation for failing to make such disclosure, (5) require brokers who sell stock of a U.S. real property holding corporation to a foreign person to withhold 15% of the amount realized on the sale, and (6) deny dividends derived from regulated investment companies and REITs the tax deduction for the U.S.-sourced portion of such dividends received from a foreign-owned corporation.</p> <p>The bill also increases from 30% to 35% the rate of the continuous levy on payments to Medicare providers and suppliers for unpaid taxes.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114s915v80" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-06-29">
<action-date>2015-04-14</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to Senate without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p><strong>Real Estate Investment and Jobs Act of 2015 </strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This section increases from 5% to 10% the stock ownership threshold in a real estate investment trust (REIT) for exempting such stock as a U.S. real property interest on disposition. </p> <p>(Sec. 3) This section provides for an increase from 10% to 15% of the rate of withholding of tax on dispositions of U.S. real property interests. </p> <p>(Sec. 4) This section requires any corporation that is a U.S. real property holding company during a specified period to disclose such status to the Internal Revenue Service, the corporation's shareholders, and the public. The corporation is subject to penalties for failure to make such a disclosure. </p> <p>(Sec. 5) This section requires a broker to deduct and withhold a tax equal to 15% of the amount realized on the disposition of stock of a U.S. real property holding company by a foreign person.</p> <p>(Sec. 6) This provision exempts regulated investment companies (RICs) and REITs from tax rules governing the treatment of stock of a domestic corporation as a U.S. real property holding company. </p> <p>(Sec. 7) This section provides that neither RICs nor REITs shall not be treated as domestic corporations for purposes of determining whether dividends from a foreign corporation are eligible for the tax deduction for the U.S-sourced portion of such dividends. </p> <p>(Sec. 8) This section increases from 30% to 35% the rate of the continuous levy on payments made after 180 days after the enactment of this Act to Medicare providers and suppliers for unpaid taxes. <br> </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
