<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="834" measure-id="id114s834" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-03-23" update-date="2016-10-11">
<title>Sport Fish Restoration and Recreational Boating Safety Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s834v01" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-10-11">
<action-date>2015-07-23</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to Senate amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Sport Fish Restoration and Recreational Boating Safety Act</b></p> <p>(Sec. 3) This bill amends the Dingell-Johnson Sport Fish Restoration Act to reauthorize the Sport Fish Restoration and Boating Trust Fund through FY2023.</p> <p>The bill revises the formula used to distribute funds from the trust fund. Amounts are set aside through FY2023 for Coast Guard recreational boating safety personnel and activities and the National Recreational Boating Survey.</p> <p>(Sec. 4) The bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to extend trust fund transfer restriction exceptions until October 1, 2023.</p> <p>(Sec. 5) The bill revokes a limitation on the amount the Coast Guard is authorized to allocate for national boating safety activities of national nonprofit public service organizations.</p> <p>(Sec. 7) The National Boating Safety Advisory Council is extended through FY2023.</p> <p>(Sec. 8) The bill amends the Coastal Wetlands Planning, Protection and Restoration Act to require the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers to report on the effectiveness of coastal wetlands restoration projects in improving the quality of fish and wildlife habitat conditions in Louisiana.</p> <p>(Sec. 9) The U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service must evaluate and report its administrative services for the trust fund each year.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114s834v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-04-19">
<action-date>2015-03-23</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Sport Fish Restoration and Recreational Boating Safety Act</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Dingell-Johnson Sport Fish Restoration Act to establish the formula for allocating through FY2023 appropriations from the Sport Fish Restoration and Boating Trust Fund.</p> <p>The formula increases the allocation for coastal wetlands planning, protection, and restoration while decreasing the allocation for boating safety. It also limits funding that may be used under the Clean Vessel Act for capital improvement and infrastructure projects to support facilities that meet state requirements for minimizing the introduction of pollutants into waterways.</p>  <p>The formula and requirements for allocating funds for administrative expenses are modified. </p> <p> Amounts are set aside through FY2023 for recreational boating safety personnel and activities, the National Boating Safety Advisory Council, boating safety activities of national nonprofit public service organizations, and the National Recreational Boating Survey.</p>  <p> The bill revokes a limitation on the amount the Coast Guard is authorized to allocate for national boating safety activities of national nonprofit public service organizations.</p> <p>The advisory council is extended through FY2023.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
