<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2978" measure-id="id114s2978" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-05-25" update-date="2016-06-02">
<title>Protect Continuing Physician Education and Patient Care Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2978v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-06-02">
<action-date>2016-05-25</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Protecting Continuing Physical Education and Patient Care Act</b></p> <p> This bill amends title XI (General Provisions, Peer Review, Administrative Simplification) of the Social Security Act to exempt from required manufacturer transparency reporting to the Department of Health and Human Services any transfer of value to a covered recipient of peer-reviewed journals, journal reprints, journal supplements, conference reports, and medical textbooks that directly benefit patients or are intended for patient use.</p> <p>The bill also excludes from such mandatory reporting any indirect payment or transfer of value to a covered recipient who is a physician:</p> <ul> <li>for speaking at, or preparing educational materials for, an educational event for physicians or other health care professionals that does not commercially promote a covered drug, device, biological, or medical supply; or</li> <li>that serves the sole purpose of providing the physician with medical education, such as the tuition required to attend an educational event or any materials given physicians at such an event.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
