<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1995" measure-id="id114s1995" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-08-05" update-date="2015-09-28">
<title>Outdoor Recreation Legacy Partnership Grant Program Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1995v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-09-28">
<action-date>2015-08-05</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Outdoor Recreation Legacy Partnership Grant Program Act of 2015</b></p> <p>This bill directs the Department of the Interior to establish an outdoor recreation legacy partnership grant program under which Interior awards grants to eligible entities (the states, their political subdivisions, special purpose districts, and Indian Tribes) for projects to: (1) acquire land and water for parks and other outdoor recreation purposes, and (2) develop new or renovate existing outdoor recreation facilities. </p> <p>As a condition for receiving a grant, an eligible entity shall provide matching funds in cash or in kind equal to 100% of the amounts available under the grant. </p> <p>A grant recipient may use the grant to acquire land or water providing outdoor recreation opportunities to the public.</p> <p>A grant may also be used to develop or renovate outdoor recreational facilities, with priority given to projects that: </p> <ul> <li>create or significantly enhance access to park and recreational opportunities in an urban neighborhood or community;</li> <li>engage and empower underserved communities and youth;</li> <li>provide opportunities for youth employment or job training;</li> <li>establish or expand public-private partnerships;</li> <li>take advantage of coordination among various levels of government. </li> </ul> <p>Grant funds may not be used for specified costs, facilities, and activities, including the acquisition of lands or interests that restrict access to particular persons.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
