<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1503" measure-id="id114s1503" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-06-04" update-date="2015-09-03">
<title>Lyme and Tick-Borne Disease Prevention, Education, and Research Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1503v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-09-03">
<action-date>2015-06-04</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Lyme and Tick-Borne Disease Prevention, Education, and Research Act of 2015</b></p> <p>This bill requires the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to establish the Tick-Borne Diseases Advisory Committee to advise HHS on how to: (1) ensure coordination with other federal agencies, private organizations, and constituency groups regarding efforts to address Lyme disease and other tick-borne diseases; (2) ensure that a broad spectrum of scientific viewpoints is considered in public health policy decisions and that information disseminated to the public and physicians is based on the best available science; and (3) advise federal agencies on priorities related to tick-borne diseases.</p> <p>HHS must coordinate federal activities related to tick-borne diseases and conduct or support activities related to tick-borne diseases, including:</p> <ul> <li>developing diagnostic tools and tests,</li> <li>improving the efficient utilization of diagnostic tests,</li> <li>surveillance and reporting,</li> <li>providing and promoting access to a clearinghouse of information,</li> <li>increasing public education,</li> <li>creating a physician education program on the latest research and treatment options for Lyme disease,</li> <li>research on tick repellents and strategies for the control of ticks,</li> <li>exploring the potential for vaccines,</li> <li>establishing epidemiological research objectives, and</li> <li>determining the effectiveness of different treatments. </li> </ul> <p>HHS must report on scientific conferences that cost the federal government more than $100,000 and address tick-borne diseases.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
