<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="869" measure-id="id114s869" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-03-26" update-date="2015-05-05">
<title>All-of-the-Above Federal Building Energy Conservation Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s869v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-05-05">
<action-date>2015-03-26</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>All-Of-The-Above Federal Building Energy Conservation Act of 2015 </strong></p> <p> Amends the National Energy Conservation Policy Act to extend energy performance requirements for federal buildings in FY2016-FY2017 (from a 33% reduction from 2003 energy consumption level for FY2016 to a 36% reduction for FY2017).</p> <p>Requires the Department of Energy (DOE) to review the results of the implementation of such requirements by December 31, 2017 (currently, December 31, 2014) and, based on such review, report to Congress on the feasibility of requiring each agency to apply energy conservation measures to, and improve the design for the construction of, agency buildings to achieve a reduction in energy consumption. </p> <p>Requires designated facility energy managers to consider using a system to manage energy use at their facilities in accordance with the International Organization for Standardization standard numbered 50001 and entitled &quot;Energy Management Systems.&quot;</p> <p>Establishes exemptions from energy and water evaluation requirements. </p> <p> Amends the Energy Conservation and Production Act to revise the definition of &quot;federal building&quot; to include buildings altered by federal agencies, and to define &quot;major renovation,&quot; for purposes of such Act. Requires DOE to establish revised federal building energy efficiency performance standards after the approval of revisions of ASHRAE Standard 90.1 or the International Energy Conservation Code (IECC) to meet or exceed such revisions, including requiring, unless new or renovated federal buildings are demonstrated not to be life-cycle cost effective: (1) such buildings to be designed to achieve energy consumption levels that are at least 30% below the levels established in the ASHRAE Standard or the IECC, and (2) no less than 30% of the hot water demand for each new building or building undergoing a major renovation to be met through the installation and use of solar hot water heaters. </p> <p>Requires DOE to review federal building energy standards once every five years and upgrade to the standards to include all new energy efficiency and renewable energy measures that are technologically feasible and economically justified if DOE determines that significant energy savings would result. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
