<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2492" measure-id="id114s2492" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-02-03" update-date="2016-03-18">
<title>Encouraging Americans to Save Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2492v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-03-18">
<action-date>2016-02-03</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Encouraging Americans to Save Act </strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to expand the tax credit for retirement savings contributions to: (1) make such credit refundable; (2) allow individual taxpayers (excluding dependents and full-time students) who have attained age 18 as of the close of the taxable year a credit for 50% of their retirement savings contributions up to $1,000; (3) increase the maximum income threshold for determining eligibility for the credit; and (4) allow direct deposit of credit amounts into the taxpayer's retirement savings vehicle (e.g., MyRA or Roth IRA account). </p> <p>The Department of the Treasury shall educate taxpayers on the benefits of the credit for retirement savings contributions. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
