<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2456" measure-id="id114s2456" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-01-20" update-date="2016-09-29">
<title>Dynamic Repayment Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2456v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-09-29">
<action-date>2016-01-20</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Dynamic Repayment Act of 2016 </b></p> <p>This bill amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 to replace several existing federal student loan programs with a single repayment plan that caps annual debt repayments based on income and forgives remaining balances after 20 or 30 years of payments. </p> <p>The bill terminates the authority of the Department of Education (ED) to make federal Direct Stafford Loans, Direct Unsubsidized Stafford Loans, and Direct PLUS loans, subject to exceptions for existing student borrowers, PLUS loans made to parents of undergraduates, and Direct Consolidation Loans. </p> <p>To replace the programs, the bill establishes the Income Dependent Education Assistance (IDEA) Loan Program and the IDEA Loan Repayment Program, which: </p> <ul> <li> limit annual repayments based on the borrower's income; </li> <li> forgive remaining balances after either 20 or 30 years of payments, depending on the amount of the loan; and </li> <li>prohibit the accrual of interest on loans for active duty service members. </li> </ul> <p>The bill amends the Social Security Act (SSAct) to require ED and the Department of Health and Human Services to exchange information necessary to use the National Directory of New Hires to assist in the collection of student loans. </p> <p>The bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) require the Department of the Treasury to disclose to ED tax return information necessary to carry out the IDEA Loan Repayment Program, and (2) to exclude loan forgiveness under the program from gross income. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
