<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1430" measure-id="id114s1430" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-21" update-date="2016-11-04">
<title>Marine Oil Spill Prevention Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1430v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-11-04">
<action-date>2015-05-21</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Marine Oil Spill Prevention Act</b></p> <p>This bill address issues related to preventing and responding to oil spills.</p>  <p>This bill amends the Gulf of Mexico Energy Security Act of 2006 to extend the moratorium on oil and gas leasing in certain areas in the Gulf of Mexico until June 30, 2027.</p> <p>This bill sets forth provisions concerning Coast Guard responsibilities, including designating areas that are at heightened risk of oil spills and implementing measures to ameliorate that risk. </p> <p> This bill amends the Oil Pollution Act of 1990 to establish a Gulf Coast Regional Citizens' Advisory Council to advise on facilities and tank vessels. </p>   <p> This bill makes an owner of oil responsible for oil spill cleanup. Currently, owners of oil are only responsible if the oil is being transported in a single-hull vessel.</p> <p>This bill amends the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act to permit the Coast Guard or the Department of Commerce to request a National Transportation Safety Board investigation of any accident occurring in the Outer Continental Shelf (OCS). </p> <p>Commerce must establish an inspection fee for OCS facilities for the cost of inspections of facilities and other duties.</p> <p>This bill requires a comprehensive review of the capacity of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) to respond to oil spills. NOAA must develop and maintain oil spill trajectory modeling capability.</p>  <p></s></p>     <p> <p>The Coast Guard must evaluate and validate oil pollution containment and removal methods and technologies.</p> <p>NOAA must carry out long-term marine environment monitoring and research program for the Gulf of Mexico.</p> <p>The bill requires the Coast Guard to publish within 12 hours an Incident Action Plan in response to an oil spill.</p>  <p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
