<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="878" measure-id="id114s878" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-03-26" update-date="2016-04-20">
<title>A bill to establish a State residential building energy efficiency upgrades loan pilot program.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s878v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-04-20">
<action-date>2015-03-26</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill amends the Energy Policy and Conservation Act to require the Department of Energy (DOE) to establish a voluntary loan program to provide support to a state, territory, and tribal organization (eligible entity) in establishing or expanding programs that provide financing to residential property owners or tenants (recipient households) for energy efficiency upgrades of residential buildings.</p> <p>DOE must establish favorable terms for a loan provided to an eligible entity. An eligible entity shall use a loan to establish or expand one or more financing programs that: (1) enable recipient households to undertake residential energy efficiency upgrades, (2) may require an outlay of capital by recipient households, and (3) incorporate a consumer-friendly repayment approach. </p>  <p>To offset the cost of this bill, the bill amends the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007 to decrease the authorization of appropriations for the Zero Net Energy Commercial Buildings Initiative for FY2016-FY2018.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
