<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="37" measure-id="id114s37" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-01-06" update-date="2015-01-16">
<title>Core Opportunity Resources for Equity and Excellence Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s37v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-01-16">
<action-date>2015-01-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Core Opportunity Resources for Equity and Excellence Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>Amends the school improvement program under part A of title I of the the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (ESEA) to require states to adopt student achievement standards that lead to college and career readiness by high school graduation.</p> <p>Requires each state school improvement plan to ensure that the state's public school system enables students to meet those standards by providing them with fair and equitable access to the core resources for learning. </p> <p>Includes among the core resources for learning:</p> <ul> <li>high-quality instructional teams;</li> <li>rigorous academic standards and curricula that lead to college and career readiness by high school graduation;</li> <li>equitable and instructionally appropriate class sizes;</li> <li>up-to-date instructional materials, technology, and supplies;</li> <li>effective school library programs;</li> <li>school facilities and technology, including physically and environmentally sound school buildings and well-equipped instructional spaces;</li> <li>specialized instruction support teams providing assessment, diagnosis, counseling, educational, therapeutic, and other necessary services as part of a comprehensive program to meet student needs; and </li> <li>effective programs to engage families and the community in education.</li> </ul> <p>Prohibits states that fail to make progress toward eliminating inequities in access to the core resources for learning for two or more consecutive years from receiving funds under any competitive grant program authorized by the ESEA.</p> <p>Requires the annual report cards publicly disseminated by states and their local educational agencies (LEAs) to include information on the performance of LEAs and schools in providing students with fair and equitable access to the core resources for learning.</p> <p>Requires states to identify any of their LEAs as needing improvement if they: (1) fail for two consecutive years to make adequate yearly progress toward state academic content and achievement standards, or (2) have received a waiver of the ESEA's statutory or regulatory requirements from the Secretary of Education. </p> <p>Requires states to: (1) identify any inequities in access to the core resources of learning in schools served by an LEA that has been identified as needing improvement, and (2) work with the LEA to address those inequities.</p> <p>Prohibits the Secretary from waiving this Act's requirements for accountability in providing students with access to the core resources for learning.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
