<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2972" measure-id="id114s2972" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-05-23" update-date="2016-08-26">
<title>GRANT Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2972v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-08-26">
<action-date>2016-05-23</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Grant Reform and New Transparency Act of 2016 or the GRANT Act</strong></p> <p>This bill directs the Office of Management and Budget to upgrade any public website for finding federal grant opportunities to: (1) serve as a central point of information on, and provide full access for applicants to, competitive grants; and (2) capture in one site, or provide electronic links to, other relevant databases.</p> <p>Executive agencies shall post on such website: (1) a clear statement of the purpose, duration, and eligibility requirements of the grant and, for merit-based grants, a description of the manner in which applications or proposals will be evaluated, ranked, and selected; (2) agency contacts and application deadlines; and (3) copies of each proposal that resulted in a grant award, the final grant agreement, and selection documentation and justification. Under certain circumstances, agencies may limit postings to proposal abstracts or executive summaries, redact personally identifiable information, and exclude sensitive information about critical infrastructure.</p> <p>Agencies must evaluate: (1) the ability of the applicant to carry out the grant, manage funds according to accepted cost accounting principles, and comply with federal fund recipient reporting requirements; (2) the past performance and integrity of the applicant; (3) whether the applicant has received other federal funds; and (4) any interagency duplication of efforts for research grants.</p> <p> Agencies must post a forecast of all non-emergency grant solicitations the agency expects to issue for the upcoming calendar year.</p> <p>Upon an applicant's request, an agency must explain the basis for an award decision of a grant exceeding $100,000 pursuant to a merit-based selection procedure.</p> <p>Inspectors General shall review the effectiveness of agency conflicts of interest policy with respect to the peer review process for competitive grants in order to detect favoritism.</p> <p>The Government Accountability Office shall report on the size and training of the federal grants workforce, on whether a warrant system similar to that used in the federal acquisition system should be established for federal officials authorized to award grants, and on recommendations for improving such workforce.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
