<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2342" measure-id="id114s2342" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-12-02" update-date="2016-07-18">
<title>Territories Medicare Prescription Drug Assistance Equity Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2342v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-07-18">
<action-date>2015-12-02</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Territories Medicare Prescription Drug Assistance Equity Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>This bill amends titles XVIII (Medicare) and XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to make certain subsidies available to Medicare prescription drug program beneficiaries who reside in Puerto Rico or&nbsp;another U.S. territory. Current law makes&nbsp;such beneficiaries ineligible for premium and cost-sharing subsidies, but&nbsp;establishes a process for&nbsp;U.S. territories&nbsp;to apply&nbsp;for financial assistance with respect to the provision of Medicare prescription drugs. The bill eliminates&nbsp;this process and makes the subsidies available to beneficiaries who reside in a&nbsp;U.S. territory&nbsp;and are otherwise eligible. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
