<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="393" measure-id="id114s393" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-02-05" update-date="2015-07-02">
<title>Berryessa Snow Mountain National Monument Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s393v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-07-02">
<action-date>2015-02-05</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Berryessa Snow Mountain National Monument Act</b></p> <p> Establishes the Berryessa Snow Mountain National Monument, to consist of federal land and interests in federal land within Napa, Lake, Mendocino, Solano, Glenn, Colusa, and Yolo counties in California. </p>  <p>Continues to provide historical and adequate access to private inholdings in the Monument. </p> <p> <p>Requires a comprehensive plan for the protection and management of the federal land included within the Monument. Requires such plan to: (1) include a weed management component, (2) include a native fish passage and habitat quality improvement component, and (3) include a component that addresses public safety and environmental clean-up issues associated with illegal marijuana production. </p> <p>Permits grazing in the Conservation Area: (1) to continue, if established before this Act's enactment; (2) if not established before enactment, only to the extent that it is consistent with the purposes for which the Monument was established; or (3) through issuing annual targeted permits for the control of noxious weeds, fire suppression, or to provide other ecological benefits. </p> <p>Establishes the Berryessa Snow Mountain National Monument Advisory Council to advise with respect to the preparation and implementation of the management plan. Requires the appointment of one Council member to represent Indian tribes. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
