<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2522" measure-id="id114s2522" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-02-09" update-date="2016-11-04">
<title>A bill to amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to build partnerships to prevent violence by extremists.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2522v01" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-11-04">
<action-date>2016-07-11</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to Senate amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(Sec. 1) This bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to establish within the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) the Office for Partnerships Against Violent Extremism (OPAVE), to be headed by an Assistant Secretary.</p> <p>The Assistant Secretary shall be responsible for:</p> <ul> <li>leading DHS efforts to counter violent extremism;</li> <li>developing a digital engagement strategy that expands DHS outreach efforts to counter violent extremist messaging by exploring ways to utilize relevant technologies and social media platforms and maximizing other resources available to DHS;</li> <li>serving as DHS's primary representative in coordinating countering violent extremism efforts with other federal agencies and nongovernmental organizations;</li> <li>serving as the primary DHS-level representative in coordinating with the Department of State on international countering violent extremism issues;</li> <li>providing guidance, in coordination with the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), regarding the use of grants made to state, local, and tribal governments under the allowable uses guidelines related to countering violent extremism; and</li> <li>developing a plan to expand philanthropic support for domestic efforts related to countering violent extremism. </li> </ul> <p>DHS shall submit to Congress a comprehensive DHS strategy and an implementation plan to counter violent extremism in the United States.</p> <p>The Assistant Secretary must submit an annual report on the OPAVE, which shall include:</p> <ul> <li>a description of the status of the programs and policies of DHS for countering violent extremism in the United States;</li> <li>a description of OPAVE efforts to cooperate with and provide assistance to other federal agencies;</li> <li>qualitative and quantitative metrics for evaluating the success of such programs and policies;</li> <li>an accounting of grants and cooperative agreements awarded by DHS to counter violent extremism and all training specifically aimed at countering violent extremism sponsored by DHS;</li> <li>an analysis of how DHS's activities to counter violent extremism correspond and adapt to the threat environment;</li> <li>a summary of how civil rights and liberties are protected in DHS activities to counter violent extremism;</li> <li>an evaluation of the use of State Homeland Security Grant Program (SHSGP) and Urban Area Security Initiative (UASI) grants and cooperative agreements awarded to support efforts of local communities to counter violent extremism; and</li> <li>a description of how the OPAVE incorporated lessons learned from the countering violent extremism programs and policies of foreign, state, local, tribal, and territorial governments and stakeholder communities.</li> </ul> <p> DHS's Office for Civil Rights and Civil Liberties shall conduct annual reviews to ensure that all OPAVE activities related to countering violent extremism respect the privacy, civil rights, and civil liberties of all persons. </p> <p>The bill prohibits the use of funds provided under the SHSGP or the UASI to support any organization or group that has knowingly or recklessly funded domestic or international terrorism or that is known to engage in or recruit to such activities.</p> <p>This bill shall be repealed seven years after its enactment.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114s2522v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-03-29">
<action-date>2016-02-09</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to establish within the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) the Office for Partnerships Against Violent Extremism (the Office), to be headed by an Assistant Secretary.</p> <p>The Assistant Secretary shall be responsible for:</p> <ul> <li>leading DHS efforts to counter violent extremism;</li> <li>developing a digital engagement strategy that expands DHS outreach efforts to counter violent extremist messaging by exploring ways to utilize relevant technologies and social media platforms and maximizing other resources available to DHS;</li> <li>serving as DHS's primary representative in coordinating countering violent extremism efforts with other federal agencies and nongovernmental organizations;</li> <li>serving as the primary DHS-level representative in coordinating with the Department of State on international countering violent extremism issues;</li> <li>providing guidance, in coordination with the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), regarding the use of grants made to state, local, and tribal governments under the allowable uses guidelines related to countering violent extremism;</li> <li>developing a plan to expand philanthropic support for domestic efforts related to countering violent extremism; and</li> <li>administering grants to counter violent extremism.</li> </ul> <p>The Assistant Secretary, in coordination with FEMA and the Officer for Civil Rights and Civil Liberties of DHS, shall establish, and provide an implementation plan for, a grant program to assist eligible community groups and organizations in establishing counter-messaging campaigns targeting violent extremism and to strengthen community programs to counter violent extremism. </p> <p>The Secretary of DHS shall submit to Congress a comprehensive DHS strategy and an implementation plan to counter violent extremism in the United States.</p> <p>The Assistant Secretary must submit annual reports on DHS and Office programs, policies, and efforts to counter violent extremism. The Office for Civil Rights and Civil Liberties shall conduct annual reviews to ensure that all Office activities related to countering violent extremism respect the privacy, civil rights, and civil liberties of all persons.</p> <p>This Act shall be repealed seven years after its enactment.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
