<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2405" measure-id="id114s2405" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-12-15" update-date="2016-02-22">
<title>METH Disclosure Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2405v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-02-22">
<action-date>2015-12-15</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Meth Exposure to the Home Disclosure Act or the METH Disclosure Act</b></p> <p>This bill directs the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD), in coordination with the Environmental Protection Agency and any other federal agency with knowledge of methamphetamine-based hazards, to promulgate regulations meeting certain criteria for the disclosure of methamphetamine-based hazards in housing (other than newly constructed or never occupied housing) offered for sale or lease.</p> <p>&quot;Methamphetamine-based hazard&quot; means any condition that causes exposure to any hazardous substance, pollutant, or contaminant associated with the manufacture of methamphetamine that would result in adverse human health effects.</p> <p>HUD may carry out necessary investigations, and any U.S. district court within the jurisdiction of which one is carried out may issue orders for compliance with it.</p> <p>The bill prescribes civil money penalties for violations of this Act.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
