<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="634" measure-id="id114s634" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-03-03" update-date="2015-03-31">
<title>Disaster Assistance Fairness and Accountability Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s634v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-03-31">
<action-date>2015-03-03</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Disaster Assistance Fairness and Accountability Act of 2015</b></p> <p>Amends the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to prohibit the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) from taking any actions to recoup from a recipient assistance provided in relation to a major disaster declared by the President on or after January 1, 2012, if: (1) the recipient's application was made in good faith and provided accurate information and the receipt of such assistance could reasonably have been expected by the recipient, or (2) the receipt of such assistance occurred more than three years before FEMA first notifies the recipient of FEMA's intent to recoup. </p> <p>Requires FEMA, in carrying out a recoupment of disaster assistance that is not prohibited under this Act, to provide documentation that demonstrates that the recipient did not apply in good faith with accurate information or could not reasonably have expected to receive such assistance.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
