<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1784" measure-id="id114s1784" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-07-16" update-date="2015-08-24">
<title>Federal Prisons Accountability Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1784v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-08-24">
<action-date>2015-07-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Federal Prisons Accountability Act of 2015 </b> </p> <p>This bill amends the federal criminal code to require the Director of the Bureau of Prisons to be appointed by the President and confirmed by the Senate. Currently, the Director is appointed by the Attorney General. <br /></p> <p> <p class="MsoNormal">The bill permits continued service by the incumbent Director for three months after the date of enactment. The President may appoint that individual to be the Director of the Bureau of Prisons in accordance with the requirements of this Act. <br /></p> </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
