<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2130" measure-id="id114s2130" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-10-05" update-date="2015-10-27">
<title>An Act Making Appropriations for National Security and for Other Purposes, 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2130v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-10-27">
<action-date>2015-10-05</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>An Act Making Appropriations for National Security and for Other Purposes, 2016 </b></p> <p>Provides FY2016 appropriations for the Department of Defense, energy and water development, the Department of Homeland Security, military construction, the Department of Veterans Affairs, the Department of State, foreign operations, and related programs. </p> <p><i>Department of Defense Appropriations Act, 2016 </i></p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Department of Defense (DOD) for military activities, including:</p> <ul> <li> Military Personnel; </li> <li>Operation and Maintenance; </li> <li>Procurement; </li> <li>Research, Development, Test, and Evaluation; </li> <li>Revolving and Management Funds; </li> <li>Other Department of Defense Programs; </li> <li>Related Agencies; and </li> <li>Overseas Contingency Operations. </li> </ul> <p><i>Energy and Water Development and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2016</i> </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers for civil works projects and to the Department of the Interior for the Central Utah Project and the Bureau of Reclamation. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Department of Energy (DOE) for Energy Programs, including: </p> <ul> <li>Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy, </li> <li>Electricity Delivery and Energy Reliability, </li> <li>Nuclear Energy, </li> <li>Fossil Energy Research and Development, </li> <li>Non-Defense Environmental Cleanup, and </li> <li>Science. </li> </ul> <p>Provides appropriations to DOE for: </p> <ul> <li>the Atomic Energy Defense Activities of the National Nuclear Security Administration, </li> <li>Environmental and Other Defense Activities, and </li> <li>the Power Marketing Administrations. </li> </ul> <p>Provides appropriations to the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission and other independent agencies. </p> <p><i>Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2016 </i></p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Department of Homeland Security. </p> <p>Provides appropriations for Departmental Management and Operations for the Office of the Secretary and Executive Management, the Office of the Under Secretary for Management, the Office of the Chief Financial Officer, the Office of the Chief Information Officer, Analysis and Operations, and the Office of Inspector General. </p> <p>Provides appropriations for Security, Enforcement, and Investigations for the U.S. Customs and Border Protection, the U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement, the Transportation Security Administration, the U.S. Coast Guard, and the U.S. Secret Service. </p> <p>Provides appropriations for Protection, Preparedness, Response, and Recovery for the National Protection and Programs Directorate, the Office of Health Affairs, and the Federal Emergency Management Agency. </p> <p>Provides appropriations for Research, Development, Training, and Services for the U.S. Citizen and Immigration Services, the Federal Law Enforcement Training Center, Science and Technology, and the Domestic Nuclear Detection Office. </p> <p><i>Military Construction, Veterans Affairs, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2016 </i></p> <p>Provides appropriations to DOD for Military Construction for the Army; Navy and Marine Corps; Air Force; Defense-Wide agencies and activities (other than military departments); the Army and Air National Guard; and the Army, Navy, and Air Force Reserves. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to DOD for the North Atlantic Treaty Organization Security Investment Program. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to DOD for Construction and Operation and Maintenance of Family Housing for the Army, Navy and Marine Corps, Air Force, and Defense-Wide agencies and activities (other than military departments). </p> <p>Provides appropriations for the Department of Defense Base Closure Account. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Department of Veterans Affairs for the Veterans Benefits Administration, the Veterans Health Administration, the National Cemetery Administration, and Departmental Administration. </p> <p>Provides appropriations for the American Battle Monuments Commission, the U.S. Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims, Cemeterial Expenses of the Army, and the Armed Forces Retirement Home. </p> <p><i>Department of State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 2016</i> </p> <p>Provides appropriations to the Department of State for Administration of Foreign Affairs, International Organizations, International Commissions, Related Agencies and Programs, and Other Commissions. </p> <p>Provides appropriations for the U.S. Agency for International Development. </p> <p>Provides appropriations for Bilateral Economic Assistance, International Security Assistance, Multilateral Assistance, Export and Investment Assistance, and Overseas Contingency Operations. </p> <p>Sets forth permissible, restricted, and prohibited uses for funds provided by this and other appropriations Acts. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
