<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="3245" measure-id="id114s3245" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-07-14" update-date="2016-09-15">
<title>Title VIII Nursing Workforce Reauthorization Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s3245v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-09-15">
<action-date>2016-07-14</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Title VIII Nursing Workforce Reauthorization Act of 2016</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Public Health Service Act to extend through FY2021 support for nursing workforce programs and grants.</p> <p>Eligibility for advanced nursing education grants is expanded to include education programs for clinical nurse leaders and all combined registered nurse and graduate degree programs. (Clinical nurse leaders are advanced generalist clinicians who apply research and coordinate care in order to improve outcomes for patients.) To be eligible for these grants, clinical nurse specialist programs must provide registered nurses with full-time clinical nurse specialist education that qualifies the nurses to provide a full range of care.</p> <p>Programs for loan repayment and scholarships for nurses, loans for nursing faculty, and geriatric care education are extended through FY2021. Grants for increasing nursing workforce diversity are also extended through FY2021.</p> <p>Nurse education, practice, and quality grants are extended through FY2021 and eligibility is expanded to include nurse-managed health clinics.</p> <p>Grants for nursing career ladder programs are expanded to: (1) promote career advancement for individuals to become registered nurses or advanced education nurses; and (2) support internships and residency programs to encourage mentoring and the development of specialties.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
