<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2909" measure-id="id114s2909" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-05-10" update-date="2016-11-02">
<title>CAPTIVE Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2909v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-11-02">
<action-date>2016-05-10</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p> <b>Clarifying Amendment to Provide Terrorism Victims Equity Act or the CAPTIVE Act</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Terrorism Risk Insurance Act of 2002 regarding the blocked assets of a terrorist party which shall be subject to execution or attachment in aid of execution in order to satisfy a judgment based upon an act of terrorism in an action brought by or on behalf of the person obtaining the judgment.</p> <p>The bill redefines &quot;blocked asset&quot; to include any asset seized or frozen by the United States under the Foreign Narcotics Kingpin Designation Act. </p> <p>The bill also defines a &quot;person&quot; who has obtained such a judgment as a natural person who, at the time the act of terrorism was committed upon which the judgment was obtained, was:</p> <ul> <li>a national of the United States;</li> <li>a member of the U.S. Armed Forces; or</li> <li>otherwise an employee of the federal government, or of a federal government contractor, acting within the scope of employment.</li> </ul> <p>If the person described is deceased, the personal representative of the estate of that deceased person shall count as the person.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
