<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="985" measure-id="id114s985" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-04-16" update-date="2015-04-28">
<title>United States Coast Guard Commemorative Coin Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s985v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-04-28">
<action-date>2015-04-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>United States Coast Guard Commemorative Coin Act</b></p> <p> Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to mint and issue in commemoration of the United States Coast Guard: (1) $5 gold coins, (2) $1 silver coins, and (3) half-dollar clad coins. </p> <p>Requires the design of such coins to be emblematic of the traditions, history, and heritage of the Coast Guard, and its role in securing our nation since 1790. </p> <p>Prescribes design requirements. </p> <p>Restricts the issuance of such coins to the one-year period beginning on January 1, 2018.</p> <p>Prescribes the sale price of the coins and coin surcharges. Requires such surcharges to be paid by the Secretary to the National Coast Guard Museum Association to help finance the design and construction of the National Coast Guard Museum.</p> <p>Directs the Secretary to ensure that minting and issuing coins under this Act will not result in any net cost to the federal government.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
