<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1731" measure-id="id114s1731" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-07-09" update-date="2015-12-08">
<title>Homeless Veterans Services Protection Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1731v35" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-12-08">
<action-date>2015-10-29</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed Senate amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Homeless Veterans Services Protection Act of 2015</strong></p> <p> (Sec. 2) This bill eliminates the minimum continuous active duty service requirement for homeless veterans to receive certain benefits, including: (1) outreach, (2) rehabilitative services, (3) vocational counseling and training, (4) transitional housing assistance, (5) supportive services for very low-income veteran families in permanent housing, and (6) health care for homeless veterans with special needs.</p> <p>(Sec. 3) Homeless veterans are exempted from disqualification for such benefits because of discharge or dismissal from the Armed Forces under conditions other than honorable, except for discharge by reason of a general court-martial. </p> <p>(Sec. 4) Veteran is defined for purposes of such benefits as a person who served in the active military, naval, or air service, regardless of length of service, and who was discharged or released therefrom, except for a person who: (1) received a dishonorable discharge, or (2) was discharged or dismissed by reason of a general court-martial.</p> <p> (Sec. 5) The Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) shall conduct related training and education for appropriate VA and grant recipient personnel.</p> <p>(Sec. 6) Services for which a homeless veteran receives a grant under the VA comprehensive service programs for homeless veterans may include furnishing care for a dependent under the veteran's care. </p> <p>(Sec. 7) The VA shall prescribe implementing regulations within 270 days. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114s1731v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-11-04">
<action-date>2015-07-09</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Homeless Veterans Services Protection Act of 2015</strong></p> <p> This bill eliminates the minimum continuous active duty service requirement for homeless veterans to receive certain benefits, including: (1) outreach, (2) rehabilitative services, (3) vocational counseling and training, (4) transitional housing assistance, (5) supportive services for very low-income veteran families in permanent housing, and (6) health care for homeless veterans with special needs.</p> <p>Homeless veterans are exempted from disqualification for such benefits because of discharge or dismissal from the Armed Services under conditions other than honorable, except for discharge by reason of a general court-martial. </p> <p>Veteran is defined for purposes of such benefits as a person who served in the active military, naval, or air service, regardless of length of service, and who was discharged or released therefrom, except for a person who: (1) received a dishonorable discharge, or (2) was discharged or dismissed by reason of a general court-martial.</p> <p> The Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) shall conduct related training and education for appropriate VA and grant recipient personnel.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
