<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1233" measure-id="id114s1233" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-06" update-date="2015-06-17">
<title>PURPA PLUS Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1233v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-06-17">
<action-date>2015-05-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>PURPA's Legislative Upgrade to State Authority Act or the PURPA PLUS Act</b></p> <p>Amends the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978, with respect to Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) authority to prescribe rules requiring electric utilities to offer to sell and purchase electric energy to and from any qualifying cogeneration or small power production facility.</p> <p>Permits state regulatory authorities or nonregulated electric utilities, acting under state authority, to set rates exceeding the incremental cost of alternative electric energy for purchases from any such qualifying facility of up to two megawatts capacity. (Current law requires FERC to set rates that do not exceed the incremental cost to the electric utility of alternative electric energy.)</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
