<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2499" measure-id="id114s2499" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-02-04" update-date="2016-03-17">
<title>Health Savings Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2499v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-03-17">
<action-date>2016-02-04</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Health Savings Act of 2016</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code, with respect to the taxation of health savings accounts (HSAs), to: </p> <ul> <li>rename high deductible health plans as HSA-qualified health plans; </li> <li>allow spouses who have both attained age 55 to make increased catch-up contributions to the same HSA; </li> <li>make Medicare Part A (hospital insurance benefits) beneficiaries eligible to participate in an HSA;</li> <li>allow individuals eligible for hospital care or medical services under a medical care program of the Indian Health Service or of a tribal organization to participate in an HSA; </li> <li>allow individuals eligible to receive medical benefits under certain TRICARE plans to participate in an HSA;</li> <li>allow members of a health care sharing ministry to participate in an HSA; </li> <li>allow individuals who receive primary care services in exchange for a fixed periodic fee or payment, or who receive health care benefits from an onsite medical clinic of an employer, to participate in an HSA; </li> <li>include amounts paid for prescriptions and over-the-counter medicines or drugs as &quot;qualified medical expenses&quot; for which distributions from an HSA or an Archer Medical Savings Account may be used; and </li> <li>allow HSA distributions to be used to purchase health insurance coverage.</li> </ul> <p>The bill amends the federal bankruptcy code to exempt HSAs from creditor claims in bankruptcy. </p> <p>The bill amends the Social Security Act to reauthorize the use of Medicaid health opportunity accounts. </p> <p>The bill allows a medical care tax deduction for: (1) exercise equipment, physical fitness programs, and membership at a fitness facility; (2) nutritional and dietary supplements; and (3) periodic fees paid to a primary care physician and amounts paid for pre-paid primary care services. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
