<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="546" measure-id="id114s546" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-02-24" update-date="2016-08-05">
<title>RESPONSE Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s546v35" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-08-05">
<action-date>2016-05-09</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed Senate amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>RESPONSE Act of 2016</b></p> <p> (Sec. 2) This bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to direct the Federal Emergency Management Agency to establish the Railroad Emergency Services Preparedness, Operational Needs, and Safety Evaluation (RESPONSE) Subcommittee of the National Advisory Council.</p> <p>The RESPONSE Subcommittee shall develop recommendations, as appropriate, for improving emergency first responder training and resource allocation for hazardous materials (hazmat) incidents involving railroads after evaluating the following topics:</p> <ul> <li> the quality and application of training for local emergency first responders related to rail hazmat incidents, with a particular focus on local emergency responders and small communities near railroads;</li> <li>the effectiveness of funding levels related to training local emergency first responders for rail hazmat incidents, with a particular focus on local emergency first responders and small communities near railroads; and</li> <li>the strategy for integrating commodity flow studies, mapping, rail and hazmat databases and other relevant data for local emergency first responders and increasing the rate of access to the individual responder in existing or emerging communications technology.</li> </ul> <p>The RESPONSE Subcommittee shall terminate within four years after this bill's enactment, unless given a one-year extension.</p> <ul> <ul> </ul> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114s546v80" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-12-02">
<action-date>2015-07-21</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to Senate without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p><b>RESPONSE Act of 2015</b></p> <p> (Sec. 2) This bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to direct the Federal Emergency Management Agency to establish the Railroad Emergency Services Preparedness, Operational Needs, and Safety Evaluation (RESPONSE) Subcommittee of the National Advisory Council.</p> <p>The RESPONSE Subcommittee shall evaluate the following topics and develop recommendations, as appropriate, for improving emergency responder training and resource allocation for hazardous materials incidents involving railroads:</p> <ul> <li> the quality and application of training for local emergency first responders related to rail hazardous materials (hazmat) incidents, with a particular focus on local emergency responders and small communities near railroads;</li> <li>the effectiveness of funding levels related to training local emergency responders for rail hazmat incidents, with a particular focus on local emergency responders and small communities;</li> <li>a strategy for integration of commodity flow studies, mapping, and access platforms for local emergency responders and how to increase the rate of access to the individual responder in existing or emerging communications technology;</li> <li> the need for emergency response plans for rail, similar to existing law related to maritime and stationary facility emergency hazmat response plans;</li> <li> the need for a rail hazmat incident database;</li> <li> increasing access to relevant, useful, and timely information for the local emergency responder for training purposes and in the event of a rail hazmat incident; and </li> <li> determining the most appropriate agencies and offices for the implementation of the recommendations.</li> </ul> <p>The RESPONSE Subcommittee shall terminate within four years after this Act's enactment, unless given one-year extensions.</p> <ul> <ul> </ul> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114s546v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-03-10">
<action-date>2015-02-24</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>RESPONSE Act of 2015</b></p> <p> Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to direct the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency to establish the Railroad Emergency Services Preparedness, Operational Needs, and Safety Evaluation Subcommittee of the National Advisory Council.</p> <p>Directs the Subcommittee to evaluate the following topics and develop recommendations, as appropriate, for improving emergency responder training and resource allocation for hazardous materials incidents involving railroads:</p> <ul> <li> the quality and application of training for local emergency first responders related to rail hazardous materials incidents, with a particular focus on local emergency responders and small communities near railroads;</li> <li>the effectiveness of funding levels related to training local emergency responders for rail hazardous materials incidents, with a particular focus on local emergency responders and small communities;</li> <li>a strategy for integration of commodity flow studies, mapping, and access platforms for local emergency responders and how to increase the rate of access to the individual responder in existing or emerging communications technology;</li> <li> the need for emergency response plans for rail, similar to existing law related to maritime and stationary facility emergency response plans for hazardous materials;</li> <li> the need for a rail hazardous materials incident database;</li> <li> increasing access to relevant, useful, and timely information for the local emergency responder for training purposes and in the event of a rail hazardous materials incident; and </li> <li> determining the most appropriate agencies and offices for the implementation of the recommendations.</li> </ul> <p>Terminates the Subcommittee not later than four years after this Act's enactment, subject to one year extensions.</p> <ul> <ul> </ul> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
