<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="726" measure-id="id114s726" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-03-12" update-date="2015-03-27">
<title>Community Financial Protection Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s726v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-03-27">
<action-date>2015-03-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Community Financial Protection Act of 2015</b></p> <p> Amends the Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010 to require the Director of the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau (CFPB) to request reports through the prudential regulator from a person that is either an insured depository institution or an insured credit union with total assets of $10 billion or less (persons).</p> <p>Prohibits the Director from making such requests for an industry-wide report, or for a report pertaining to two or more such persons. </p> <p>Requires the Director, as a prerequisite to making such request, to make a showing to the prudential regulator that publicly available information pertaining to such person(s) is insufficient for the purposes of either: (1) supporting the role of the CFPB in implementing federal consumer financial laws; (2) supporting examination activities of the CFPB; or (3) risk assessment and detection concerning consumers and consumer financial markets.</p> <p>Authorizes the prudential regulator to deny any request for a report or information made by the Director with respect to such persons.</p> <p>Requires the prudential regulator who fulfills the Director's request for a report to do so with reports that have been furnished to a federal or state agency (or are required to have been furnished to a federal or state agency.</p> <p>Instructs the Director to accept existing reports in formats consistent with those submitted to the prudential regulator and federal and state agencies if the prudential regulator has determined that they provide the information requested.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
