<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1360" measure-id="id114s1360" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-18" update-date="2016-03-15">
<title>A bill to amend the limitation on liability for passenger rail accidents or incidents under section 28103 of title 49, United States Code, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1360v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-03-15">
<action-date>2015-05-18</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill revises the limitation on passenger rail transportation liability to increase from $200 million to $500 million, adjusted annually for inflation, the aggregate allowable awards to all rail passengers, against all defendants, for all claims, including any for punitive damages, arising from a single accident or incident.</p> <p>The Department of Transportation (DOT) must consider, within two years after enactment of this Act, whether to:</p> <ul> <li>make any needed additional adjustments to the liability cap; and</li> <li>establish or adjust mandatory coverage for Amtrak, any high-speed railroad authority or operator, any commuter authority or operator, any rail carrier, or any state (listed entities).</li> </ul> <p>The total minimum liability coverage Amtrak must maintain for claims through insurance and self-insurance shall increase from $200 million per accident or incident to $500 million, unless DOT, by regulation, determines that a different minimum level of financial responsibility is necessary or sufficient to satisfy claims.</p> <p>DOT may make a grant to Amtrak or another listed entity as a reasonable reimbursement, considering ability to meet increased costs and impacts on safety and service, to offset any incremental increase in the cost of insurance resulting from this Act.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
