<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2313" measure-id="id114s2313" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-11-19" update-date="2016-01-22">
<title>Philanthropic Facilitation Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2313v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-01-22">
<action-date>2015-11-19</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Philanthropic Facilitation Act </strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) expand the definition of, and requirements relating to, "program-related investments" made by private foundations to for-profit entities to further certain charitable purposes; (2) allow a judicial determination (i.e., declaratory judgment) as to whether investments in any entity qualify as program-related investments; (3) require expanded reporting by for-profit entities that receive program-related investments of their gross income, expenses, disbursements, and other information; and (4) allow public inspection of any petition seeking a determination that an investment by a private foundation is a program-related investment and of any information reported by organizations receiving program-related investments. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
