<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1390" measure-id="id114s1390" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-20" update-date="2015-07-07">
<title>Native American Indian Education Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1390v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-07-07">
<action-date>2015-05-20</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Native American Indian Education Act</b></p> <p> Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 to direct the Department of Education to pay institutions of higher education the out-of-state tuition of their Indian students if the schools are required to provide a tuition-free education, with the support of their state, to Native American Indian students in fulfillment of a condition under which the college or state received its original grant of land and facilities from the federal government.</p> <p>Limits that payment each fiscal year to the institution's total out-of-state tuition for Native American Indian students in academic year 2014-2015.</p> <p>Treats such payments as reimbursements to such institutions from their states.</p> <p>Rescinds unobligated discretionary appropriations to offset the costs of this program.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
