<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1672" measure-id="id114s1672" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-06-24" update-date="2015-10-07">
<title>Commercial Driver Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1672v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-10-07">
<action-date>2015-06-24</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Commercial Driver Act</b></p> <p>This bill directs the Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration to establish a test program to allow states to enter into interstate compacts with contiguous states, approved by the governor of each state, to standardize the requirements for drivers operating commercial motor vehicles in interstate commerce. </p> <p>A commercial driver's license issued by one state participating in a compact shall be recognized as valid in every state participating in the compact. </p> <p>Nothing in this Act may be construed to limit or change the authority to operate in interstate commerce for drivers over age 21, including by setting the minimum age requirement to receive a Class A commercial driver's license at age 18.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
