<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1288" measure-id="id114s1288" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-12" update-date="2015-07-15">
<title>Welfare Abuse Prevention Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1288v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-07-15">
<action-date>2015-05-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Welfare Abuse Prevention Act</b></p> <p>This bill amends part A (Temporary Assistance for Needy Families) (TANF) of title IV of the Social Security Act to require any state receiving a TANF block grant to maintain policies and practices to ensure that cash assistance disbursed through an electronic benefit transfer card or an electronic payment card shall not be used to withdraw more than $25 per day from an automated teller machine or through a cash-back procedure at a point of sale terminal.</p> <p>The Department of Health and Human Services shall reduce to $0 the state family assistance grant payable to any state which, within two years after enactment of this Act, has not reported on its implementation of this cash withdrawal limit or has not implemented such a limit.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
