<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2973" measure-id="id114s2973" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-05-23" update-date="2016-07-12">
<title>A bill to increase the micro-purchase threshold for universities, independent research institutes, and non-profit research organizations.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2973v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-07-12">
<action-date>2016-05-23</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill increases the micro-purchase threshold for activities by institutions of higher education, nonprofit research organizations, or independent research institutes under federal procurement contracts, grants, or cooperative agreements to: (1) $10,000; or (2) a higher threshold determined by the head of the relevant executive agency consistent with clean audit findings, internal institutional risk assessment, or state law. Micro-purchases at or below the threshold are exempt from certain: (1) requirements under the Small Business Act and contracting goals of the Department of Defense, the U.S. Coast Guard, or the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) to award contracts to small businesses owned and controlled by socially and economically disadvantaged individuals, historically black colleges and universities, or other minority institutions; (2) competitive quotation and price evaluation standards; and (3) Buy American requirements for the use of supplies manufactured in the United States.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
