<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="742" measure-id="id114s742" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-03-16" update-date="2016-04-25">
<title>Stop Wasteful Federal Bonuses Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s742v01" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-04-25">
<action-date>2016-03-14</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to Senate amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Stop Wasteful Federal Bonuses Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill prohibits a federal agency from awarding a bonus to any employee for five years after the end of a fiscal year in which the agency makes an adverse&nbsp;finding relating to the employee. An &quot;adverse finding&quot; is a determination that an employee's conduct violated: (1) a policy of the agency for which the employee may be removed or suspended for at least 14 days, or (2) a law for which the employee may be imprisoned for more than one year.</p> <p> The bill requires an agency to issue an order directing an employee to repay&nbsp;a bonus awarded in any year in which such a finding is made. As a condition of receiving a bonus awarded after this Act's enactment, an employee must certify that he or she shall repay the bonus in accordance with such an order. </p> <p>An employee deemed to be ineligible for a bonus or against whom a repayment order is issued may appeal to the Merit Systems Protection Board.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114s742v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-03-28">
<action-date>2015-03-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Stop Wasteful Federal Bonuses Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>Prohibits a federal agency from awarding a bonus to any employee for five years after the end of a fiscal year in which the Inspector General of the agency or another senior ethics official&nbsp;or the Comptroller General makes an adverse&nbsp;finding relating to the employee. Requires repayment of a&nbsp;bonus awarded in any year in which an adverse finding is made. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
