<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="383" measure-id="id114s383" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-02-05" update-date="2016-03-24">
<title>Indian Trust Asset Reform Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s383v01" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-03-24">
<action-date>2016-02-08</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to Senate amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Indian Trust Asset Reform Act</b></p> <p>TITLE I--RECOGNITION OF TRUST RESPONSIBILITY</p> <p> (Sec. 102) This bill reaffirms the federal government's fiduciary responsibilities to Indians.</p> <p>TITLE II--INDIAN TRUST ASSET MANAGEMENT DEMONSTRATION PROJECT</p> <p><em>Indian Trust Asset Management Demonstration Project Act of 2015</em></p> <p>(Sec. 203) The Department of the Interior must establish an Indian trust asset management demonstration project that allows tribes to propose Indian trust asset management plans. To be approved by Interior, these plans must establish objectives and priorities for trust assets and allocate sufficient funding for asset management to meet the objectives and priorities.</p> <p>(Sec. 205) Interior may approve a trust asset management plan that allows the Indian tribe to enter into, approve, and carry out a surface leasing transaction or forest land management activity without Interior's approval, under certain conditions.</p> <p>The United States is not liable for losses that result from: (1) a forest land management activity or lease under a trust asset management plan, or (2) management standards under a trust asset management plan that are less-stringent than Interior otherwise requires.</p> <p>TITLE III--IMPROVING EFFICIENCY AND STREAMLINING PROCESSES</p> <p> (Sec. 303) Interior may establish an Under Secretary for Indian Affairs who is to report directly to the Secretary of the Interior and coordinate with the Office of the Special Trustee for American Indians (OST) to ensure an orderly transition of the functions of the OST to an agency or bureau within Interior. </p> <p>(Sec. 304) Interior must prepare a transition plan and timetable for the termination of the OST.</p> <p>(Sec. 305) Appraisals and valuations of Indian trust property must be administered by a single administrative entity within Interior.</p> <p>Interior must establish minimum qualifications for individuals to prepare appraisals and valuations of Indian trust property. An appraisal or valuation by a qualified person is considered final without being reviewed or approved by Interior.</p> <p>(Sec. 306) Representatives of entities that advise Interior on Indian program budget or funding issues may make recommendations regarding the use of savings realized from the transfer of the functions of the OST.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114s383v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-07-02">
<action-date>2015-02-05</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Indian Trust Asset Reform Act</b></p> <p> Reaffirms the federal government's fiduciary responsibilities to Indians. </p> <p></p> <p> <em>Indian Trust Asset Management Demonstration Project Act of 2015</em></p> <p>Directs the Department of the Interior to establish a 10 year (but may be extended at Interior's discretion) Indian trust asset management demonstration project that allows Indian tribes to propose Indian trust asset management plans.</p> <p> Authorizes Interior to establish an Under Secretary for Indian Affairs who is to: (1) report directly to the Secretary of the Interior; (2) assume the functions of the Assistant Secretary for Indian Affairs; and (3) coordinate with the Special Trustee for American Indians to ensure an orderly transition of the functions of the Special Trustee to the Bureau of Indian Affairs, or to any other agency or bureau within Interior. </p> <p>Requires Interior to prepare a transition plan and timetable for the termination of the Office of Special Trustee for American Indians. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
