<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1807" measure-id="id114s1807" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-07-21" update-date="2015-10-26">
<title>RISE Small Business Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1807v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-10-26">
<action-date>2015-07-21</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Regulatory Impact Scale on the Economy Small Business Act of 2015 or the RISE Small Business Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>Requires a federal agency, before promulgating a proposed or final rule that it determines is likely to have an annual effect on the economy of at least $100 million, to assign the rule to, and publish in the Federal Register, the following category that applies based on the highest possible annual effect the agency determines the rule is likely to have on the economy: </p> <ul> <li>category 1 rule likely to result in an annual effect of between $100 million and $499,999,999; </li> <li> category 2 rule likely to result in an annual effect of between $500 million and $999,999,999; </li> <li> category 3 rule likely to result in an annual effect of between $1 billion and $4,999,999,999; </li> <li> category 4 rule likely to result in an annual effect of between $5 billion and $9,999,999,999; and </li> <li> category 5 rule likely to result in an annual effect of not less than $10 billion.</li> </ul> <p>Directs: (1) each agency to submit to the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs (OIRA) annually a list of the rules, by category, that the agency published during the preceding year; and (2) OIRA to publish each list and an estimate of the costs and benefits of each included rule on www.reginfo.gov.</p> <p>Defines &quot;significant economic impact&quot; for purposes of provisions concerning initial and final regulator flexibility analyses as an annual economic effect of at least $100 million.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
