<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1480" measure-id="id114s1480" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-06-02" update-date="2015-06-24">
<title>Lobbying and Campaign Finance Reform Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1480v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-06-24">
<action-date>2015-06-02</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Lobbying and Campaign Finance Reform Act of 2015 </b></p> <p> Amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (FECA) to declare that, for purposes of dollar limits on contributions, any bundled contribution forwarded by a currently registered lobbyist or a political committee established or controlled by one to an authorized committee of a candidate, a leadership political action committee, or a political party committee shall be treated as both a contribution made by the person forwarding it and as a contribution made by the contributor.</p> <p>Amends the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 to revise the definition of "lobbyist" with respect to its exemption from coverage of certain individuals whose lobbying activities constitute less than 20% of the time engaged in the services provided to a client over a 3-month period. Extends the 3-month period into a 2-year period.</p> <p>Amends FECA to prohibit House of Representatives and Senate candidates, Members, Senators, their agents, or any entities directly or indirectly established, financed, maintained, or controlled by or acting on behalf of one or more of them from soliciting funds from any registered lobbyist in connection with an election to the House or Senate during any period in which the chamber is in session (excluding adjournments or recesses for 10 calendar days or longer).</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
