<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="3128" measure-id="id114s3128" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-07-06" update-date="2016-10-13">
<title>American Red Cross Transparency Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s3128v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-10-13">
<action-date>2016-07-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>American Red Cross Transparency Act of 2016</strong></p> <p>This bill authorizes the Government Accountability Office (GAO) to review: (1) the internal governance of the American National Red Cross (the corporation); and (2) any program or activity carried out by the corporation that is connected to national preparedness.</p> <p>The bill grants the GAO: (1) access to, and the right to examine and copy, all records of the corporation that the GAO determines are relevant to such review; and (2) access to, and the right to interview, any employee, volunteer, agent, or member of the board of governors of the corporation whom the GAO believes has knowledge relevant to such review. The GAO may issue a subpoena and bring a civil action in U.S. District Court for the District of Columbia to enforce such access. </p> <p>The bill establishes an Office of Investigations, Compliance, and Ethics as a subcommittee of the corporation's Audit and Risk Management Committee. The office shall: (1) conduct formal investigations regarding fraud, waste, abuse, corporation policy violations, illegal or unethical conduct, or other wrongdoing relating to the corporation; and (2) report annually on trends and systemic matters confronting the corporation and on pending and completed investigations.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
