<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2134" measure-id="id114s2134" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-10-05" update-date="2015-10-15">
<title>Grow Our Own Directive: Physician Assistant Employment and Education Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2134v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-10-15">
<action-date>2015-10-05</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Grow Our Own Directive: Physician Assistant Employment and Education Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>This bill directs the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to carry out the Grow Our Own Directive or G.O.O.D. pilot program to provide educational assistance to certain former members of the Armed Forces for education and training as VA physician assistants. </p> <p>An individual is eligible to participate in the program if the individual: </p> <ul> <li>has medical or military health experience gained while serving in the Armed Forces; </li> <li>has received a certificate, associate degree, baccalaureate degree, master's degree, or postbaccalaureate training in a science relating to health care; </li> <li>has participated in the delivery of health care services or related medical services; and </li> <li>does not have a degree of doctor of medicine, doctor of osteopathy, or doctor of dentistry. </li> </ul> <p>The VA shall: </p> <ul> <li>provide educational assistance to program participants for the costs of obtaining a master's degree in physician assistant studies or a similar master's degree, </li> <li> ensure that mentors are available for program participants at each VA facility at which a participant is employed, and </li> <li>seek to partner with specified government programs and with appropriate educational institutions that offer degrees in physician assistant studies.</li> </ul> <p>The VA shall: </p> <ul> <li>establish specified standards to improve the education and and hiring of VA physician assistants, and </li> <li>implement a national plan for the retention and recruitment of VA physician assistants that includes the adoption of competitive pay standards. </li> </ul> <p>VA physician assistant pay grades are established.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
