<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2329" measure-id="id114s2329" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-11-19" update-date="2016-04-18">
<title>SECURE Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2329v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-04-18">
<action-date>2015-11-19</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Stop Extremists Coming Under Refugee Entry Act or the SECURE Act</strong></p> <p>This bill directs the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to notify each alien admitted as a refugee or asylee that he or she must register with and be interviewed and fingerprinted by DHS.</p> <p>DHS shall screen, perform a security review, and monitor all individuals seeking asylum or refugee status to ensure that they do not present a national security or terrorism risk. </p> <p>The Department of State may not approve a refugee application and DHS may not approve an asylum application for any national from the following high risk countries: </p> <ul> <li>Afghanistan, </li> <li>Algeria, </li> <li>Bahrain, </li> <li>Bangladesh, </li> <li>Egypt, </li> <li>Eritrea, </li> <li>Indonesia, </li> <li>Iran, </li> <li>Iraq, </li> <li>Jordan, </li> <li>Kazakhstan, </li> <li>Kuwait, </li> <li>Kyrgyzstan, </li> <li>Lebanon, </li> <li>Libya,</li> <li>Mali, </li> <li>Morocco, </li> <li>Nigeria,</li> <li>North Korea, </li> <li>Oman, </li> <li>Pakistan, </li> <li>Qatar, </li> <li>Russia, </li> <li>Saudi Arabia, </li> <li>Somalia, </li> <li>Sudan, </li> <li>Syria,</li> <li>Tajikistan, </li> <li>Tunisia, </li> <li>Turkey, </li> <li>United Arab Emirates, </li> <li>Uzbekistan, </li> <li>Yemen, or </li> <li>the Palestinian Territories. </li> </ul> <p>This moratorium may be lifted when specified conditions are met.</p> <p>DHS, in cooperation with the State Department, shall ensure that any new visa application is not approved: (1) for at least 30 days, and (2) until completion of an enhanced security screening.</p> <p>Unless otherwise permitted under this Act, DHS, in cooperation with the State Department, shall ensure that no alien enters the United States until after 30 days of security assessments have been conducted, regardless of whether or not the alien's country of origin is a visa waiver country.</p> <p>DHS may approve qualified applicants for enrollment in the global entry trusted traveler program regardless of the applicant's nationality or country of habitual residence. </p> <p>DHS may not approve any application for U.S. entry from an alien (other than a trusted traveler) who is a national of, or who is applying from, a high-risk country until: (1) completion of the congressional review process, and (2) enactment of a law authorizing termination of the visa moratorium.</p> <p>DHS, the State Department, and the Director of National Intelligence shall certify jointly to Congress that: (1) a national security screening process has been implemented that significantly improves the government's ability to identify security risks posed by aliens from high-risk countries, (2) the biometric entry-exit control system has been implemented, and (3) a policy has been implemented to remove aliens who have overstayed their period of lawful U.S. presence. </p> <p>In order to carry out 100% land exit tracking, DHS shall integrate the records collected through the automated entry-exit control system into an interoperable data system and any other database necessary to correlate an alien's entry and exit data.</p> <p>DHS may not: </p> <ul> <li>process travel documents of U.S. citizens (with certain exceptions) while documenting the departure of outbound individuals at each land point of entry along the Southern or Northern border; or </li> <li>designate an outbound U.S. citizen for secondary inspection or collect biometric information from a U.S. citizen under outbound inspection procedures unless criminal or other prohibited activity has been detected or is strongly suspected. </li> </ul> <p>An individual shall not be permitted to leave the United States if, during outbound inspection, DHS detects previous unresolved criminal activity by the individual. </p> <p>Any individual in asylum status, refugee status, legal permanent resident status, or any other permanent or temporary visa status who: </p> <ul> <li>intends to remain in the United States in such status for longer than six months shall submit to DHS a signed affidavit stating that the alien has not voted in any federal election, and will not register to vote or vote in any such election while in such status; or </li> <li>illegally registers to vote or votes in any federal election after receiving such status or visa shall not be eligible to apply for permanent residence or citizenship, or shall lose permanent residence status if ready granted it and be subject to deportation.</li> </ul> <p>State and local governments: </p> <ul> <li>shall require individuals registering to vote in federal elections to provide proof of citizenship, </li> <li>may not accept an affirmation of citizenship as proof of citizenship for voter registration purposes, and </li> <li>may require identification information from voter registration applicants.</li> </ul> <p>Beginning one year after admission, a refugee or asylee: (1) is ineligible for assistance under specified federal means-tested programs, and (2) may not claim the earned income tax credit. An alien who applies for and receives such assistance or who claims and is allowed such credit shall be permanently prohibited from U.S. naturalization.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
