<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2258" measure-id="id114s2258" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-11-09" update-date="2016-04-08">
<title>Surface Transportation Project Delivery Program Improvement Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2258v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-04-08">
<action-date>2015-11-09</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Surface Transportation Project Delivery Program Improvement Act</b></p> <p>This bill revises requirements for any written agreement under the surface transportation project delivery program that a state makes with the Department of Transportation (DOT) to assume responsibilities assigned by DOT with respect to one or more highway projects within the state under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969.</p> <p>Such an agreement shall emphasize that the state is solely responsible and liable for carrying out DOT responsibilities, including the defense of any civil action, without further DOT approval, under the program.</p> <p>DOT shall:</p> <ul> <li>audit a participating state annually (currently, semiannually) for the first two as well as the last two years of the first four years of a state's particiaption;</li> <li>meet with the state to review implementation of its assignment agreement, and discuss plans for the first annual audit, within 180 days after execution of the agreement; and</li> <li>ensure that the time period for completing an annual audit, from initiation to completion (including public comment and responses to those comments), does not exceed 180 days.</li> </ul> <p>DOT shall also determine the team to carry out an audit, which shall include at least one member the state designates (who may have relevant expertise and experience and not be an employee of either the state or DOT).</p> <p> In cooperation with the American Association of State Highway and Transportation Officials, DOT shall carry out education, training, peer exchange, and other initiatives to:</p> <ul> <li>assist states in developing the capacity to participate in the assignment program, and</li> <li>promote information sharing and collaboration among states participating in the program.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
