<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="922" measure-id="id114s922" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-04-14" update-date="2015-06-16">
<title>Corporate Tax Dodging Prevention Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s922v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-06-16">
<action-date>2015-04-14</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Corporate Tax Dodging Prevention Act </strong></p> <p> Amends the Internal Revenue Code, with respect to the taxation of the foreign-source income of domestic corporations, to:</p> <ul> <li> eliminate the deferral of tax on the foreign-source income of U.S. corporations for taxable years beginning after December 31, 2015; </li> <li> deny the foreign tax credit to large integrated oil companies that are dual capacity taxpayers; </li> <li> limit the offset of the foreign tax credit to income that is subject to U.S. tax;</li> <li> treat foreign corporations managed and controlled in the United States as domestic corporations for U.S. tax purposes;</li> <li>limit the tax deduction of the interest expense of a U.S. corporation that is a member of a financial reporting group (i.e., a group that prepares consolidated financial statements according to generally accepted accounting principles or international financial reporting standards); and </li> <li> revise rules for the taxation of inverted corporations (i.e., U.S. corporations that acquire foreign companies to reincorporate in a foreign jurisdiction with income tax rates lower than the United States) to provide that a foreign corporation that acquires the properties of a U.S. corporation or partnership after May 8, 2014, shall be treated as an inverted corporation and thus subject to U.S. taxation if, after such acquisition it holds more than 50% of the stock of the new entity (expanded affiliated group).</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
