<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1240" measure-id="id114s1240" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-07" update-date="2015-09-21">
<title>Cerros del Norte Conservation Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1240v01" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-09-21">
<action-date>2015-09-09</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to Senate amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Cerros del Norte Conservation Act</b></p> <p> (Sec. 3) Designates the Cerro del Yuta Wilderness (comprising approximately 13,420 acres) and Rio San Antonio Wilderness (comprising approximately 8,120 acres) within the Rio Grande del Norte National Monument in New Mexico as wilderness and as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System. </p>  <p>Sets forth requirements for the management of the wilderness areas regarding: (1) livestock grazing, (2) the creation of protective perimeters and buffer zones, and (3) the jurisdiction of the state of New Mexico respecting fish and wildlife located on public land in New Mexico. </p> <p>Releases specified public land within the San Antonio Wilderness Study Area not designated as wilderness by this Act from further study for such a designation.</p> <p>Requires the wilderness areas to be administered as components of the National Landscape Conservation System.</p> <p>Withdraws any federal land within the wilderness areas, including any acquired land or interest, from: (1) entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws; (2) location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and (3) operation of the mineral leasing, mineral materials, and geothermal leasing laws.</p> <p>Denies that anything in this Act enlarges, diminishes, or otherwise modifies any treaty rights. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114s1240v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-07-01">
<action-date>2015-05-07</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Cerros del Norte Conservation Act</b> <p>Designates the Cerro del Yuta Wilderness (comprising approximately 13,420 acres) and Rio San Antonio Wilderness (comprising approximately 8,000 acres) within the Rio Grande del Norte National Monument in New Mexico as wilderness and as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System. <times/> <p>Releases specified public land within the San Antonio Wilderness Study Area not designated as wilderness by this Act from further study for such a designation.</p> <p>Requires the wilderness areas to be administered as components of the National Landscape Conservation System.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
