<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="3295" measure-id="id114s3295" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-09-07" update-date="2016-10-04">
<title>National Cybersecurity Preparedness Consortium Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s3295v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-10-04">
<action-date>2016-09-07</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>National Cybersecurity Preparedness Consortium Act of 2016</b></p> <p>This bill authorizes the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to work with a consortium, including the National Cybersecurity Preparedness Consortium, to support efforts to address cybersecurity risks and incidents, including threats or acts of terrorism.</p> <p>DHS may work with such a consortium to assist its national cybersecurity and communications integration center to:</p> <ul> <li>provide training to state and local first responders and officials, develop curriculums, and provide technical assistance; </li> <li>conduct cross-sector cybersecurity training and simulation exercises for state and local governments, critical infrastructure owners and operators, and private industry; </li> <li>help states and communities develop cybersecurity information sharing programs; and </li> <li>help incorporate cybersecurity risk and incident prevention and response into existing state and local emergency plans and continuity of operations plans. </p> </li></ul> <p>DHS's authority to carry out this bill terminates five years after its enactment.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
