<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="529" measure-id="id114s529" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-02-12" update-date="2015-03-16">
<title>Combating Human Trafficking Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s529v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-03-16">
<action-date>2015-02-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Combating Human Trafficking Act of 2015</b></p> <p><i>Enhancing Services for Runaway and Homeless Victims of Youth Trafficking Act of 2015</i></p> <p>Amends the Runaway and Homeless Youth Act with respect to grants to states, localities, and private entities to carry out research, evaluation, demonstration, and service projects regarding activities designed to increase knowledge concerning, and to improve services for, runaway youth and homeless youth.</p> <p>Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to give priority to proposed projects relating to staff training in:</p> <UL> <LI>the behavioral and emotional effects of severe forms of trafficking in persons and sex trafficking, <LI>responding to youth who are showing effects of severe forms of trafficking in persons and sex trafficking, and <LI>agency-wide strategies for working with runaway and homeless youth who are victims of trafficking. </LI> </UL> <p>Extends the Secretary's authority to make grants to nonprofit private agencies for the purpose of providing street-based services to runaway and homeless, and street youth, who have been subjected to, or are at risk of being subjected to, sexual abuse, prostitution, or sexual exploitation. Extends the scope of such grants also to street-based services to runaway and homeless, and street youth, who have been subjected to, or are at risk of being subjected to, severe forms of trafficking in persons and sex trafficking.</p> <p>Amends the Missing Children's Assistance Act to include among the required uses of the Office of Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention's annual grant to the National Center for Missing and Exploited Children operation of a cyber tipline to provide online users and electronic service providers an effective means of reporting Internet-related child sexual exploitation in the area of child sex trafficking, including child prostitution (currently, in the area of child prostitution).</p> <p><i>Human Trafficking Prevention and Recovery Act of 2015</i></p> <p>Requires the Interagency Task Force to Monitor and Combat Trafficking to review trafficking in persons in the United States.</p> <p>Directs the Comptroller General to report to Congress on: (1) the efforts of federal and state law enforcement agencies to combat human trafficking in the United States, and (2) each federal grant program one of whose purposes is to combat human trafficking or assist victims of trafficking.</p> <p>Amends the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 to include programs that provide housing to victims of trafficking among grant-receiving state, local, and tribal service programs for victims of trafficking.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
