<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="146" measure-id="id114s146" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-01-12" update-date="2015-07-23">
<title>Public Access to Public Land Guarantee Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s146v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-07-23">
<action-date>2015-01-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Public Access to Public Land Guarantee Act </b></p> <p> Directs the Department of the Interior or the Department of Agriculture, with respect to land under their respective jurisdictions, pursuant to a state or local government offer, to enter into an agreement under which the United States may accept funds from the state or local government to reopen any unit of the National Park System, the National Wildlife Refuge System, or the National Forest System within the state or local government during any period in which there is a lapse in appropriations for that unit.</p> <p>Makes such authority effective only during a period in which the department is unable to operate and manage covered units at normal levels. </p> <p>Requires the appropriate department to refund to the state or local government all amounts it provided to the United States under such an agreement: (1) upon enactment of an Act retroactively appropriating amounts sufficient to maintain normal operating levels at the reopened covered unit, or (2) on the date on which the state or local government establishes that the department collected entrance or user fees for the covered units during the period in which the agreement was in effect. </p> <p>Allows the appropriate department, if such refund requirements are not met, to reimburse the state or local government voluntarily for any amounts it provided to the United States under such an agreement. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
