<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="216" measure-id="id114s216" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-01-21" update-date="2015-01-30">
<title>National Prostate Cancer Plan Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s216v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-01-30">
<action-date>2015-01-21</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>National Prostate Cancer Plan Act</b></p> <p>Establishes in the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) the National Prostate Cancer Council on Screening, Early Detection, Assessment, and Monitoring of Prostate Cancer to: (1) develop and implement a strategic plan for the accelerated development of diagnostic tools for prostate cancer, (2) review the effectiveness of diagnostic tools for prostate cancer, (3) coordinate prostate cancer research and services across federal agencies, (4) evaluate all active federal prostate cancer programs, and (5) ensure the inclusion of men at high risk for prostate cancer in clinical, research, and service efforts.</p> <p>Directs the Council to submit annual reports. Requires the first report to include recommendations based on an evaluation of prostate cancer research and gaps in the development and validation of diagnostic tools for prostate cancer. Requires subsequent reports to include an outline for a national research plan, roles for specified agencies, an analysis of the disparities in the incidence and mortality of prostate cancer in high-risk men, and a review of the progress towards the realization of the strategic plan. </p> <p>Terminates the Council on December 31, 2020.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
