<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="718" measure-id="id114s718" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-03-11" update-date="2016-09-02">
<title>A bill to modify the boundary of Petersburg National Battlefield in the Commonwealth of Virginia, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s718v01" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-09-02">
<action-date>2016-08-30</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to Senate amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p> (Sec. 1) This bill modifies the boundary of Petersburg National Battlefield in Virginia to include the land and interests in land identified on the map titled &quot;Petersburg National Battlefield Boundary Expansion,&quot; and dated March 2016. </p> <p>The Department of the Interior may acquire lands and interests from willing sellers only, by donation, purchase, exchange, or transfer. </p> <p>Interior shall administer any acquired lands or interests as a part of the Battlefield. </p> <p>The bill transfers:</p> <ul> <li>from Interior to the Department of the Army administrative jurisdiction over approximately 1.170 acres of land for the Fort Lee Military Reservation, and</li> <li>from the Army to Interior administrative jurisdiction over approximately 1.171 acres of land for the Battlefield. </li> </ul> <p>The transferred lands shall not be subject to reimbursement or consideration. </p> <p>The land transferred to the Army shall be excluded from the boundary of the Battlefield.</p> <p>The land transferred to Interior shall be included within the boundary of the Battlefield and administered as part of it. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114s718v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-08-10">
<action-date>2015-03-11</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p> Modifies the boundary of Petersburg National Battlefield in Virginia to include the land and interests in land identified on the map titled &quot;Petersburg National Battlefield Boundary Expansion,&quot; and dated June 2007. </p> <p>Transfers from the Department of the Interior to the Department of the Army (DA) administrative jurisdiction over approximately 1.170 acres of land for the Fort Lee Military Reservation.</p> <p>Transfers from DA to Interior administrative jurisdiction over approximately 1.171 acres of land for the Battlefield. </p> <p>Requires inclusion of the conveyed land within the boundary of the Petersburg National Battlefield. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
