<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1266" measure-id="id114s1266" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-11" update-date="2015-07-27">
<title>HUBZone Expansion Act of 2015</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1266v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-07-27">
<action-date>2015-05-11</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>HUBZone Expansion Act of 2015</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Small Business Act to expand the HUBZone (historically underutilized business zone) program of Small Business Administration loans to small businesses in HUBZone areas for communities affected by base realignment and closure<b>.</b></p> <p>The expansion includes the areas that can be used by small businesses whose principal offices are located in base closure HUBZones, with at least 35% of their employees residing in:</p> <ul> <li> a HUBZone,</li> <li>a census tract in which the base closure HUBZone is wholly contained,</li> <li> a census tract that intersects the boundaries of the base closure HUBZone, or</li> <li> a census tract contiguous with these census tracts.</li> </ul> <p>HUBZone eligibility assistance for base closure areas is extended from five years to eight years after their closure.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
