<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="2726" measure-id="id114s2726" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-03-17" update-date="2016-04-15">
<title>Iran Terrorism and Human Rights Sanctions Act of 2016</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s2726v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-04-15">
<action-date>2016-03-17</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Iran Terrorism and Human Rights Sanctions Act of 2016</strong></p> <p>This bill prescribes requirements for mandatory sanctions with respect to: </p> <ul> <li>Iran's Revolutionary Guard Corps (IRGC) and entities it owns in whole or in part, </li> <li>Mahan Air, </li> <li>Iran's support of terrorism, </li> <li>Iran's human rights abuses, </li> <li>certain Iranian individuals, </li> <li>persons who conduct transactions with or on behalf of certain Iranian individuals, and </li> <li>financial institutions that engage in certain transactions on behalf of persons involved in human rights abuses or that export sensitive technology to Iran.</li> </ul> <p>The Department of the Treasury shall establish and publish in the Federal Register an IRGC watch list.</p> <p>The bill prescribes prohibitions against Iran's direct and indirect access to the U.S. financial system.</p> <p>The Iran Threat Reduction and Syria Human Rights Act of 2012 is amended to authorize a state or local government to divest its assets from, or prohibit investment in, any person that engages in investment or business activities with the IRGC or a person on the Treasury's list of designated nationals and blocked persons. </p> <p>The bill specifies additional requirements for removal of a person's designation as a state sponsor of terrorism.</p> <p>The Department of State may assist individuals and entities working in Iran for the purpose of supporting and promoting the rule of law, civil society, and economic opportunity. </p> <p>The President shall: (1) designate within the State Department a Special Coordinator on Human Rights and Democracy in Iran; and (2) report to Congress on U.S. citizens, including dual citizens, detained by Iran or Iranian-supported groups. </p> <p>Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty and Voice of America shall increase programming to Iran.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
