<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="s" measure-number="1207" measure-id="id114s1207" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-06" update-date="2015-06-15">
<title>A bill to direct the Secretary of Energy to establish a grant program under which the Secretary shall make grants to eligible partnerships to provide for the transformation of the electric grid by the year 2030, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114s1207v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-06-15">
<action-date>2015-05-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Next Generation Electric Systems Act </b></p> <p>This bill requires the Department of Energy (DOE) to establish a grants program for eligible partnerships to develop and implement projects related to achieving the transformation of the future electric grid by the year 2030 using a comprehensive approach to electric system design and architecture. </p> <p>Eligible partnerships may include any institution of higher education, National Laboratory, representative of a state or local government, representative of an Indian tribe, federal power marketing administration, industry expert, or nonprofit industry trade association, but must include at least one electric utility (either investor-owned or publicly owned), technology provider, rural electric cooperative, Regional Transmission Organization, or Independent System Operator.</p> <p>DOE must, when selecting eligible partnerships to receive grants, give priority to those proposing projects for which a cost-share is to be provided. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
