<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-concurrent" star-print="no-star-print"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 SCON 24 ATS: Authorizing the use of Emancipation Hall in the Capitol Visitor Center for the unveiling of the marble bust of Vice President Richard Cheney on December 3, 2015.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-11-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. CON. RES. 24</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20151105">November 5, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S342">Mr. Blunt</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S174">Mr. McConnell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S270">Mr. Schumer</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S198">Mr. Reid</cosponsor>) submitted the following concurrent resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>CONCURRENT RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Authorizing the use of Emancipation Hall in the Capitol Visitor Center for the unveiling of the
			 marble bust of Vice President Richard Cheney on December 3, 2015.</official-title></form>
	<resolution-body>
		<section id="id556379303E224E81A4FBBA0A5733A612" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Use of Emancipation Hall for the unveiling of the marble bust of Vice President Richard Cheney</header>
 <subsection id="id1E557AECB56742B3B941F61BB5990ACC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Emancipation Hall in the Capitol Visitor Center is authorized to be used for a ceremony to unveil the marble bust of Vice President Richard Cheney on December 3, 2015.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id91C16E42C49B4498A37C19CF70170F0B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Preparations</header><text>The Architect of the Capitol and the Capitol Police Board shall take such action as may be necessary with respect to physical preparations and security for the ceremony described in subsection (a).</text></subsection></section></resolution-body></resolution>


