<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-concurrent" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 SCON 2 ATS: Authorizing the use of Emancipation Hall in the Capitol Visitor Center for a ceremony to present the Congressional Gold Medal to the First Special Service Force, in recognition of its superior service during World War II.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>S. CON. RES. 2</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20150108">January 8, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S314">Mr. Tester</sponsor> submitted the following concurrent resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>CONCURRENT RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Authorizing the use of Emancipation Hall in the Capitol Visitor Center for a ceremony to present
			 the Congressional Gold Medal to the First Special Service Force, in
			 recognition of its superior service during World War II.</official-title></form>
	<resolution-body>
		<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="S1" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text></text>
		</section><section id="id8E161315221E4745A4CE40710EA1A56D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Use of Emancipation Hall for ceremony to present Congressional Gold Medal to First Special Service
			 Force</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Emancipation Hall in the Capitol Visitor Center is
authorized to be used on February 3, 2015, for a ceremony to present the Congressional Gold Medal
			 to the
First Special Service Force collectively, in recognition of
its superior service during World War II. Physical preparations for the conduct of the ceremony
			 shall be carried
out in accordance with such conditions as the Architect
of the Capitol may prescribe.</text>
		</section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


