<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-concurrent" star-print="no-star-print"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 SCON 13 IS: Authorizing the use of Emancipation Hall in the Capitol Visitor Center for a ceremony to present the Congressional Gold Medal to the American Fighter Aces.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-04-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. CON. RES. 13</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20150420">April 20, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S338">Mr. Manchin</sponsor> submitted the following concurrent resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSRA00">Committee on Rules and Administration</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>CONCURRENT RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Authorizing the use of Emancipation Hall in the Capitol Visitor Center for a ceremony to present
			 the Congressional Gold Medal to the American Fighter Aces.</official-title></form>
	<resolution-body id="HA56D2CA3BE52479A91C98BF14D43E7F0" style="OLC">
		<section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF7A5DD422AF44091B46138B26C58FF88" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Use of Emancipation Hall for ceremony to present Congressional Gold Medal to American Fighter Aces</header>
 <subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id13D294297BFA49B082999B045033E632"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Emancipation Hall in the Capitol Visitor Center is authorized to be used on May 20, 2015, for a ceremony to present the Congressional Gold Medal to the American Fighter Aces collectively, in recognition of their heroic military service and defense of our country's freedom throughout the history of aviation warfare.</text>
 </subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6AFF99EB4C5A447B9D47E927ACCAB7B8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Preparations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Physical preparations for the conduct of the ceremony described in subsection (a) shall be carried out in accordance with such conditions as may be prescribed by the Architect of the Capitol.</text></subsection></section></resolution-body></resolution>


