<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-concurrent"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 SCON 1 IS: Expressing the sense of Congress that a carbon tax is not in the economic interest of the United States.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress>114th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. CON. RES. 1</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20150107">January 7, 2015</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S299">Mr. Vitter</sponsor> submitted the following concurrent resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>CONCURRENT RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing the sense of Congress that a carbon tax is not in the economic interest of the United
			 States.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas a carbon tax is regressive in nature and would
			 unfairly burden those vulnerable individuals and families in the United
			 States
			 that are already struggling with increasing electricity rates and a slow
			 economic recovery;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas a carbon tax would increase the cost of every good
			 manufactured in the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas a carbon tax would harm the entire United States
			 manufacturing sector;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas European nations that have adopted carbon policies and regulatory regimes have forced
			 energy poverty on their citizens and undermined their economies;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the increase in production of domestic fossil energy
			 resources on private and State-owned land has created significant job
			 growth
			 and private capital investment; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas affordable and reliable energy sources are
			 critical to maintaining the United States global competitiveness: Now,
			 therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="S1" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That it is the sense of Congress that
			 a carbon tax would be detrimental to families and businesses in the United
			 States, and
			 is
			 not in the interest of the United States.</text></section></resolution-body></resolution>


