<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="H88FD47BE199340E195761B144CC35F3B" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-concurrent" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HCON 69 IH: Expressing the sense of Congress that any reform or repeal of the last-in, first-out method of accounting for inventories (LIFO) would cause irreparable and unnecessary damage to United States businesses.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress> 
<session display="yes">1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. CON. RES. 69</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action display="yes"> 
<action-date date="20150729">July 29, 2015</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000816">Mr. Williams</sponsor> submitted the following concurrent resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>CONCURRENT RESOLUTION</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">Expressing the sense of Congress that any reform or repeal of the last-in, first-out method of accounting for inventories (LIFO) would cause irreparable and unnecessary damage to United States businesses.</official-title> 
</form> 
<preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the last-in, first-out method of accounting for inventories (LIFO) is a widely used and accepted inventory accounting method that has been part of the Federal internal revenue laws since 1939;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas LIFO is not a loophole and therefore should not be treated as such in any reform of the Federal internal revenue laws; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the preservation of LIFO is in the economic interest of the United States: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble> <resolution-body style="traditional" id="H3E4132A8C373464089D3B06440971EFB"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HD0690A4C68EF4BF4B3E8A042FC59D52B"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That it is the sense of Congress that irreparable and unnecessary damage to United States businesses would result from reform or repeal of the last-in, first-out method of accounting for inventories (LIFO) provided under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/472">section 472</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text></section> 
</resolution-body> 
</resolution> 


