<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="H674B2DE44DB14DDC9D5AE10911AE70CB" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-concurrent" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HCON 61 IH: Authorizing the use of the Capitol Grounds for the 2nd Annual Fallen Firefighters Congressional Flag Presentation Ceremony.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. CON. RES. 61</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20150713">July 13, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000210">Mr. King of New York</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="R000578">Mr. Reichert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000096">Mr. Pascrell</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H000874">Mr. Hoyer</cosponsor>) submitted the following concurrent resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>CONCURRENT RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Authorizing the use of the Capitol Grounds for the 2nd Annual Fallen Firefighters Congressional
			 Flag Presentation Ceremony.</official-title>
	</form>
	<resolution-body id="H80DB331347A545DB94F45C05BD90E0F5" style="OLC">
		<section id="H32B26709E8474F9286A1F22206D0EDF9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Use of Capitol Grounds for Fallen Firefighters Congressional Flag Presentation Ceremony</header>
 <subsection id="H2F467DB07AD24DB9A9997F04C8CC9B73"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Congressional Fire Services Institute and the National Fallen Firefighters Foundation (in this resolution referred to jointly as the <quote>sponsor</quote>) shall be permitted to sponsor a public event, the 2nd Annual Fallen Firefighters Congressional Flag Presentation Ceremony (in this resolution referred to as the <quote>event</quote>), on the Capitol Grounds in order to honor the firefighters who died in the line of duty in 2014.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8E5EF76206BF4B57ADF0A5D4B28950D4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Date of event</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The event shall be held on September 30, 2015, or on such other date as the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate jointly designate.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HABB52587699044B49C33A2D99B7BC24C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Terms and conditions</header>
 <subsection id="HA85505DC97FD4A46BFCBABA92CDC35CD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Under conditions to be prescribed by the Architect of the Capitol and the Capitol Police Board, the event shall be—</text>
 <paragraph id="H1749FCB200B949109C7E5017822DFB3C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">free of admission charge and open to the public; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE6FC83232A6F45F885566D6111D85138"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">arranged not to interfere with the needs of Congress.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC1A4B48355A94F0EBABFDB7D1C20B840"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Expenses and liabilities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The sponsor shall assume full responsibility for all expenses and liabilities incident to all activities associated with the event.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HD763F72C2BC042F984265CC196C158AA"><enum>3.</enum><header>Event preparations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subject to the approval of the Architect of the Capitol, the sponsor is authorized to erect upon the Capitol Grounds such stage, sound amplification devices, and other related structures and equipment as may be required for the event.</text>
 </section><section id="H0F1593858DD645AC8E0DAC7C10DB8886"><enum>4.</enum><header>Additional arrangements</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Architect of the Capitol and the Capitol Police Board are authorized to make such additional arrangements as may be required to carry out the event.</text>
 </section><section id="H2902CB8D2BD64A0D98EF6E0B71517663"><enum>5.</enum><header>Enforcement of restrictions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Capitol Police Board shall provide for enforcement of the restrictions contained in section 5104(c) of title 40, United States Code, concerning sales, advertisements, displays, and solicitations on the Capitol Grounds, as well as other restrictions applicable to the Capitol Grounds, with respect to the event.</text>
		</section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


