<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="H9AF501E130C94D88B418BAF8DBFF0D58" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Enrolled-Bill" resolution-type="house-concurrent" star-print="no-star-print" stage-count="1">  
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title> HCON 64 ENR: Authorizing the use of Emancipation Hall in the Capitol Visitor Center for a ceremony to present the Congressional Gold Medal to the Monuments Men.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">IV</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">One Hundred Fourteenth Congress of the United States of America</congress> 
<session display="yes">At the First Session</session><enrolled-dateline>Begun and held at the City of Washington on Tuesday, the sixth day of January, two thousand and fifteen</enrolled-dateline> 
<legis-num>H. CON. RES. 64</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no"></current-chamber>
<action>
<action-date date="20150728">July 28, 2015</action-date>
<action-desc>Agreed to</action-desc>
</action> 
<legis-type>CONCURRENT RESOLUTION</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">Authorizing the use of Emancipation Hall in the Capitol Visitor Center for a ceremony to present the Congressional Gold Medal to the Monuments Men.</official-title> 
</form> 
<resolution-body id="H462288544E3D4E67A86ECB950BFA0958" style="OLC"> 
<section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3980635A152A416DBB8705EFD9D1E83E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Use of Emancipation Hall for ceremony to present Congressional Gold Medal to the Monuments Men</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Emancipation Hall in the Capitol Visitor Center is authorized to be used on October 22, 2015, for a ceremony to present the Congressional Gold Medal to the Monuments Men collectively, in recognition of their heroic role in the preservation, protection, and restitution of monuments, works of art, and artifacts of cultural importance during and following World War II. Physical preparations for the conduct of the ceremony shall be carried out in accordance with such conditions as the Architect of the Capitol may prescribe.</text> </section> </resolution-body> <attestation><attestation-group><role>Clerk of the House of Representatives.</role></attestation-group><attestation-group><role>Secretary of the Senate.</role></attestation-group></attestation> </resolution> 

