<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="H3FAFCA5A4E3045F383F4A5CBB367DBF4" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-concurrent" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HCON 30 IH: Supporting the designation of the year of 2015 as the International Year of Soils and supporting locally led soil conservation.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-03-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. CON. RES. 30</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20150326">March 26, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000467">Mr. Thompson of Pennsylvania</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000580">Ms. Michelle Lujan Grisham of New Mexico</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001045">Mr. Harper</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="J000255">Mr. Jones</cosponsor>) submitted the following concurrent resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>CONCURRENT RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Supporting the designation of the year of 2015 as the International Year of Soils and supporting
			 locally led soil conservation.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
 <whereas><text>Whereas many of our international partners are designating 2015 as the International Year of Soils;</text> </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas soil is vitally important for food security and essential ecosystem functions;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas soil conservation efforts in the United States are often locally led;</text> </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 2015 also marks the 80th anniversary of the signing of the Soil Conservation Act on April 27, 1935;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas soils, as the foundation for agricultural production, essential ecosystem functions, and food security, are key to sustaining life on Earth;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas soils and the science of soils contribute to improved water quality, food safety and security, healthy ecosystems, and human health; and</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas soil, plant, animal, and human health are intricately linked: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble> <resolution-body id="HE7B7C64C4A9F464E9CABC70A6BD4D4B9" style="traditional"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H9F9C3CB88F784500AF053CE7A13F8DCC" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That Congress—</text>
 <paragraph id="H06BEC7824E234E67981E1430091BC53E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the designation of an International Year of Soils;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7C4086B3E996447AAFE2675BC0842B73"><enum>(2)</enum><text>encourages the public to participate in activities that celebrate the importance of soils to our current and future well-being; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H258C2EF34A744B8EAE666392774E8855"><enum>(3)</enum><text>supports conservation of the Nation’s soils, through landowner participation in the Conservation Reserve Program, the Environmental Quality Incentives Program, the Conservation Stewardship Program, the Agricultural Conservation Easement Program, and the Regional Conservation Partnership Program as authorized by the Food Security Act of 1985 as amended (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/3801">16 U.S.C. 3801 et seq.</external-xref>), and the Small Watershed Rehabilitation Program as authorized by the Watershed Protection and Flood Prevention Act as amended (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1001">16 U.S.C. 1001 et seq.</external-xref>), delivered in partnership with local soil and water conservation districts.</text>
			</paragraph></section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


