<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="HD257018DDC9340C1816D54BDA1BA4F1F" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-concurrent" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HCON 63 IH: To express the sense of the Congress that any Executive order that infringes on the powers and duties of the Congress under article I, section 8 of the Constitution, or that would require the expenditure of Federal funds not specifically appropriated for the purpose of the Executive order, is advisory only and has no force or effect unless enacted as law.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-07-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. CON. RES. 63</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20150715">July 15, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000290">Ms. Jenkins of Kansas</sponsor> submitted the following concurrent resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>CONCURRENT RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To express the sense of the Congress that any Executive order that infringes on the powers and
			 duties of the Congress under article I, section 8 of the Constitution, or
			 that would require the expenditure of Federal funds not specifically
			 appropriated for the purpose of the Executive order, is advisory only and
			 has no force or effect unless enacted as law.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
 <whereas><text>Whereas some Executive orders have infringed on the prerogatives of the Congress and resulted in the expenditure of Federal funds not appropriated for the specific purposes of those Executive orders: Now, therefore, be it</text>
		</whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body id="H7EC441DA9D294C84BB06E3662C5B6813" style="traditional">
 <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H58ECB3B804B94F37AF48DE09B1D96496" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That it is the sense of the Congress that any Executive order issued by the President before, on, or after the date of the approval of this resolution that infringes on the powers and duties of the Congress under article I, section 8 of the Constitution, or that would require the expenditure of Federal funds not specifically appropriated for the purpose of the Executive order, is advisory only and has no force or effect unless enacted as law.</text>
		</section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


