<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="H3FB902AF32C14FD7945454A20B9B1FD8" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-concurrent" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HCON 10 IH: Recognizing the challenges and burdens associated with the rising costs of a college education.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-01-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. CON. RES. 10</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20150127">January 27, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000043">Mr. Fattah</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>) submitted the following concurrent resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>CONCURRENT RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Recognizing the challenges and burdens associated with the rising costs of a college education.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
 <whereas><text>Whereas a college education is inextricably linked to economic opportunity in the United States and the American Dream;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas a college education is integral to the vibrancy and potency of the American workforce;</text> </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas an estimated 30 percent of job openings will require an associate’s degree or some college by 2020;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the rising costs of higher education are an obstacle to college matriculation and completion;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Federal student loan debt for all borrowers exceeds $1 trillion;</text> </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Federal, State, and local governments are pursuing strategies and innovations which will make higher education more affordable and accessible;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas better utilizing our community colleges to address the rising costs of higher education is one such strategy;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas there are 1,100 or more community colleges in the United States;</text> </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas approximately 40 percent of undergraduate students attend a community college;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas community colleges provide a cost-effective option to pursuing a college degree;</text> </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas community colleges offer open admission;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the cost of community college is approximately 50 percent lower than traditional colleges and universities;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Administration recently highlighted the importance of community colleges through the America’s College Promise proposal and made a significant step in addressing the costs of higher education;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas this proposal would provide two years of community college free for hardworking students who are enrolled at least half-time in a community college and maintain a good GPA;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas this proposal could benefit approximately 9,000,000 students if all States participate;</text> </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas an average of $3,800 in tuition per year could be saved for full-time community college students through this proposal;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Congress has a significant role in making college more affordable and accessible; and</text> </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Congress can pass legislation which will reduce the rising costs of a college education making college more accessible for all students: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body id="H3DA37D1FBB5A4B4B9E98FBE7EFADB208" style="traditional">
 <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H3C23D62AD7E34C859598EA8CFF5B49F3" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That Congress—</text> <paragraph id="HDC5EE185C16D4DB7BE25995996641363"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognizes the challenges and burdens associated with the rising costs of a college education;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H196D9244977641EC811D787017A27809"><enum>(2)</enum><text>acknowledges the benefits of community colleges in providing an affordable and cost effective way to obtain a college degree;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3CAAAA0335F64573AE64748111B93FB9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>supports the goals and ideals of the America’s College Promise proposal; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF09539990E634541A0E4713C69EF3A65"><enum>(4)</enum><text>commits to pursuing strategies in the 114th Congress which will make college more affordable and accessible for all students.</text>
			</paragraph></section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


