<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="HD020CB13584F4189930116D15B30B126" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-concurrent" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HCON 94 IH: Expressing the sense of the Congress regarding the treatment of State Governors who have made a determination with respect to Syrian refugees.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-11-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. CON. RES. 94</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20151118">November 18, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001187">Mr. Meadows</sponsor> submitted the following concurrent resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>CONCURRENT RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Expressing the sense of the Congress regarding the treatment of State Governors who have made a
			 determination with respect to Syrian refugees.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
 <whereas><text>Whereas a Governor is the chief executive officer of their State; and</text> </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Federal Government should not be able to override a Governor’s decision with respect to refugees: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body id="H71223F2FD8384BA4B3560E2A6A4306CD" style="traditional">
 <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H018EEB04758B4DEA9182BC8E7318A7B0" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That in the case of a Governor requesting that Syrian refugees not be resettled in their State (whether temporarily or permanently), no Federal official should take any adverse action against, or withhold funds from, the State, and no Federal official should take any other action designed to persuade or entice the Governor to reverse such a request.</text>
		</section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


