<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="H58722D282E98487B90B9D63365242200" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-concurrent" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HCON 87 IH: Expressing support for designation of October 28 as “Honoring the Nation’s First Responders Day”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-10-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. CON. RES. 87</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20151026">October 26, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001187">Mr. Meadows</sponsor> submitted the following concurrent resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>CONCURRENT RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Expressing support for designation of October 28 as <quote>Honoring the Nation’s First Responders Day</quote>.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
 <whereas><text>Whereas the term first responders includes all fire, police, EMT, and volunteer first responder workers in the United States;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas there are over 25,300,000 first responders in the United States today, working to keep our communities safe;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas first responders, both professional and volunteer, deserve to be recognized for their commitment to safety, defense, and honor; and</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas October 28 would be an appropriate day to establish as <quote>Honoring the Nation’s First Responders Day</quote>: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body id="H67F6C7D2C4EA43BB903FFCFE129582A8" style="traditional">
 <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H741960E74A5342EA9FB10BB36E4FAFCD" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="H4721007B1DE948679F5F646624799FEE"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supports the designation of <quote>Honoring the Nation’s First Responders Day</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAD354225AC51413FAEF0A8934FC5540D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>honors and recognizes the contributions of volunteer firefighters, policemen, and other service men and women; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H33E15B5085344DCF85E30B1101F2533D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>encourages the people of the United States to observe <quote>Honoring the Nation’s First Responders Day</quote> with appropriate ceremonies and activities that promote awareness of the contributions of the Nation’s First Responders.</text>
			</paragraph></section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


