<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="HD85623F170AA4C2E867E54B832D0C22E" key="H" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" resolution-type="house-concurrent" star-print="no-star-print">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HCON 52 IH: Honoring American veterans disabled for life.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-05-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">114th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. CON. RES. 52</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20150522">May 22, 2015</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000462">Ms. Frankel of Florida</sponsor> submitted the following concurrent resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans’ Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>CONCURRENT RESOLUTION</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">Honoring American veterans disabled for life.</official-title>
	</form>
	<preamble>
 <whereas><text>Whereas the men and women serving in the United States Armed Forces have been integral in shaping and developing American liberty;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the members of the Armed Forces make great sacrifices to preserve our ideals and perpetuate freedom and democracy at home and abroad;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas many members of the Armed Forces incurred permanent wounds, illnesses, and injuries as a direct consequence of their service in the Armed Forces;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Department of Veterans Affairs recognizes 3,600,000 veterans currently living with service-connected disabilities;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas many veterans are permanently disabled throughout their lives and, in many cases, must rely on the support of their families and friends when these visible and invisible burdens become too much to bear alone;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas in recognition of the service and sacrifice of the Nation’s veterans, Congress approved the construction of the American Veterans Disabled for Life Memorial in the District of Columbia; and</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the American Veterans Disabled for Life Memorial was dedicated on October 5, 2014, to serve as a permanent reminder of those who were not lost to war, but were left with permanent disabilities as a result of their military service: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble>
	<resolution-body id="H25B5CFF9C42D45A79C41FCB1C32105F8" style="traditional">
 <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HC17C417748B44F2493040C3794A5BB4B" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum></enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That Congress honors American veterans disabled for life and expresses appreciation to the men and women left permanently wounded, ill, or injured as a result of their service in the Armed Forces.</text>
		</section></resolution-body>
</resolution>


