<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="sres" measure-number="182" measure-id="id114sres182" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-19" update-date="2015-05-27">
<title>A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate that Defense laboratories have been, and continue to be, on the cutting edge of scientific and technological advancement and supporting the designation of May 14, 2015, as the "Department of Defense Laboratory Day".</title>
<summary summary-id="id114sres182v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-05-27">
<action-date>2015-05-19</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Supports the designation of May 14, 2015, as the Department of Defense Laboratory Day in recognition of the work and accomplishments of the national network of Defense laboratories.</p> <p> Recognizes that supporting research and development, including federally sponsored work performed at the Defense laboratories, is key to maintaining U.S. innovation and competitiveness in a global economy. </p> <p>Acknowledges that the Defense laboratory system knowledge base, technologies, and techniques serve as a foundation for the defense industrial base. </p> <p>Reaffirms the importance of investment in Defense laboratories to preserving the technological superiority of the Armed Forces in the 21st century.</p> <p>Encourages the Defense laboratories, the executive branch agencies, and Congress to hold an outreach event on May 14, 2015, Department of Defense Laboratory Day, to raise public awareness of the work of the Defense laboratories.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114sres182v82" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-05-27">
<action-date>2015-05-19</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed Senate without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.)</p> <p>Supports the designation of May 14, 2015, as the Department of Defense Laboratory Day in recognition of the work and accomplishments of the national network of Defense laboratories.</p> <p> Recognizes that supporting research and development, including federally sponsored work performed at the Defense laboratories, is key to maintaining U.S. innovation and competitiveness in a global economy. </p> <p>Acknowledges that the Defense laboratory system knowledge base, technologies, and techniques serve as a foundation for the defense industrial base. </p> <p>Reaffirms the importance of investment in Defense laboratories to preserving the technological superiority of the Armed Forces in the 21st century.</p> <p>Encourages the Defense laboratories, the executive branch agencies, and Congress to hold an outreach event on May 14, 2015, Department of Defense Laboratory Day, to raise public awareness of the work of the Defense laboratories.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
