<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="sres" measure-number="564" measure-id="id114sres564" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-09-15" update-date="2016-10-31">
<title>A resolution condemning North Korea's fifth nuclear test on September 9, 2016.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114sres564v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-10-31">
<action-date>2016-09-15</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Condemns the North Korean regime for continuing its dangerous provocations. Calls on: (1) such regime to unconditionally abandon its nuclear weapons and missile programs, and (2) China to exercise its leverage to halt such programs.</p> <p>Reaffirms the U.S. commitment to defending allies in the region, including through deployment of a Terminal High Altitude Area Defense battery to South Korea and through joint U.S.-Japan efforts to develop the next generation of missile defense interceptors. Reinforces longstanding U.S. commitments to provide extended deterrence to South Korea and Japan.</p> <p>Expresses support for ongoing efforts to strengthen the U.S.-South Korea alliance, to defend the alliance against provocations by North Korea, and to protect U.S. Armed Forces stationed on the Korean Peninsula.</p> <p>Calls on all Security Council members to pass new measures under Article 41 of the United Nations Charter, including:</p> <ul> <li> stricter measures to eliminate exceptions in current Security Council resolution sanctions; </li> <li> further restrictions on imports and exports of such sectoral commodities as coal, iron, and precious metals and the prohibition on fuel oil exports to North Korea; </li> <li> elimination of access to international financial markets and banking for entities involved in North Korea's nuclear and ballistic missile programs; </li> <li> restrictions on the use of North Korean subcontractors in global supply chains;</li> <li> restrictions on the supply of aviation fuel and a ban on civilian aviation; </li> <li> a ban on bulk cash transfers to and from North Korea; </li> <li> prevention of the use of North Korean labor in third-country projects and agreements; and </li> <li> a downgrading of North Korean diplomatic representation.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
