<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="sres" measure-number="333" measure-id="id114sres333" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-12-10" update-date="2016-01-04">
<title>A resolution to direct the Senate Legal Counsel to appear as amicus curiae in the name of the Senate in Bank Markazi, The Central Bank of Iran v. Deborah D. Peterson, et al. (S. Ct.)</title>
<summary summary-id="id114sres333v82" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-01-04">
<action-date>2015-12-10</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed Senate without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded becasue action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p>Directs the Senate Legal Counsel to appear as amicus curiae on behalf of the Senate in the case of <EM>Bank Markazi, The Central Bank of Iran v. Deborah D. Peterson, et al.</EM>, to defend the constitutionality of section 502 of the Iran Threat Reduction and Syria Human Rights Act of 2012.</p> <p>(Sec. 502 of that Act makes available for attachment, with respect to judgments against Iran for damages for personal injury or death caused by an act of torture, extrajudicial killing, aircraft sabotage, or hostage-taking, or the provision of material support or resources for such an act, any financial asset that is: (1) property in the United States of a foreign securities intermediary doing business in the United States, (2) a blocked asset that is property identified in and the subject of proceedings in<em> Peterson et al. v. Islamic Republic of Iran et al</em>., and (3) equal in value to a financial asset of Iran that such foreign securities intermediary or a related intermediary holds abroad.)</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114sres333v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-01-04">
<action-date>2015-12-10</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Directs the Senate Legal Counsel to appear as amicus curiae on behalf of the Senate in the case of <EM>Bank Markazi, The Central Bank of Iran v. Deborah D. Peterson, et al.</EM>, to defend the constitutionality of section 502 of the Iran Threat Reduction and Syria Human Rights Act of 2012.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
