<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="sres" measure-number="153" measure-id="id114sres153" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-04-28" update-date="2015-04-29">
<title>A resolution recognizing the importance of the United States-Japan relationship to safeguarding global security, prosperity, and human rights.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114sres153v82" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-04-29">
<action-date>2015-04-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed Senate without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p>Reaffirms the importance of the U.S.-Japan alliance for maintaining peace and stability in the Asia-Pacific region and beyond, including through U.S. extended deterrence, the revision of the Guidelines for United States-Japan Defense Cooperation, and Japan's policy of Proactive Contribution to Peace based on the principles of international cooperation.</p> <p>Supports: (1) efforts to further strengthen the U.S.-Japan alliance to confront emerging challenges, including cyber and space; and (2) U.S.-Japan cooperation in safeguarding maritime security and ensuring freedom of navigation, commerce, and overflight in the East and South China Seas. </p> <p> Acknowledges, without taking a position on the ultimate sovereignty of the Senkaku Islands, that they are under Japan's administration and opposes any unilateral actions to undermine such administration. </p> <p>Reaffirms that the United States remains committed under the Treaty of Mutual Cooperation and Security to respond to any armed attack in the territories under Japan's administration.</p> <p> Recognizes Japan's support in addressing global challenges that threaten the security of people everywhere. </p> <p>Supports U.S.-Japan academic, scientific, technical, and cultural exchanges. </p> <p>Promotes U.S.-Japan economic and trade ties, including the empowerment of women.</p> <p>Calls for U.S.-Japan cooperation in the promotion of human rights. </p> <p>States that nothing in this resolution shall be construed as a declaration of war or authorization to use force.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114sres153v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-04-29">
<action-date>2015-04-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Reaffirms the importance of the U.S.-Japan alliance for maintaining peace and stability in the Asia-Pacific region and beyond. </p> <p>Supports: (1) efforts to further strengthen the U.S.-Japan alliance to confront emerging challenges, including cyber and space; and (2) U.S.-Japan cooperation in safeguarding maritime security and ensuring freedom of navigation, commerce, and overflight in the East and South China Seas. </p> <p> Acknowledges, without taking a position on the ultimate sovereignty of the Senkaku Islands, that they are under Japan's administration and opposes any unilateral actions to undermine such administration. </p> <p>Reaffirms that the United States remains committed under the Treaty of Mutual Cooperation and Security to respond to any armed attack in the territories under Japan's administration. </p> <p>Supports U.S.-Japan academic, scientific, technical, and cultural exchanges. </p> <p>Promotes U.S.-Japan economic and trade ties. </p> <p>Calls for U.S.-Japan cooperation in the promotion of human rights. </p> <p>States that nothing in this resolution shall be construed as a declaration of war or authorization to use force.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
