<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="sres" measure-number="368" measure-id="id114sres368" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-02-09" update-date="2016-05-09">
<title>A resolution supporting efforts by the Government of Colombia to pursue peace and the end of the country's enduring internal armed conflict and recognizing United States support for Colombia at the 15th anniversary of Plan Colombia.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114sres368v82" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-05-09">
<action-date>2016-04-27</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed Senate without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The expanded summary of the Senate reported version is repeated here.)</p> <p>Reaffirms the support of the government and people of the United States for the people of Colombia in their pursuit of peace. </p> <p> Commends efforts to bring an end to Colombia's internal armed conflict.</p> <p> Maintains the Senate's commitment to the victims of Colombia's armed conflict and urges the negotiating parties to forge an agreement that holds accountable perpetrators of serious violations of human rights and ensures that they are appropriately punished.</p> <p>Encourages the Department of State to develop a comprehensive strategy to ensure the successful implementation of a potential peace accord in Colombia that is endorsed by the Colombian people. </p> <p>Reaffirms the Senate's commitment to continued partnership between the United States and Colombia on issues of mutual security, including counternarcotics cooperation, combating transnational organized crime, and ensuring justice for those who have caused indelible harm to our populations.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114sres368v80" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-03-21">
<action-date>2016-03-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to Senate without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p>Reaffirms the support of the government and people of the United States for the people of Colombia in their pursuit of peace. </p> <p> Commends efforts to bring an end to Colombia's internal armed conflict.</p> <p> Maintains the Senate's commitment to the victims of Colombia's armed conflict and urges the negotiating parties to forge an agreement that holds accountable perpetrators of serious violations of human rights and ensures that they are appropriately punished.</p> <p>Encourages the Department of State to develop a comprehensive strategy to ensure the successful implementation of a potential peace accord in Colombia that is endorsed by the Colombian people. </p> <p>Reaffirms the Senate's commitment to continued partnership between the United States and Colombia on issues of mutual security, including counternarcotics cooperation, combating transnational organized crime, and ensuring justice for those who have caused indelible harm to our populations.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114sres368v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-02-10">
<action-date>2016-02-09</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Reaffirms the support of the government and people of the United States for the people of Colombia in their pursuit of peace. </p> <p> Commends efforts to bring an end to Colombia's internal armed conflict.</p> <p> Maintains the Senate's commitment to the victims of Colombia's armed conflict and urges the negotiating parties to forge an agreement that holds accountable perpetrators of serious violations of human rights and ensures that they are appropriately punished.</p> <p>Encourages the Department of State to develop a comprehensive strategy to ensure the successful implementation of a potential peace accord in Colombia that is endorsed by the Colombian people. </p> <p>Reaffirms the Senate's commitment to continued partnership between the United States and Colombia on issues of mutual security. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
