<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="sres" measure-number="432" measure-id="id114sres432" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-04-20" update-date="2016-08-03">
<title>A resolution supporting respect for human rights and encouraging inclusive governance in Ethiopia.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114sres432v80" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-08-03">
<action-date>2016-06-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to Senate without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.)</p> <p>Condemns the: </p> <ul> <li>killings of peaceful protesters and excessive use of force by Ethiopian security forces; </li> <li>arrest of journalists, students, activists and political leaders who exercise their constitutional rights to freedom of assembly and expression through peaceful protests; and </li> <li>abuse of the Anti-Terrorism Proclamation to stifle political and civil dissent and journalistic freedoms. </li> </ul> <p>Urges protesters in Ethiopia to refrain from violence.</p> <p>Calls on the government of Ethiopia to:</p> <ul> <li>halt the use of excessive force by security forces; </li> <li>investigate the killings and excessive use of force that took place as a result of protests in the Oromia region; </li> <li>release dissidents, activists, and journalists who have been jailed for exercising constitutional rights;</li> <li>respect the right to freedom of peaceful assembly and guarantee freedom of the press and mass media; and </li> <li>repeal proclamations that can be used to prohibit funding for organizations that investigate human rights violations, engage in peaceful political dissent, or advocate for greater political freedoms or proclamations that prohibit or otherwise limit those displaced from their land from seeking judicial redress. </li> </ul> <p>Calls on: (1) the Department of State to improve oversight of U.S. assistance, and review security assistance, to Ethiopia; and (2) the U.S. Agency for International Development to lead efforts to develop a strategy to support improved democracy and governance in Ethiopia. </p> <p>Supports the peaceful efforts of the Ethiopian people to exercise their constitutional rights.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114sres432v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-05-27">
<action-date>2016-04-20</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Condemns the: </p> <ul> <li>killings of peaceful protesters and excessive use of force by Ethiopian security forces; </li> <li>arrest of journalists, students, activists and political leaders who exercise their constitutional rights to freedom of assembly and expression through peaceful protests; and </li> <li>abuse of the Anti-Terrorism Proclamation to stifle political and civil dissent and journalistic freedoms. </li> </ul> <p>Urges protesters in Ethiopia to refrain from violence.</p> <p>Calls on the government of Ethiopia to:</p> <ul> <li>halt the use of excessive force by security forces; </li> <li>investigate the killings and excessive use of force that took place as a result of protests in the Oromia region; </li> <li>release dissidents, activists, and journalists who have been jailed for exercising constitutional rights;</li> <li>respect the right to freedom of peaceful assembly and guarantee freedom of the press and mass media; and </li> <li>repeal proclamations that can be used to prohibit funding for organizations that investigate human rights violations, engage in peaceful political dissent, or advocate for greater political freedoms or proclamations that prohibit or otherwise limit those displaced from their land from seeking judicial redress. </li> </ul> <p>Calls on: (1) the Department of State to improve oversight of U.S. assistance, and review security assistance, to Ethiopia; and (2) the U.S. Agency for International Development to lead efforts to develop a strategy to support improved democracy and governance in Ethiopia. </p> <p>Supports the peaceful efforts of the Ethiopian people to exercise their constitutional rights.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
