<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="sres" measure-number="524" measure-id="id114sres524" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-07-11" update-date="2016-08-30">
<title>A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate on the conflict in Yemen.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114sres524v80" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-08-30">
<action-date>2016-07-14</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to Senate without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.)</p> <p>Expresses the sense of the Senate that:</p> <ul> <li> all sides to the current conflict in Yemen should abide by international obligations to protect civilians, facilitate the delivery of humanitarian relief throughout the country, and respect negotiated cease-fires and work toward a lasting political settlement; </li> <li>U.S.-supported Saudi military operations in Yemen should take all feasible precautions to reduce the risk of harm to civilians and civilian objects, and should increase prioritization of targeting of designated foreign terrorist organizations, including al Qaeda in the Arabian Peninsula and affiliates of the Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant; </li> <li> the Houthi-Saleh forces engaged in the conflict in Yemen should cease indiscriminate shelling of areas inhabited by civilians and should allow free access by humanitarian relief organizations seeking to deliver aid to civilian populations under siege; and </li> <li> a reconstruction and stabilization plan should be developed alongside a negotiated political framework, in consultation with local stakeholders and with robust financing from the international community, including Gulf Cooperation Council countries that have previously made pledges to fund Yemen's post-conflict reconstruction. </li> </ul> <ul> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114sres524v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-10-31">
<action-date>2016-07-11</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Expresses the sense of the Senate that:</p> <ul> <li> all sides to the conflict in Yemen should abide by international obligations to protect civilians, facilitate the delivery of humanitarian relief, respect cease-fires, and work toward a political settlement; </li> <li>U.S.-supported Saudi military operations in Yemen should take all feasible precautions to reduce the risk of harm to civilians and should increase prioritization of targeting of designated foreign terrorist organizations; </li> <li> the Houthi-Saleh forces should cease indiscriminate shelling of areas inhabited by civilians and should allow free access by humanitarian relief organizations seeking to deliver aid to civilian populations; and </li> <li> a reconstruction and stabilization plan should be developed alongside a negotiated political framework, with robust financing from the international community, including Gulf Cooperation Council countries that have pledged to fund Yemen's post-conflict reconstruction. </li> </ul> <ul> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
