<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="sres" measure-number="274" measure-id="id114sres274" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-10-01" update-date="2015-10-23">
<title>A resolution commemorating the 25th anniversary of the peaceful and democratic reunification of Germany.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114sres274v82" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-10-23">
<action-date>2015-10-22</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed Senate without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The expanded summary of the Senate reported version is repeated here.)</p> <p>Celebrates 25 years of a united Germany. </p> <p> Honors the courage of the people of Germany, the United States, and other countries who served in the Cold War to bring freedom to Central and Eastern Europe. </p> <p>Recognizes the importance of the alliance between the United States and Germany in: (1) common defense, (2) a shared commitment to a free and unified Europe, and (3) an expanding economic prosperity under the rule of law throughout Europe. </p> <p>Expresses to the people of Germany an appreciation for their commitment to the promotion of freedom through leadership in providing international assistance, support for peacekeeping and international security efforts, and acceptance of refugees, including efforts by the people of Germany in Afghanistan, Bosnia and Herzegovina, Kosovo, Lebanon, Sudan, and Ukraine.</p> <p>Reaffirms the friendship between the government and people of the United States and the government and people of Germany.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114sres274v80" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-10-13">
<action-date>2015-10-08</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to Senate without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p>Celebrates 25 years of a united Germany. </p> <p> Honors the courage of the people of Germany, the United States, and other countries who served in the Cold War to bring freedom to Central and Eastern Europe. </p> <p>Recognizes the importance of the alliance between the United States and Germany in: (1) common defense, (2) a shared commitment to a free and unified Europe, and (3) an expanding economic prosperity under the rule of law throughout Europe. </p> <p>Expresses to the people of Germany an appreciation for their commitment to the promotion of freedom through leadership in providing international assistance, support for peacekeeping and international security efforts, and acceptance of refugees, including efforts by the people of Germany in Afghanistan, Bosnia and Herzegovina, Kosovo, Lebanon, Sudan, and Ukraine.</p> <p>Reaffirms the friendship between the government and people of the United States and the government and people of Germany.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114sres274v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-10-05">
<action-date>2015-10-01</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Celebrates 25 years of a united Germany. </p> <p> Honors the courage of the people of Germany, the United States, and other countries who served in the Cold War to bring freedom to Central and Eastern Europe. </p> <p>Recognizes the importance of the alliance between the United States and Germany in: (1) common defense, (2) a shared commitment to a free and unified Europe, and (3) an expanding economic prosperity under the rule of law throughout Europe. </p> <p>Expresses to the people of Germany an appreciation for their commitment to the promotion of freedom through leadership in providing international assistance, support for peacekeeping efforts, and acceptance of refugees. </p> <p>Reaffirms the friendship between the government and people of the United States and the government and people of Germany.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
