<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="sres" measure-number="606" measure-id="id114sres606" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-09-29" update-date="2016-10-05">
<title>A resolution honoring the memories and legacies of the 3 law enforcement officers who lost their lives in the attack on July 17, 2016, in Baton Rouge, Louisiana, condemning that attack, and recognizing the heroism of law enforcement personnel and first responders.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114sres606v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-10-05">
<action-date>2016-09-29</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Condemns the attack in Baton Rouge, Louisiana, on July 17, 2016.</p> <p>Honors the memory of the law enforcement officers who lost their lives.</p> <p>Recognizes the bravery, heroism, and dedication of law enforcement officials, emergency medical responders, and other individuals who offered support and assistance.</p> <p>Offers condolences to the families, friends, and loved ones of the victims.</p> <p>Expresses hope for the full recovery of individuals who were wounded.</p> <p>Stands united against violence and in support of individuals who work to protect communities and keep the United States safe.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
