<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="sres" measure-number="485" measure-id="id114sres485" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-06-09" update-date="2016-10-07">
<title>A resolution urging the Government of the Democratic Republic of the Congo to comply with constitutional limits on presidential terms and fulfill its constitutional mandate for a democratic transition of power in 2016.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114sres485v35" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-10-07">
<action-date>2016-09-13</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed Senate amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the Senate on July 14, 2016. The summary of that version is repeated here.)</p> <p>Expresses concern with respect to the failure of the Democratic Republic of the Congo (DRC) to take actions required to hold elections in November 2016 as required by its Constitution.</p> <p>Recognizes that impunity and lack of effective rule of law undermine democracy and that the arrest and detention of civil society activists and the harassment of political opponents close political space and repress peaceful dissent. </p> <p>Reaffirms support for democracy and good governance in sub-Saharan Africa.</p> <p>Calls on the DRC government and all other parties to respect the Constitution of the DRC and ensure a free, open, peaceful, and democratic transition of power. Urges such government to demonstrate leadership and commitment to elections by accelerating concrete steps towards holding elections, including registering voters and protecting partisan political speech and activities.</p> <p>Encourages such government and all other relevant parties to engage in a focused discussion to advance the electoral process and reach consensus on the way forward by establishing a detailed electoral calendar for all elections and enabling the candidate selection and campaign process.</p> <p>Urges the President of the United States, in close coordination with regional and international partners, to:</p> <ul> <li> continuously verify that such necessary technical dialogue occurs and proceeds in a time and manner required to ensure the conduct of timely elections; </li> <li> use appropriate means to ensure the objectives of this resolution, which may include imposition of additional targeted sanctions on individuals or entities responsible for violence and human rights violations and undermining democratic processes in the DRC; and </li> <li> continue U.S. policy with respect to providing support for the organizing of free, fair, and peaceful national elections.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114sres485v01" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-08-09">
<action-date>2016-07-14</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to Senate amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Expresses concern with respect to the failure of the Democratic Republic of the Congo (DRC) to take actions required to hold elections in November 2016 as required by its Constitution.</p> <p>Recognizes that impunity and lack of effective rule of law undermine democracy and that the arrest and detention of civil society activists and the harassment of political opponents close political space and repress peaceful dissent. </p> <p>Reaffirms support for democracy and good governance in sub-Saharan Africa.</p> <p>Calls on the DRC government and all other parties to respect the Constitution of the DRC and ensure a free, open, peaceful, and democratic transition of power. Urges such government to demonstrate leadership and commitment to elections by accelerating concrete steps towards holding elections, including registering voters and protecting partisan political speech and activities.</p> <p>Encourages such government and all other relevant parties to engage in a focused discussion to advance the electoral process and reach consensus on the way forward by establishing a detailed electoral calendar for all elections and enabling the candidate selection and campaign process.</p> <p>Urges the President of the United States, in close coordination with regional and international partners, to:</p> <ul> <li> continuously verify that such necessary technical dialogue occurs and proceeds in a time and manner required to ensure the conduct of timely elections; </li> <li> use appropriate means to ensure the objectives of this resolution, which may include imposition of additional targeted sanctions on individuals or entities responsible for violence and human rights violations and undermining democratic processes in the DRC; and </li> <li> continue U.S. policy with respect to providing support for the organizing of free, fair, and peaceful national elections.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114sres485v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-08-09">
<action-date>2016-06-09</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Urges: (1) the government of the Democratic Republic of the Congo (DRC) and all other relevant parties to engage in a credible, independently monitored, and technical dialogue to reach consensus on a way forward on establishing a detailed electoral calendar and organizing elections; and (2) such government to respect the constitution of the DRC and ensure a free, open, peaceful, and democratic transition of power.</p> <p>Expresses solidarity with the people of the DRC to choose their own government in an atmosphere free of violence, threats, and intimidation. Calls for the release of Fred Bauma and Yves Makwambala.</p> <p>Commits to maintain vigilance and scrutiny of the electoral process in the DRC.</p> <p>Pledges to examine continuously the use of all appropriate means to ensure the objectives of this resolution, including the imposition of targeted sanctions on individuals or entities responsible for violence and human rights violations and for undermining democratic processes in the DRC.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
