<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="sres" measure-number="284" measure-id="id114sres284" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-10-08" update-date="2015-10-15">
<title>A resolution recognizing the importance of mental health globally and highlighting the contributions and value of mental health, psychosocial support, and human capacity, particularly in development contexts and humanitarian settings.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114sres284v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-10-15">
<action-date>2015-10-08</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p> Recognizes the importance of World Mental Health Day.</p> <p>Affirms the continued support of the United States for making resources available to provide mental health services and build capacity, particularly in countries affected by conflict and crisis.</p> <p>Honors the importance of trained mental health workers as they enhance human well-being and mental health, restore functioning, and save lives through mental health and psychosocial support services.</p> <p>Calls on relevant agencies to integrate mental health and psychosocial support services into programs, funding opportunities, and budget allocations in order to improve quality of life for individuals living with mental health disorders.</p> <p>Commends the dedication of those who work to improve the mental health of all individuals, and the important contributions and bravery of individuals who live with or have overcome mental health disorders.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
