<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="sres" measure-number="222" measure-id="id114sres222" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-07-13" update-date="2015-09-21">
<title>A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate that the Federation Internationale de Football Association should immediately eliminate gender pay inequity and treat all athletes with the same respect and dignity.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114sres222v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-09-21">
<action-date>2015-07-13</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Urges: (1) the Federation Internationale de Football Association to eliminate gender pay inequity and treat all athletes with respect and dignity; and (2) all other local, state, federal, and international organizations to eliminate gender pay inequity.</p> <p>Expresses support for an end to gender pay inequity in the workplace, including athletic competitions.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
