<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="sres" measure-number="121" measure-id="id114sres121" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-03-26" update-date="2015-04-23">
<title>A resolution amending rule XV of the Standing Rules of the Senate to provide for consideration of a minimum number of amendments.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114sres121v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-04-23">
<action-date>2015-03-26</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Amends Rule XV (Standing Committees) of the Standing Rules of the Senate to make it in order in the Senate during the consideration of any bill, resolution, or other amendable matter to consider at least five germane amendments offered each by the majority and by the minority.</p> <p>Specifies a general procedure for the offering of these amendments if cloture is invoked before either the majority or the minority has offered all five of its minimum number of amendments.</p> <p>Allows exemption from this germaneness requirement for one amendment offered by a member of the majority and one amendment offered by a member of the minority, but only upon the agreement of three-fifths of all Senators.</p>  <p>Authorizes the majority leader and minority leader, by mutual agreement, to call up additional germane amendments under this Rule in equal number by members of the majority and of the minority.</p> <p>Limits consideration of such an amendment by the Senate to two hours, divided equally between the majority and the minority.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
