<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="sres" measure-number="280" measure-id="id114sres280" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-10-07" update-date="2015-10-14">
<title>A resolution recognizing the month of October 2015 as "National Women's Small Business Month".</title>
<summary summary-id="id114sres280v82" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-10-14">
<action-date>2015-10-07</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed Senate without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.)</p> <p>Recognizes: (1) October 2015 as National Women's Small Business Month; (2) the significant contributions of women small business owners and women entrepreneurs to the small business community; and (3) the importance of creating policies that promote a business-friendly environment for small business owners free of unnecessary regulations and red tape.</p> <p>Honors the vital role of U.S. women small business owners and entrepreneurs during such Month.</p> <p>Supports and encourages young women entrepreneurs to pursue their passions and create more start-up businesses.</p> <p>Supports efforts to increase awareness of the value of women-owned small businesses on the U.S. economy.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114sres280v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-10-13">
<action-date>2015-10-07</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Recognizes: (1) October 2015 as National Women's Small Business Month, (2) the significant contributions of women small business owners and women entrepreneurs to the small business community, and (3) the importance of creating policies that promote a business-friendly environment for small business owners free of unnecessary regulations and red tape.</p> <p>Honors the vital role of U.S. women small business owners and entrepreneurs during this Month.</p> <p>Supports and encourages young women entrepreneurs to pursue their passions and create more start-up businesses.</p> <p>Supports efforts to increase awareness of the value of women-owned small businesses on the U.S. economy.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
