<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="sres" measure-number="566" measure-id="id114sres566" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-09-15" update-date="2016-09-21">
<title>A resolution supporting the goals and ideals of National Domestic Violence Awareness Month, commending domestic violence victim advocates, domestic violence victim service providers, crisis hotline staff, and first responders serving victims of domestic violence for their compassionate support of victims of domestic violence, and expressing the sense of the Senate that Congress should continue to support efforts to end domestic violence and hold perpetrators of domestic violence accountable.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114sres566v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-09-21">
<action-date>2016-09-15</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Supports the goals and ideals of National Domestic Violence Awareness Month.</p> <p>Expresses the sense of the Senate that Congress should: (1) continue to raise awareness of domestic violence in the United States and the corresponding devasting effects of domestic violence on survivors, families, and communities; and (2) pledge continued support for programs designed to assist survivors, hold perpetrators accountable, and bring an end to domestic violence.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114sres566v82" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-09-21">
<action-date>2016-09-15</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed Senate without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.)</p> <p>Supports the goals and ideals of National Domestic Violence Awareness Month.</p> <p>Expresses the sense of the Senate that Congress should: (1) continue to raise awareness of domestic violence in the United States and the corresponding devastating effects of domestic violence on survivors, families, and communities; and (2) pledge continued support for programs designed to assist survivors, hold perpetrators accountable, and bring an end to domestic violence.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
