<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="sres" measure-number="542" measure-id="id114sres542" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-07-14" update-date="2016-10-20">
<title>A resolution recognizing the 70th anniversary and the importance of the Lanham Act by designating July 2016 as "National Anti-Counterfeiting Consumer Education and Awareness Month".</title>
<summary summary-id="id114sres542v82" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-10-20">
<action-date>2016-07-14</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed Senate without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.)</p> <p>Recognizes the 70th anniversary of the signing of the Trademark Act of 1946 (the Lanham Act) by President Harry S. Truman.</p> <p>Designates July 2016 as National Anti-Counterfeiting Consumer Education and Awareness Month. Expresses support for the goal of such month: to educate the public about the potential dangers counterfeit products pose to consumer health and safety.</p> <p>Affirms the continuing importance and need for comprehensive education and awareness efforts to equip U.S. consumers with the information and tools they need to safeguard against illegal counterfeit products in traditional and Internet commerce and other electronic commerce platforms.</p> <p>Reaffirms the U.S. commitment to combating counterfeiting by promoting: (1) awareness about the harm of counterfeiting to consumers and brand owners, and (2) new education programs and campaigns to reduce the supply of and demand for counterfeit products.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114sres542v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-10-20">
<action-date>2016-07-14</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Recognizes the 70th anniversary of the signing of the Trademark Act of 1946 (the Lanham Act) by President Harry S. Truman.</p> <p>Designates July 2016 as National Anti-Counterfeiting Consumer Education and Awareness Month. Expresses support for the goal of such month: to educate the public about the potential dangers counterfeit products pose to consumer health and safety.</p> <p>Affirms the continuing importance and need for comprehensive education and awareness efforts to equip U.S. consumers with the information and tools they need to safeguard against illegal counterfeit products in traditional and Internet commerce and other electronic commerce platforms.</p> <p>Reaffirms the U.S. commitment to combating counterfeiting by promoting: (1) awareness about the harm of counterfeiting to consumers and brand owners, and (2) new education programs and campaigns to reduce the supply of and demand for counterfeit products.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
