<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="sres" measure-number="120" measure-id="id114sres120" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-03-26" update-date="2015-04-30">
<title>A resolution modifying extended debate in the Senate to improve the legislative process.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114sres120v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-04-30">
<action-date>2015-03-26</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Amends Rule XXII (Precedence of Motions) of the Standing Rules of the Senate to consider cloture of debate to have been invoked unless one more than two-fifths of all Senators votes in the negative. (The two-thirds affirmative vote requirement remains for measures or motions to amend the Senate rules.)</p> <p>Declares that cloture fails, and it is in order for the Majority Leader (or a designee) to initiate extended debate on the measure in question, if the vote to close debate is decided in the affirmative by a majority of Senators voting, a quorum being present, and in the negative by more than two-fifths of all Senators.</p> <p>Prescribes related procedures with respect to extended debate.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
