<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="sres" measure-number="520" measure-id="id114sres520" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-07-07" update-date="2016-10-13">
<title>A resolution reaffirming the strong relationship, both in defense and trade, between the United States and the United Kingdom.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114sres520v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-10-13">
<action-date>2016-07-07</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Reaffirms that the special relationship between the United States and the United Kingdom will not be affected by the outcome of the June 23, 2016, European Union membership referendum or by changes to the United Kingdom's relationship with the European Union.</p> <p>Recognizes that continued defense and intelligence cooperation between the United States and the United Kingdom is vital to the national security of both countries.</p> <p>Expresses support for the continued political and military leadership displayed by both nations in the North Atlantic Treaty Organization.</p> <p>Urges the President to commence discussions with the government of the United Kingdom, at its request, to ensure the continuance of the current bilateral trade relationship and, as necessary, negotiations for the development of a free-trade agreement between the two countries. </p> <ul> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
