<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="sres" measure-number="581" measure-id="id114sres581" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-09-27" update-date="2016-10-21">
<title>No Vote No Recess Resolution</title>
<summary summary-id="id114sres581v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-10-21">
<action-date>2016-09-27</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>No Vote No Recess Resolution</strong></p> <p>Prohibits the Senate, between September 27, 2016, and the end of the 114th Congress, from adjourning, remaining adjourned, or recessing for more than two days and convening solely in a pro forma session unless, by the beginning of the adjournment or the pro forma session, it has taken action on any presidential nomination for a position as a justice of the U.S. Supreme Court by:</p> <UL> <li>holding a hearing and a vote on the nomination in the Senate Committee on the Judiciary, and</li> <li>holding a confirmation vote on it in the full Senate.</li> </UL> <p>Prescribes procedures for Senate adjournments and recesses during such period. </p> <p>Prohibits the Presiding Officer from entertaining a request to suspend the operation of this resolution by unanimous consent or motion.</p> <p>States that nothing in this resolution shall be construed in a manner that is inconsistent with S. Res. 296 (108th Congress) or any other Senate emergency procedures or practices.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
