<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="sres" measure-number="180" measure-id="id114sres180" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-19" update-date="2015-06-08">
<title>A resolution urging additional sanctions against the Democratic People's Republic of Korea, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114sres180v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-06-08">
<action-date>2015-05-19</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Finds that North Korea: (1) represents a serious threat to the national security of the United States and its allies in East Asia, and to international peace and stability; and (2) violates the human rights of its own people.</p> <p> Urges the Secretary of State and the Secretary of the Treasury to impose additional sanctions against North Korea, targeting its financial assets and its redesignation as a state sponsor of terror. </p> <p>Warns the President against resuming negotiations with North Korea, either bilaterally or as part of the Six Party talks, without strict pre-conditions, including that North Korea: (1) adhere to its denuclearization commitments outlined in the 2005 Joint Statement of the Six-Party talks, (2) commit to halting its ballistic missile and proliferation activities, (3) cease military provocations, and (4) improve its human rights record.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
