<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="sres" measure-number="535" measure-id="id114sres535" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-07-14" update-date="2016-10-31">
<title>A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate regarding the trafficking of illicit fentanyl into the United States from Mexico and China.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114sres535v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-10-31">
<action-date>2016-07-14</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Expresses the sense of the Senate that:</p> <ul> <li> the use of illicit fentanyl in the United States and the resulting overdose deaths are a public health crisis;</li> <li> the trafficking of illicit fentanyl into the United States, especially by transnational criminal organizations, is a problem that requires close cooperation between the U.S. government and the governments of Mexico and China; and </li> <li>all three such countries should develop joint actions to stop such trafficking.</li> </ul> <p>Calls for the United States to:</p> <ul> <li>support the efforts of, and use its diplomatic and law enforcement resources in partnership with, the governments of Mexico and China to stop such trafficking;</li> <li> take further measures to reduce and prevent heroin and fentanyl consumption through the use of evidence-based prevention, treatment, and recovery services; and </li> <li>provide access to treatment and rehabilitation to help individuals with substance use disorders recover.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
