<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="sres" measure-number="81" measure-id="id114sres81" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-02-12" update-date="2015-03-04">
<title>A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate that children trafficked for sex in the United States should not be treated or regarded as child prostitutes because there is no such thing as a "child prostitute", only children who are victims or survivors of rape and sex trafficking.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114sres81v82" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-03-04">
<action-date>2015-02-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed Senate without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.)</p> <p>Encourages: (1) all federal entities to treat children trafficked for sex as victims or survivors of rape and sex trafficking; and (2) lawmakers, law enforcement, the media, and the public to reframe the trafficking of children for sex as an act of violence against children.</p> <p>Expresses support for: (1) efforts to arrest and prosecute sex traffickers and buyers of children trafficked for sex in accordance with applicable state and federal sex trafficking statutes and state child protection laws; (2) survivors of child sex trafficking and efforts to raise awareness of the comprehensive services necessary to heal from the trauma of sexual violence and exploitation; and (3) ending the demand for children in the commercial sex market by ensuring that children in the United States are not for sale and that any person who is trafficking or purchasing a child for sex is punished under the full force of the law.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114sres81v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-03-04">
<action-date>2015-02-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Encourages: (1) all federal entities to treat children trafficked for sex as victims or survivors of rape and sex trafficking; and (2) lawmakers, law enforcement, the media, and the public to reframe the trafficking of children for sex as an act of violence against children.</p> <p>Expresses support for: (1) efforts to arrest and prosecute sex traffickers and buyers of children trafficked for sex in accordance with applicable state and federal sex trafficking statutes and state child protection laws; (2) survivors of child sex trafficking and efforts to raise awareness of the comprehensive services necessary to heal from the trauma of sexual violence and exploitation; and (3) ending the demand for children in the commercial sex market by ensuring that children in the United States are not for sale and that any person who is trafficking or purchasing a child for sex is punished under the full force of the law.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
