<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="sres" measure-number="370" measure-id="id114sres370" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-02-10" update-date="2016-02-23">
<title>A resolution recognizing that for nearly 40 years, the United States and the Association of South East Asian Nations (ASEAN) have worked toward stability, prosperity, and peace in Southeast Asia.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114sres370v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-02-23">
<action-date>2016-02-10</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Welcomes the leaders of the Association of South East Asian Nations (ASEAN) to the United States for the February 2016 U.S.-ASEAN summit meeting at Rancho Mirage, California.</p> <p> Supports the elevation of the United States-ASEAN relationship to a strategic partnership and recommits the United States to ASEAN centrality. </p> <p>Urges ASEAN to continue its efforts to foster greater integration and unity. </p> <p>Supports efforts by ASEAN nations to address maritime and territorial disputes through peaceful, diplomatic, and legitimate regional and international arbitration mechanisms. </p> <p>Urges all parties to maritime and territorial disputes in the Asia-Pacific region to: (1) respect the status quo; (2) cease land reclamation activities; and (3) refrain from inhabiting or garrisoning or otherwise militarizing uninhabited islands, reefs, shoals, and other features. </p> <p>Opposes: (1) unilateral declarations of administrative and military districts in contested areas in the South China Sea, (2) the imposition of new fishing regulations covering disputed areas in the South China Sea, and (3) actions to prevent another country from exercising its sovereign rights to the resources of the exclusive economic zone and continental shelf.</p> <p>Urges parties to refrain from unilateral actions that cause permanent physical change to the marine environment.</p> <p>Supports efforts by ASEAN and China to develop an effective Code of Conduct. </p> <p>Urges ASEAN to reaffirm the decision of the Permanent Court of Arbitration in The Hague's ruling with respect to the case between the Philippines and China. </p> <p>Supports efforts by U.S. partners and allies in ASEAN to enhance the maritime capabilities of a country or regional organizations to respond to emerging maritime threats and illegal activities in the Asia-Pacific region.</p> <p>Reaffirms the enhancement of U.S.-ASEAN economic engagement, including the elimination of barriers to cross-border commerce.</p> <p>Supports: (1) the Lower Mekong Initiative, (2) the Young Southeast Asian Leaders Initiative, and (3) capacity building for the promotion of human rights. </p> <p>Reaffirms the commitment of the United States to continue joint efforts with ASEAN to halt human smuggling and trafficking of persons. </p> <p>Encourages the President to communicate to ASEAN leaders the importance of releasing political prisoners and ending politically motivated prosecutions.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
