<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="sres" measure-number="562" measure-id="id114sres562" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-09-15" update-date="2016-10-20">
<title>A resolution expressing support for designation of the week of October 9, 2016, through October 15, 2016, as "Earth Science Week".</title>
<summary summary-id="id114sres562v82" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-10-20">
<action-date>2016-09-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed Senate without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.)</p> <p>Supports the designation of the week of October 9-15, 2016, as Earth Science Week.</p> <p>Expresses strong support for the goals and ideals of Earth Science Week to increase understanding of and interest in the earth sciences at the local, state, national, and international levels. </p> <p>Recognizes the importance of education and public outreach efforts to ensure that the people of the United States gain a better understanding of and appreciation for the impact of the earth sciences on their daily lives. </p> <p>Encourages K-12 students to participate in local, state, and national events in connection with Earth Science Week and to get involved in the celebration by exploring artistic and academic applications of the earth sciences. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114sres562v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-10-20">
<action-date>2016-09-15</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Supports the designation of the week of October 9-15, 2016, as Earth Science Week.</p> <p>Expresses strong support for the goals and ideals of Earth Science Week to increase understanding of and interest in the earth sciences at the local, state, national, and international levels. </p> <p>Recognizes the importance of education and public outreach efforts to ensure that the people of the United States gains a better understanding and appreciation for the impact of the earth sciences on their daily lives. </p> <p>Encourages K-12 students to participate in local, state, and national events in connection with Earth Science Week and to get involved in the celebration by exploring artistic and academic applications of the earth sciences. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
