<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="sres" measure-number="183" measure-id="id114sres183" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-21" update-date="2015-05-28">
<title>A resolution calling for suspension of construction of artificial land formations on islands, reefs, shoals, and other features of the Spratly Islands and for a peaceful and multilateral resolution to the South China Sea territorial dispute.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114sres183v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-05-28">
<action-date>2015-05-21</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Condemns China's unilateral construction of artificial land formations in the disputed Spratly Islands. </p> <p>Urges all parties to maritime and territorial disputes in the region to respect the status quo, exercise self-restraint in the conduct of activities that would undermine stability or escalate disputes, refrain from inhabiting or garrisoning presently uninhabited islands, reefs, shoals, and other features, and refrain from unilateral actions that cause permanent physical change to the marine environment pending final delimitation. </p> <p>Urges China to clarify: (1) the meaning of its &quot;nine dash line&quot; claim and the maritime areas it claims within that space, and (2) its intentions with respect to establishing &quot;necessary military defense&quot; on reclaimed features. </p> <p>Reaffirms U.S. support for the member states of the Association of Southeast Asian Nations as they seek to develop a code of conduct of parties in the South China Sea with China, and urges China to enter into such negotiations in a serious manner. </p> <p>Supports: (1) efforts to strengthen regional maritime domain awareness; (2) efforts to strengthen maritime partner capacity, including through the sale and transfer of technology that promotes maritime domain awareness; and (3) continuation of U.S. Armed Forces operations in support of freedom of navigation rights in international waters and air space in the South China Sea.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
