<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="sres" measure-number="167" measure-id="id114sres167" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-05" update-date="2015-05-07">
<title>A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate regarding the courageous work and life of Argentinian prosecutor Alberto Nisman, and calling for a swift and transparent investigation into his tragic death in Buenos Aires on January 18, 2015.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114sres167v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-05-07">
<action-date>2015-05-05</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Offers condolences to the family of Argentinian prosecutor Alberto Nisman.</p> <p> Recognizes Mr. Nisman's courageous work in dedicating his life to the investigation of the bombing of the Argentine Israelite Mutual Association (AMIA) in Buenos Aires, Argentina, which killed 85 people and wounded more than 300. </p> <p>Calls for a swift, transparent, and internationally backed investigation into Mr. Nisman's death, and encourages the public release of the investigation's results.</p> <p>Urges the President to offer technical assistance to the government of Argentina in solving Mr. Nisman's death, as well as the ongoing investigation of the AMIA bombing. </p> <p>Expresses serious concern about: (1) Iran's terrorist network in Argentina, the United States, and all of the Western Hemisphere; and (2) attempts by President Cristina Kirchner and her government to discredit Mr. Nisman and raise unfounded hypotheses on Mr. Nisman's findings and death. </p> <p>Urges the President to to monitor Iran's activities in Latin America and the Caribbean, as is mandated by the Countering Iran in the Western Hemisphere Act of 2012.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
