<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="sres" measure-number="329" measure-id="id114sres329" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-12-07" update-date="2015-12-08">
<title>A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate regarding an agreement reached at the United Nations Climate Change Conference held in Paris in December 2015.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114sres329v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-12-08">
<action-date>2015-12-07</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Expresses the sense of the Senate that a protocol, amendment, extension, or other agreement (agreement) relating to the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change, entered into force March 21, 1994, shall have no force or effect in the United States and no funds shall be authorized in its support, including for the Green Climate Fund, until it has been submitted to Senate for advice and consent, if the agreement: </p> <ul> <li> fulfills mitigation commitments through existing and future regulations that would put our national industries at a disadvantage compared to the industries of developing countries; </li> <li>includes a financial commitment that will not go into effect without subsequent congressional legislation or authorization; </li> <li>represents an agreement to be overseen by an international administrative entity covering a wide range of topics, including mitigation, adaptation, finance, technology transfer, capacity building, transparency, implementation, and compliance; or </li> <li>establishes a mechanism to assess contributions or commitments for future compliance.</li></ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
