<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="sres" measure-number="139" measure-id="id114sres139" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-04-16" update-date="2015-05-20">
<title>A resolution commemorating the 20th anniversary of the attack on the Alfred P. Murrah Federal Building.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114sres139v82" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-05-20">
<action-date>2015-04-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed Senate without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.)</p> <p>Sends best wishes to the families, friends, and neighbors of the 168 people killed in the April 19, 1995, terrorist bombing of the Alfred P. Murrah Federal Building in Oklahoma City, Oklahoma. Expresses gratitude for the recovery of those injured in the bombing.</p> <p>Thanks the first responders, rescue workers, medical personnel, and volunteers who answered the call for help that morning and in the weeks that followed.</p> <p>Declares that the Senate, on the 20th anniversary of that day, resolves to work with the people of the United States to promote the goals and mission established by the Oklahoma City National Memorial.</p> <p>Commends the people of Oklahoma City for their progress over the past two decades, for demonstrating their commitment to the ability of hope to triumph over violence, and for their perseverance in standing for the strength of goodness in overcoming evil.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114sres139v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-05-20">
<action-date>2015-04-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Sends best wishes to the families, friends, and neighbors of the 168 people killed in the April 19, 1995, terrorist bombing of the Alfred P. Murrah Federal Building in Oklahoma City, Oklahoma. Expresses gratitude for the recovery of those injured in the bombing.</p> <p>Thanks the first responders, rescue workers, medical personnel, and volunteers who answered the call for help that morning and in the weeks that followed.</p> <p>Declares that the Senate, on the 20th anniversary of that day, resolves to work with the people of the United States to promote the goals and mission established by the Oklahoma City National Memorial.</p> <p>Commends the people of Oklahoma City for their progress over the past two decades, for demonstrating their commitment to the ability of hope to triumph over violence, and for their perseverance in standing for the strength of goodness in overcoming evil.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
