<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="sres" measure-number="29" measure-id="id114sres29" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-01-20" update-date="2015-01-23">
<title>A resolution condemning the terrorist attacks in Paris, offering condolences to the families of the victims, expressing solidarity with the people of France, and reaffirming fundamental freedom of expression.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114sres29v82" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-01-23">
<action-date>2015-01-20</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed Senate without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.)</b></p> <p>Condemns the terrorist attacks and murders at the French newspaper <i>Charlie Hebdo</i> and the kosher market Hyper Cacher in Paris. </p> <p>Expresses: (1) condolences to the families of the victims and to the Republic of France; and (2) solidarity with the people of the Republic of France, and pays tribute to our shared values, ideals, and liberties, including the freedom of thought and expression and freedom of the press. </p> <p>Recognizes the statements from Muslim majority nations and leaders across the world that terrorist attacks purportedly conducted in Islam's name, such as the Paris attacks, are an affront to the Muslim faith. </p> <p>Reaffirms the support of the House of Representatives for the government of France to bring the perpetrators of this violence to justice and to prevent future attacks.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114sres29v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-01-23">
<action-date>2015-01-20</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Condemns the terrorist attacks and murders at the French newspaper <i>Charlie Hebdo</i> and the kosher market Hyper Cacher in Paris. </p> <p>Expresses: (1) condolences to the families of the victims and to the Republic of France; and (2) solidarity with the people of the Republic of France, and pays tribute to our shared values, ideals, and liberties, including the freedom of thought and expression and freedom of the press. </p> <p>Recognizes the statements from Muslim majority nations and leaders across the world that terrorist attacks purportedly conducted in Islam's name, such as the Paris attacks, are an affront to the Muslim faith. </p> <p>Reaffirms the support of the House of Representatives for the government of France to bring the perpetrators of this violence to justice and to prevent future attacks.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
