<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="sres" measure-number="264" measure-id="id114sres264" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-09-22" update-date="2015-09-30">
<title>A resolution designating September 23, 2015, as "National Falls Prevention Awareness Day" to raise awareness and encourage the prevention of falls among older adults.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114sres264v82" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-09-30">
<action-date>2015-09-22</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed Senate without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.)</p> <p>Designates September 23, 2015, as National Falls Prevention Awareness Day. </p> <p>Recognizes that there are cost-effective falls prevention programs and policies. </p> <p>Commends the Falls Free Coalition and others for their efforts to increase awareness of falls prevention.</p> <p>Urges the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, the Administration for Community Living, and others to continue developing, evaluating, and promoting interventions and programs to prevent falls.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114sres264v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-09-25">
<action-date>2015-09-22</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Designates September 23, 2015, as National Falls Prevention Awareness Day. </p> <p>Recognizes that there are cost-effective falls prevention programs and policies. </p> <p>Commends the Falls Free Coalition and others for their efforts to increase awareness of falls prevention.</p> <p>Urges the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, the Administration for Community Living, and others to continue developing, evaluating, and promoting interventions and programs to prevent falls.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
