<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="sres" measure-number="320" measure-id="id114sres320" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-11-19" update-date="2016-01-04">
<title>A resolution congratulating the people of Burma on their commitment to peaceful elections.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114sres320v35" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-01-04">
<action-date>2015-12-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed Senate amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the Senate on December 10, 2015. The summary of that version is repeated here.)</p> <p>Congratulates the people of Burma for embracing democracy through their participation in the November 8, 2015, general elections and for their efforts in developing a democratic society.</p> <p>Recognizes the National League for Democracy's victory as a reflection of the will of the Burmese people. </p> <p>Calls on the Union Solidarity Development Party to undertake a peaceful transfer of power to a new government.</p> <p>Encourages all parties to pursue national reconciliation talks.</p> <p>Recognizes that important impediments remain to the realization of full democratic and civilian government in Burma, including the reservation of unelected seats for the military and the disenfranchisement of groups including the Rohingya. </p> <p>Calls on the government of Burma to support meaningful efforts to reform the 2008 Constitution of Burma. </p> <p> Encourages the President to ensure that any changes in U.S. policy toward Burma, including the relaxation of any restrictions, are aligned with support for genuine democratic transition.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114sres320v01" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-12-15">
<action-date>2015-12-10</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to Senate amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Congratulates the people of Burma for embracing democracy through their participation in the November 8, 2015, general elections and for their efforts in developing a democratic society.</p> <p>Recognizes the National League for Democracy's victory as a reflection of the will of the Burmese people. </p> <p>Calls on the Union Solidarity Development Party to undertake a peaceful transfer of power to a new government.</p> <p>Encourages all parties to pursue national reconciliation talks.</p> <p>Recognizes that important impediments remain to the realization of full democratic and civilian government in Burma, including the reservation of unelected seats for the military and the disenfranchisement of groups including the Rohingya. </p> <p>Calls on the government of Burma to support meaningful efforts to reform the 2008 Constitution of Burma. </p> <p> Encourages the President to ensure that any changes in U.S. policy toward Burma, including the relaxation of any restrictions, are aligned with support for genuine democratic transition.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114sres320v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-11-25">
<action-date>2015-11-19</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Congratulates the people of Burma for embracing democracy through their participation in the November 8, 2015, general elections and for their efforts in developing a democratic society.</p> <p>Recognizes the National League for Democracy's victory as a reflection of the will of the Burmese people. </p> <p>Calls on the Union Solidarity Development Party to undertake a peaceful transfer of power to a new government.</p> <p>Encourages all parties to pursue national reconciliation talks.</p> <p>Recognizes that important impediments remain to the realization of full democratic and civilian government, including the reservation of unelected seats for the military and the disenfranchisement of groups including the Rohingya. </p> <p>Calls on the government of Burma to support meaningful efforts to reform the 2008 Constitution of Burma. </p> <p>Supports negotiations between the government of Burma and ethnic-based peoples and organizations. </p> <p>Encourages the President to take further steps toward normalization of relations with Burma. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
