<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="sres" measure-number="552" measure-id="id114sres552" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-09-12" update-date="2016-10-31">
<title>A resolution commemorating the fifteenth anniversary of NATO's invocation of Article V to defend the United States following the terrorist attacks of September 11, 2001.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114sres552v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-10-31">
<action-date>2016-09-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Commemorates the 15th anniversary of NATO's invocation of Article V to defend the United States after the terrorist attacks of September 11, 2001.</p> <p>Commends: (1) the contributions of the NATO allies and partners of the United States in the fight against terrorism and in pursuit of international security, and (2) the NATO alliance for decisions taken at the July 2016 Warsaw Summit and the President for investing in the European Reassurance Initiative to enhance deterrence and project international stability beyond NATO.</p> <p>Honors those men and women who have died for the cause of common defense of the North Atlantic Treaty allies.</p> <p>Recommits the United States to the treaty, especially to common defense of treaty allies, and affirms that the United States remains fully prepared, capable, and willing to honor its commitments under Article V.</p> <p>Encourages all NATO allies to continue their valuable contributions to the alliance, including by investing at least 2% of gross domestic product in national defense spending.</p> <p>Reaffirms the U.S. commitment to deterring those who seek to destabilize the Euro-Atlantic area and to maintaining an &quot;Open Door&quot; policy on welcoming new members. Welcomes the alliance's invitation to Montenegro.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
