<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="sres" measure-number="109" measure-id="id114sres109" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-03-24" update-date="2015-05-27">
<title>A resolution acknowledging and honoring brave young men from Hawaii who enabled the United States to establish and maintain jurisdiction in remote equatorial islands as prolonged conflict in the Pacific led to World War II.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114sres109v82" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-05-27">
<action-date>2015-05-21</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed Senate without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.)</p> <p>Honors the accomplishments of the Hui Panala 'au colonists and the young men who helped secure and maintain U.S. jurisdiction over equatorial islands in the Pacific Ocean during the years leading up to and the months immediately following the bombing of Pearl Harbor and the entry of the United States into World War II.</p> <p>Acknowledges the local, national, and international significance of the seven-year colonization of such islands by the United States, which resulted in the United States extending sovereignty into the Equatorial Pacific. </p> <p>Recognizes the dedication of the young men, the majority of whom were Native Hawaiian, who participated in the Equatorial Pacific colonization project.</p> <p>Extends condolences to the families of Carl Kahalewai, Joseph Keliihananui, and Richard Whaley for the loss of their loved ones in the service of the United States.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114sres109v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-04-10">
<action-date>2015-03-24</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Honors the accomplishments of the Hui Panala 'au colonists and the young men who helped secure and maintain U.S. jurisdiction over equatorial islands in the Pacific Ocean during the years leading up to and the months immediately following the bombing of Pearl Harbor and the entry of the United States into World War II.</p> <p>Acknowledges the local, national, and international significance of the seven-year colonization of such islands by the United States, which resulted in the United States extending sovereignty into the Equatorial Pacific. </p> <p>Recognizes the dedication of the young men, the majority of whom were Native Hawaiian, who participated in the Equatorial Pacific colonization project.</p> <p>Extends condolences to the families of Carl Kahalewai, Joseph Keliihananui, and Richard Whaley for the loss of their loved ones in the service of the United States. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
