<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="sres" measure-number="391" measure-id="id114sres391" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-03-08" update-date="2016-03-09">
<title>A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate to oppose the transfer of foreign enemy combatants from the detention facilities at United States Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba, to the United States homeland.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114sres391v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-03-09">
<action-date>2016-03-08</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Rejects the ``Plan to Close Guantanamo Bay Detention Facility,'' presented by the President on February 23, 2016, to transfer, release, or assist in the transfer or release to the U.S. homeland of detainees at United States Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba.</p> <p>Determines that any attempt by the President to undertake such release or transfer is in direct violation of specified public laws.</p> <p>Finds that the Guantanamo Bay detention facility is the optimal location to house dangerous foreign enemy combatants and should not be closed. </p> <p>Asserts that any potential transfer or release to the U.S. homeland of Guantanamo detainees represents a national security threat due to the risk of providing law of war detainees with constitutional rights and protections, including the potential for release into the United States, and, particularly, a threat to the security of local communities in Kansas, Colorado, and South Carolina.</p> <p>Demands that the President abandon any plans to transfer Guantanamo detainees to the U.S. homeland without explicit congressional authorization.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
