<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="sres" measure-number="310" measure-id="id114sres310" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-11-09" update-date="2016-01-04">
<title>A resolution condemning the ongoing sexual violence against women and children from Yezidi, Christian, Shabak, Turkmen, and other religious communities by Islamic State of Iraq and Syria militants and urging the prosecution of the perpetrators and those complicit in these crimes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114sres310v35" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-01-04">
<action-date>2015-12-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed Senate amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Condemns the sexual violence against women and children from Yezidi, Christian, Shabak, Turkmen, and other religious communities.</p> <p> Calls on the Attorney General to begin the investigation and prosecution of any U.S. citizens alleged to be perpetrators of or complicit in these crimes. </p> <p> Calls on the government of Iraq and the governments of other countries to arrest and prosecute individuals involved in these crimes.</p> <p> Defines &quot;complicit'' as having knowingly and willingly supported, promoted, enabled, aided, or encouraged crimes involving sexual violence against women and children from Yezidi, Christian, Shabak, Turkmen, or other religious communities by Islamic State of Iraq and Syria militants, including actions to deny, cover up, or alter evidence of such crimes. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114sres310v80" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-11-18">
<action-date>2015-11-17</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to Senate without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.)</p> <p>Condemns the sexual violence against women and children from Yezidi, Christian, Shabak, Turkmen, and other religious communities.</p> <p> Calls on the Attorney General to begin the investigation and prosecution of any U.S. citizens alleged to be perpetrators of or complicit in these crimes. </p> <p> Calls on the government of Iraq and the governments of other countries to arrest and prosecute individuals involved in these crimes.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114sres310v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-11-16">
<action-date>2015-11-09</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Condemns the sexual violence against women and children from Yezidi, Christian, Shabak, Turkmen, and other religious communities.</p> <p> Calls on the Attorney General to begin the investigation and prosecution of any U.S. citizens alleged to be perpetrators of or complicit in these crimes. </p> <p> Calls on the government of Iraq and the governments of other countries to arrest and prosecute individuals involved in these crimes.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
