<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="sres" measure-number="118" measure-id="id114sres118" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-03-26" update-date="2015-04-28">
<title>A resolution amending rule XXXI of the Standing Rules for the Senate, to provide for timely consideration of nominations.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114sres118v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-04-28">
<action-date>2015-03-26</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Amends Rule XXXI (Executive Session - Proceedings on Nominations) of the Standing Rules of the Senate to make a covered nomination eligible for expedited consideration, if it has been on the Executive Calendar for more than 14 calendar days. </p> <p>Excludes from coverage by this resolution the nomination of an individual:</p> <ul> <li>to serve as a justice, including Chief Justice, of the U.S. Supreme Court, or</li> <li> to one of several specified positions entitled to expedited procedures under S. Res. 116 (112th Congress).</li> </ul> <p>Deems the covered nomination confirmed by the Senate unless at least 10 Senators have submitted written requests that it be considered by the full Senate in executive session before the end of the 14-day period.</p> <p>Makes a covered nomination (other than to serve as a judge or justice appointed to hold office during good behavior, or to a position at level I of the Executive Schedule [Cabinet Secretaries and certain others]) eligible for expedited consideration, under similar requirements.</p> <p>Requires the Senate to proceed to executive session and begin consideration of a nomination:</p> <ul> <li> 24 hours after the majority leader provides notice that it is eligible for expedited consideration; and</li> <li>48 hours after the majority leader provides such notice of an individual to serve as a judge or justice appointed to hold office during good behavior, or to a position at level I of the Executive Schedule.</li> </ul>  <p>Limits expedited consideration of a covered nomination to:</p> <ul> <li>four hours, evenly divided in the usual form, for a nomination to serve as a judge of a circuit court of the United States or a nomination to a position at level I of the Executive Schedule; and </li> <li>two hours, evenly divided in the usual form, for any other covered nomination. </li></ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
