<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="sres" measure-number="539" measure-id="id114sres539" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2016-07-14" update-date="2016-08-05">
<title>A resolution condemning the horrific acts of violence and hatred in Dallas, Texas, on July 7, 2016, and expressing support and prayers for all those impacted by the tragedy.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114sres539v82" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-08-05">
<action-date>2016-07-14</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed Senate without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.)</p> <p>Condemns the attack on police officers that occurred in Dallas, Texas, on July 7, 2016.</p> <p>Expresses the belief that an attack upon a police officer is an affront to the rule of law and the promise of justice, domestic tranquility, common defense, and general welfare and the blessings of liberty secured by the Constitution.</p> <p>Offers condolences to the families, friends, and loved ones of those who were killed and expresses hope for the quick and complete recovery of those who were wounded.</p> <p>Applauds the bravery and dedication of the law enforcement officials, emergency medical responders, and others who offered their support and assistance.</p> <p>Declares that the Senate stands united against violence and hatred and in support of the police officers who work to keep the country safe.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114sres539v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2016-08-05">
<action-date>2016-07-14</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Condemns the attack on police officers that occurred in Dallas, Texas, on July 7, 2016.</p> <p>Expresses the belief that an attack upon a police officer is an affront to the rule of law and the promise of justice, domestic tranquility, common defense, and general welfare and the blessings of liberty secured by the Constitution.</p> <p>Offers condolences to the families, friends, and loved ones of those who were killed and expresses hope for the quick and complete recovery of those who were wounded.</p> <p>Applauds the bravery and dedication of the law enforcement officials, emergency medical responders, and others who offered their support and assistance.</p> <p>Declares that the Senate stands united against violence and hatred and in support of the police officers who work to keep the country safe.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
