<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="sres" measure-number="193" measure-id="id114sres193" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-06-04" update-date="2015-08-04">
<title>A resolution celebrating the 50th anniversary of the historic Griswold v. Connecticut decision of the Supreme Court of the United States and expressing the sense of the Senate that the case was an important step forward in helping ensure that all people of the United States are able to use contraceptives to plan pregnancies and have healthier babies.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114sres193v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-08-04">
<action-date>2015-06-04</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Celebrates the 50th anniversary of the U.S. Supreme Court decision in <em>Griswold v. Connecticut</em>.</p> <p>Recognizes the value of the publicly funded family planning safety net in helping to realize the promise of <em>Griswold </em>and that: (1) birth control constitutes basic health care for women, (2) affordable contraceptives remain inaccessible to many poor and low-income women, and (3) investments in publicly funded family planning services help prevent unplanned pregnancies and abortions and help save taxpayer dollars.</p> <p>Encourages robust investment in publicly funded family planning services as a means to help women plan pregnancies and have healthier babies.</p> <p>Acknowledges that all women should have affordable access to the tools that help women plan and space their pregnancies.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
