<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="sres" measure-number="152" measure-id="id114sres152" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-04-28" update-date="2015-04-29">
<title>A resolution recognizing threats to freedom of the press and expression around the world and reaffirming freedom of the press as a priority in efforts of the United States Government to promote democracy and good governance.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114sres152v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-04-29">
<action-date>2015-04-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Expresses concern about the threats to freedom of the press and expression around the world following World Press Freedom Day on May 3, 2015.</p> <p> Commends journalists and media workers for promoting government accountability, defending democratic activity, and strengthening civil society.</p> <p> Pays tribute to journalists who have lost their lives carrying out their work. </p> <p>Calls on governments abroad to implement United Nations General Assembly Resolution 163 (2013).</p> <p>Condemns actions around the world that suppress freedom of the press. </p> <p>Reaffirms the centrality of freedom of the press to U.S. efforts to support democracy, mitigate conflict, and promote good governance. </p> <p>Calls on the President and the Secretary of State to: </p> <ul> <li>improve the means by which the U.S. government identifies, publicizes, and responds to threats against freedom of the press; </li> <li>urge foreign governments to conduct investigations and adjudications of the perpetrators of attacks against journalists; and </li> <li>highlight the issue of threats against freedom of the press.</li></ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
