<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="sres" measure-number="173" measure-id="id114sres173" originChamber="SENATE" orig-publish-date="2015-05-06" update-date="2015-05-07">
<title>A resolution condemning atrocities committed by Bashar al-Assad of Syria and his regime, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114sres173v00" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-05-07">
<action-date>2015-05-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in Senate</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p> Condemns the actions of Bashar al-Assad and his regime for committing brutal acts of violence against the Syrian people, for committing systematic murder, torture, rape and enforced disappearance against the Syrian people, and for using weapons of mass destruction including chemical weapons against the Syrian people.</p> <p> Condemns the loss of innocent civilian life during the course of the civil war in Syria.</p> <p> Supports the diplomatic efforts of the international coalition to drive Bashar al-Assad from office and preserve the government institutions required to restore Syria's stability.</p> <p>Objects to any role for Bashar al-Assad in any final settlement to the civil war. </p> <p>States that nothing in this resolution shall be construed as an authorization for the use of military force.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114sres173v82" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2015-05-07">
<action-date>2015-05-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed Senate without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.)</p> <p>Condemns the actions of Bashar al-Assad and his regime for committing brutal acts of violence against the Syrian people, for committing systematic murder, torture, rape and enforced disappearance against the Syrian people, and for using weapons of mass destruction including chemical weapons against the Syrian people.</p> <p> Condemns the loss of innocent civilian life during the course of the civil war in Syria.</p> <p> Supports the diplomatic efforts of the international coalition to drive Bashar al-Assad from office and preserve the government institutions required to restore Syria's stability.</p> <p>Objects to any role for Bashar al-Assad in any final settlement to the civil war. </p> <p>States that nothing in this resolution shall be construed as an authorization for the use of military force.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
