<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hres" measure-number="835" measure-id="id114hres835" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-07-14" update-date="2016-09-27">
<title>Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the United States should adopt a national policy for technology to promote consumers' access to financial tools and online commerce to promote economic growth and consumer empowerment.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hres835v81" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-09-27">
<action-date>2016-09-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.)</p> <p>Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that the United States should:</p> <ul> <li> develop a national policy to encourage the development of tools for consumers to learn and protect their assets in a way that maximizes the promise customized, connected devices hold to empower consumers, foster future economic growth, and create new commerce and markets;</li> <li> prioritize accelerating the development of alternative technologies that support transparency, security, and authentication in a way that recognizes their benefits, allows for future innovation, and responsibly protects consumers' personal information; </li> <li> recognize that technology experts can play an important role in the future development of consumer-facing technology applications for manufacturing, automobiles, telecommunications, tourism, health care, energy, and general commerce; and</li> <li> support further innovation and economic growth and ensure cybersecurity and the protection of consumer privacy.</li> </ul> <p>Calls for innovators in technology, manufacturing, automobiles, telecommunications, tourism, health care, and energy industries to commit to improving the quality of life for future generations by developing new technology that is safe and consumer protective and that is aimed at improving consumers' access to commerce.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hres835v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-09-12">
<action-date>2016-07-14</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that the United States should:</p> <ul> <li> develop a national policy to encourage the development of tools for consumers to learn and protect their assets in a way that maximizes the promise customized, connected devices hold to empower consumers, foster future economic growth, and create new commerce and markets;</li> <li> prioritize accelerating the development of alternative technologies that support transparency, security, and authentication in a way that recognizes their benefits, allows for future innovation, and responsibly protects consumers' personal information; </li> <li> recognize that technology experts can play an important role in the future development of consumer-facing technology applications for manufacturing, automobiles, telecommunications, tourism, health care, energy, and general commerce; and</li> <li> support further innovation and economic growth and ensure cybersecurity and the protection of consumer privacy.</li> </ul> <p>Calls for innovators in technology, manufacturing, automobiles, telecommunications, tourism, health care, and energy industries to commit to improving the quality of life for future generations by developing new technology that is safe and consumer protective and that is aimed at improving consumers' access to commerce.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
