<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hres" measure-number="841" measure-id="id114hres841" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-09-06" update-date="2016-10-18">
<title>Expressing the condolences of the House of Representatives on the death of the Honorable Mark Takai, a Representative from the State of Hawaii.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hres841v81" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-10-18">
<action-date>2016-09-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.)</p> <p>Declares that the House of Representatives has heard with profound sorrow of the death of the Honorable Mark Takai, a Representative from Hawaii.</p> <p>Declares that when the House adjourns on September 6, 2016, it adjourn as a further mark of respect to the memory of the deceased.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hres841v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-10-18">
<action-date>2016-09-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Declares that the House of Representatives has heard with profound sorrow of the death of the Honorable Mark Takai, a Representative from Hawaii.</p> <p>Declares that when the House adjourns on September 6, 2016, it adjourn as a further mark of respect to the memory of the deceased. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
