<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hres" measure-number="232" measure-id="id114hres232" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-04-29" update-date="2015-04-30">
<title>Encouraging greater public-private sector collaboration to promote financial literacy for students and young adults.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hres232v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-04-30">
<action-date>2015-04-29</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Supports the efforts of the President's Advisory Council on Financial Literacy in working with the public and private sectors to:</p> <ul> <li>increase financial education for youth in school and for young adults in the workplace,</li> <li>increase access to financial services,</li> <li>establish measures of national financial literacy,</li> <li>conduct research on financial knowledge, and</li> <li>strengthen financial education programs.</li> </ul> <p>Reaffirms the purposes of the Dodd-Frank Act directing federal financial agencies to partner with organizations focused on developing opportunities to place talented young minorities and women in industry internships, summer employment, and full-time positions.</p> <p>Supports the efforts of the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau to provide consumers with relevant information and decisionmaking tools regarding important financial decisions.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
