<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hres" measure-number="792" measure-id="id114hres792" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-06-20" update-date="2016-06-29">
<title>Reaffirming the United States commitment to the protection of refugees and displaced persons.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hres792v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-06-29">
<action-date>2016-06-20</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Reaffirms the bipartisan commitment of the United States to promote the safety and well-being of the millions of refugees who flee war, persecution, or torture in search of peace, hope, and freedom. </p> <p>Calls upon the U.S. government to: (1) continue its international leadership role in response to those who have been displaced, (2) find political solutions to existing conflicts and prevent new conflicts, (3) provide humanitarian and development support to countries that are hosting millions of refugees, and (4) encourage the international community to increase resources to address current and protracted refugee crises. </p> <p>Commends those who have risked their lives working individually and for nongovernmental organizations and international agencies that have provided life-saving assistance and helped protect those displaced by conflict.</p> <p>Reiterates the bipartisan U.S. commitment to protect and assist refugees and other forcibly uprooted persons.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
