<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hres" measure-number="26" measure-id="id114hres26" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-01-12" update-date="2015-01-14">
<title>Strongly supporting the quality and value of diversity and innovation in the Nation's higher education institutions, and strongly disagreeing with the President's proposal to create and administer a Postsecondary Institution Ratings System.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hres26v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-01-14">
<action-date>2015-01-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that:</p> <ul> <li>students and families should maintain the right and responsibility of determining where to enroll for postsecondary education;</li> <li>the federal government, in conjunction with states and accreditors, has a responsibility and the tools to ensure that the significant taxpayer funds that are invested in student aid each year are appropriately spent;</li> <li>the federal government could play a positive role in making information regarding postsecondary education available to prospective students;</li> <li>the Administration should work collaboratively with the higher education community to make that information more consumer friendly and accessible to students and their families; and</li> <li>the Administration's proposal to rate postsecondary institutions through an oversimplified federal rating system will lead to less choice, diversity, and innovation and should be rejected.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
