<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hres" measure-number="374" measure-id="id114hres374" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-07-23" update-date="2016-07-26">
<title>Reaffirming Singapore's strategic partnership with the United States, encompassing broad and robust economic, military-to-military, law enforcement, and counterterrorism cooperation.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hres374v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-07-26">
<action-date>2016-07-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Affirms the importance of the U.S.-Singapore strategic partnership in securing regional peace and stability.</p> <p>Applauds Singapore's leadership in counterterrorism, including the deployment of military assets as part of the anti-ISIL (Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant) coalition and innovative counterterrorism efforts within the Asia-Pacific region.</p> <p>Anticipates the deepening of the security relationship following the signing of an enhanced Defense Cooperation Agreement on December 7, 2015, and welcomes further cooperation in areas such as cybersecurity, humanitarian assistance and disaster relief, and defense technology.</p> <p>Recognizes the vitality of the U.S.-Singapore bilateral trade and investment relationship.</p> <p>Expresses support for continued close cooperation between the United States and Singapore to build capacity for commercial engagement, energy development, innovation, trade facilitation, and to achieve development goals in the Asia-Pacific region.</p> <p>Urges the Administration to continue its support of multilateral institutions and fora, working in close cooperation with partners, such as Singapore, who share a commitment to an inclusive, rules-based regional architecture.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hres374v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-08-27">
<action-date>2015-07-23</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Congratulates the people of Singapore as they celebrate 50 years of independence and nation-building.</p> <p> Reaffirms the close partnership between the United States and Singapore.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
