<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hres" measure-number="90" measure-id="id114hres90" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-02-04" update-date="2015-02-06">
<title>Recognizing the importance of the United States International Boundary Water Commission (USIBWC) and its recent efforts to address trash, sediment, and water quality issues with their Mexican counterparts, Comisi?n Internacional de L?mites y Aguas (CILA), through a proposed minute.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hres90v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-02-06">
<action-date>2015-02-04</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Expresses support for the proposal by the United States section of the International Boundary and Water Commission (USIBWC) and its Mexican counterpart to address trash, sediment, and water quality. Commends USIBWC, the Tijuana River Valley Recovery Team, and local environmental organizations for their leadership in addressing such issues. Reaffirms Congress's commitment to continue its partnerships with Mexico on protecting the transnational watersheds.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
