<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hres" measure-number="651" measure-id="id114hres651" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-03-17" update-date="2016-03-24">
<title>Condemning the recent violent terrorist attack against Taylor Force and the recent wave of terrorism against Israel and Palestinian Authority President Mahmoud Abbas' failure to condemn such attacks.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hres651v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-03-24">
<action-date>2016-03-17</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that the United States: </p> <ul> <li>should condemn every act of violence against Israeli citizens and those who visit Israel in peace and friendship; </li> <li>believes that any chance at lasting peace will only occur through peaceful, bilateral discussions coupled with sound counsel from peaceful allies; </li> <li>supports individuals and organizations working to encourage cooperation between Israelis and Palestinians dedicated to a peaceful resolution of the Israeli-Palestinian conflict; </li> <li> calls on Palestinian Authority President Abbas and the international community to join in condemning the current wave of terrorism in Israel; and </li> <li>reaffirms the strong U.S.-Israel relationship.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
