<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hres" measure-number="540" measure-id="id114hres540" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-11-30" update-date="2016-02-12">
<title>Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the policies of the United States should support a transition to near zero greenhouse gas emissions, 100 percent clean renewable energy, infrastructure modernization, green jobs, full employment, a sustainable economy, fair wages, affordable energy, expanding the middle class, and ending poverty to promote national economic competitiveness and national security and for the purpose of avoiding adverse impacts of a changing climate.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hres540v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-02-12">
<action-date>2015-11-30</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Declares that the House of Representatives shall:</p> <ul> <li>support the achievement of near zero greenhouse gas emissions nationally by January 1, 2050, through policies that shift the U.S. energy supply strategy from fossil fuels to 100% renewable energy, increase energy efficiency, and implement zero waste practices to end dependence on fossil fuels and to promote climate security, jobs, universal access to clean energy, national economic competitiveness, and national security; </li> <li> establish a national goal of deriving 50% of electricity from renewable sources by January 1, 2030; </li> <li> establish policies and programs to modernize the national infrastructure, transition toward full employment with new green jobs, and build a sustainable economy, focusing on historically unemployed or underemployed communities; </li> <li> provide educational and job training programs, transitional financial assistance, and job opportunities for displaced fossil fuel industry workers; </li> <li> provide retraining and re-employment opportunities in green jobs for military veterans; </li> <li> provide increased funding for educational, training, and job assistance programs for rural residents and for increased emergency preparation and assistance to rural communities damaged by the adverse impacts of climate change; </li> <li> help the people of the United States to establish resiliency to withstand the significant impacts of climate change; </li> <li> establish policies that capture and store carbon currently in the atmosphere by protecting forests and improving land and agricultural practices; </li> <li> support trade policies that maintain American labor and environmental standards;</li> <li>support tax incentives that promote the growth of green jobs; </li> <li> ensure universal access to clean energy for moderate- and low-income families; </li> <li> create policies or programs that result in net positive environmental and economic benefits in impacted communities, which shall receive at least 25% of revenues committed to or generated by the implementation of carbon reducing programs; </li> <li> phase out subsidies for fossil fuels; </li> <li> establish a national goal of doubling efficiency of existing buildings from 2015 levels by January 1, 2030; and </li> <li> support a policy to work with international organizations and other nations to significantly reduce greenhouse gas emissions and to set a goal to achieve near zero greenhouse gas emissions by January 1, 2050, through replacing fossil fuels with 100% renewable energy, conservation, and energy efficiency.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
