<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hres" measure-number="49" measure-id="id114hres49" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-01-26" update-date="2015-02-06">
<title>Honoring the victims of the Holocaust, commending countries and organizations for marking the 70th anniversary of the liberation of Auschwitz, and expressing the commitment of the House of Representatives to strengthen the fight against anti-Semitism, bigotry, and intolerance.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hres49v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-02-06">
<action-date>2015-01-26</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Memorializes the liberation of the Nazi concentration camp at Auschwitz and honors the victims of Nazi concentration camps, killing centers, crimes, and aggression.</p> <p>Honors the U.S. Armed Forces, the armed forces of Allied nations, underground resistance fighters, and other persons who helped defeat the Nazi regime during World War II.</p> <p>Expresses gratitude to hosts and participants in events commemorating the 70th anniversary of the liberation of Auschwitz, including a U.S. presidential delegation attending an event in Oswiecim, Poland.</p> <p>Reaffirms support for educational efforts to teach about the Holocaust, preserve the memory of those murdered, and prevent future genocide.</p> <p>Urges all countries to: (1) implement educational lessons about the Holocaust to explain how unchecked intolerance and prejudice has led to, and could lead to, atrocities as happened during the Holocaust; and (2) improve efforts to identify and combat anti-Semitism and other forms of bigotry and intolerance.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
