<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hres" measure-number="160" measure-id="id114hres160" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-03-19" update-date="2015-03-20">
<title>Welcoming the Seventh Summit of the Americas, to be held in Panama City, Panama, April 10, 2015, and April 11, 2015.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hres160v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-03-20">
<action-date>2015-03-19</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Welcomes the Seventh Summit of the Americas to be held in Panama City, Panama, April 10, 2015, and April 11, 2015.</p> <p> Believes that the Summit will: (1) be an important multilateral forum for heads of state in the Western Hemisphere to discuss common policy issues and set policy goals, and (2) provide a forum for the United States to advance its interests in the region.</p> <p>Encourages all countries in the Western Hemisphere to commit to democratic governance, free and open markets, and basic human rights and to uphold the principles enshrined in the Inter-American Democratic Charter. </p> <p>Urges heads of state to provide opportunities for all civil society organizations to provide input during events surrounding the Summit.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
