<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hres" measure-number="332" measure-id="id114hres332" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-06-18" update-date="2015-07-01">
<title>Recognizing the immeasurable contributions of fathers in the healthy development of children, supporting responsible fatherhood, and encouraging greater involvement of fathers in the lives of their children, especially on Father's Day.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hres332v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-07-01">
<action-date>2015-06-18</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Commends the millions of fathers who serve as wonderful, caring parents for their children.</p> <p>Calls on fathers across the United States to use Father's Day to: (1) reconnect and rededicate themselves to their children's lives, (2) spend Father's Day with their children, and (3) express their love and support for their children.</p> <p>Urges men to understand the level of responsibility fathering a child requires, especially in the encouragement of children's moral, mental, social, academic, emotional, physical, and spiritual development.</p> <p>Encourages active involvement of fathers in the rearing and development of their children, including the devotion of time, energy, and resources.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
