<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hres" measure-number="293" measure-id="id114hres293" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-06-03" update-date="2015-11-03">
<title>Expressing concern over anti-Israel and anti-Semitic incitement within the Palestinian Authority.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hres293v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-11-03">
<action-date>2015-11-02</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Supports individuals and organizations working to encourage cooperation between Israelis and Palestinians. </p> <p> Condemns the wave of violent attacks in Israel and the West Bank.</p> <p>Reiterates condemnation of anti-Israel and anti-Semitic incitement in the Palestinian Authority (PA) as antithetical to peace. </p> <p> Calls on the PA to: (1) discontinue incitement to violence in all PA-controlled media outlets and publicly repudiate attacks against Israelis; (2) continue security cooperation with Israel; and (3) renew direct talks with the Israelis, including the reconstitution of the Trilateral Commission on Incitement. </p> <p> Encourages responsible nations to condemn the PA's incitement to violence.</p> Supports the government of Israel in its fight against terror. <p> Directs the Department of State to monitor and publish information on all official PA incitement against Jews and Israel.</p> <p> Calls on the Administration to continue publicly repudiating and raising the issue of Palestinian anti-Israel incitement to violence in all appropriate bilateral and international forums.]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hres293v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-06-04">
<action-date>2015-06-03</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Supports individuals and organizations working to encourage cooperation between Israelis and Palestinians, including Professor Mohammed Dajani Daoudi, the Israel Palestine Center for Research and Information, United Hatzalah, and Breaking the Impasse. </p> <p>Reiterates condemnation of anti-Israel and anti-Semitic incitement in the Palestinian Authority (PA) as antithetical to peace. </p> <p>Urges President Abbas and PA officials to discontinue all official incitement and exert influence to discourage anti-Israel and anti-Semitic incitement in Palestinian civil society. </p> <p>Directs the Department of State to regularly monitor and publish information on all official PA incitement against Jews and Israel.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
