<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hres" measure-number="493" measure-id="id114hres493" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-10-26" update-date="2015-10-29">
<title>Recognizing Connecticut's Submarine Century, the 100th anniversary of the establishment of Naval Submarine Base New London, and Connecticut's historic role in supporting the undersea capabilities of the United States.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hres493v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-10-29">
<action-date>2015-10-26</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Commends the dedication and contribution to the Navy and submarine force by the people of Connecticut, both through the initial deed of gift that established what would become Naval Submarine Base New London and through their ongoing commitment to support the mission of the base and the Navy personnel assigned to it.</p> <p> Honors the submariners who have trained and served at Naval Submarine Base New London throughout its history. </p> <p> Recognizes the contribution of the industry and workforce of Connecticut in designing, building, and sustaining the Navy's submarine fleet. </p> <p>Encourages the recognition of Connecticut's Submarine Century by Congress, the Navy, and the American people.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
