<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hres" measure-number="647" measure-id="id114hres647" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-03-16" update-date="2016-04-18">
<title>Recognizing the Girl Scouts of the USA on the 100th anniversary of the Girl Scout Gold Award, the highest award in Girl Scouts, which has stood for excellence and leadership for girls everywhere since 1916.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hres647v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-04-18">
<action-date>2016-03-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Congratulates the Girl Scouts of the USA and Gold Award recipients everywhere on the centennial of the Girl Scout Gold Award.</p> <p>Recognizes the impact Girl Scout Gold Award recipients have had on the world and the lasting impact of their projects on their communities.</p> <ul> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
