<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hres" measure-number="340" measure-id="id114hres340" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-06-25" update-date="2015-06-29">
<title>Returning to the Senate H.R. 1735, a bill to authorize appropriations for fiscal year 2016 for military activities of the Department of Defense, for military construction, and for defense activities of the Department of Energy, to prescribe military personnel strengths for such fiscal year, and for other purposes, with the Senate amendment thereto.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hres340v81" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-06-29">
<action-date>2015-06-25</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.)</p> <p>Returns to the Senate H.R. 1735 (National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2016) with the Senate amendment because, in the opinion of the House of Representatives, the Senate amendment contravenes the clause of the Constitution requiring bills raising revenue to originate in the House and is an infringement of the privileges of the House.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hres340v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-06-29">
<action-date>2015-06-25</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Returns to the Senate H.R. 1735 (National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2016) with the Senate amendment because, in the opinion of the House of Representatives, the Senate amendment contravenes the clause of the Constitution requiring bills raising revenue to originate in the House and is an infringement of the privileges of the House.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
