<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hres" measure-number="708" measure-id="id114hres708" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-04-27" update-date="2016-05-26">
<title>Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the immigration policies of the United States should reduce automatic removal and detention, restore due process for immigrants, and repeal unnecessary barriers to legal immigration.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hres708v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-05-26">
<action-date>2016-04-27</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Supports immigration legislation that: </p> <ul> <li>acknowledges that immigrants and their families have inherent dignity and are deserving of human rights; </li> <li>restores immigration system fairness by updating the definition of &quot;aggravated felony&quot;; </li> <li>restores discretion to immigration judges to waive grounds of inadmissibility and deportability based on family and community equities, humanitarian considerations, other individualized circumstances, or because it is in the public interest; </li> <li>restores judicial review of case decisions to protect due process; </li> <li>eliminates mandatory detention and prolonged detention for immigrants and preserves the Department of Homeland Security's authority to exercise detention discretion; </li> <li>repeals programs that permit local law authorities to enforce federal immigration laws; and </li> <li>repeals the 3-year, 10-year, and permanent bars and other unnecessary barriers to legal immigration.</li></ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
