<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hres" measure-number="567" measure-id="id114hres567" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-12-16" update-date="2016-01-04">
<title>Expressing opposition to the European Commission interpretive notice regarding labeling Israeli products and goods manufactured in the West Bank and other areas, as such actions undermine efforts to achieve a negotiated Israeli-Palestinian peace process.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hres567v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-01-04">
<action-date>2015-12-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Opposes: (1) the European Commission interpretive notice regarding labeling Israeli products and goods manufactured in the West Bank and other areas; and (2) politically motivated acts of boycott, divestment, and sanctions against Israel or Israeli-controlled territory.</p> <p> Calls upon the European Commission, the Council of the European Union, and the European Parliament to oppose boycott, divestment, or sanctions initiatives aimed at singling out Israel, and to refrain from actions counterproductive to resolving the Israeli-Palestinian conflict.</p> <p>Encourages European Union (EU) member states to exert prudence in the implementation of the EU labeling guidelines. </p> <p>Urges the Administration to increase its influence in international forums to oppose boycott, divestment, and sanctions actions against Israel. </p> <p>Supports efforts by U.S. state legislatures to enact measures that oppose such acts against Israel. </p> <p>Reaffirms support for a negotiated two-state solution to the Israeli-Palestinian conflict.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
