<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hres" measure-number="218" measure-id="id114hres218" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-04-21" update-date="2015-04-22">
<title>Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives regarding the conditions for the United States becoming a signatory to any international agreement on greenhouse gas emissions under the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hres218v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-04-22">
<action-date>2015-04-21</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>It is the sense of the House of Representatives that the United States should not be a signatory to any protocol to, or other agreement regarding, the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change of 1992 which would: </p> <ul> <li>mandate new commitments to limit or reduce greenhouse gas emissions for the Annex I Parties unless the protocol or agreement also mandates new specific scheduled commitments to limit or reduce greenhouse gas emissions for Non-Annex I Parties within the same compliance period, </li> <li>not ensure that all parties to the agreement reduce an equal amount of greenhouse gas emissions at an equivalent rate within the same compliance period, </li> <li>result in serious harm to the U.S. economy, and </li> <li>not adequately protect U.S. intellectual property rights.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
