<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hres" measure-number="363" measure-id="id114hres363" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-07-15" update-date="2015-08-04">
<title>Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives regarding the power of Congress to protect the right to vote.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hres363v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-08-04">
<action-date>2015-07-15</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that Congress:</p> <ul> <li>has the power to prohibit voter suppression activities,</li> <li>should require every state to create and maintain an online voter registration system and automatically register eligible voters whose information is contained in the state's motor vehicle license registration system (with a 21-day opt-out period for those who wish to be taken off the registry), and</li> <li>should make Election Day a legal public holiday.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
