<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hres" measure-number="379" measure-id="id114hres379" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-07-23" update-date="2015-08-27">
<title>Reaffirming the role of the House of Representatives in the review and approval or disapproval of the Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action relating to the nuclear program of Iran.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hres379v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-08-27">
<action-date>2015-07-23</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Reaffirms the role of the House of Representatives in the review and approval or disapproval of the Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action (JCPA) relating to Iran's nuclear program. </p> <p>Disapproves of the Obama Administration's taking action through the United Nations Security Council on the JCPA before Congress has had time to review the agreement. </p> <p>States that the House of Representatives: (1) is not bound by the July 20, 2015, Security Council action to approve the JCPA; and (2) will determine whether to approve or disapprove the JCPA based solely on whether the agreement is in U.S. national security interests.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
