<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hres" measure-number="56" measure-id="id114hres56" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-01-27" update-date="2015-01-29">
<title>Affirming the support of the United States for Macedonia's accession to the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO).</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hres56v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-01-29">
<action-date>2015-01-27</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Supports Macedonia's aspirations to join the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO). </p> <p>Recognizes the cooperation between Vermont and Macedonia and the joint military partnership between the Vermont National Guard and the Army of Macedonia. </p> <p>Recognizes the significant benefits of closer economic and political ties between NATO members and Macedonia. </p> <p>Appreciates Macedonia's efforts in advancing peace, democracy, and stability. </p> <p>Calls on the Administration, the Department of State, and European allies to work with Greece and NATO allies to ensure that bilateral disputes do not impede Macedonia's NATO accession. </p> <p>Urges NATO members to formally extend an invitation to Macedonia to join NATO at one of the next meetings of the North Atlantic Council or NATO Summit in Poland in 2016.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
