<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hres" measure-number="842" measure-id="id114hres842" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-09-06" update-date="2016-10-25">
<title>Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives regarding the terrorist attacks launched against the United States on September 11, 2001, on the 15th anniversary of that date.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hres842v81" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-10-25">
<action-date>2016-09-09</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.)</p>        <p> Recognizes September 11 as a day of solemn commemoration. Extends deepest sympathies to the innocent victims of the September 11, 2001, terrorist attacks and their families, friends, and loved ones. Honors the heroism and sacrifices of U.S. military and civilian personnel and their families in defense of their country. Credits the heroism of first responders, law enforcement personnel, state and local officials, volunteers, and others who aided the victims of the attacks. Thanks the leaders and citizens of nations who have assisted and continue to stand in solidarity with the United States against terrorism in the aftermath of the attacks. <p>Commends the military and intelligence personnel involved in the removal of Osama bin Laden.</p> <p>Reasserts a commitment to opposing violent extremism against American interests and to providing the U.S. military, intelligence, and law enforcement communities with the resources and support to do so. Vows to continue to identify, intercept, and disrupt terrorists and their activities.</p> <p>Reaffirms that the American people will never forget the sacrifices made on September 11, 2001, or bow to terrorist demands. Declares that Congress stands adjourned out of respect to the victims of the attacks.</p> <p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hres842v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-10-25">
<action-date>2016-09-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p> Recognizes September 11 as a day of solemn commemoration. Extends deepest sympathies to the innocent victims of the September 11, 2001, terrorist attacks and their families, friends, and loved ones. Honors the heroism and sacrifices of U.S. military and civilian personnel and their families in defense of their country. Credits the heroism of first responders, law enforcement personnel, state and local officials, volunteers, and others who aided the victims of the attacks. Thanks the leaders and citizens of nations who have assisted and continue to stand in solidarity with the United States against terrorism in the aftermath of the attacks. <p>Commends the military and intelligence personnel involved in the removal of Osama bin Laden.</p> <p>Reasserts a commitment to opposing violent extremism against American interests and to providing the U.S. military, intelligence, and law enforcement communities with the resources and support to do so. Vows to continue to identify, intercept, and disrupt terrorists and their activities.</p> <p>Reaffirms that the American people will never forget the sacrifices made on September 11, 2001, or bow to terrorist demands. Declares that Congress stands adjourned out of respect to the victims of the attacks.</p> <p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
