<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hres" measure-number="36" measure-id="id114hres36" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-01-14" update-date="2015-03-04">
<title>Honoring the 22 years of mentoring, guidance, and educational assistance provided by the 5000 Role Models of Excellence Project and recognizing its positive impact on the lives of at-risk boys and men of color.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hres36v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-03-04">
<action-date>2015-01-14</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Honors the 5000 Role Models of Excellence Project on its 22 years of making a difference in the lives of at-risk minority boys and men. </p> <p>Commends Congresswoman Frederica S. Wilson for founding an organization devoted to improving the self-image, social skills, and academic performance of young minority boys and men.</p>  <p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
