<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hres" measure-number="120" measure-id="id114hres120" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-02-24" update-date="2015-03-04">
<title>Supporting the goals and ideals of the designation of January 1, 2015, to December 31, 2024, as the "International Decade for People of African Descent".</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hres120v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-03-04">
<action-date>2015-02-24</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Supports the goals of the International Decade for People of African Descent. </p> <p>Recalls S.Con.Res. 26 supporting the goals of the designation of the International Year for People of African Descent. </p> <p>Supports the establishment of a global affairs strategy and assistance for people of African descent. </p> <p>Supports the expansion of efforts by international organizations to address the human rights situation of people of African Descent. </p> <p>Calls upon the United States in cooperation with civil society (African descent communities, academics, activists, businesses, and philanthropic organizations) to develop domestic and global strategies to execute the goals and ideals of the International Decade for People of African Descent. </p> <p>Reaffirms the commitment of Congress to combat racism, discrimination, and intolerance in the United States and around the globe. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
