<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hres" measure-number="342" measure-id="id114hres342" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-06-25" update-date="2015-06-27">
<title>Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives regarding the enhancement of unity in America.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hres342v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-06-27">
<action-date>2015-06-25</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that the United States can achieve a more perfect union:</p> <ul> <li>through avoidance of &quot;government speech&quot; (as the state of Texas did in <i>Walker III v. Texas Division, Sons of Confederate Veterans, Inc.</i>) that promotes or displays symbols, signs, and vestiges of racism, oppression, and intimidation;</li> <li>by abating the use of government speech through signs, actions, and words that promote division and tear at the fabric of American society; and</li> <li> by taking actions to ensure that government speech does not foster division, disharmony, intolerance through government-issued or sponsored flags, signs, images, or other symbols.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
