<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hres" measure-number="401" measure-id="id114hres401" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-07-29" update-date="2015-08-27">
<title>Supporting the goals and ideals of "Vietnam Veterans Day".</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hres401v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-08-27">
<action-date>2015-07-29</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Honors and recognizes the contributions of veterans who served in the U.S. Armed Forces in Vietnam.</p> <p> Encourages states and local governments to designate a Vietnam Veterans Day.</p> <p> Encourages the people of the United States to observe Vietnam Veterans Day with appropriate ceremonies and activities that: </p> <ul> <li>provide the appreciation that such veterans deserve, but did not receive upon returning home from the war; </li> <li>demonstrate the resolve that never again shall the people of the United States disregard or denigrate a generation of veterans; </li> <li>promote awareness of the contributions of such veterans during military service as well as to their communities; </li> <li>promote awareness of the importance of entire communities empowering veterans and their families readjust to civilian life after military service; and </li> <li>promote opportunities for Vietnam veterans to assist younger veterans returning from the wars in Afghanistan and Iraq.</li></ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
