<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hres" measure-number="585" measure-id="id114hres585" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-01-13" update-date="2016-03-16">
<title>Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives regarding an Interstate 73 corridor transportation compact.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hres585v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-03-16">
<action-date>2016-01-13</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that the entering into of an agreement or compact by two or more states for cooperative effort and mutual assistance would be beneficial to the development of an Interstate 73 corridor.</p> <p> Such an agreement may incorporate the following elements to the extent that they are consistent with federal law:</p> <ul> <li>the study, development, and promotion of a plan for the design, construction, financing, and operation of such corridor through South Carolina, North Carolina, Virginia, West Virginia, Ohio, and Michigan;</li> <li>coordination of efforts to establish a common legal framework in all the signatory states to authorize and facilitate design, construction, financing, and operation of such corridor or through public-private partnerships;</li> <li>advocacy for federal funding to support the establishment of such corridor;</li> <li>making available to the corridor project funding and resources that are or may be appropriated by the signatory states and allocated for that purpose; and</li> <li>doing all things necessary or convenient to facilitate and coordinate the corridor's design, construction, financing, and operation.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
