<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hres" measure-number="148" measure-id="id114hres148" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-03-10" update-date="2016-03-03">
<title>Calling on the Government of Iran to follow through on repeated promises of assistance in the case of Robert Levinson, the longest held United States hostage in our Nation's history.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hres148v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-03-03">
<action-date>2016-02-29</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Recognizes that Robert Levinson is the longest held U.S. hostage in our nation's history.</p> <p> Notes the pledges by and renewed commitment of Iranian officials to provide their government's assistance in the Robert Levinson case.</p> <p> Urges Iran, as a humanitarian gesture, to act on its promises to assist in the Robert Levinson case and to provide the U.S. government immediately with all available information from all Iranian government entities regarding Robert Levinson's disappearance.</p> <p> Urges the President and U.S. allies to continue to raise the Robert Levinson case with Iranian officials at every opportunity. </p> <p> Expresses sympathy to Robert Levinson's family for their anguish and expresses hope that their ordeal can be brought to an end in the near future.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hres148v81" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-03-01">
<action-date>2016-02-29</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.)</p> <p>Recognizes that Robert Levinson is the longest held U.S. civilian in our nation's history.</p> <p> Notes the pledges by current Iranian officials to provide their government's assistance in the Robert Levinson case.</p> <p> Urges Iran, as a humanitarian gesture, to intensify its cooperation in the Robert Levinson case and to share the results of its investigation into his disappearance with the U.S. government.</p> <p> Urges the President and U.S. allies to continue to raise the Robert Levinson case with Iranian officials at every opportunity. </p> <p> Expresses sympathy to Robert Levinson's family for their anguish and expresses hope that their ordeal can be brought to an end in the near future.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hres148v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-03-13">
<action-date>2015-03-10</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Recognizes that Robert Levinson is the longest held U.S. civilian in our nation's history.</p> <p> Notes the pledges by current Iranian officials to provide their government's assistance in the Robert Levinson case.</p> <p> Urges Iran, as a humanitarian gesture, to intensify its cooperation in the Robert Levinson case and to share the results of its investigation into his disappearance with the U.S. government.</p> <p> Urges the President and U.S. allies to continue to raise the Robert Levinson case with Iranian officials at every opportunity. </p> <p> Expresses sympathy to Robert Levinson's family for their anguish and expresses hope that their ordeal can be brought to an end in the near future.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
