<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hres" measure-number="467" measure-id="id114hres467" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-10-08" update-date="2015-10-13">
<title>Establishing the Select Committee on Gun Violence Prevention.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hres467v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-10-13">
<action-date>2015-10-08</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Establishes the House Select Committee on Gun Violence Prevention to investigate and report on:</p> <ul> <li>the causes of mass shootings,</li> <li>methods to improve the federal firearms purchaser background check system,</li> <li>connections between access to firearms and dangerously mentally ill individuals,</li> <li>strengthening federal penalties for trafficking and straw purchasing of firearms,</li> <li>closing loopholes that allow some domestic abusers continued access to firearms,</li> <li>linkages between firearms and suicide,</li> <li>gun violence's effect on public health,</li> <li>the correlation between state gun violence prevention laws and the incidence of gun violence,</li> <li>the importance of having reliable and accurate information on gun violence and its toll on our nation,</li> <li>the implementation of effective gun violence prevention laws in accordance with the Second Amendment to the Constitution, and</li> <li>rates of gun violence in large metropolitan areas.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
