<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hres" measure-number="419" measure-id="id114hres419" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-09-15" update-date="2015-09-16">
<title>Recognizing the importance of frontline health workers toward accelerating progress on global health and saving the lives of women and children, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hres419v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-09-16">
<action-date>2015-09-15</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Reaffirms the critical role of frontline health workers in achieving core global health goals, including ending preventable child and maternal deaths, ensuring global health security, and achieving an AIDS-free generation.</p> <p>Commends the progress made by the United States in helping to build local capacity and to save lives in the world's most vulnerable communities by training and supporting frontline health care workers.</p> <p> Acknowledges that in the aftermath of natural disasters, disease outbreaks, and conflict frontline health workers continue to perform critical services.</p> <p> Calls on all relevant federal agencies to develop a comprehensive health workforce strengthening strategy for increasing access to qualified health workers in developing countries.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
