<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hres" measure-number="443" measure-id="id114hres443" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-09-25" update-date="2015-09-28">
<title>Commending the Departments of Defense and Veterans Affairs for their joint campaign to raise awareness during September, Suicide Prevention Month, to reduce suicide among members of the United States Armed Forces and veterans.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hres443v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-09-28">
<action-date>2015-09-25</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Commends the Department of Defense and the Department of Veterans Affairs for raising awareness during Suicide Prevention Month of the life-saving resources available to those who have served, or are currently serving, in uniform.</p> <p> Supports the goals of National Suicide Prevention Awareness Month, &quot;The Power of 1&quot; campaign, and efforts to improve outreach to individuals at risk for suicide, especially those addressed to veterans and members of the U.S. Armed Forces.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
