<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hres" measure-number="381" measure-id="id114hres381" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-07-27" update-date="2015-09-30">
<title>To refer H.R. 3133, a bill making congressional reference to the United States Court of Federal Claims pursuant to sections 1492 and 2509 of title 28, United States Code, of certain Indian land-related takings claims of the Grand Traverse Band of Ottawa and Chippewa Indians of Michigan and its individual members.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hres381v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-09-30">
<action-date>2015-07-27</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Refers H.R. 3133, which directs the Department of the Treasury to pay an unspecified sum to the Grand Traverse Band of Ottawa and Chippewa Indians of Michigan and its members pursuant to a judgment rendered by the U.S. Court of Federal Claims, to the chief judge of the U.S. Court of Federal Claims for a determination as to whether the Band has legal or equitable claims for just compensation against the United States for land-related takings occurring between 1855 and 1900 within the areas reserved for the Band and its members by the Treaty with the Ottawa and Chippewa.</p> <p>Directs the chief judge to report back to the House of Representatives providing findings of fact and conclusions of law to inform Congress of:</p> <ul> <li>the nature, extent, and character of such claims;</li> <li> whether the Band has good cause to be excused from the limitations period established by the Indian Claims Commission Act of 1946 for filing such claims (August 13, 1946, to August 13, 1951); </li> <li> whether any other statute of limitations bar or the doctrine of laches is applicable to the Band's claims and, if so, whether the Band has good cause to be excused from its operation; and </li> <li> the amount of just compensation, if any, legally or equitably due from the United States to the Band.</li> </ul> </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
