<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hres" measure-number="848" measure-id="id114hres848" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-09-07" update-date="2016-09-09">
<title>Calling for the maintenance of effective trade remedies for United States manufacturers and producers by ensuring that any foreign country designated as a nonmarket economy country under the Tariff Act of 1930 retain this status until it demonstrates that it meets all of the criteria for treatment as a market economy set forth in section 771(18)(B) of such Act.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hres848v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-09-09">
<action-date>2016-09-07</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Calls on:</p> <ul> <li> the President to apply U.S. antidumping and countervailing duty laws against nonmarket economy countries,</li> <li>the President to retain the status of any country currently designated as a nonmarket economy country until it meets certain criteria for treatment as a market economy country,</li> <li>nonmarket economy countries to eliminate all direct and indirect subsidies and other market-distorting government policies benefitting the production and export of goods to the United States, and</li> <li>such countries to enter into binding and enforceable agreements for removing excess production capacity and withdrawing state intervention in and control over their economies.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
