<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hres" measure-number="780" measure-id="id114hres780" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-06-13" update-date="2016-08-12">
<title>Urging respect for the constitution of the Democratic Republic of the Congo in the democratic transition of power in 2016.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hres780v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-08-12">
<action-date>2016-06-13</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[The United States should impose sanctions on government officials of the Democratic Republic of the Congo (DRC) who impede progress toward a democratic transition through credible elections that respect the will of the Congolese. </blockquote> <p>Sanctions should target core figures in President Kabila's government for visa denials and asset freezes. </p> <p>Economic and security assistance should be reviewed for possible termination, while preserving humanitarian assistance, until the election crisis is resolved. </p> <p>The President of the United States should lift sanctions only when: (1) President Kabila has declared that he will not remain in power once his term ends and has made verifiable progress towards holding national elections, or (2) the DRC has held a free and fair presidential election and a new President has been sworn in. </p> <p>The United States should: (1) support independent DRC civil society organizations and media, and (2) investigate and target money laundering activities by key figures close to President Kabila and those financial institutions involved in such activities.</p> <p>The United States should coordinate efforts with key Western and African partners, including through other financial intelligence units.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
