<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hres" measure-number="755" measure-id="id114hres755" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-05-26" update-date="2016-06-06">
<title>Amending the Rules of the House of Representatives to observe a moment of silence in the House on the first legislative day of each month for those killed or wounded in United States engagements in Iraq, Afghanistan, and other countries where Americans are serving in harms way.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hres755v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-06-06">
<action-date>2016-05-26</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Amends rule XIV (Order and Priority of Business) of the Rules of the House of Representatives to declare that, on the first legislative day of each month on which there is a record vote on any bill or joint resolution, immediately after that vote, a moment of silence shall be observed in the House of Representatives on behalf of those killed or wounded (as well as their families) in current U.S. engagements in Iraq, Afghanistan, and other countries where Americans are serving in harm's way. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
