<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hres" measure-number="658" measure-id="id114hres658" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-03-22" update-date="2016-03-24">
<title>Condemning in the strongest terms the terrorist attacks in Brussels on March 22, 2016, which murdered more than 30 innocent people, and severely wounded many more.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hres658v81" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-03-24">
<action-date>2016-03-23</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.)</p> <p>Condemns the terrorist attacks in Brussels on March 22, 2016, which murdered more than 30 innocent people and severely wounded many more.</p> <p> Expresses sympathy and condolences for those killed and injured in the attacks and for their families and friends.</p> <p> Pledges support for the government of Belgium in its efforts to bring to justice those involved with the planning and execution of the attacks.</p> <p> Declares that the Islamic State of Iraq and Syria (ISIS) poses a fundamental threat to the universal value of freedom in all countries.</p> <p> States the concern of the House of Representatives about the flow of foreign fighters to and from the Middle East and West and North Africa and the threat they pose. </p> <p> Expresses readiness to assist the government and people of Belgium to respond to the threat posed by ISIS and its terrorist affiliates.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hres658v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-03-24">
<action-date>2016-03-22</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Condemns the terrorist attacks in Brussels on March 22, 2016, which murdered more than 30 innocent people and severely wounded many more.</p> <p> Expresses sympathy and condolences for those killed and injured in the attacks and for their families and friends.</p> <p> Pledges support for the government of Belgium in its efforts to bring to justice those involved with the planning and execution of the attacks.</p> <p> Declares that the Islamic State of Iraq and Syria (ISIS) poses a fundamental threat to the universal value of freedom in all countries.</p> <p> States the concern of the House of Representatives about the flow of foreign fighters to and from the Middle East and West and North Africa and the threat they pose. </p> <p> Expresses readiness to assist the government and people of Belgium to respond to the threat posed by ISIS and its terrorist affiliates.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
