<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hres" measure-number="910" measure-id="id114hres910" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-09-28" update-date="2016-10-28">
<title>Supporting the ideals and goals of the "International Day for the Elimination of Violence against Women".</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hres910v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-10-28">
<action-date>2016-09-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Supports the goals of the International Day for the Elimination of Violence against Women.</p> <p> Honors those working domestically and internationally to eliminate violence against women and girls.</p> <p> Encourages the President to: </p> <ul> <li>address the needs of women and girls experiencing violence through funding for participatory survivor-led programs; </li> <li>prioritize protections for women and children in fragile and conflict zones; </li> <li>address increased rates of violence against marginalized women due to race, ethnicity, gender and sexual identity, and socioeconomic status; and</li> <li>increase opportunities for women and girls worldwide, including opportunities for education and economic participation.</li></ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
