<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hres" measure-number="525" measure-id="id114hres525" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-11-16" update-date="2015-11-17">
<title>Urging the Administration to work with North Atlantic Treaty Organization member states to invoke Article 5 of the North Atlantic Treaty in response to the Paris attacks.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hres525v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-11-17">
<action-date>2015-11-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Calls on the President, in response to the Paris attacks, to work closely with other North Atlantic Treaty Organization members to invoke Article 5 of the North Atlantic Treaty (which states that &quot;The Parties agree that an armed attack against one or more of them in Europe or North America shall be considered an attack against them all . . . .&quot;). </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
