<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hres" measure-number="237" measure-id="id114hres237" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-04-30" update-date="2015-05-13">
<title>Declaring that achieving the primary goal of the National Plan to Address Alzheimer's Disease of the Department of Health and Human Services to prevent and effectively treat Alzheimer's disease by 2025 is an urgent national priority.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hres237v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-05-13">
<action-date>2015-04-30</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Expresses commitment to strengthening the quality of care and expanding support for individuals with Alzheimer's disease and related dementias and their family caregivers. </p> <p>Declares that: (1) achieving the primary goal of the National Plan to Address Alzheimer's Disease to prevent and effectively treat Alzheimer's by 2025 is an urgent national priority, and (2) bold action and considerable increases in funding are necessary to meet that goal.</p> <p>Encourages: (1) greater collaboration between governments to advance a global Alzheimer's and dementia research plan; (2) innovative public-private partnerships, financing tools, incentives, and other mechanisms to accelerate the pursuit of disease-modifying therapies.</p> <p> Calls for: (1) significantly increasing the funding for Alzheimer's research in FY2016; and (2) developing a plan for FY2017-FY2020 to meet the target of the Advisory Council on Alzheimer's Research, Care, and Services for the United States to spend $2 billion each year on Alzheimer's research.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
