<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hres" measure-number="617" measure-id="id114hres617" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-02-23" update-date="2016-02-25">
<title>Providing for authority to initiate litigation for actions by the President or other executive branch officials inconsistent with their duties under the Constitution of the United States with respect to the unlawful transfer of individuals detained at United States Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hres617v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-02-25">
<action-date>2016-02-23</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Authorizes the Speaker of the House of Representatives to initiate or intervene in civil actions on behalf of the House of Representatives in a federal court of competent jurisdiction to seek any appropriate relief regarding the failure of the President, the head of any department or agency, or any other executive branch officer or employee to act in a manner consistent with that official's duties under the Constitution and laws of the United States regarding the transfer of any individual detained at Guantanamo. </p> <p>Directs the Speaker to notify the House of a decision to initiate or intervene in any such civil action.</p> <p> States that the Office of the General Counsel of the House shall represent the House in any such civil action, and may employ outside counsel and other experts.</p> <p> Defines &quot;individual detained at Guantanamo&quot; as any individual located at United States Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba, as of October 1, 2009, who: </p> <ul> <li> is not a U.S. citizen or a member of the Armed Forces; and </li> <li> is in the custody or under the control of the Department of Defense, or otherwise under detention at United States Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
