<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hres" measure-number="636" measure-id="id114hres636" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-03-03" update-date="2016-03-04">
<title>Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives regarding Burma's 2015 elections.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hres636v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-03-04">
<action-date>2016-03-03</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Recognizes the Burmese peoples' profound desire for change as reflected in the vote on November 8, 2015. </p> <p>Acknowledges the important roles played by the international community, Election Day workers, party observers, and domestic election observers in preventing fraud. </p> <p>Acknowledges that while Burma has taken steps toward democratic rule, constitutional, legal, economic, and security issues remain unresolved. </p> <p>Expresses concern about ongoing attacks in the Kachin and Shan states and the plight of the Rohingya people. </p> <p>Urges the government and all other stakeholders to support constitutional reform. </p> <p>Calls on the President and the Department of State to focus on: </p> <ul> <li>securing solutions to human rights and humanitarian problems, including fulfillment of the 11 human rights and security commitments made by the current President of Burma to President Obama; </li> <li>supporting changes to structural and systemic impediments to the realization of full democratic and civilian government; </li> <li>bringing about the release of all political prisoners, including those awaiting trial or sentencing; and </li> <li>supporting an end to offensives against ethnic nationalities and the creation of a peaceful federal union acceptable to the people of Burma. </li> </ul> <p>Urges the incumbent government to support a timely and peaceful transfer of power to the new government.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
