<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hres" measure-number="198" measure-id="id114hres198" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-04-13" update-date="2015-04-27">
<title>To establish standards defining impeachable "high crimes and misdemeanors" within the meaning of Article II, section 4 as applied to the President of the United States.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hres198v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-04-27">
<action-date>2015-04-13</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Declares that the following presidential actions shall constitute impeachable &quot;high crimes and misdemeanors,&quot; which will cause the House of Representatives to vote articles of impeachment to send to the Senate for trial:</p> <ul> <li> initiating war without express congressional authorization; </li> <li> killing American citizens in the United States or abroad who are not engaged in active hostilities against the United States without due process (unless the killing was necessary to prevent imminent serious physical danger to third parties); </li> <li> failing to superintend subordinates guilty of chronic constitutional abuses; </li> <li>spending appropriated funds in violation of conditions imposed for expenditure; </li> <li> intentionally lying to Congress to obtain an authorization for war; </li> <li> failing to take care that the laws be faithfully executed through signing statements or systematic policies of nonenforcement; </li> <li> substituting executive agreements for treaties; </li> <li> intentionally lying under oath to a federal judge or grand jury; </li> <li> misusing federal agencies to advance a partisan political agenda; </li> <li> refusing to comply with a congressional subpoena for documents or testimony issued for a legitimate legislative purpose; and</li> <li>issuing executive orders or presidential memoranda that infringe upon or circumvent the constitutional powers of Congress.</li> </ul> <p>Makes this Act effective upon passage by the House of Representatives.</p> <ul> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
