<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hres" measure-number="359" measure-id="id114hres359" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-07-10" update-date="2015-09-30">
<title>Providing that the House of Representatives disagrees with the majority opinion in Obergefell et al. v. Hodges, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hres359v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-09-30">
<action-date>2015-07-10</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Declares that the House of Representatives: (1)&nbsp;disagrees with the Supreme Court's&nbsp;majority opinion in <em>Obergefell v. Hodges</em> and its holdings that the&nbsp;Fourteenth Amendment to the Constitution requires states to license marriages between same-sex couples and requires states to recognize same-sex marriages performed out-of-state; and (2) agrees with the four dissenting opinions, which uphold the traditional definition of marriage as a union between one man and one woman and the original meaning of the Fourteenth Amendment.</p> <p>Expresses the sense of the House that:</p> <ul> <li>the traditional definition of marriage is a union between one man and one woman;</li> <li>the majority opinion in <em>Obergefell</em> unconstitutionally and indefensibly distorts the definition of marriage;</li> <li>states may refuse to be bound by the holding in <em>Obergefell</em>;</li> <li>states are not required to license same-sex marriage or recognize same-sex marriages performed in other states; and</li> <li>&nbsp;individuals, businesses, churches, religious groups, and other faith-based organizations are encouraged, empowered, and protected to exercise their faith without fear of legal or government interference.</li></ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
