<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hres" measure-number="853" measure-id="id114hres853" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-09-08" update-date="2016-10-28">
<title>Authorizing the Speaker of the House of Representatives to initiate or intervene in a civil action regarding the compliance of the executive branch with the provision of law prohibiting relinquishment of the responsibility of the National Telecommunications and Information Administration with respect to Internet domain name system functions.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hres853v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-10-28">
<action-date>2016-09-08</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Authorizes the Speaker of the House of Representatives to initiate or intervene in civil actions in a federal court of competent jurisdiction to seek appropriate relief regarding the failure of the President, any department or agency head, or any other executive branch officer or employee to act in a manner consistent with that official's duties with respect to the implementation of provisions of the Commerce, Justice, Science, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2016, or any related provision, regarding the relinquishment of the National Telecommunications and Information Administration's responsibility with respect to Internet domain name system functions.</p> <p>The Speaker shall notify the House of any decision to initiate or intervene in any such civil action.</p> <p>The House's Office of the General Counsel, at the direction of the Speaker, shall represent the House in any such civil action and may employ the services of outside counsel and other experts. The chair of the Committee on House Administration shall publish in the Congressional Record a statement setting forth the aggregate amounts expended by the Office on outside counsel and other experts for each calendar quarter.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
