<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hres" measure-number="739" measure-id="id114hres739" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-05-18" update-date="2016-05-27">
<title>Reaffirming the commitment of the United States to the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO).</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hres739v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-05-27">
<action-date>2016-05-18</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that: (1) the United States reaffirms its commitment to the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) as the foundation of transatlantic security and defense, (2) NATO serves as a critical coalition in preserving transatlantic peace and stability, and (3) NATO's continuing development of new capabilities and technologies to combat terrorism and a changing international security environment are crucial to enhancing national security and strengthening the ability of the United States to combat security threats. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
