<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hres" measure-number="196" measure-id="id114hres196" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-04-13" update-date="2015-04-16">
<title>Condemning the recent terrorist attacks in Tunis that resulted in the tragic loss of 21 innocent lives.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hres196v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-04-16">
<action-date>2015-04-13</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Condemns the recent terrorist attacks in Tunis, Tunisia, that resulted in the loss of 21 innocent lives, and extends sympathies to all those affected by this tragedy. </p> <p>Expresses solidarity with the people of Tunisia and pays tribute to our shared values and liberties. </p> <p>Encourages Tunisians to stand together in opposition to extremism and violence. </p> <p>Supports the government of Tunisia's efforts to ensure that those individuals who committed or supported these attacks are brought to justice. </p> <p>Reaffirms the commitment of the United States to work with Tunisia to fight against violent extremists. </p> <p>Affirms the U.S. commitment to strengthening our bilateral relationship and engaging in a strategic partnership with Tunisia.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
