<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hres" measure-number="850" measure-id="id114hres850" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-09-08" update-date="2016-09-15">
<title>Recognizing suicide as a public health problem and expressing support for designation of September as "National Suicide Prevention Month".</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hres850v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-09-15">
<action-date>2016-09-08</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Expresses support for the designation of National Suicide Prevention Month.</p> <p>Recognizes suicide as a preventable public health problem and supports declaring that suicide prevention should be a priority.</p> Promotes awareness that suicide most often occurs when stressors exceed the current coping abilities of an individual suffering from a mental health condition.]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
