<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hres" measure-number="295" measure-id="id114hres295" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-06-03" update-date="2015-06-16">
<title>Supporting local law enforcement agencies in their continued work to serve our communities, and supporting their use of body worn cameras to promote transparency to protect both citizens and officers alike.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hres295v81" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-06-16">
<action-date>2015-06-10</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.)</p> <p>Recognizes: (1) law enforcement agencies and officers for protecting us and making our communities safer; and (2) the potential for the use of body-worn cameras by on-duty law enforcement officers to improve community relations, increase transparency, and protect citizens and police.</p> <p>Encourages law enforcement agencies to consider the use of body-worn cameras. </p> <ul> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id114hres295v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-06-08">
<action-date>2015-06-03</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Recognizes: (1) law enforcement agencies and officers for protecting us and making our communities safer; and (2) the potential for the use of body-worn cameras by on-duty law enforcement officers to improve community relations, increase transparency, and protect citizens and police.</p> <p>Encourages law enforcement agencies to consider the use of body-worn cameras. </p> <ul> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
