<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hres" measure-number="485" measure-id="id114hres485" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2015-10-21" update-date="2015-10-23">
<title>Expressing solidarity with the people of Israel in the wake of recent terrorist attacks and condemning the Palestinian Authority for inciting an atmosphere of violence.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hres485v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2015-10-23">
<action-date>2015-10-21</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Expresses support for the recent terrorism victims and their families in Israel, the people of Israel, and the government of Israel.</p> <p> Condemns terrorism committed under the auspices of the Palestinian Authority (PA), and calls on Palestinian leaders to cease supporting or allowing terrorist activities in Israel.</p> <p> Urges the President to condemn the attacks carried out against innocent Israelis and freeze U.S. funding to the PA until their leaders openly increase efforts to end their incitement of violence.</p> <p> Expresses concern about the use of national security waivers to continue supplying aid to the PA.</p> <p>Demands as a condition of continued U.S. aid that the President re-certify that the PA government and all its ministers have publicly accepted and are complying with the principles which demand the recognition of Israel's right to exist and the acceptance of previous Israeli-Palestinian agreements. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
