<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hres" measure-number="805" measure-id="id114hres805" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-07-05" update-date="2016-07-11">
<title>Supporting the goals and ideals of "National Latino AIDS Awareness Day" on October 15, 2016, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hres805v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-07-11">
<action-date>2016-07-05</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Expresses support for: (1) the goals and ideals of National Latino AIDS Awareness Day; (2) the implementation of the National HIV/AIDS Strategy; (3) effective and comprehensive HIV prevention education programs; (4) appropriate funding of HIV/AIDS prevention, care, treatment, research, and housing; and (5) a comprehensive prevention and treatment strategy that empowers stakeholders to engage their communities to help decrease violence, discrimination, and stigma towards individuals who disclose their sexual orientation or HIV status and to normalize voluntary testing practices.</p> <p>Encourages individuals, especially Latinos, to get tested for HIV.</p> <p>Commends the work of organizations providing services to people living with and vulnerable to HIV/AIDS.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
