<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="114" measure-type="hres" measure-number="861" measure-id="id114hres861" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2016-09-12" update-date="2016-10-28">
<title>Supporting respect for human rights and encouraging inclusive governance in Ethiopia.</title>
<summary summary-id="id114hres861v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2016-10-28">
<action-date>2016-09-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>Condemns: (1) the killing of peaceful protesters and excessive use of force by Ethiopian security forces; (2) the detention of journalists, students, activists and political leaders who exercise their constitutional rights to freedom of assembly and expression through peaceful protests; and (3) the abuse of the Anti-Terrorism Proclamation to stifle political and civil dissent and journalistic freedoms. </p> <p>Urges protesters in Ethiopia to refrain from violence.</p> <p>Calls on the government of Ethiopia to:</p> <ul> <li>end the use of excessive force by security forces; </li> <li>investigate the killings and excessive use of force that took place as a result of protests in the Oromia and Amhara regions; </li> <li>release dissidents, activists, and journalists who have been imprisoned for exercising constitutional rights;</li> <li>respect the right to peaceful assembly and guarantee freedom of the press;</li> <li> engage in open consultations with citizens regarding its development strategy;</li> <li>allow a United Nations rapporteur to conduct an independent examination of the state of human rights in Ethiopia; and</li> <li>investigate and report on the circumstances surrounding the September 3, 2016, shootings and fire at Qilinto Prison.</li> </ul> <p>Calls on such government to repeal proclamations that:</p> <ul> <li>can be used to harass or prohibit funding for organizations that investigate human rights violations, engage in peaceful political dissent, or advocate for greater political freedoms;</li> <li>prohibit those displaced from their land from seeking judicial redress;</li> <li>permit the detention of peaceful protesters and political opponents who legally exercise their rights to freedom of expression and association; and</li> <li> limit peaceful nonprofit operations in Ethiopia. </li> </ul> <p>Calls on: (1) the Department of State to review security assistance, and improve oversight of U.S. assistance, to Ethiopia; and (2) the U.S. Agency for International Development to lead efforts to develop a strategy to support improved democracy and governance in Ethiopia. </p> <p>Supports the peaceful efforts of the Ethiopian people to exercise their constitutional rights.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
